<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Bayesian beagle</title>
<link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Quarto blog of LLM-generated summaries of Arxiv preprints</description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.450</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Have Seen Me Before? Automating Dataset Updates Towards Reliable and Timely Evaluation</title>
  <dc:creator>Jiahao Ying, Yixin Cao, Bo Wang, Wei Tang, Yizhe Yang, Shuicheng Yan</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Have_Seen_Me_Before_Automating_Dataset_Updates_Towards_Reliable_and_Timely_Evaluation/2024-02-19-Have_Seen_Me_Before_Automating_Dataset_Updates_Towards_Reliable_and_Timely_Evaluation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.11894v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article discusses the challenges faced by Large Language Models (LLMs) in evaluating datasets due to data leakage and the high cost of manual dataset curation. The authors propose to automate dataset updates for reliable and timely evaluation by generating unseen and high-quality testing samples based on existing ones to mitigate leakage issues. They introduce two strategies: mimicking and extending, which were verified through experiments to be effective in dealing with data leakage issues. The section also evaluates the performance of baseline models on original and mimicked datasets, the impact of cognitive levels and seed popularity on model performance, and the validation and evaluation process for the mimicked and extended benchmarks. Additionally, it provides a comprehensive evaluation of the responses to specific questions related to mathematical and statistical concepts.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The mimicking and extending strategies effectively mitigate data leakage issues and provide a balanced difficulty of datasets for fair and fine-grained analysis.</li>
<li>The impact of cognitive levels and seed popularity on model performance is significant, with more popular seeds leading to better model performance.</li>
<li>The human evaluation results validate the reliability and effectiveness of the framework in automatic question generation, demonstrating high scores for fluency, coherence, and answer accuracy.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The proposed strategies for automating dataset updates offer a practical solution with minimal human effort, but data leakage issues still impact model performance.</li>
<li>The findings on the impact of cognitive levels and seed popularity on model performance contribute to a better understanding of how to control the difficulty of generated questions and ensure the quality of extended datasets.</li>
<li>The high scores obtained in the human evaluation results validate the reliability and effectiveness of the framework in automatic question generation, underscoring the significance of the section in demonstrating the robustness and accuracy of the question generation process.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-20</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.11894v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.11894v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.11894v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.11894v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>21484</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Have_Seen_Me_Before_Automating_Dataset_Updates_Towards_Reliable_and_Timely_Evaluation/2024-02-19-Have_Seen_Me_Before_Automating_Dataset_Updates_Towards_Reliable_and_Timely_Evaluation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.11894v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>BIDER: Bridging Knowledge Inconsistency for Efficient Retrieval-Augmented LLMs via Key Supporting Evidence</title>
  <dc:creator>Jiajie Jin, Yutao Zhu, Yujia Zhou, Zhicheng Dou</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/BIDER_Bridging_Knowledge_Inconsistency_for_Efficient_Retrieval_Augmented_LLMs_via_Key_Supporting_Evidence/2024-02-19-BIDER_Bridging_Knowledge_Inconsistency_for_Efficient_Retrieval_Augmented_LLMs_via_Key_Supporting_Evidence.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/BIDER_Bridging_Knowledge_Inconsistency_for_Efficient_Retrieval_Augmented_LLMs_via_Key_Supporting_Evidence/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12174v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>BIDER is a method that refines retrieval documents into Key Supporting Evidence (KSE) through knowledge synthesis, supervised fine-tuning, and preference alignment.</li>
<li>The approach boosts LLMs’ answer quality by 7% while reducing input content length in retrieval documents by 80%, outperforming existing methods.</li>
<li>The proposed KSE simulation effectively equips LLMs with essential information for accurate question answering.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>BIDER refines retrieval documents into KSE through knowledge synthesis, supervised fine-tuning, and preference alignment.</li>
<li>The approach boosts LLMs’ answer quality by 7% while reducing input content length in retrieval documents by 80%, outperforming existing methods.</li>
<li>The proposed KSE simulation effectively equips LLMs with essential information for accurate question answering.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The method performs less effectively in complex datasets like HotpotQA compared with NQ and TQA, suggesting that additional factors need to be considered for complex tasks.</li>
<li>BIDER requires separate training for each dataset and generator, limiting its use across different tasks and generators.</li>
<li>The datasets are based solely on Wikipedia, while real-world RAG applications involve diverse sources with varied writing styles, which may require further refinement.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-20</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12174v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12174v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12174v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12174v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5963</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/BIDER_Bridging_Knowledge_Inconsistency_for_Efficient_Retrieval_Augmented_LLMs_via_Key_Supporting_Evidence/2024-02-19-BIDER_Bridging_Knowledge_Inconsistency_for_Efficient_Retrieval_Augmented_LLMs_via_Key_Supporting_Evidence.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12174v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Your Large Language Model is Secretly a Fairness Proponent and You Should Prompt it Like One</title>
  <dc:creator>Tianlin Li, Xiaoyu Zhang, Chao Du, Tianyu Pang, Qian Liu, Qing Guo, Chao Shen, Yang Liu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Your_Large_Language_Model_is_Secretly_a_Fairness_Proponent_and_You_Should_Prompt_it_Like_One/2024-02-19-Your_Large_Language_Model_is_Secretly_a_Fairness_Proponent_and_You_Should_Prompt_it_Like_One.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Your_Large_Language_Model_is_Secretly_a_Fairness_Proponent_and_You_Should_Prompt_it_Like_One/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12150v1/x2.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article introduces FairThinking, a pipeline designed to prompt large language models (LLMs) with specific roles to elicit diverse viewpoints for fair expressions. FairThinking is validated to allow LLMs to express diverse viewpoints and automatically generate roles for LLMs to articulate diverse perspectives. It is evaluated on GPT-3.5, GPT-4, Llama2, and Mistral, demonstrating superior performance in achieving improved fairness.</li>
<li>Questions are categorized into Comparative Questions, Targeted Open-Ended Questions, and General Open-Ended Questions based on the number of demographic parties mentioned. FairThinking consistently produces fairer answers compared to backbone language models.</li>
<li>Human studies evaluate the quality of questions generated by BiasAsker and Comparative Questions, as well as the ability of LLMs to provide fair answers and perspectives. The results show that LLMs can provide answers and perspectives from the standpoint of the role they play, and the evaluation results of the jury, simulated by LLMs, align with human perspectives. Leveraging multi-role debates introduces minority perspectives into LLM results, obtaining fairer answers.</li>
<li>The roles and personalities of the jurors and debaters in a debate on gender equality in the workplace are described, highlighting the diverse perspectives and beliefs of the participants.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>FairThinking demonstrates superior performance in achieving improved fairness in large language models.</li>
<li>Questions categorized by FairThinking consistently produce fairer answers compared to backbone language models.</li>
<li>Leveraging multi-role debates introduces minority perspectives into LLM results, obtaining fairer answers.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides valuable insights into addressing the prevalent issue of unfairness in large language models and demonstrates the significance of FairThinking in mitigating bias and promoting fairness.</li>
<li>The study highlights the importance of considering diverse perspectives for fair and unbiased expressions, especially in addressing societal issues and promoting diverse viewpoints.</li>
<li>The diverse perspectives and beliefs of the participants in the debate on gender equality in the workplace underscore the complexity of the issue and the importance of personal experiences and role models in shaping individuals’ beliefs and advocacy for gender equality.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-20</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12150v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12150v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12150v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12150v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>17302</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Your_Large_Language_Model_is_Secretly_a_Fairness_Proponent_and_You_Should_Prompt_it_Like_One/2024-02-19-Your_Large_Language_Model_is_Secretly_a_Fairness_Proponent_and_You_Should_Prompt_it_Like_One.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12150v1/x2.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Explain then Rank: Scale Calibration of Neural Rankers Using Natural Language Explanations from Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Puxuan Yu, Daniel Cohen, Hemank Lamba, Joel Tetreault, Alex Jaimes</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Explain_then_Rank_Scale_Calibration_of_Neural_Rankers_Using_Natural_Language_Explanations_from_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-19-Explain_then_Rank_Scale_Calibration_of_Neural_Rankers_Using_Natural_Language_Explanations_from_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Explain_then_Rank_Scale_Calibration_of_Neural_Rankers_Using_Natural_Language_Explanations_from_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12276v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article discusses the process of scale calibration in ranking systems and the challenges of adjusting the scale for neural rankers.</li>
<li>The study explores the potential of large language models (LLMs) to provide uncertainty measurements for a query and document pair that correlate with the scale-calibrated scores.</li>
<li>By employing Monte Carlo sampling to gauge relevance probabilities from LLMs and incorporating natural language explanations (NLEs) to articulate this uncertainty, the study carries out comprehensive tests on two major document ranking datasets.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The study reveals that the approach leveraging NLEs outperforms existing calibration methods under various training scenarios, leading to better calibrated neural rankers.</li>
<li>NLE-based approaches consistently surpass the performance of neural models that process raw text queries and documents, across different training objectives.</li>
<li>The aggregate MC method substantially surpasses the use of only the most probable explanation in both ranking and scale calibration, across both literal and conditional explanation setups.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The study effectively demonstrates the effectiveness of NLEs generated by LLMs in enhancing the scale calibration of neural rankers, often maintaining or even boosting ranking performance in most scenarios.</li>
<li>The study highlights the limitations of the expected calibration error (ECE) metric and proposes the adoption of class-balanced ECE (CB-ECE) to address the bias in using ECE for scale calibration data.</li>
<li>A case study demonstrates the superior effectiveness of the NLE-based methods in assessing the relevance of a query to a specific document, attributing the improvement to the deeper contextual understanding provided by LLM-generated NLEs.</li>
<li>Future research could focus on increasing the efficiency of NLE generation through techniques like distillation and enhancing the reliability of explanations to develop better calibrated rankers.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-20</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12276v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12276v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12276v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12276v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>9445</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Explain_then_Rank_Scale_Calibration_of_Neural_Rankers_Using_Natural_Language_Explanations_from_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-19-Explain_then_Rank_Scale_Calibration_of_Neural_Rankers_Using_Natural_Language_Explanations_from_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12276v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Structured Chain-of-Thought Prompting for Few-Shot Generation of Content-Grounded QA Conversations</title>
  <dc:creator>Md Arafat Sultan, Jatin Ganhotra, Ramón Fernandez Astudillo</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Structured_Chain_of_Thought_Prompting_for_Few_Shot_Generation_of_Content_Grounded_QA_Conversations/2024-02-19-Structured_Chain_of_Thought_Prompting_for_Few_Shot_Generation_of_Content_Grounded_QA_Conversations.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/../bayesian-beagle.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article introduces a structured chain-of-thought (SCoT) prompting approach to generating content-grounded multi-turn question-answer conversations using a pre-trained large language model (LLM).</li>
<li>The proposal is based on a structured breakdown of the complex task into a number of states in a state machine, allowing for actions corresponding to various subtasks to be executed in their own dedicated states.</li>
<li>The experimental results show that SCoT prompting</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-20</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.11770v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.11770v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.11770v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.11770v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>15974</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Structured_Chain_of_Thought_Prompting_for_Few_Shot_Generation_of_Content_Grounded_QA_Conversations/2024-02-19-Structured_Chain_of_Thought_Prompting_for_Few_Shot_Generation_of_Content_Grounded_QA_Conversations.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Is Open-Source There Yet? A Comparative Study on Commercial and Open-Source LLMs in Their Ability to Label Chest X-Ray Reports</title>
  <dc:creator>Felix J. Dorfner, Liv Jürgensen, Leonhard Donle, Fares Al Mohamad, Tobias R. Bodenmann, Mason C. Cleveland, Felix Busch, Lisa C. Adams, James Sato, Thomas Schultz, Albert E. Kim, Jameson Merkow, Keno K. Bressem, Christopher P. Bridge</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Is_Open_Source_There_Yet_A_Comparative_Study_on_Commercial_and_Open_Source_LLMs_in_Their_Ability_to_Label_Chest_X_Ray_Reports/2024-02-19-Is_Open_Source_There_Yet_A_Comparative_Study_on_Commercial_and_Open_Source_LLMs_in_Their_Ability_to_Label_Chest_X_Ray_Reports.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.12298v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The study compared the performance of commercial and open-source large language models (LLMs) in labeling chest x-ray reports.</li>
<li>Two datasets were used, one from Massachusetts General Hospital and the other from the ImaGenome dataset.</li>
<li>The study found that open-source LLMs performed comparably to GPT-4 in labeling chest x-ray reports, especially with few-shot prompting.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Comparison of Zero-Shot Prompting:</strong>
<ul>
<li>GPT-4 outperformed open-source models on the ImaGenome dataset, achieving a micro F1-score of 0.975.</li>
<li>Llama2-70B was the best performing open-source model with a micro F1-score of 0.972.</li>
<li>On the institutional dataset, GPT-4 achieved a micro F1-score of 0.975, while QWEN1.5-72B and Llama2-70B achieved micro F1-scores of 0.952 and 0.950, respectively.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Comparison of Few-Shot Prompting:</strong>
<ul>
<li>GPT-4 achieved a micro F1-score of 0.984 on the ImaGenome dataset, while Llama2-70B achieved a micro F1-score of 0.970.</li>
<li>On the institutional dataset, GPT-4 achieved a micro F1-score of 0.973, while QWEN1.5-72B, Llama2-70B, and Mixtral-8x7B achieved micro F1-scores of 0.965, 0.965, and 0.963, respectively.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Ensemble Model Performance:</strong>
<ul>
<li>An ensemble model of Mixtral-8x7B, Llama2-70B, and QWEN1.5-72B closely matched the performance of GPT-4 on the institutional dataset with few-shot prompts, achieving a micro F1-score of 0.971.</li>
</ul></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The study demonstrated that open-source LLMs are a viable alternative to proprietary models for medical tasks such as radiology report classification.</li>
<li>Open-source LLMs offer cost advantages, privacy, and reproducibility over proprietary models.</li>
<li>The study had limitations related to prompt design and class imbalances in the datasets, which could impact model performance.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the study provides valuable insights into the performance of open-source LLMs in medical tasks and highlights their potential as an alternative to proprietary models. Further research is needed to optimize prompt design and address class imbalances in datasets.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-20</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12298v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12298v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12298v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12298v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>14656</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Is_Open_Source_There_Yet_A_Comparative_Study_on_Commercial_and_Open_Source_LLMs_in_Their_Ability_to_Label_Chest_X_Ray_Reports/2024-02-19-Is_Open_Source_There_Yet_A_Comparative_Study_on_Commercial_and_Open_Source_LLMs_in_Their_Ability_to_Label_Chest_X_Ray_Reports.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.12298v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>CovRL: Fuzzing JavaScript Engines with Coverage-Guided Reinforcement Learning for LLM-based Mutation</title>
  <dc:creator>Jueon Eom, Seyeon Jeong, Taekyoung Kwon</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/CovRL_Fuzzing_JavaScript_Engines_with_Coverage_Guided_Reinforcement_Learning_for_LLM_based_Mutation/2024-02-19-CovRL_Fuzzing_JavaScript_Engines_with_Coverage_Guided_Reinforcement_Learning_for_LLM_based_Mutation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.12222v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper introduces CovRL-Fuzz, a novel technique that combines Large Language Models (LLMs) with reinforcement learning from coverage feedback to improve fuzzing for JavaScript engines.</li>
<li>CovRL-Fuzz outperforms existing fuzzers in terms of code coverage and bug-finding capabilities, identifying 48 real-world security-related bugs, including 39 previously unknown vulnerabilities and 11 CVEs.</li>
<li>The implementation of CovRL-Fuzz involves context-aware mutations, coverage-weighted rewarding, and finetuning using the Proximal Policy Optimization (PPO) algorithm, demonstrating its effectiveness in achieving high code coverage and bug detection.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>CovRL-Fuzz significantly outperforms existing fuzzers in identifying real-world security-related bugs, including previously unknown vulnerabilities.</li>
<li>The use of context-aware mutations and coverage-weighted rewarding in CovRL-Fuzz improves code coverage and minimizes syntax and semantic errors.</li>
<li>The finetuning of CovRL-Fuzz using the PPO algorithm demonstrates its effectiveness in enhancing automated testing and bug-finding processes.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The introduction of CovRL-Fuzz represents a significant advancement in the field of fuzzing, particularly for JavaScript engines, and has the potential to enhance automated testing and bug-finding processes.</li>
<li>The section on the design of CovRL-Fuzz provides a detailed description of the technique’s workflow and components, highlighting its technical sophistication and potential for improving fuzzing processes.</li>
<li>The implementation and evaluation of CovRL-Fuzz demonstrate its effectiveness in achieving high code coverage, low error rates, and bug detection, setting a new standard for fuzzing techniques in JavaScript engines.</li>
<li>The results of the manual analysis and ablation study confirm the superiority of CovRL-Fuzz in discovering unique bugs and achieving higher coverage improvements, further emphasizing its significance in bug detection and software testing.</li>
<li>The identification of specific vulnerabilities in JavaScript engines underscores the importance of understanding and mitigating potential security risks associated with these engines.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-20</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12222v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12222v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12222v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12222v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>22740</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/CovRL_Fuzzing_JavaScript_Engines_with_Coverage_Guided_Reinforcement_Learning_for_LLM_based_Mutation/2024-02-19-CovRL_Fuzzing_JavaScript_Engines_with_Coverage_Guided_Reinforcement_Learning_for_LLM_based_Mutation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.12222v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Do Large Language Models Understand Logic or Just Mimick Context?</title>
  <dc:creator>Junbing Yan, Chengyu Wang, Jun Huang, Wei Zhang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Do_Large_Language_Models_Understand_Logic_or_Just_Mimick_Context/2024-02-19-Do_Large_Language_Models_Understand_Logic_or_Just_Mimick_Context.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/../bayesian-beagle.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Large language models (LLMs) have received extensive attention for their exceptional performance in logical reasoning and symbolic inference.</li>
<li>This paper investigates the reasoning capabilities of LLMs on two logical reasoning datasets using counterfactual methods to replace context text and modify logical concepts.</li>
<li>The findings suggest that LLMs do not truly understand logical rules; rather, in-context learning has simply enhanced the likelihood of these models arriving at the correct answers.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The Chain of Thought (COT) in-context examples markedly improve the performance of large-scale models on logical reasoning tasks.</li>
<li>Large models demonstrate resilience to distracting elements within in-context examples, such as extraneous text, reasoning chains, and patterns.</li>
<li>Large models do not genuinely comprehend logical principles; rather, they rely on probabilistic associations between input examples and outputs.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The study highlights the limitations of LLMs in truly understanding logical rules, despite their exceptional performance in logical reasoning tasks.</li>
<li>The findings suggest that the success of LLMs in logical reasoning tasks may be attributed to in-context learning and probabilistic associations rather than genuine comprehension of logical principles.</li>
<li>The study raises questions about the effectiveness of current pre-training mechanisms for LLMs in addressing logical reasoning tasks and suggests the need for alternative pre-training strategies tailored to these requirements.</li>
<li>The paper also explores methods to enhance the model’s logical reasoning capabilities independent of context-based examples, providing insights for future research in this area.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-20</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12091v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12091v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12091v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12091v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>12694</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Do_Large_Language_Models_Understand_Logic_or_Just_Mimick_Context/2024-02-19-Do_Large_Language_Models_Understand_Logic_or_Just_Mimick_Context.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Microstructures and Accuracy of Graph Recall by Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Yanbang Wang, Hejie Cui, Jon Kleinberg</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Microstructures_and_Accuracy_of_Graph_Recall_by_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-19-Microstructures_and_Accuracy_of_Graph_Recall_by_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.11821v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article investigates the accuracy of graph recall by Large Language Models (LLMs) and highlights the challenges faced by LLMs in accurately recalling and encoding graphs described in text.</li>
<li>It discusses the methodology and results of a study on the accuracy of graph recall by LLMs, indicating that LLMs underperform in the graph recall test and tend to forget edges rather than hallucinate them.</li>
<li>The section also explores the correlation between the performance of LLMs in graph recall and link prediction tasks, emphasizing the significance of understanding LLM’s graph reasoning abilities.</li>
<li>Additionally, it highlights the development of datasets and frameworks to integrate graphs with LLMs and the lack of studies addressing the basic question of whether LLMs can accurately remember the graph they are supposed to reason upon.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs underperform in graph recall and exhibit biased microstructures, which could have implications for their performance in more complex graph reasoning tasks.</li>
<li>LLMs struggle with accurately recalling graph structures, and the study raises questions about the impact of memory clearance and sex priming on LLMs’ graph recall performance.</li>
<li>LLM’s behavior in different graph reasoning tasks can be subtly revealed by examining their microstructural patterns, which is crucial for leveraging LLMs to advance the field of Graph Machine Learning.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The findings of the article have implications for improving LLMs’ ability to reason on graphs and understanding the mechanisms of their information decoding and recall.</li>
<li>The lack of existing literature addressing the accuracy of graph recall by LLMs is highlighted, indicating a gap in research that needs to be addressed.</li>
<li>The lack of coherence in one of the sections makes it difficult to discern any significance or implications of its content in the broader context of the paper.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-20</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.11821v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.11821v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.11821v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.11821v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>20039</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Microstructures_and_Accuracy_of_Graph_Recall_by_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-19-Microstructures_and_Accuracy_of_Graph_Recall_by_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.11821v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Shall We Talk: Exploring Spontaneous Collaborations of Competing LLM Agents</title>
  <dc:creator>Zengqing Wu, Shuyuan Zheng, Qianying Liu, Xu Han, Brian Inhyuk Kwon, Makoto Onizuka, Shaojie Tang, Run Peng, Chuan Xiao</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Shall_We_Talk_Exploring_Spontaneous_Collaborations_of_Competing_LLM_Agents/2024-02-19-Shall_We_Talk_Exploring_Spontaneous_Collaborations_of_Competing_LLM_Agents.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/../bayesian-beagle.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The article explores the spontaneous collaborations of competing large language model (LLM) agents in various scenarios, including Keynesian Beauty Contest (KBC), Bertrand Competition (BC), and Emergency Evacuation (EE). The study reveals that LLM agents are capable of spontaneously forming collaborations even within competitive settings, demonstrating their capacity to mimic competition and cooperation in human societies.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>KBC:</strong>
<ul>
<li>LLM agents possess the ability to initiate spontaneous collaboration within competitive tasks via textual communication.</li>
<li>Spontaneous collaborations among LLM agents underscore their deep comprehension of competitive tasks and their capacity to pursue collaboration in competitive settings, crucial for accurately simulating social phenomena.</li>
<li>Personas play a significant role in shaping the spontaneous cooperative behaviors of LLM agents.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>BC:</strong>
<ul>
<li>LLM agents exhibit spontaneous collusion and tacit agreements, leading to higher profits and cartel-like behavior.</li>
<li>Communication between LLM agents enhances trust and reduces the likelihood of triggering a price war, leading to increased profits.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>EE:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Communication among evacuees speeds up their evacuation, making it more stable and orderly.</li>
<li>Information sharing and encouragement among evacuees help quickly find the appropriate exit and provide emotional support.</li>
</ul></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study provides valuable insights into the capabilities of LLM agents in simulating human social interactions, including spontaneous collaborations. However, the article does not address potential biases or limitations of using LLM agents in social simulations.</li>
<li>The preliminary tests of other LLMs, such as GPT-3.5, Gemini Pro, and Claude 2, indicate that they are not suitable for simulating the scenarios studied in the article.</li>
<li>The parameter settings of the GPT-4 model are well-suited for each scenario, balancing randomness and stability based on the specific requirements of each case study.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the article provides a comprehensive exploration of the capabilities of LLM agents in simulating spontaneous collaborations in competitive scenarios, offering valuable insights for computational social science. However, further research is needed to address potential biases and limitations of using LLM agents in social simulations.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-20</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12327v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12327v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12327v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12327v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>15395</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Shall_We_Talk_Exploring_Spontaneous_Collaborations_of_Competing_LLM_Agents/2024-02-19-Shall_We_Talk_Exploring_Spontaneous_Collaborations_of_Competing_LLM_Agents.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Distilling Large Language Models for Text-Attributed Graph Learning</title>
  <dc:creator>Bo Pan, Zheng Zhang, Yifei Zhang, Yuntong Hu, Liang Zhao</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Distilling_Large_Language_Models_for_Text_Attributed_Graph_Learning/2024-02-19-Distilling_Large_Language_Models_for_Text_Attributed_Graph_Learning.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.12022v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The academic article discusses the development of a framework to distill Large Language Models (LLMs) for Text-Attributed Graph (TAG) learning. The proposed framework aims to synergize LLMs and graph models by distilling the power of LLMs to a local graph model on TAG learning. The article presents a novel framework for distilling LLMs’ knowledge to graph models for TAG learning, which involves an intermediate interpreter model that bridges the LLM and the student model. The proposed method consistently outperforms the baseline methods by an average improvement of 1.25% across four datasets.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Text-Attributed Graphs (TAGs):</strong> TAGs are graphs of connected textual documents, which have been predominantly utilized across various domains, including citation networks, e-commerce networks, social media, recommendation systems, and web page analytics.</li>
<li><strong>Large Language Models (LLMs):</strong> LLMs have demonstrated remarkable capabilities in few-shot and zero-shot TAG learning, but they suffer from scalability, cost, and privacy issues.</li>
<li><strong>Proposed Framework:</strong> The proposed framework for distilling LLMs’ knowledge to graph models for TAG learning involves an intermediate interpreter model that bridges the LLM and the student model. The method consistently outperforms the baseline methods by an average improvement of 1.25% across four datasets.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The proposed framework demonstrates significant improvements in TAG learning, but it is influenced by the design of prompts for the LLM, potentially affecting the quality of generated rationales.</li>
<li>The capabilities of LLMs also influence the correctness of the prediction and rationales, and high-capability LLMs are required for the distillation framework to generate reasonable rationales.</li>
<li>The article does not address potential ethical considerations related to the use of LLMs and the privacy concerns associated with the deployment, fine-tuning, and maintenance of LLMs.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the article provides a comprehensive framework for distilling LLMs for TAG learning, but it is essential to consider the potential limitations and ethical implications of using LLMs for this purpose. Further research is needed to address these concerns and enhance the practical applicability of the proposed framework.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-20</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12022v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12022v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12022v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12022v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>12730</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Distilling_Large_Language_Models_for_Text_Attributed_Graph_Learning/2024-02-19-Distilling_Large_Language_Models_for_Text_Attributed_Graph_Learning.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.12022v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>ArtPrompt: ASCII Art-based Jailbreak Attacks against Aligned LLMs</title>
  <dc:creator>Fengqing Jiang, Zhangchen Xu, Luyao Niu, Zhen Xiang, Bhaskar Ramasubramanian, Bo Li, Radha Poovendran</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ArtPrompt_ASCII_Art_based_Jailbreak_Attacks_against_Aligned_LLMs/2024-02-19-ArtPrompt_ASCII_Art_based_Jailbreak_Attacks_against_Aligned_LLMs.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.11753v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The article discusses the development of the ArtPrompt jailbreak attack, which exploits vulnerabilities in large language models (LLMs) to bypass safety measures and provoke unintended and unsafe behaviors. The attack leverages the weaknesses of LLMs in recognizing certain words, substituting them with ASCII art to increase the probability of bypassing safety measures. The authors propose a benchmark, Vision-in-Text Challenge (VITC), to evaluate the capabilities of LLMs in recognizing prompts that cannot be solely interpreted by semantics. Experimental evaluations demonstrate that ArtPrompt is effective against various victim LLMs, outperforming existing jailbreak attacks in terms of helpful rate, harmfulness score, and attack success rate. The section also provides detailed setups for baseline jailbreak attacks, defense settings, and experimental results on font recognition by different LLMs.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The ArtPrompt jailbreak attack effectively bypasses safety measures and induces undesired behaviors from LLMs.</li>
<li>Experimental evaluations demonstrate the superiority of ArtPrompt over other jailbreak attacks in terms of helpful rate, harmfulness score, and attack success rate.</li>
<li>The choice of font and arrangement of ASCII art significantly impact the effectiveness of the ArtPrompt attack.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The vulnerabilities of LLMs exposed by the ArtPrompt attack have significant implications for the safety and security of LLMs in real-world applications.</li>
<li>The study underscores the need for robust defenses to mitigate the impact of jailbreak attacks on LLMs.</li>
<li>The findings contribute to understanding the vulnerabilities and defenses of large language models against jailbreaking attacks.</li>
<li>The ethical statement emphasizes the potential misuse of the vulnerabilities and the responsible dissemination of the code and prompts used in the experiments to the community for further research and red-teaming of LLMs.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-20</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.11753v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.11753v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.11753v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.11753v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>17374</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ArtPrompt_ASCII_Art_based_Jailbreak_Attacks_against_Aligned_LLMs/2024-02-19-ArtPrompt_ASCII_Art_based_Jailbreak_Attacks_against_Aligned_LLMs.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.11753v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Enhancing Large Language Models for Text-to-Testcase Generation</title>
  <dc:creator>Saranya Alagarsamy, Chakkrit Tantithamthavorn, Chetan Arora, Aldeida Aleti</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Enhancing_Large_Language_Models_for_Text_to_Testcase_Generation/2024-02-19-Enhancing_Large_Language_Models_for_Text_to_Testcase_Generation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Enhancing_Large_Language_Models_for_Text_to_Testcase_Generation/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.11910v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article introduces a text-to-testcase generation approach based on a fine-tuned large language model with an effective prompting design.</li>
<li>The approach substantially outperforms other large language models (LLMs) in generating test cases for open-source projects.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Effectiveness of the Proposed Approach:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The proposed approach outperforms all other LLMs, achieving 78.5% syntactic correctness, 67.09% requirement alignment, and 61.7% code coverage for generated test cases.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Effect of Fine-Tuning:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Fine-tuning the LLMs improves syntax correctness by 223%, requirement alignment by 164%, and code coverage by 153%.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Effect of Prompting:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Improved prompts substantially improve the performance of LLMs, increasing syntax correctness by 223%, requirement alignment by 164%, and code coverage by 153%.</li>
</ul></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Internal Validity:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The hyper-parameter optimization and potential training data leakage of LLMs could impact the study’s internal validity.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Construct Validity:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The subjectivity in prompt tuning and robustness may affect the study’s construct validity.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>External Validity:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The generalizability of the findings to other open-source projects could impact the study’s external validity.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>
<p>The study provides valuable insights into the effectiveness of fine-tuning and prompting for LLMs in text-to-testcase generation. However, potential threats to validity and generalizability should be considered in future research.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-20</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.11910v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.11910v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.11910v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.11910v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>9643</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Enhancing_Large_Language_Models_for_Text_to_Testcase_Generation/2024-02-19-Enhancing_Large_Language_Models_for_Text_to_Testcase_Generation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.11910v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Learning to Edit: Aligning LLMs with Knowledge Editing</title>
  <dc:creator>Yuxin Jiang, Yufei Wang, Chuhan Wu, Wanjun Zhong, Xingshan Zeng, Jiahui Gao, Liangyou Li, Xin Jiang, Lifeng Shang, Ruiming Tang, Qun Liu, Wei Wang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Learning_to_Edit_Aligning_LLMs_with_Knowledge_Editing/2024-02-19-Learning_to_Edit_Aligning_LLMs_with_Knowledge_Editing.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.11905v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The proposed Learning to Edit (LTE) framework aims to align large language models (LLMs) with knowledge editing through two phases: Alignment Phase and Inference Phase.</li>
<li>LTE outperforms existing methods in knowledge editing tasks, demonstrating robustness, minimal interference with general tasks, and rapid editing speeds.</li>
<li>Ethical standards and safeguards are crucial to prevent misuse and harmful outcomes in knowledge editing.</li>
<li>A threefold strategy enhances the fault tolerance of the retrieval model while maintaining single editing performance.</li>
<li>Table 9 presents a performance comparison on Single Editing, focusing on fluency, average edit success, portability, and locality.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LTE demonstrates superiority in knowledge editing performance, robustness, and rapid editing speeds.</li>
<li>Ethical standards and safeguards are crucial to prevent misuse and harmful outcomes in knowledge editing.</li>
<li>The threefold strategy enhances the fault tolerance of the retrieval model while maintaining single editing performance.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The proposed LTE framework offers a novel approach to knowledge editing, addressing the limitations of existing methods and demonstrating superior performance.</li>
<li>The results of the LTE method in knowledge editing tasks highlight its potential to establish a new state-of-the-art in knowledge editing.</li>
<li>Ethical standards and safeguards are essential to prevent harmful or inappropriate outputs in knowledge editing.</li>
<li>The threefold strategy presented in the article is crucial for improving the fault tolerance and robustness of the retrieval model while maintaining its performance.</li>
<li>The quantitative data in Table 9 provides essential insights into the effectiveness of the editing process in different aspects of text quality and adaptability.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-20</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.11905v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.11905v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.11905v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.11905v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>18854</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Learning_to_Edit_Aligning_LLMs_with_Knowledge_Editing/2024-02-19-Learning_to_Edit_Aligning_LLMs_with_Knowledge_Editing.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.11905v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>All Language Models Large and Small</title>
  <dc:creator>Zhixun Chen, Yali Du, David Mguni</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/All_Language_Models_Large_and_Small/2024-02-19-All_Language_Models_Large_and_Small.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.12061v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The Language Optimising Network Distribution (LONDI) framework aims to selectively employ large language models (LLMs) only where complex decision-making and reasoning are required while using low-resource LMs everywhere else.</li>
<li>The LONDI framework consists of two language models, an LM, a large LM (LLM), and a reinforcement learning module that uses switching controls to quickly learn in which system states to call the LLM.</li>
<li>The LONDI framework is tested in various tasks and is shown to significantly lower computational costs.</li>
<li>The section discusses the solution to Switcher’s problem and introduces the LONDI system, which aims to optimize the usage of the DEEPTHINK model while respecting a budget constraint on the number of allowed DEEPTHINK calls during training.</li>
<li>The LONDI system outperforms other systems and effectively manages computational resources while achieving high performance.</li>
<li>The section introduces the LONDI framework, which combines large language models (LLM) and language models (LM) to improve performance and reduce computational cost.</li>
<li>The budget-oriented variant, LONDI-B, offers increased control and precision and showcases performance improvements and computational cost decreases.</li>
<li>The section introduces the notation and proofs related to the contraction property of T and presents the three statements to be proven and then proceeds to prove them.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The LONDI framework significantly lowers computational costs while maintaining high performance.</li>
<li>LONDI outperforms other systems and effectively manages computational resources while achieving high performance.</li>
<li>The LONDI framework combines large language models to improve performance and reduce computational costs.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The LONDI framework demonstrates potential for practical applications by significantly reducing computational costs and preserving budgetary constraints on LLM calls.</li>
<li>The experiments conducted demonstrate the adaptability and robustness of LONDI in different environments and with varying components.</li>
<li>The section provides detailed proofs for Theorem 3, Proposition 1, and Theorem 2, contributing to the overall credibility and reliability of the research.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-20</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12061v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12061v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12061v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12061v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>16291</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/All_Language_Models_Large_and_Small/2024-02-19-All_Language_Models_Large_and_Small.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.12061v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Groot: Adversarial Testing for Generative Text-to-Image Models with Tree-based Semantic Transformation</title>
  <dc:creator>Yi Liu, Guowei Yang, Gelei Deng, Feiyue Chen, Yuqi Chen, Ling Shi, Tianwei Zhang, Yang Liu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Groot_Adversarial_Testing_for_Generative_Text_to_Image_Models_with_Tree_based_Semantic_Transformation/2024-02-19-Groot_Adversarial_Testing_for_Generative_Text_to_Image_Models_with_Tree_based_Semantic_Transformation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Groot_Adversarial_Testing_for_Generative_Text_to_Image_Models_with_Tree_based_Semantic_Transformation/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12100v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper introduces Groot, an automated framework for adversarial testing of text-to-image models, addressing the safety concerns of Not-Safe-For-Work (NSFW) content.</li>
<li>Groot leverages tree-based semantic transformation, semantic decomposition, and sensitive element drowning strategies to refine adversarial prompts and achieve a high success rate (93.66%) on leading text-to-image models.</li>
<li>The paper evaluates Groot’s effectiveness and efficiency, comparing it with existing methods and conducting an ablation study to assess the individual and combined effectiveness of its strategies.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Introduction to Text-to-Image Generative Models:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Text-to-image generative models have gained popularity but face challenges in preventing NSFW content generation.</li>
<li>Current efforts to jailbreak text-to-image models face three main challenges: inefficiency, focus on deceiving safety filters, and scalability of manual prompt crafting.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Groot’s Solution:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Groot introduces tree-based semantic transformation and leverages semantic decomposition and sensitive element drowning to refine adversarial prompts.</li>
<li>Groot achieves a 93.66% success rate, outperforming existing methods and demonstrating the effectiveness of its strategies.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Evaluation and Ablation Study:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Groot’s effectiveness is compared with existing methods, showing superior performance and efficiency.</li>
<li>An ablation study confirms the combined effectiveness of semantic decomposition and sensitive element drowning in Groot.</li>
</ul></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper provides a comprehensive and innovative solution to the challenges of adversarial testing for text-to-image models.</li>
<li>The evaluation and ablation study demonstrate the effectiveness and efficiency of Groot’s strategies.</li>
<li>However, the paper acknowledges limitations related to the randomness of text-to-image models and the absence of an established dataset for adversarial prompts.</li>
<li>Ethical considerations and safety concerns are highlighted, emphasizing the responsible application of text-to-image models.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-20</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12100v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12100v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12100v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12100v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6862</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Groot_Adversarial_Testing_for_Generative_Text_to_Image_Models_with_Tree_based_Semantic_Transformation/2024-02-19-Groot_Adversarial_Testing_for_Generative_Text_to_Image_Models_with_Tree_based_Semantic_Transformation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12100v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>An Empirical Evaluation of LLMs for Solving Offensive Security Challenges</title>
  <dc:creator>Minghao Shao, Boyuan Chen, Sofija Jancheska, Brendan Dolan-Gavitt, Siddharth Garg, Ramesh Karri, Muhammad Shafique</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/An_Empirical_Evaluation_of_LLMs_for_Solving_Offensive_Security_Challenges/2024-02-19-An_Empirical_Evaluation_of_LLMs_for_Solving_Offensive_Security_Challenges.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.11814v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article evaluates the performance of Large Language Models (LLMs) in solving Capture the Flag (CTF) challenges, comparing their success rates with human participants and analyzing their strengths and weaknesses.</li>
<li>It discusses the process of human-in-the-loop (HITL) evaluation and the fully automated workflow for CTF solving using different LLMs.</li>
<li>The study provides insights into the challenges and limitations of relying solely on LLMs without human intervention, emphasizing the importance of human feedback in the CTF-solving process.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs achieved a higher success rate than an average human participant in solving CTF challenges.</li>
<li>GPT-4 performed particularly well in automating CTF solving, highlighting its effectiveness in cybersecurity challenges.</li>
<li>The study emphasizes the importance of human feedback and intervention in enhancing the accuracy of LLM-generated solutions.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The findings have implications for cybersecurity education and the systematic evaluation of offensive cybersecurity capabilities in LLMs.</li>
<li>The study highlights the limitations of relying solely on LLMs without human intervention, emphasizing the importance of human feedback and intervention in the CTF-solving process.</li>
<li>The challenges presented in the article cover a wide range of cybersecurity topics, providing participants with practical scenarios to test their skills and knowledge in various domains of cybersecurity.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-20</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.11814v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.11814v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.11814v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.11814v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>16332</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/An_Empirical_Evaluation_of_LLMs_for_Solving_Offensive_Security_Challenges/2024-02-19-An_Empirical_Evaluation_of_LLMs_for_Solving_Offensive_Security_Challenges.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.11814v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>ChatGPT Based Data Augmentation for Improved Parameter-Efficient Debiasing of LLMs</title>
  <dc:creator>Pengrui Han, Rafal Kocielnik, Adhithya Saravanan, Roy Jiang, Or Sharir, Anima Anandkumar</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ChatGPT_Based_Data_Augmentation_for_Improved_Parameter_Efficient_Debiasing_of_LLMs/2024-02-19-ChatGPT_Based_Data_Augmentation_for_Improved_Parameter_Efficient_Debiasing_of_LLMs.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.11764v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article introduces a novel approach using ChatGPT to generate synthetic training data for debiasing Large Language Models (LLMs). Two strategies, Targeted Prompting and General Prompting, are proposed, with the study leveraging resource-efficient LLM debiasing using adapter tuning and comparing the effectiveness of synthetic data to existing debiasing datasets. The results show that ChatGPT can efficiently produce high-quality training data for debiasing other LLMs, surpassing existing datasets in debiasing performance while preserving internal knowledge of pre-trained LLMs. The synthetic data exhibits generalizability across categories, effectively mitigating various biases, including intersectional ones. Additionally, tables 16 and 17 present attribute words for gender and racial bias data through targeted prompting, reflecting societal perceptions and expectations, while tables 19 and 20 present attribute words for racial and religious bias data, emphasizing positive aspects of racial and religious identities. A comprehensive list of attribute words associated with religious bias data is provided, offering detailed insight into various aspects and themes related to religion and spirituality.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>ChatGPT can efficiently produce high-quality training data for debiasing other LLMs, surpassing existing datasets in debiasing performance while preserving internal knowledge of pre-trained LLMs.</li>
<li>Synthetic data exhibits generalizability across categories, effectively mitigating various biases, including intersectional ones.</li>
<li>The attribute words in the tables reflect societal perceptions and expectations related to gender, race, and religion, emphasizing positive aspects of racial and religious identities, and providing detailed insight into various aspects and themes related to religion and spirituality.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study highlights the potential of synthetic data in advancing the fairness of LLMs with minimal retraining cost, offering a promising solution to the challenging endeavor of debiasing. The findings underscore the effectiveness of the proposed synthetic data generation approach in mitigating biases across various categories and models, contributing to the robustness of parameter-efficient debiasing methods. The tables provide valuable insight into stereotypes and biases associated with gender, race, and religion, highlighting the need to address and challenge these biases. The attribute words reflect the potential for positive change and transformation within racial and religious communities, promoting inclusivity and empathy. The comprehensive list of attribute words offers a detailed understanding of the various aspects and themes related to religion and spirituality, emphasizing the multidisciplinary nature of religious bias data.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-20</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.11764v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.11764v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.11764v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.11764v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>45188</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ChatGPT_Based_Data_Augmentation_for_Improved_Parameter_Efficient_Debiasing_of_LLMs/2024-02-19-ChatGPT_Based_Data_Augmentation_for_Improved_Parameter_Efficient_Debiasing_of_LLMs.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.11764v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>ROSE Doesn’t Do That: Boosting the Safety of Instruction-Tuned Large Language Models with Reverse Prompt Contrastive Decoding</title>
  <dc:creator>Qihuang Zhong, Liang Ding, Juhua Liu, Bo Du, Dacheng Tao</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ROSE_Doesnt_Do_That_Boosting_the_Safety_of_Instruction_Tuned_Large_Language_Models_with_Reverse_Prompt_Contrastive_Decoding/2024-02-19-ROSE_Doesnt_Do_That_Boosting_the_Safety_of_Instruction_Tuned_Large_Language_Models_with_Reverse_Prompt_Contrastive_Decoding.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.11889v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The Reverse prOmpt contraStive dEcoding (ROSE) method aims to improve the safety of existing instruction-tuned large language models (LLMs) without additional training by suppressing undesired outputs induced by reverse prompts to boost the probability of safe output. Experiments show consistent and significant safety improvements across various LLMs, with potential for combination with other safety-tuned methods for better performance.</li>
<li>The ROSE method consistently outperforms regular decoding and other inference-time counterparts, with in-depth analyses on the impact of different prompts and the parameter α. It demonstrates robustness and complementary benefits to safety-tuned methods, enhancing the safety and general-purpose ability of LLMs.</li>
<li>ROSE is effective in enhancing the safety performance of existing safety-tuned LLMs, defending against attacks and encouraging safer outputs, with potential for broader applicability in improving LLM safety.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The ROSE method significantly improves safety across various LLMs without additional training.</li>
<li>ROSE consistently outperforms regular decoding and other inference-time counterparts, demonstrating robustness and complementary benefits to safety-tuned methods.</li>
<li>ROSE enhances the safety performance of existing safety-tuned LLMs, defending against attacks and encouraging safer outputs.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study demonstrates the potential of the ROSE method to address safety concerns associated with LLMs, offering consistent and significant safety improvements across various tasks and LLMs.</li>
<li>The method’s flexibility and potential for combination with other safety-tuned methods make it a valuable contribution to the field of LLM research.</li>
<li>The comparison between automatic evaluators and human evaluation adds credibility to the study’s findings, contributing to the comprehensive understanding of the evaluation process and the reliability of the results.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-20</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.11889v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.11889v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.11889v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.11889v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>17552</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ROSE_Doesnt_Do_That_Boosting_the_Safety_of_Instruction_Tuned_Large_Language_Models_with_Reverse_Prompt_Contrastive_Decoding/2024-02-19-ROSE_Doesnt_Do_That_Boosting_the_Safety_of_Instruction_Tuned_Large_Language_Models_with_Reverse_Prompt_Contrastive_Decoding.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.11889v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Uncertainty quantification in fine-tuned LLMs using LoRA ensembles</title>
  <dc:creator>Oleksandr Balabanov, Hampus Linander</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Uncertainty_quantification_in_fine_tuned_LLMs_using_LoRA_ensembles/2024-02-19-Uncertainty_quantification_in_fine_tuned_LLMs_using_LoRA_ensembles.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Uncertainty_quantification_in_fine_tuned_LLMs_using_LoRA_ensembles/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12264v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Fine-tuning large language models (LLMs) can improve task-specific performance, but understanding what the fine-tuned model has learned, forgotten, and how to trust its predictions is still lacking.</li>
<li>The study derives uncertainty quantification for fine-tuned LLMs using low-rank adaptation ensembles and analyzes three common multiple-choice datasets.</li>
<li>The study hypothesizes about signals from entropic uncertainty measures for data domains that are inherently difficult for a given architecture to learn.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The study provides a principled uncertainty quantification for fine-tuned LLMs using low-rank adaptation ensembles.</li>
<li>The analysis of entropic uncertainty measures can be used to reason about dataset complexity and model efficacy on the target domain.</li>
<li>The study draws quantitative conclusions on the relative complexity, out-of-distribution behavior, and model efficacy on different target domains.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study provides valuable insights into uncertainty quantification for fine-tuned LLMs, but it does not address potential biases or limitations in the methodology.</li>
<li>The use of low-rank adaptation ensembles for posterior approximation is a promising approach, but further research is needed to validate its effectiveness across different LLM architectures and datasets.</li>
<li>The study’s focus on multiple-choice question answers limits the generalizability of its findings to other types of tasks and domains. Additional research is needed to explore the application of uncertainty quantification in a broader context.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-20</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12264v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12264v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12264v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12264v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7900</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Uncertainty_quantification_in_fine_tuned_LLMs_using_LoRA_ensembles/2024-02-19-Uncertainty_quantification_in_fine_tuned_LLMs_using_LoRA_ensembles.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12264v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
