<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Bayesian beagle</title>
<link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Quarto blog of LLM-generated summaries of Arxiv preprints</description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.450</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Time series forecasting with high stakes: A field study of the air cargo industry</title>
  <dc:creator>Abhinav Garg, Naman Shukla</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Time_series_forecasting_with_high_stakes_A_field_study_of_the_air_cargo_industry/2024-07-29-Time_series_forecasting_with_high_stakes_A_field_study_of_the_air_cargo_industry.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Time_series_forecasting_with_high_stakes_A_field_study_of_the_air_cargo_industry/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.20192v1/extracted/5762096/artifacts/LADD_light.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper presents a comprehensive approach to demand forecasting at the origin-destination (O&amp;D) level for the air cargo industry.</li>
<li>The authors leverage a mixture of experts framework, combining statistical and advanced deep learning models to provide reliable forecasts for cargo demand over a six-month horizon.</li>
<li>The results demonstrate that the proposed approach outperforms industry benchmarks, offering actionable insights for cargo capacity allocation and strategic decision-making in the air cargo industry.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The study introduces a forecasting framework that combines multiple statistical and machine learning models to predict cargo demand at the origin and destination level.</li>
<li>The authors employ a mixture of experts framework, which allows them to select the best-performing model for each sample based on historical performance, thereby enhancing the overall prediction accuracy.</li>
<li>The research is conducted within the context of a major air cargo carrier, providing a real-world application of the proposed method, and validated across diverse market segments.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper presents a comprehensive and practical approach to demand forecasting in the air cargo industry, addressing the unique challenges and complexities of this market.</li>
<li>The authors demonstrate the effectiveness of their approach by outperforming industry benchmarks and providing actionable insights for decision-making.</li>
<li>However, the study does not discuss potential limitations or uncertainties in the data, such as the impact of unexpected events or economic fluctuations on cargo demand.</li>
<li>Additionally, the paper does not provide a detailed comparison of the performance of individual models within the mixture of experts framework, which could be useful for understanding the strengths and weaknesses of each model.</li>
<li>Finally, the study does not discuss the potential for generalizing the proposed approach to other industries or contexts, which could be a valuable direction for future research.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-30</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.20192v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.20192v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.20192v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.20192v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>4780</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Time_series_forecasting_with_high_stakes_A_field_study_of_the_air_cargo_industry/2024-07-29-Time_series_forecasting_with_high_stakes_A_field_study_of_the_air_cargo_industry.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.20192v1/extracted/5762096/artifacts/LADD_light.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Language-Conditioned Offline RL for Multi-Robot Navigation</title>
  <dc:creator>Steven Morad, Ajay Shankar, Jan Blumenkamp, Amanda Prorok</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Language_Conditioned_Offline_RL_for_Multi_Robot_Navigation/2024-07-29-Language_Conditioned_Offline_RL_for_Multi_Robot_Navigation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Language_Conditioned_Offline_RL_for_Multi_Robot_Navigation/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.20164v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper presents a method for developing navigation policies for multi-robot teams that interpret and follow natural language instructions. The policies are conditioned on embeddings from pretrained Large Language Models (LLMs) and trained via offline reinforcement learning with as little as 20 minutes of randomly-collected data. The experiments on a team of five real robots show that these policies generalize well to unseen commands, indicating an understanding of the LLM latent space. The method requires no simulators or environment models and produces low-latency control policies that can be deployed directly to real robots without finetuning.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The method enables low-latency multi-agent control through natural language.</li>
<li>A method to generate large amounts of multi-agent training data from a single robot is proposed.</li>
<li>A one-line change to Q-learning improves offline training stability.</li>
<li>The policies can generalize to unseen commands, solely through value estimation.</li>
<li>The first demonstration of offline multi-agent RL on robots in the real-world is presented.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper does not provide a detailed comparison with other methods for multi-robot navigation.</li>
<li>The method relies on pretrained LLMs, which may not be available for all languages or domains.</li>
<li>The experiments are limited to a team of five robots, and it is unclear how the method scales to larger teams.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the limitations of the offline reinforcement learning approach, such as the need for a large amount of data and the potential for overfitting.</li>
<li>The paper does not provide a detailed analysis of the computational requirements of the method, which is important for real-world deployment.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-30</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.20164v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.20164v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.20164v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.20164v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8102</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Language_Conditioned_Offline_RL_for_Multi_Robot_Navigation/2024-07-29-Language_Conditioned_Offline_RL_for_Multi_Robot_Navigation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.20164v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Enhancing Code Translation in Language Models with Few-Shot Learning via Retrieval-Augmented Generation</title>
  <dc:creator>Manish Bhattarai, Javier E. Santos, Shawn Jones, Ayan Biswas, Boian Alexandrov, Daniel O&#39;Malley</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Enhancing_Code_Translation_in_Language_Models_with_Few_Shot_Learning_via_Retrieval_Augmented_Generation/2024-07-29-Enhancing_Code_Translation_in_Language_Models_with_Few_Shot_Learning_via_Retrieval_Augmented_Generation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/../bayesian-beagle.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article discusses the impact of climate change on the global economy, focusing on the potential costs and benefits of adaptation and mitigation strategies.</li>
<li>The authors argue that while the costs of climate change are significant, the benefits of taking action to mitigate and adapt to its effects can outweigh these costs.</li>
<li>The article presents a comprehensive review of the existing literature on the economics of climate change, highlighting the key findings and methodological challenges.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Climate change poses significant economic risks</strong>: The article highlights the potential costs of climate change, including damage to infrastructure, reduced agricultural productivity, and increased health risks.</li>
<li><strong>Adaptation and mitigation strategies can be cost-effective</strong>: The authors argue that the benefits of taking action to mitigate and adapt to climate change can outweigh the costs, particularly in the long term.</li>
<li><strong>Methodological challenges remain</strong>: The article highlights the challenges of accurately estimating the costs and benefits of climate change, including the difficulty of predicting future climate scenarios and the complex interactions between climate change and the economy.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides a comprehensive review of the existing literature on the economics of climate change, but it may not fully capture the latest developments in the field.</li>
<li>The authors acknowledge the methodological challenges of estimating the costs and benefits of climate change, but they do not provide a clear roadmap for addressing these challenges.</li>
<li>The article focuses primarily on the economic impacts of climate change, but it does not fully consider the social and environmental implications of different adaptation and mitigation strategies.</li>
<li>The authors argue that the benefits of taking action to mitigate and adapt to climate change can outweigh the costs, but they do not provide a detailed analysis of the potential trade-offs between different strategies.</li>
<li>The article does not fully consider the potential role of technological innovation in reducing the costs and increasing the benefits of climate change mitigation and adaptation.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-30</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.19619v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.19619v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.19619v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.19619v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>0</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>programming</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Enhancing_Code_Translation_in_Language_Models_with_Few_Shot_Learning_via_Retrieval_Augmented_Generation/2024-07-29-Enhancing_Code_Translation_in_Language_Models_with_Few_Shot_Learning_via_Retrieval_Augmented_Generation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>QAEA-DR: A Unified Text Augmentation Framework for Dense Retrieval</title>
  <dc:creator>Hongming Tan, Shaoxiong Zhan, Hai Lin, Hai-Tao Zheng, Wai Kin, Chan</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/QAEA_DR_A_Unified_Text_Augmentation_Framework_for_Dense_Retrieval/2024-07-29-QAEA_DR_A_Unified_Text_Augmentation_Framework_for_Dense_Retrieval.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/QAEA_DR_A_Unified_Text_Augmentation_Framework_for_Dense_Retrieval/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.20207v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper introduces a novel text augmentation framework called QAEA-DR, which aims to improve dense retrieval by transforming raw documents into information-dense text formats. This framework generates two types of text representations: question-answer pairs and element-driven events, using large language models (LLMs) zero-shot prompting. The proposed approach, QAEA-DR, has a positive impact on dense retrieval, supported by both theoretical analysis and empirical experiments.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>QAEA-DR is a unified text augmentation framework that integrates question-answer generation and event extraction for dense retrieval, addressing the issue of losing key information in dense retrieval.</li>
<li>The framework generates high-quality alternative texts that concentrate on key information, improving semantic similarity with the query.</li>
<li>QAEA-DR employs a scoring-based evaluation and regeneration mechanism in LLM prompting to further enhance the quality of generated texts.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper provides a well-structured and coherent summary of the proposed QAEA-DR framework, highlighting its potential to improve dense retrieval.</li>
<li>The use of LLMs for generating question-answer pairs and element-driven events is a promising approach, as it allows for the extraction of high-level semantic information and the removal of noise from the original text.</li>
<li>The paper could benefit from further discussion on the limitations and potential biases of the proposed approach, as well as any methodological issues or conflicting evidence that may arise.</li>
<li>The paper could also explore the potential for integrating other text augmentation techniques or alternative methods for generating high-quality alternative texts.</li>
<li>Future research could focus on evaluating the performance of QAEA-DR on a wider range of datasets and tasks, as well as comparing it to other state-of-the-art text augmentation methods for dense retrieval.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-30</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.20207v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.20207v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.20207v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.20207v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>9720</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/QAEA_DR_A_Unified_Text_Augmentation_Framework_for_Dense_Retrieval/2024-07-29-QAEA_DR_A_Unified_Text_Augmentation_Framework_for_Dense_Retrieval.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.20207v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Orca: Ocean Significant Wave Height Estimation with Spatio-temporally Aware Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Zhe Li, Ronghui Xu, Jilin Hu, Zhong Peng, Xi Lu, Chenjuan Guo, Bin Yang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Orca_Ocean_Significant_Wave_Height_Estimation_with_Spatio_temporally_Aware_Large_Language_Models/2024-07-29-Orca_Ocean_Significant_Wave_Height_Estimation_with_Spatio_temporally_Aware_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Orca_Ocean_Significant_Wave_Height_Estimation_with_Spatio_temporally_Aware_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.20053v1/extracted/5761628/mosico.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper introduces a novel ocean significant wave height (SWH) estimation framework called Orca, which addresses the limitations of traditional and machine learning-based methods. Orca leverages the few-shot learning ability of Large Language Models (LLMs) and enhances their spatio-temporal reasoning capabilities with a novel spatiotemporal aware encoding module. The framework capitalizes on the robust generalization ability of LLMs to estimate SWH effectively with limited data.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Orca Framework</strong>: The proposed Orca framework enhances the limited spatio-temporal reasoning abilities of classic LLMs with a novel spatiotemporal aware encoding module. This module enables Orca to effectively estimate SWH with limited buoy observational data.</li>
<li><strong>Prompt Templates and Embedding Module</strong>: Orca uses a specific prompt templates and embedding module to leverage the pre-trained LLM for SWH estimation. This design aims to achieve accurate SWH estimations using limited observed data by leveraging the robust generalization capabilities of LLMs.</li>
<li><strong>Spatio-temporal Encoding</strong>: To enhance spatio-temporal reasoning, Orca segments buoy-based data into overlapping temporal patches and proposes a novel spatial encoding module. This module ensures that the model accurately reflects the physical location of buoys in the estimations.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Data Sparsity</strong>: The paper addresses the challenge of data sparsity in SWH estimation by using LLMs as the backbone of the estimation. However, the scarcity of real-world data may still limit the potential of machine learning models, including Orca.</li>
<li><strong>Spatio-temporal Correlations</strong>: Orca aims to capture the strong spatio-temporal correlations in wave variations, which is crucial for accurate SWH estimation. However, the effectiveness of the proposed spatio-temporal encoding module in capturing these correlations needs further validation.</li>
<li><strong>Methodological Limitations</strong>: The paper does not discuss potential methodological limitations, such as the impact of the choice of LLMs, the design of prompt templates, or the influence of hyperparameters on the performance of Orca.</li>
<li><strong>Generalizability</strong>: The paper focuses on the</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-30</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.20053v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.20053v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.20053v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.20053v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>3804</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Orca_Ocean_Significant_Wave_Height_Estimation_with_Spatio_temporally_Aware_Large_Language_Models/2024-07-29-Orca_Ocean_Significant_Wave_Height_Estimation_with_Spatio_temporally_Aware_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.20053v1/extracted/5761628/mosico.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>ByteCheckpoint: A Unified Checkpointing System for LLM Development</title>
  <dc:creator>Borui Wan, Mingji Han, Yiyao Sheng, Zhichao Lai, Mofan Zhang, Junda Zhang, Yanghua Peng, Haibin Lin, Xin Liu, Chuan Wu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ByteCheckpoint_A_Unified_Checkpointing_System_for_LLM_Development/2024-07-29-ByteCheckpoint_A_Unified_Checkpointing_System_for_LLM_Development.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ByteCheckpoint_A_Unified_Checkpointing_System_for_LLM_Development/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.20143v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>ByteCheckpoint is a PyTorch-native multi-framework LLM checkpointing system that supports automatic online checkpoint resharding. It employs a data/metadata disaggregated storage architecture, decoupling checkpoint storage from parallelism strategies and training frameworks. The system introduces an efficient asynchronous tensor merging technique to address irregular tensor sharding and several I/O performance optimizations to enhance checkpoint saving and loading efficiency. Experimental results demonstrate substantial advantages in reducing checkpoint saving and loading costs compared to baseline methods.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>ByteCheckpoint employs a data/metadata disaggregated storage architecture, which decouples checkpoint storage from parallelism strategies and training frameworks.</li>
<li>The system introduces an efficient asynchronous tensor merging technique to address the irregular tensor sharding problem.</li>
<li>ByteCheckpoint proposes several I/O performance optimizations, including a fine-grained fully asynchronous save pipeline, a Ping-Pong pinned memory pool, and a workload-balanced deduplication mechanism.</li>
<li>Experimental results demonstrate that ByteCheckpoint significantly reduces checkpoint saving and loading costs compared to baseline methods.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>ByteCheckpoint presents a promising solution for efficient checkpointing in LLM development. Its data/metadata disaggregated storage architecture and asynchronous tensor merging technique effectively address the challenges of checkpoint resharding and irregular tensor sharding. The proposed I/O performance optimizations further enhance the system’s efficiency. However, the system’s scalability and performance in handling extremely large-scale LLMs remain to be evaluated. Additionally, the system’s compatibility with other deep learning frameworks beyond PyTorch needs to be explored.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-30</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.20143v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.20143v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.20143v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.20143v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>10038</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ByteCheckpoint_A_Unified_Checkpointing_System_for_LLM_Development/2024-07-29-ByteCheckpoint_A_Unified_Checkpointing_System_for_LLM_Development.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.20143v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>CollectiveSFT: Scaling Large Language Models for Chinese Medical Benchmark with Collective Instructions in Healthcare</title>
  <dc:creator>Jingwei Zhu, Minghuan Tan, Min Yang, Ruixue Li, Hamid Alinejad-Rokny</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/CollectiveSFT_Scaling_Large_Language_Models_for_Chinese_Medical_Benchmark_with_Collective_Instructions_in_Healthcare/2024-07-29-CollectiveSFT_Scaling_Large_Language_Models_for_Chinese_Medical_Benchmark_with_Collective_Instructions_in_Healthcare.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/../bayesian-beagle.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study focuses on the Comprehensive Medical Benchmark in Chinese (CMB) and showcases how dataset diversity and distribution in supervised fine-tuning (SFT) can enhance LLM performance.</li>
<li>The authors successfully trained a smaller base model to achieve scores comparable to larger models, indicating that a diverse and well-distributed dataset can optimize performance regardless of model size.</li>
<li>The study suggests that even smaller models may reach high performance levels with carefully curated and varied datasets.</li>
<li>The authors integrated a wide range of instructional content, addressing potential issues such as data quality inconsistencies.</li>
<li>The results imply that a broader spectrum of training data may enhance a model’s ability to generalize and perform effectively across different medical scenarios, highlighting the importance of dataset quality and diversity in fine-tuning processes.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>A smaller base model was successfully trained to achieve scores comparable to larger models, demonstrating that a diverse and well-distributed dataset can optimize performance regardless of model size.</li>
<li>The study highlights the importance of dataset quality and diversity in fine-tuning processes, as a broader spectrum of training data may enhance a model’s ability to generalize and perform effectively across different medical scenarios.</li>
<li>The authors integrated a wide range of instructional content, addressing potential issues such as data quality inconsistencies.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study effectively demonstrates the potential of using diverse datasets to improve model performance using SFT.</li>
<li>The authors acknowledge that while the fine-tuned smaller models excel at answering multiple-choice questions accurately and effectively, they may lose some of their conversational abilities.</li>
<li>The study also highlights common problems associated with smaller models, such as hallucination, which can undermine the reliability of the model’s responses and pose a significant challenge for its deployment in sensitive domains like healthcare.</li>
<li>Future work should focus on developing strategies to preserve the conversational capabilities of fine-tuned models and reduce instances of hallucination.</li>
<li>Overall, the method shows great potential for improving the efficiency and effectiveness of LLMs, but it requires careful consideration and further innovation to fully realize its benefits.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-30</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.19705v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.19705v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.19705v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.19705v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>2837</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/CollectiveSFT_Scaling_Large_Language_Models_for_Chinese_Medical_Benchmark_with_Collective_Instructions_in_Healthcare/2024-07-29-CollectiveSFT_Scaling_Large_Language_Models_for_Chinese_Medical_Benchmark_with_Collective_Instructions_in_Healthcare.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>AutoScale: Automatic Prediction of Compute-optimal Data Composition for Training LLMs</title>
  <dc:creator>Feiyang Kang, Yifan Sun, Bingbing Wen, Si Chen, Dawn Song, Rafid Mahmood, Ruoxi Jia</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/AutoScale_Automatic_Prediction_of_Compute_optimal_Data_Composition_for_Training_LLMs/2024-07-29-AutoScale_Automatic_Prediction_of_Compute_optimal_Data_Composition_for_Training_LLMs.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/AutoScale_Automatic_Prediction_of_Compute_optimal_Data_Composition_for_Training_LLMs/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.20177v1/extracted/5762071/figs/main_fig_crop.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper proposes AutoScale, an automated tool that finds a compute-optimal data composition for training at any desired target scale. The authors demonstrate that the optimal data composition for a fixed compute budget varies depending on the scale of the training data, and the common practice of empirically determining an optimal composition using small-scale experiments will not yield the optimal data mixtures when scaling up to the final model. AutoScale first determines the optimal composition at a small scale using a novel bi-level optimization framework, Direct Data Optimization (DDO), and then fits a predictor to estimate the optimal composition at larger scales. The predictor’s design is inspired by the theoretical analysis of scaling laws related to data composition. In empirical studies with pre-training 774M Decoder-only LMs (GPT-2 Large) on RedPajama dataset, AutoScale decreases validation perplexity at least 25% faster than any baseline with up to 38% speed up compared to without reweighting, achieving the best overall performance across downstream tasks.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The optimal data composition for a fixed compute budget varies depending on the scale of the training data.</li>
<li>AutoScale, an automated tool, finds a compute-optimal data composition for training at any desired target scale.</li>
<li>AutoScale first determines the optimal composition at a small scale using a novel bi-level optimization framework, Direct Data Optimization (DDO).</li>
<li>AutoScale then fits a predictor to estimate the optimal composition at larger scales, inspired by the theoretical analysis of scaling laws related to data composition.</li>
<li>In empirical studies, AutoScale decreases validation perplexity at least 25% faster than any baseline with up to 38% speed up compared to without reweighting, achieving the best overall performance across downstream tasks.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The paper presents an interesting approach to finding a compute-optimal data composition for training large language models (LLMs) at any desired target scale. The authors demonstrate that the optimal data composition for a fixed compute budget varies depending on the scale of the training data, which is a significant finding. The proposed AutoScale tool, which uses a novel bi-level optimization framework, Direct Data Optimization (DDO), and a predictor to estimate the optimal</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-30</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.20177v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.20177v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.20177v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.20177v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>11502</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/AutoScale_Automatic_Prediction_of_Compute_optimal_Data_Composition_for_Training_LLMs/2024-07-29-AutoScale_Automatic_Prediction_of_Compute_optimal_Data_Composition_for_Training_LLMs.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.20177v1/extracted/5762071/figs/main_fig_crop.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Do LLMs Really Adapt to Domains? An Ontology Learning Perspective</title>
  <dc:creator>Huu Tan Mai, Cuong Xuan Chu, Heiko Paulheim</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Do_LLMs_Really_Adapt_to_Domains_An_Ontology_Learning_Perspective/2024-07-29-Do_LLMs_Really_Adapt_to_Domains_An_Ontology_Learning_Perspective.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Do_LLMs_Really_Adapt_to_Domains_An_Ontology_Learning_Perspective/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.19998v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>This paper investigates the question of whether Large Language Models (LLMs) can adapt to domains and remain consistent in the extraction of structured knowledge, or if they only learn lexical senses instead of reasoning. The authors devise a controlled experiment setup that uses WordNet to synthesize parallel corpora, with English and gibberish terms. They examine the differences in the outputs of LLMs for each corpus in two OL tasks: relation extraction and taxonomy discovery. Empirical results show that off-the-shelf LLMs do not consistently reason over semantic relationships between concepts, and instead leverage senses and their frame. However, fine-tuning improves the performance of LLMs on lexical semantic tasks even when the domain-specific terms are arbitrary and unseen during pre-training, hinting at the applicability of pre-trained LLMs for OL.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Off-the-shelf LLMs do not consistently reason over semantic relationships between concepts, and instead leverage senses and their frame.</li>
<li>Fine-tuning improves the performance of LLMs on lexical semantic tasks even when the domain-specific terms are arbitrary and unseen during pre-training.</li>
<li>The applicability of pre-trained LLMs for OL is hinted at by the empirical results.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The study focuses on a limited number of LLMs, and a more comprehensive evaluation of various models would provide a more robust understanding of their capabilities.</li>
<li>The use of gibberish terms may not fully capture the complexity of domain-specific language, and further research is needed to explore the performance of LLMs in real-world domain-specific scenarios.</li>
<li>The study does not address the potential impact of the size of the LLMs on their ability to adapt to domains and reason over semantic relationships.</li>
<li>The authors do not discuss the potential implications of their findings for the development and application of LLMs in various domains.</li>
<li>The study does not explore the potential of other techniques, such as transfer learning or multi-task learning, to improve the performance of LLMs in domain-specific tasks.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-30</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.19998v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.19998v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.19998v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.19998v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7696</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Do_LLMs_Really_Adapt_to_Domains_An_Ontology_Learning_Perspective/2024-07-29-Do_LLMs_Really_Adapt_to_Domains_An_Ontology_Learning_Perspective.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.19998v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Sentiment Analysis of Lithuanian Online Reviews Using Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Brigita Vileikytė, Mantas Lukoševičius, Lukas Stankevičius</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Sentiment_Analysis_of_Lithuanian_Online_Reviews_Using_Large_Language_Models/2024-07-29-Sentiment_Analysis_of_Lithuanian_Online_Reviews_Using_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/../bayesian-beagle.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper focuses on sentiment analysis of Lithuanian five-star-based online reviews from multiple domains, using transformer models for the first time.</li>
<li>The authors apply pre-trained multilingual Large Language Models (LLMs), specifically fine-tuning BERT and T5 models.</li>
<li>The fine-tuned models perform well, especially when sentiments are less ambiguous, with 80.74% and 89.61% testing recognition accuracy for the most popular one- and five-star reviews, respectively.</li>
<li>The fine-tuned models significantly outperform current commercial state-of-the-art general-purpose LLM GPT-4.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The fine-tuned BERT and T5 models perform well in sentiment analysis of Lithuanian online reviews, with high testing recognition accuracy for the most popular one- and five-star reviews.</li>
<li>The fine-tuned models significantly outperform current commercial state-of-the-art general-purpose LLM GPT-4.</li>
<li>The fine-tuned models are effective in handling the inherent difficulty of the task, especially when sentiments are less ambiguous.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper provides a valuable contribution to the field of sentiment analysis for less-studied and less-resourced languages such as Lithuanian.</li>
<li>The use of transformer models and fine-tuning of BERT and T5 models is a novel approach to sentiment analysis of Lithuanian online reviews.</li>
<li>The high testing recognition accuracy of the fine-tuned models demonstrates the effectiveness of the approach.</li>
<li>However, the paper does not provide a detailed comparison of the performance of the fine-tuned models with other existing methods for sentiment analysis of Lithuanian online reviews.</li>
<li>Additionally, the paper does not discuss the potential limitations of the approach, such as the need for large amounts of labeled data for fine-tuning the models.</li>
<li>Further research is needed to evaluate the generalizability of the approach to other less-studied and less-resourced languages.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-30</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.19914v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.19914v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.19914v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.19914v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8863</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Sentiment_Analysis_of_Lithuanian_Online_Reviews_Using_Large_Language_Models/2024-07-29-Sentiment_Analysis_of_Lithuanian_Online_Reviews_Using_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Concise Thoughts: Impact of Output Length on LLM Reasoning and Cost</title>
  <dc:creator>Sania Nayab, Giulio Rossolini, Giorgio Buttazzo, Nicolamaria Manes, Fabrizio Giacomelli</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Concise_Thoughts_Impact_of_Output_Length_on_LLM_Reasoning_and_Cost/2024-07-29-Concise_Thoughts_Impact_of_Output_Length_on_LLM_Reasoning_and_Cost.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/../bayesian-beagle.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>This study investigates the effectiveness of the Chain-of-thought (CoT) approach in controlling the output length of language models. The authors test the CoT approach by using the phrase “Limit the length of the reasoning to LEN words” and observe that the accuracy with the vicuna-13b-v1.5 model improves with all ranges of LEN. However, the inference time and the output length distribution are not efficient. The authors also test the CoT approach with the phrase “Limit the length of the answer to LEN words” and observe that the accuracy decreases as compared to the base results. The study concludes that the CoT is specifically for testing the reasoning capabilities of the LLMs and that the CCoT approach is a promising direction for further research.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The accuracy with the vicuna-13b-v1.5 model improves with all ranges of LEN when using the CoT approach with the phrase “Limit the length of the reasoning to LEN words.”</li>
<li>The accuracy decreases when using the CoT approach with the phrase “Limit the length of the answer to LEN words” as compared to the base results.</li>
<li>The CoT approach is specifically for testing the reasoning capabilities of the LLMs.</li>
<li>The CCoT approach is a promising direction for further research.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The study provides a novel approach to controlling the output length of language models using the CoT and CCoT approaches. However, the study has some limitations. First, the study only tests the CoT and CCoT approaches with the vicuna-13b-v1.5 model, and it is unclear if the results would generalize to other models. Second, the study only tests the CoT and CCoT approaches with a limited range of LEN values, and it is unclear if the results would hold for other LEN values. Third, the study does not provide a clear explanation of why the accuracy decreases when using the CoT approach with the phrase “Limit the length of the answer to LEN words.” Finally, the study does not provide any comparison with other approaches to controlling the output length of language models.</p>
<p>Overall, the study provides a promising direction for further research on controlling the output length of language</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-30</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.19825v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.19825v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.19825v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.19825v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>9488</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>programming</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Concise_Thoughts_Impact_of_Output_Length_on_LLM_Reasoning_and_Cost/2024-07-29-Concise_Thoughts_Impact_of_Output_Length_on_LLM_Reasoning_and_Cost.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Advancing Multimodal Large Language Models in Chart Question Answering with Visualization-Referenced Instruction Tuning</title>
  <dc:creator>Xingchen Zeng, Haichuan Lin, Yilin Ye, Wei Zeng</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Advancing_Multimodal_Large_Language_Models_in_Chart_Question_Answering_with_Visualization_Referenced_Instruction_Tuning/2024-07-29-Advancing_Multimodal_Large_Language_Models_in_Chart_Question_Answering_with_Visualization_Referenced_Instruction_Tuning.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Advancing_Multimodal_Large_Language_Models_in_Chart_Question_Answering_with_Visualization_Referenced_Instruction_Tuning/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.20174v1/x2.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper presents an approach to improve the performance of multimodal large language models (MLLMs) in chart question answering (CQA) tasks. The authors identify limitations in current MLLMs and CQA datasets, such as unbalanced data distribution and inconsistent data quality, which hinder their performance. To address these issues, the authors propose a two-stage data engine that filters existing datasets and enlarges them through LLM-based generation techniques. This approach ensures a broader range of high-quality data that captures the characteristics of charts. The authors also incorporate a mixture-of-resolution adaptation strategy and unfreeze the vision encoder during model training, which significantly improves the performance of their MLLM on CQA tasks. Experimental results show that their model outperforms state-of-the-art CQA models, even with a more compact dataset. The authors also contribute a benchmark for future advancements in MLLMs for CQA tasks.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Current MLLMs and CQA datasets have limitations, such as unbalanced data distribution and inconsistent data quality, which hinder their performance in CQA tasks.</li>
<li>A two-stage data engine that filters existing datasets and enlarges them through LLM-based generation techniques can improve the performance of MLLMs in CQA tasks.</li>
<li>Incorporating a mixture-of-resolution adaptation strategy and unfreezing the vision encoder during model training can significantly improve the performance of MLLMs in CQA tasks.</li>
<li>The proposed model outperforms state-of-the-art CQA models, even with a more compact dataset.</li>
<li>A benchmark is contributed for future advancements in MLLMs for CQA tasks.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The paper presents a novel approach to improve the performance of MLLMs in CQA tasks. The authors identify limitations in current MLLMs and CQA datasets and propose a two-stage data engine to address these issues. The proposed approach ensures a broader range of high-quality data that captures the characteristics of charts. The authors also incorporate a mixture-of-resolution adaptation strategy and unfreeze the vision encoder during model training, which significantly improves the performance</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-30</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.20174v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.20174v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.20174v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.20174v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>11032</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Advancing_Multimodal_Large_Language_Models_in_Chart_Question_Answering_with_Visualization_Referenced_Instruction_Tuning/2024-07-29-Advancing_Multimodal_Large_Language_Models_in_Chart_Question_Answering_with_Visualization_Referenced_Instruction_Tuning.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.20174v1/x2.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>LLMs’ Understanding of Natural Language Revealed</title>
  <dc:creator>Walid S. Saba</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLMs_Understanding_of_Natural_Language_Revealed/2024-07-29-LLMs_Understanding_of_Natural_Language_Revealed.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2407.19630v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The article “LLMs’ Understanding of Natural Language Revealed” by Walid S. Saba explores the limitations of large language models (LLMs) in understanding natural language. The author argues that while LLMs can generate human-like coherent language, they do not truly understand language beyond superficial inferences. The article focuses on testing LLMs for their language understanding capabilities by performing operations that are the opposite of ‘text generation’. The author conducted tests involving various linguistic phenomena, including intension, knowledge, belief, and other propositional attitudes, copredication, nominal modification, metonymy, and reference resolution. The results show that LLMs fail to make the right inferences in contexts with propositional attitudes, fail to recognize copredication, and fail to capture the real semantic content of nominal modification. The article concludes that building an AI that fully understands natural language text is not as simple as most superficial studies have concluded.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs do not truly understand language beyond superficial inferences, despite their ability to generate human-like coherent language.</li>
<li>LLMs fail to make the right inferences in contexts with propositional attitudes, such as knowledge, belief, and truth.</li>
<li>LLMs fail to recognize copredication, where a single reference is used to refer to several entities of different types.</li>
<li>LLMs fail to capture the real semantic content of nominal modification, where there is usually one or more adjectives modifying a head noun.</li>
<li>LLMs fail to make the right inferences in metonymy, where an entity e1 is used to refer indirectly to another entity e2 that stands in some relation to e1.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article provides a comprehensive analysis of the limitations of LLMs in understanding natural language. The author’s approach of testing LLMs for their language understanding capabilities by performing operations that are the opposite of ‘text generation’ is a novel and effective way to evaluate their performance. The article highlights the importance of recognizing the subtle errors in understanding that LLMs make, which can lead to a complete misunderstanding of the larger piece of text. The author’s use of examples to illustrate the limitations of LLMs is effective in demonstrating their inability to make</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-30</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.19630v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.19630v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.19630v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.19630v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>10131</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLMs_Understanding_of_Natural_Language_Revealed/2024-07-29-LLMs_Understanding_of_Natural_Language_Revealed.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2407.19630v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>SeaLLMs 3: Open Foundation and Chat Multilingual Large Language Models for Southeast Asian Languages</title>
  <dc:creator>Wenxuan Zhang, Hou Pong Chan, Yiran Zhao, Mahani Aljunied, Jianyu Wang, Chaoqun Liu, Yue Deng, Zhiqiang Hu, Weiwen Xu, Yew Ken Chia, Xin Li, Lidong Bing</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SeaLLMs_3_Open_Foundation_and_Chat_Multilingual_Large_Language_Models_for_Southeast_Asian_Languages/2024-07-29-SeaLLMs_3_Open_Foundation_and_Chat_Multilingual_Large_Language_Models_for_Southeast_Asian_Languages.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SeaLLMs_3_Open_Foundation_and_Chat_Multilingual_Large_Language_Models_for_Southeast_Asian_Languages/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.19672v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>SeaLLMs 3 is a large language model designed for Southeast Asian languages, addressing the lack of inclusivity and equitable distribution of AI advancements across diverse linguistic and cultural communities. The model covers a comprehensive range of languages spoken in the region, including English, Chinese, Indonesian, Vietnamese, Thai, Tagalog, Malay, Burmese, Khmer, Lao, Tamil, and Javanese.</p>
<p>SeaLLMs 3 employs efficient language enhancement techniques and a specially constructed instruction tuning dataset, significantly reducing training costs while maintaining high performance and versatility. The model excels in tasks such as world knowledge, mathematical reasoning, translation, and instruction following, achieving state-of-the-art performance among similarly sized models.</p>
<p>The model’s development prioritized safety and reliability, addressing both general and culture-specific considerations and incorporating mechanisms to reduce hallucinations. The model is trained to be aware of its knowledge boundary and refuse what it does not know, with a novel benchmark, SeaRefuse, introduced to evaluate this capability.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Inclusive AI for Southeast Asian Languages</strong>: SeaLLMs 3 is designed to bridge the gap in AI development for Southeast Asian languages, providing advanced large language model capabilities to underserved linguistic and cultural communities.</li>
<li><strong>Efficient Language Enhancement</strong>: The model employs efficient language enhancement techniques, training language-specific neurons only based on a foundation model, significantly reducing overall training cost.</li>
<li><strong>High Performance and Versatility</strong>: SeaLLMs 3 achieves state-of-the-art performance among models with similar sizes, excelling across a diverse array of tasks such as world knowledge, mathematical reasoning, translation, and instruction following.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>While SeaLLMs 3 represents a significant advancement in the development of large language models for Southeast Asian languages, there are potential areas for improvement and further research.</p>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Limited Language Coverage</strong>: While the model covers a comprehensive range of languages spoken in Southeast Asia, there are still many languages in the region that are not included. Future iterations could aim to expand the model’s language coverage.</li>
<li>**Data Availability and Quality</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-30</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.19672v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.19672v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.19672v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.19672v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5720</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SeaLLMs_3_Open_Foundation_and_Chat_Multilingual_Large_Language_Models_for_Southeast_Asian_Languages/2024-07-29-SeaLLMs_3_Open_Foundation_and_Chat_Multilingual_Large_Language_Models_for_Southeast_Asian_Languages.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.19672v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>When to Stop? Towards Efficient Code Generation in LLMs with Excess Token Prevention</title>
  <dc:creator>Lianghong Guo, Yanlin Wang, Ensheng Shi, Wanjun Zhong, Hongyu Zhang, Jiachi Chen, Ruikai Zhang, Yuchi Ma, Zibin Zheng</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/When_to_Stop_Towards_Efficient_Code_Generation_in_LLMs_with_Excess_Token_Prevention/2024-07-29-When_to_Stop_Towards_Efficient_Code_Generation_in_LLMs_with_Excess_Token_Prevention.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/When_to_Stop_Towards_Efficient_Code_Generation_in_LLMs_with_Excess_Token_Prevention/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.20042v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper “When to Stop? Towards Efficient Code Generation in LLMs with Excess Token Prevention” addresses the issue of inefficient code generation in large language models (LLMs) due to the continual generation of excess tokens. This problem not only wastes computational resources but also leads to significant energy consumption and harms developer productivity. The authors propose a solution called CodeFast, an inference acceleration approach for Code LLMs that terminates the inference process when unnecessary excess tokens are detected.</p>
<p>CodeFast consists of three main components: an automatic data construction framework to obtain training data, a unified lightweight model called GenGuard to predict whether to terminate inference at the current step, and the enhancement of Code LLM with GenGuard to accelerate its inference in code generation tasks. The authors conducted extensive experiments with CodeFast on five representative Code LLMs across four widely used code generation datasets, demonstrating significant improvements in inference speed without compromising the quality of generated code.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>CodeFast can significantly improve the inference speed of various Code LLMs in code generation, ranging from 34% to 452%.</li>
<li>CodeFast is stable across different parameter settings and can generalize to untrained datasets.</li>
<li>The proposed approach is effective in addressing the excess token generation issue, which is a significant bottleneck in the inference speed of Code LLMs for code generation tasks.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The paper presents a well-structured and comprehensive study on the excess token generation issue in Code LLMs and proposes a novel solution to address this problem. The authors provide a detailed description of their approach, along with extensive experiments and results to support their claims. However, there are a few potential limitations and areas for improvement:</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper focuses on the excess token generation issue in the context of code generation tasks. It would be interesting to explore whether this issue also affects other tasks, such as text summarization or translation, and if the proposed solution can be adapted to address these problems.</li>
<li>The authors mention that their approach is stable across different parameter settings, but they do not provide a detailed analysis of the impact of varying these parameters on the performance of CodeFast. A more comprehensive analysis of the sensitivity of CodeFast to different parameter settings would be beneficial.</li>
<li></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-30</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.20042v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.20042v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.20042v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.20042v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>12130</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>programming</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/When_to_Stop_Towards_Efficient_Code_Generation_in_LLMs_with_Excess_Token_Prevention/2024-07-29-When_to_Stop_Towards_Efficient_Code_Generation_in_LLMs_with_Excess_Token_Prevention.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.20042v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Can Editing LLMs Inject Harm?</title>
  <dc:creator>Canyu Chen, Baixiang Huang, Zekun Li, Zhaorun Chen, Shiyang Lai, Xiongxiao Xu, Jia-Chen Gu, Jindong Gu, Huaxiu Yao, Chaowei Xiao, Xifeng Yan, William Yang Wang, Philip Torr, Dawn Song, Kai Shu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Can_Editing_LLMs_Inject_Harm/2024-07-29-Can_Editing_LLMs_Inject_Harm.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Can_Editing_LLMs_Inject_Harm/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.20224v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper explores the potential risks of knowledge editing techniques in Large Language Models (LLMs), specifically focusing on the possibility of injecting harm into LLMs. The authors propose a new type of threat, Editing Attack, and investigate its two major risks: Misinformation Injection and Bias Injection. Through extensive experiments, they demonstrate that editing attacks can effectively inject both misinformation and biased information into LLMs, and even increase the bias in LLMs’ general outputs via a single biased sentence injection. The paper also highlights the high degree of stealthiness of editing attacks, as they have minimal impact on LLMs’ general knowledge or reasoning capacities.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Editing attacks can effectively inject both misinformation and biased information into LLMs, with high effectiveness.</li>
<li>A single biased sentence injection can increase the bias in LLMs’ general outputs, demonstrating a catastrophic impact on overall fairness.</li>
<li>Editing attacks exhibit a high degree of stealthiness, as they have minimal impact on LLMs’ general knowledge or reasoning capacities.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The paper provides a comprehensive analysis of the potential risks of knowledge editing techniques in LLMs. However, there are some limitations and areas for future research. The experiments were conducted on LLMs with a relatively small scale of parameters, and the effectiveness of editing attacks on larger models should be further assessed. Additionally, the paper calls for more research on developing defense methods based on the inner mechanisms of editing and enhancing LLMs’ intrinsic robustness against editing attacks.</p>
<p>The paper also raises ethical concerns regarding the potential misuse of knowledge editing techniques to inject misinformation or biased information into LLMs. The authors emphasize the need for open discussions from different stakeholders on the governance of open-source LLMs to maximize the benefit and minimize the potential risk.</p>
<p>In conclusion, the paper highlights the critical misuse risks of knowledge editing techniques and the fragility of LLMs’ safety alignment under editing attacks. It calls for more research on understanding the inner mechanisms of editing attacks, designing defense techniques, and enhancing LLMs’ intrinsic robustness.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-30</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.20224v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.20224v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.20224v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.20224v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>9390</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Can_Editing_LLMs_Inject_Harm/2024-07-29-Can_Editing_LLMs_Inject_Harm.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.20224v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Detecting and Understanding Vulnerabilities in Language Models via Mechanistic Interpretability</title>
  <dc:creator>Jorge García-Carrasco, Alejandro Maté, Juan Trujillo</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Detecting_and_Understanding_Vulnerabilities_in_Language_Models_via_Mechanistic_Interpretability/2024-07-29-Detecting_and_Understanding_Vulnerabilities_in_Language_Models_via_Mechanistic_Interpretability.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Detecting_and_Understanding_Vulnerabilities_in_Language_Models_via_Mechanistic_Interpretability/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.19842v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper explores the use of Mechanistic Interpretability (MI) techniques to detect and understand vulnerabilities in Large Language Models (LLMs). The authors propose a method that involves identifying the subset of the model responsible for a specific task, generating adversarial samples for that task, and using MI techniques to discover and understand the possible vulnerabilities. The method is showcased on a pretrained GPT-2 Small model performing the task of predicting 3-letter acronyms.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper proposes a new method to detect and understand vulnerabilities in language models by systematically identifying and understanding the circuit associated with a given task and automatically generating adversarial samples related to the task.</li>
<li>The proposed method is showcased on a case study to locate and understand vulnerabilities on the task of 3-letter acronym prediction using GPT-2 Small.</li>
<li>The authors claim that this is the first work that analyzes vulnerabilities of models from the MI perspective, which can provide valuable insights to detect, understand, and potentially mitigate or solve these vulnerabilities without requiring extra adversarial training or risking inadvertently causing collateral effects.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper provides a novel approach to detect and understand vulnerabilities in LLMs, which can be useful for improving the robustness and reliability of these models.</li>
<li>The proposed method is showcased on a specific task and model, and its generalizability to other tasks and models needs to be further investigated.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss any potential limitations or shortcomings of the proposed method, such as its computational complexity or the need for large amounts of data to generate adversarial samples.</li>
<li>The paper does not provide a comparison with other existing methods for detecting and understanding vulnerabilities in LLMs, which could help to better evaluate the effectiveness and efficiency of the proposed method.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss any potential ethical or societal implications of the proposed method, such as the potential misuse of adversarial samples to attack LLMs in real-world applications.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-30</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.19842v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.19842v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.19842v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.19842v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6824</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Detecting_and_Understanding_Vulnerabilities_in_Language_Models_via_Mechanistic_Interpretability/2024-07-29-Detecting_and_Understanding_Vulnerabilities_in_Language_Models_via_Mechanistic_Interpretability.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.19842v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>rLLM: Relational Table Learning with LLMs</title>
  <dc:creator>Weichen Li, Xiaotong Huang, Jianwu Zheng, Zheng Wang, Chaokun Wang, Li Pan, Jianhua Li</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/rLLM_Relational_Table_Learning_with_LLMs/2024-07-29-rLLM_Relational_Table_Learning_with_LLMs.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/rLLM_Relational_Table_Learning_with_LLMs/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.20157v1/x3.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper introduces rLLM (relationLLM), a PyTorch library designed for Relational Table Learning (RTL) with Large Language Models (LLMs). The core idea is to decompose state-of-the-art Graph Neural Networks, LLMs, and Table Neural Networks into standardized modules, enabling the fast construction of novel RTL-type models in a simple “combine, align, and co-train” manner. The authors present a simple RTL method named BRIDGE and introduce three novel relational tabular datasets (TML1M, TLF2K, and TACM12K) by enhancing classic datasets. The rLLM library aims to serve as a useful and easy-to-use development framework for RTL-related tasks.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>rLLM Library</strong>: The paper introduces a PyTorch library, rLLM, designed for Relational Table Learning (RTL) with Large Language Models (LLMs). The library decomposes state-of-the-art Graph Neural Networks, LLMs, and Table Neural Networks into standardized modules, enabling the fast construction of novel RTL-type models.</li>
<li><strong>BRIDGE Method</strong>: The authors present a simple RTL method named BRIDGE, which utilizes TNNs to process table data and leverages the “foreign keys” in relational tables to construct relationships between table samples, analyzed using GNNs. This approach takes into account multiple tables and the relationships between them.</li>
<li><strong>Novel Datasets</strong>: The paper introduces three novel relational tabular datasets (TML1M, TLF2K, and TACM12K) by enhancing classic datasets. Each dataset is obtained by enhancing existing classical datasets and is accompanied by a standard classification task. These datasets are well-organized and easy-to-use, making them suitable for designing novel RTL-type methods.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Limited Evaluation</strong>: The paper does not provide a comprehensive evaluation of the rLLM library or the BRIDGE method. The experimental results are limited to the TML1M dataset, and the comparison is only made with TNN-type methods. A more extensive evaluation,</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-30</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.20157v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.20157v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.20157v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.20157v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5065</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/rLLM_Relational_Table_Learning_with_LLMs/2024-07-29-rLLM_Relational_Table_Learning_with_LLMs.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.20157v1/x3.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Teaching LLMs at Charles University: Assignments and Activities</title>
  <dc:creator>Jindřich Helcl, Zdeněk Kasner, Ondřej Dušek, Tomasz Limisiewicz, Dominik Macháček, Tomáš Musil, Jindřich Libovický</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Teaching_LLMs_at_Charles_University_Assignments_and_Activities/2024-07-29-Teaching_LLMs_at_Charles_University_Assignments_and_Activities.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/../bayesian-beagle.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper presents teaching materials, particularly assignments and ideas for classroom activities, from a new course on large language models (LLMs) taught at Charles University.</li>
<li>The course was composed of 13 sessions with various levels of interactivity, including lectures, directed discussions, quizzes, and practical work with LLMs.</li>
<li>The assignments included experiments with LLM inference for weather report generation and machine translation.</li>
<li>Classroom activities included class quizzes, focused research on downstream tasks and datasets, and an interactive “best paper” session aimed at reading and comprehension of research papers.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Weather Report Generation:</strong> Students worked in small teams to generate weather reports using LLMs. They experimented with various decoding parameters and models, including Mistral 7B, Mistral 7B Instruct, Phi-2, and Aya-101. The students reported difficulties in generating factually accurate outputs from the models.</li>
<li><strong>Machine Translation:</strong> Students were given paragraphs of text in 21 languages and instructed to translate them using an LLM into English and then into a language of their choice. They experimented with prompt engineering and decoding parameters. The students could generally match the quality of commercial MT systems when translating into English from medium-resourced languages. However, translating into their languages appeared challenging.</li>
<li><strong>Classroom Activities:</strong> The course included various classroom activities such as discussions, class quizzes, focused research on downstream tasks and datasets, and an interactive “best paper” session. These activities aimed to encourage student participation and critical thinking.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper provides a detailed overview of the course structure and activities, which can be beneficial for educators looking to develop similar courses.</li>
<li>The use of practical assignments and interactive sessions can help students better understand the concepts and applications of LLMs.</li>
<li>However, the paper does not provide a detailed evaluation of the course’s effectiveness or student learning outcomes. It would be beneficial to have more information on how the course impacted students’ understanding and application of LLMs.</li>
<li>The paper also does not discuss potential challenges or limitations in implementing the course, such as the need for specialized hardware or the time required for students to complete the assignments.</li>
<li>The course’s focus</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-30</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.19798v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.19798v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.19798v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.19798v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>2201</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Teaching_LLMs_at_Charles_University_Assignments_and_Activities/2024-07-29-Teaching_LLMs_at_Charles_University_Assignments_and_Activities.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>OptiMUS-0.3: Using Large Language Models to Model and Solve Optimization Problems at Scale</title>
  <dc:creator>Ali AhmadiTeshnizi, Wenzhi Gao, Herman Brunborg, Shayan Talaei, Madeleine Udell</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/OptiMUS_0.3_Using_Large_Language_Models_to_Model_and_Solve_Optimization_Problems_at_Scale/2024-07-29-OptiMUS_0.3_Using_Large_Language_Models_to_Model_and_Solve_Optimization_Problems_at_Scale.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/OptiMUS_0.3_Using_Large_Language_Models_to_Model_and_Solve_Optimization_Problems_at_Scale/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.19633v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper introduces OptiMUS-0.3, a Large Language Model (LLM)-based system designed to formulate and solve (mixed integer) linear programming problems from their natural language descriptions. The system is capable of developing mathematical models, writing and debugging solver code, evaluating the generated solutions, and improving efficiency and correctness of its model and code based on these evaluations. OptiMUS-0.3 utilizes a modular structure to process problems, allowing it to handle problems with long descriptions and complex data without long prompts. Experiments demonstrate that OptiMUS-0.3 outperforms existing state-of-the-art methods on easy datasets by more than 12% and on hard datasets (including a new dataset, NLP4LP, released with this paper that features long and complex problems) by more than 8%.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>OptiMUS-0.3 is an LLM-based system that can formulate and solve (mixed integer) linear programming problems from natural language descriptions, outperforming existing state-of-the-art methods.</li>
<li>The system uses a modular structure to process problems, allowing it to handle long descriptions and complex data without long prompts.</li>
<li>OptiMUS-0.3 can improve efficiency and correctness of its model and code based on evaluations of generated solutions.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>While OptiMUS-0.3 demonstrates promising results, there are potential limitations and areas for improvement. The system’s reliance on LLMs may introduce challenges related to ensuring correctness and completeness of the output, as LLMs can suffer from hallucination and generate incorrect or incomplete solutions. Additionally, the system’s performance on real-world, complex problems with large problem data and long descriptions may be affected by the limitations of LLMs in handling such inputs. Further research and development are needed to address these challenges and improve the system’s performance and reliability.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-30</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.19633v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.19633v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.19633v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.19633v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>9822</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>programming</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/OptiMUS_0.3_Using_Large_Language_Models_to_Model_and_Solve_Optimization_Problems_at_Scale/2024-07-29-OptiMUS_0.3_Using_Large_Language_Models_to_Model_and_Solve_Optimization_Problems_at_Scale.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.19633v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
