<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Bayesian beagle</title>
<link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Quarto blog of LLM-generated summaries of Arxiv preprints</description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.450</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Codebook LLMs: Adapting Political Science Codebooks for LLM Use and Adapting LLMs to Follow Codebooks</title>
  <dc:creator>Andrew Halterman, Katherine A. Keith</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Codebook_LLMs_Adapting_Political_Science_Codebooks_for_LLM_Use_and_Adapting_LLMs_to_Follow_Codebooks/2024-07-15-Codebook_LLMs_Adapting_Political_Science_Codebooks_for_LLM_Use_and_Adapting_LLMs_to_Follow_Codebooks.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Codebook_LLMs_Adapting_Political_Science_Codebooks_for_LLM_Use_and_Adapting_LLMs_to_Follow_Codebooks/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10747v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>This article discusses the use of large language models (LLMs) for labeling and analyzing text data in political science. The authors argue that political scientists should make a codebook-construct label assumption, which assumes that an LLM should follow the definition and exclusion criteria of a construct/label provided in a codebook. The authors conduct experiments using Mistral 7B Instruct as their LLM and find that restructuring the original codebooks gives modest gains in zero-shot performance, but the model still struggles to comply with the constraints of the codebooks. Instruction-tuning Mistral on one of their datasets gives significant gains over zero-shot inference. The authors hope their conceptualization of the codebook-specific task, assumptions, and instruction-tuning pipeline will help political scientists adapt to the LLM era.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Restructuring the original codebooks gives modest gains in zero-shot performance, but the model still struggles to comply with the constraints of the codebooks.</li>
<li>Instruction-tuning Mistral on one of their datasets gives significant gains over zero-shot inference (0.76 versus 0.53 micro F1).</li>
<li>The authors’ conceptualization of the codebook-specific task, assumptions, and instruction-tuning pipeline will help political scientists adapt to the LLM era.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article provides a valuable contribution to the field of political science by addressing the challenges of using LLMs for labeling and analyzing text data. The authors’ conceptualization of the codebook-specific task and their instruction-tuning pipeline are well-structured and coherent. However, the article does not provide a detailed analysis of the limitations and potential biases of using LLMs for this purpose. Additionally, the authors do not discuss the potential impact of their findings on the broader field of political science or the implications for other disciplines that use text data. Further research is needed to address these issues and to evaluate the generalizability of the authors’ findings.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10747v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10747v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10747v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10747v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>14142</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Codebook_LLMs_Adapting_Political_Science_Codebooks_for_LLM_Use_and_Adapting_LLMs_to_Follow_Codebooks/2024-07-15-Codebook_LLMs_Adapting_Political_Science_Codebooks_for_LLM_Use_and_Adapting_LLMs_to_Follow_Codebooks.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10747v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Understanding the Importance of Evolutionary Search in Automated Heuristic Design with Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Rui Zhang, Fei Liu, Xi Lin, Zhenkun Wang, Zhichao Lu, Qingfu Zhang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Understanding_the_Importance_of_Evolutionary_Search_in_Automated_Heuristic_Design_with_Large_Language_Models/2024-07-15-Understanding_the_Importance_of_Evolutionary_Search_in_Automated_Heuristic_Design_with_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Understanding_the_Importance_of_Evolutionary_Search_in_Automated_Heuristic_Design_with_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10873v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Automated heuristic design (AHD) aims to automatically select, refine, or construct effective heuristics, eliminating the need for rich domain expertise.</li>
<li>The advent of large language models (LLMs) has introduced new tools for AHD, with initial efforts focusing on framing AHD as an evolutionary program search (EPS) problem.</li>
<li>This work seeks to address inconsistent benchmark settings, inadequate baselines, and lack of detailed component analysis in existing LLM-based EPS methods.</li>
<li>A large-scale benchmark is conducted, examining all existing LLM-based EPS methods and a proposed baseline on four AHD problems across nine LLMs and five independent runs.</li>
<li>The study provides empirical grounding for the importance of evolutionary search in LLM-based AHD approaches and contributes to the advancement of future EPS algorithmic development.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Major Findings:</strong></p>
<ol type="1">
<li>The inherent generative capability of LLMs alone is insufficient for AHD problems, providing empirical justification for coupling LLMs with a search mechanism, i.e., the LLM-based EPS paradigm.</li>
<li>The performance of existing LLM-based EPS methods varies significantly across different AHD problems and LLM choices, suggesting more diverse benchmarks and applications are needed to establish a better understanding of this emergent paradigm for AHD.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The study addresses the need for a more adequate baseline beyond random search and intuitive heuristics for a meaningful and representative comparison in AHD.</li>
<li>The proposed baseline, ()-EPS, is inspired by the (1+1)-ES and few-shot prompting, aiming to simulate the lower bound of the performance of the EPS paradigm.</li>
<li>The work provides a comprehensive evaluation of existing LLM-based EPS methods, highlighting the necessity of coupling LLMs with a search strategy for tackling AHD problems effectively.</li>
<li>The study’s findings contribute to the advancement of future EPS algorithmic development and foster accessibility and reproducibility by fully open-sourcing the benchmark and corresponding results.</li>
<li>Potential limitations of the study include the focus on a specific set of LLMs and AHD problems, which may not generalize</li>
</ul>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10873v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10873v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10873v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10873v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>9933</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Understanding_the_Importance_of_Evolutionary_Search_in_Automated_Heuristic_Design_with_Large_Language_Models/2024-07-15-Understanding_the_Importance_of_Evolutionary_Search_in_Automated_Heuristic_Design_with_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10873v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Large Language Model-based FMRI Encoding of Language Functions for Subjects with Neurocognitive Disorder</title>
  <dc:creator>Yuejiao Wang, Xianmin Gong, Lingwei Meng, Xixin Wu, Helen Meng</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Large_Language_Model_based_FMRI_Encoding_of_Language_Functions_for_Subjects_with_Neurocognitive_Disorder/2024-07-15-Large_Language_Model_based_FMRI_Encoding_of_Language_Functions_for_Subjects_with_Neurocognitive_Disorder.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Large_Language_Model_based_FMRI_Encoding_of_Language_Functions_for_Subjects_with_Neurocognitive_Disorder/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10376v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>This study explores language-related functional changes in older adults with Neurocognitive Disorders (NCD) using Large Language Model (LLM)-based fMRI encoding and brain scores. The research aims to address the limitations of existing studies that predominantly focus on healthy, young adults. The findings reveal that higher cognitive abilities correspond to better brain scores, with correlations peaking in the middle temporal gyrus. This study highlights the potential of fMRI encoding models and brain scores for detecting early functional changes in NCD patients.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The study applies an fMRI encoding model based on LlaMA2 to investigate NCD subjects, generating brain scores to quantify the association between brain areas and language functions.</li>
<li>Brain scores for the higher cognitive-level group are consistently better than those of the lower cognitive-level group, and the correlation between brain scores and cognition peaks in the middle temporal gyrus (r = 0.51) and the superior frontal gyrus (r = 0.46).</li>
<li>This study provides a feasible direction for further developing interpretable machine-learning models based on language-related fMRI signals for early NCD detection.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study’s primary limitation is the uncertainty surrounding the extent of semantic or syntactic information contained in the embeddings of LlaMA2-Cantonese.</li>
<li>The brain areas responsible for language processing may also be activated by semantic stimuli generated through vision. In the future, multi-modal semantic information should be comprehensively considered to construct a robust encoding model for understanding the interplay between different modalities and language functions.</li>
<li>The study could benefit from a larger sample size and a more diverse range of NCD subjects to increase the generalizability of the findings.</li>
<li>The research could also explore the potential of other LLMs, such as GPT-3 or BERT, for fMRI encoding and brain score analysis in NCD subjects.</li>
<li>The study does not discuss the potential implications of these findings for clinical practice or the development of targeted interventions for NCD patients. Future research should consider the practical applications of these findings.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10376v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10376v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10376v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10376v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>4280</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Large_Language_Model_based_FMRI_Encoding_of_Language_Functions_for_Subjects_with_Neurocognitive_Disorder/2024-07-15-Large_Language_Model_based_FMRI_Encoding_of_Language_Functions_for_Subjects_with_Neurocognitive_Disorder.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10376v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Good, The Bad, and The Greedy: Evaluation of LLMs Should Not Ignore Non-Determinism</title>
  <dc:creator>Yifan Song, Guoyin Wang, Sujian Li, Bill Yuchen Lin</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/The_Good_The_Bad_and_The_Greedy_Evaluation_of_LLMs_Should_Not_Ignore_Non_Determinism/2024-07-15-The_Good_The_Bad_and_The_Greedy_Evaluation_of_LLMs_Should_Not_Ignore_Non_Determinism.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/The_Good_The_Bad_and_The_Greedy_Evaluation_of_LLMs_Should_Not_Ignore_Non_Determinism/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10457v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The study titled “The Good, The Bad, and The Greedy: Evaluation of LLMs Should Not Ignore Non-Determinism” explores the performance differences between greedy decoding and sampling in large language models (LLMs). The research aims to address the limitations of current LLM evaluations, which often overlook non-determinism and focus on a single output per example. Through extensive experiments, the authors observe that greedy decoding generally outperforms sampling methods for most evaluated tasks. They also find consistent performance across different LLM sizes and alignment methods, noting that alignment can reduce sampling variance. Furthermore, the best-of-N sampling approach demonstrates that smaller LLMs can match or surpass larger models such as GPT-4-Turbo, highlighting the untapped potential of smaller LLMs.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Greedy decoding outperforms sampling methods for most evaluated tasks, with consistent performance across different LLM sizes and alignment methods.</li>
<li>Alignment methods, such as DPO, can significantly reduce the sampling variance for most benchmarks.</li>
<li>Smaller LLMs can match or surpass larger models such as GPT-4-Turbo using the best-of-N sampling approach, highlighting the untapped potential of smaller LLMs.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The study provides valuable insights into the performance differences between greedy decoding and sampling in LLMs. However, there are some limitations and areas for further research.</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>The study focuses on a limited number of LLMs and benchmarks, which may not be representative of the broader landscape of LLMs and tasks.</li>
<li>The research does not explore the impact of different decoding parameters, such as temperature and repetition penalty, on the performance of LLMs.</li>
<li>The study does not address the potential biases and limitations of the benchmarks used, which could impact the generalizability of the findings.</li>
<li>The research does not discuss the potential implications of the findings for real-world applications of LLMs, such as chatbots or content generation tools.</li>
</ol>
<p>In conclusion, the study provides a valuable contribution to the understanding of non-determinism in LLM evaluations. However, further research is needed to address the limitations and explore the broader implications of the findings.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10457v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10457v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10457v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10457v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5472</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/The_Good_The_Bad_and_The_Greedy_Evaluation_of_LLMs_Should_Not_Ignore_Non_Determinism/2024-07-15-The_Good_The_Bad_and_The_Greedy_Evaluation_of_LLMs_Should_Not_Ignore_Non_Determinism.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10457v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>NTSEBENCH: Cognitive Reasoning Benchmark for Vision Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Pranshu Pandya, Agney S Talwarr, Vatsal Gupta, Tushar Kataria, Vivek Gupta, Dan Roth</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/NTSEBENCH_Cognitive_Reasoning_Benchmark_for_Vision_Language_Models/2024-07-15-NTSEBENCH_Cognitive_Reasoning_Benchmark_for_Vision_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/NTSEBENCH_Cognitive_Reasoning_Benchmark_for_Vision_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10380v1/extracted/5731050/figures/Figure1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper introduces a new dataset, NTSEBench, designed to evaluate the cognitive multi-modal reasoning and problem-solving skills of large models. The dataset comprises 2,728 multiple-choice questions with 4,642 images across 26 categories, sourced from the NTSE examination conducted in India. The questions focus on visual and textual general aptitude, not relying on rote learning. The authors establish baselines on the dataset using state-of-the-art LLMs and VLMs and propose four distinct modeling strategies to handle different modalities (text and images) in the dataset instances.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The NTSEBench dataset is introduced, consisting of 2,728 multiple-choice questions with 4,642 images across 26 categories, sourced from the NTSE examination in India.</li>
<li>The dataset focuses on visual and textual general aptitude questions that do not rely on rote learning.</li>
<li>Baselines are established on the dataset using state-of-the-art LLMs and VLMs.</li>
<li>Four distinct modeling strategies are proposed to handle different modalities (text and images) in the dataset instances.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper does not provide a detailed analysis of the performance of the proposed modeling strategies on the NTSEBench dataset.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the limitations of the proposed dataset or the potential biases that may be present in the data.</li>
<li>The paper does not provide a comparison of the proposed dataset with other existing datasets for evaluating the cognitive reasoning skills of large models.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential applications of the proposed dataset in real-world scenarios.</li>
<li>The paper does not provide a detailed discussion of the potential ethical implications of using the proposed dataset for evaluating the cognitive reasoning skills of large models.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10380v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10380v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10380v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10380v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7146</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/NTSEBENCH_Cognitive_Reasoning_Benchmark_for_Vision_Language_Models/2024-07-15-NTSEBENCH_Cognitive_Reasoning_Benchmark_for_Vision_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10380v1/extracted/5731050/figures/Figure1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Q-Sparse: All Large Language Models can be Fully Sparsely-Activated</title>
  <dc:creator>Hongyu Wang, Shuming Ma, Ruiping Wang, Furu Wei</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Q_Sparse_All_Large_Language_Models_can_be_Fully_Sparsely_Activated/2024-07-15-Q_Sparse_All_Large_Language_Models_can_be_Fully_Sparsely_Activated.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Q_Sparse_All_Large_Language_Models_can_be_Fully_Sparsely_Activated/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10969v1/x4.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level1">
<h1>Summary:</h1>
<p><strong>Q-Sparse: All Large Language Models can be Fully Sparsely-Activated</strong></p>
<p>The paper introduces Q-Sparse, a simple yet effective approach to training sparsely-activated large language models (LLMs). Q-Sparse enables full sparsity of activations in LLMs, which can bring significant efficiency gains in inference. This is achieved by applying top-k sparsification to the activations and the straight-through-estimator to the training. The key results from this work are:</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>Q-Sparse can achieve results comparable to those of baseline LLMs while being much more efficient at inference time.</li>
<li>An inference-optimal scaling law for sparsely-activated LLMs is presented.</li>
<li>Q-Sparse is effective in different settings, including training-from-scratch, continue-training of off-the-shelf LLMs, and finetuning.</li>
<li>Q-Sparse works for both full-precision and 1-bit LLMs (e.g., BitNet b1.58).</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level1">
<h1>Major Findings:</h1>
<ol type="1">
<li>Q-Sparse enables full sparsity of activations in LLMs, which can bring significant efficiency gains in inference.</li>
<li>Q-Sparse can achieve results comparable to those of baseline LLMs while being much more efficient at inference time.</li>
<li>An inference-optimal scaling law for sparsely-activated LLMs is presented.</li>
<li>Q-Sparse is effective in different settings, including training-from-scratch, continue-training of off-the-shelf LLMs, and finetuning.</li>
<li>Q-Sparse works for both full-precision and 1-bit LLMs (e.g., BitNet b1.58).</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level1">
<h1>Analysis and Critique:</h1>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper does not provide a detailed comparison of Q-Sparse with other sparsity-inducing methods, such as pruning or distillation.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential impact of sparsity on the generalization performance of LLMs.</li>
<li>The paper does not provide a detailed analysis of the computational and memory overhead of Q-Sparse.</li>
</ol>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10969v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10969v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10969v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10969v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5530</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Q_Sparse_All_Large_Language_Models_can_be_Fully_Sparsely_Activated/2024-07-15-Q_Sparse_All_Large_Language_Models_can_be_Fully_Sparsely_Activated.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10969v1/x4.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Leveraging LLM-Respondents for Item Evaluation: a Psychometric Analysis</title>
  <dc:creator>Yunting Liu, Shreya Bhandari, Zachary A. Pardos</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Leveraging_LLM_Respondents_for_Item_Evaluation_a_Psychometric_Analysis/2024-07-15-Leveraging_LLM_Respondents_for_Item_Evaluation_a_Psychometric_Analysis.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Leveraging_LLM_Respondents_for_Item_Evaluation_a_Psychometric_Analysis/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10899v1/extracted/5732709/wrightmap.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study explores the use of six different LLMs (GPT-3.5, GPT-4, Llama 2, Llama 3, Gemini-Pro, and Cohere Command R Plus) and various combinations of them using sampling methods to produce responses with psychometric properties similar to human answers.</li>
<li>Results show that some LLMs have comparable or higher proficiency in College Algebra than college students, but no single LLM mimics human respondents due to narrow proficiency distributions.</li>
<li>An ensemble of LLMs can better resemble college students’ ability distribution.</li>
<li>The item parameters calibrated by LLM-Respondents have high correlations (e.g.&nbsp;&gt; 0.8 for GPT-3.5) compared to their human calibrated counterparts, and closely resemble the parameters of the human subset (e.g.&nbsp;0.02 Spearman correlation difference).</li>
<li>Several augmentation strategies are evaluated for their relative performance, with resampling methods proving most effective, enhancing the Spearman correlation from 0.89 (human only) to 0.93 (augmented human).</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Some LLMs have comparable or higher proficiency in College Algebra than college students, but no single LLM mimics human respondents due to narrow proficiency distributions.</li>
<li>An ensemble of LLMs can better resemble college students’ ability distribution.</li>
<li>The item parameters calibrated by LLM-Respondents have high correlations (e.g.&nbsp;&gt; 0.8 for GPT-3.5) compared to their human calibrated counterparts, and closely resemble the parameters of the human subset (e.g.&nbsp;0.02 Spearman correlation difference).</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study provides a novel application of Item Response Theory (IRT) to LLM abilities, revealing a first-of-its-kind distribution spread of abilities from multiple promptings.</li>
<li>The study holds much promise for the automatic curation of items for tutoring systems, as AI respondents could be used as an initial filtering phase to reliably narrow down a larger item pool, and then have human respondents further refine the selection using the more manageable subset</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10899v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10899v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10899v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10899v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5642</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Leveraging_LLM_Respondents_for_Item_Evaluation_a_Psychometric_Analysis/2024-07-15-Leveraging_LLM_Respondents_for_Item_Evaluation_a_Psychometric_Analysis.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10899v1/extracted/5732709/wrightmap.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>SLIP: Securing LLMs IP Using Weights Decomposition</title>
  <dc:creator>Yehonathan Refael, Adam Hakim, Lev Greenberg, Tal Aviv, Satya Lokam, Ben Fishman, Shachar Seidman</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SLIP_Securing_LLMs_IP_Using_Weights_Decomposition/2024-07-15-SLIP_Securing_LLMs_IP_Using_Weights_Decomposition.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SLIP_Securing_LLMs_IP_Using_Weights_Decomposition/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10886v1/extracted/5732621/slip-diagram.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper introduces a novel hybrid inference algorithm, named SLIP, designed to protect edge-deployed models from theft. SLIP is the first hybrid protocol that is both practical for real-world applications and provably secure, with zero accuracy degradation and minimal impact on latency. The protocol involves partitioning the model between two computing resources, one secure but expensive, and another cost-effective but vulnerable. This is achieved through matrix decomposition, ensuring that the secure resource retains a maximally sensitive portion of the model’s IP while performing a minimal amount of computations, and vice versa for the vulnerable resource. The protocol includes security guarantees that prevent attackers from exploiting the partition to infer the secured information.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>SLIP is a novel hybrid inference algorithm that protects edge-deployed models from theft, with zero accuracy degradation and minimal impact on latency.</li>
<li>The protocol involves partitioning the model between two computing resources, one secure but expensive, and another cost-effective but vulnerable, through matrix decomposition.</li>
<li>The secure resource retains a maximally sensitive portion of the model’s IP while performing a minimal amount of computations, and vice versa for the vulnerable resource.</li>
<li>The protocol includes security guarantees that prevent attackers from exploiting the partition to infer the secured information.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The paper presents an innovative approach to securing the intellectual property of large language models (LLMs) deployed on edge devices. The proposed SLIP protocol offers a practical and provably secure solution to protect models from theft, with minimal impact on latency and no accuracy degradation. The use of matrix decomposition to partition the model between two computing resources is a novel approach that ensures the secure resource retains the most sensitive information while performing minimal computations.</p>
<p>However, the paper does not provide a detailed comparison with existing methods for securing LLMs, which could help to better understand the advantages and limitations of the proposed approach. Additionally, the paper does not discuss the potential impact of the protocol on the overall performance of the model, such as the effect on inference time or the computational resources required for the secure and vulnerable resources. Further research is needed to evaluate the performance of the SLIP protocol in real-world scenarios and compare it with existing methods.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10886v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10886v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10886v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10886v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8145</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SLIP_Securing_LLMs_IP_Using_Weights_Decomposition/2024-07-15-SLIP_Securing_LLMs_IP_Using_Weights_Decomposition.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10886v1/extracted/5732621/slip-diagram.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>GraphEval: A Knowledge-Graph Based LLM Hallucination Evaluation Framework</title>
  <dc:creator>Hannah Sansford, Nicholas Richardson, Hermina Petric Maretic, Juba Nait Saada</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/GraphEval_A_Knowledge_Graph_Based_LLM_Hallucination_Evaluation_Framework/2024-07-15-GraphEval_A_Knowledge_Graph_Based_LLM_Hallucination_Evaluation_Framework.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/GraphEval_A_Knowledge_Graph_Based_LLM_Hallucination_Evaluation_Framework/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10793v1/extracted/5732436/grapheval_process.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper presents GraphEval, a hallucination evaluation framework for Large Language Models (LLMs) based on representing information in Knowledge Graph (KG) structures. The method identifies specific triples in the KG that are prone to hallucinations, providing more insight into where in the response a hallucination has occurred. The framework improves balanced accuracy on various hallucination benchmarks when used with state-of-the-art natural language inference (NLI) models. Additionally, the authors explore the use of GraphEval for hallucination correction, named GraphCorrect, and demonstrate that the majority of hallucinations can be rectified.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>GraphEval is a hallucination evaluation framework that uses KG structures to represent information, providing a higher level of insight into where in the output a hallucination has occurred than previous metrics.</li>
<li>Using GraphEval in conjunction with state-of-the-art NLI models leads to an improvement in balanced accuracy on various hallucination benchmarks compared to using raw NLI models.</li>
<li>The authors introduce GraphCorrect, a method for hallucination correction that leverages the structure of the KG, effectively rectifying a significant proportion of hallucinations present in LLM outputs.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper does not provide a comprehensive comparison of GraphEval with other existing hallucination detection methods, making it difficult to assess its performance relative to other approaches.</li>
<li>The authors do not discuss the potential limitations of using KGs for hallucination detection, such as the complexity of constructing accurate KGs or the potential for information loss during the KG construction process.</li>
<li>The paper does not address the issue of open-domain hallucination detection, which may be an important consideration for real-world applications of LLMs.</li>
<li>The evaluation of GraphCorrect is based on the use of hallucination evaluation frameworks, which may not accurately reflect the true performance of the method in correcting hallucinations. A manual evaluation of the corrected outputs would provide a more reliable assessment of the method’s effectiveness.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential for using GraphEval and GraphCorrect in conjunction with other LLM-based hallucination detection and correction methods, which could further</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10793v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10793v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10793v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10793v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5868</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/GraphEval_A_Knowledge_Graph_Based_LLM_Hallucination_Evaluation_Framework/2024-07-15-GraphEval_A_Knowledge_Graph_Based_LLM_Hallucination_Evaluation_Framework.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10793v1/extracted/5732436/grapheval_process.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Enhancing Medication Recommendation with LLM Text Representation</title>
  <dc:creator>Yu-Tzu Lee</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Enhancing_Medication_Recommendation_with_LLM_Text_Representation/2024-07-15-Enhancing_Medication_Recommendation_with_LLM_Text_Representation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2407.10453v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary:</strong></p>
<p>The paper proposes a method to enhance medication recommendation by utilizing Large Language Models (LLMs) for text representation. The method aims to increase the utilization of unstructured or semi-structured data, such as clinical notes, which contain complex terminology. The proposed method can be applied to existing base models and improve medication recommendation performance with the combination representation of text and medical codes. The experiments conducted on two different datasets demonstrate that LLM text representation alone can even demonstrate a comparable ability to medical code representation alone.</p>
<p><strong>Major Findings:</strong></p>
<ol type="1">
<li>The proposed method of using LLM text representation for medication recommendation can improve the performance of existing base models.</li>
<li>The combination representation of text and medical codes can maintain performance at a certain level.</li>
<li>The LLM text representation contains valuable information for medication recommendation, and its combination with medical code embeddings maintains performance at a certain level.</li>
</ol>
<p>**Analysis and Critique</p>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10453v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10453v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10453v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10453v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>31783</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>recommender</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Enhancing_Medication_Recommendation_with_LLM_Text_Representation/2024-07-15-Enhancing_Medication_Recommendation_with_LLM_Text_Representation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2407.10453v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>By My Eyes: Grounding Multimodal Large Language Models with Sensor Data via Visual Prompting</title>
  <dc:creator>Hyungjun Yoon, Biniyam Aschalew Tolera, Taesik Gong, Kimin Lee, Sung-Ju Lee</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/By_My_Eyes_Grounding_Multimodal_Large_Language_Models_with_Sensor_Data_via_Visual_Prompting/2024-07-15-By_My_Eyes_Grounding_Multimodal_Large_Language_Models_with_Sensor_Data_via_Visual_Prompting.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/By_My_Eyes_Grounding_Multimodal_Large_Language_Models_with_Sensor_Data_via_Visual_Prompting/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10385v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper proposes a visual prompting approach for sensor data using multimodal large language models (MLLMs). The authors design a visual prompt that directs MLLMs to utilize visualized sensor data alongside the target sensory task descriptions. They also introduce a visualization generator that automates the creation of optimal visualizations tailored to a given sensory task, eliminating the need for prior task-specific knowledge. The proposed approach is evaluated on nine sensory tasks involving four sensing modalities, achieving an average of 10% higher accuracy than text-based prompts and reducing token costs by 15.8.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The proposed visual prompting approach for sensor data using MLLMs achieves an average of 10% higher accuracy than text-based prompts.</li>
<li>The visualization generator automates the creation of optimal visualizations tailored to a given sensory task, eliminating the need for prior task-specific knowledge.</li>
<li>The proposed approach reduces token costs by 15.8 compared to text-based prompts.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper presents a novel approach to grounding MLLMs with sensor data by providing visualized sensor data as images, which improves performance and reduces costs compared to the text-based baseline.</li>
<li>The visualization generator is a significant contribution, as it enables MLLMs to independently generate optimal visualizations using tools available in public libraries.</li>
<li>The experiments conducted on nine different sensory tasks across four modalities demonstrate the broad applicability of the proposed approach.</li>
<li>However, the paper does not discuss the limitations of the proposed approach, such as the potential for overfitting to specific visualizations or the generalizability of the visualization generator to other sensing tasks.</li>
<li>The paper also does not provide a comparison with other state-of-the-art methods for grounding MLLMs with sensor data, which could have strengthened the evaluation of the proposed approach.</li>
<li>The paper could benefit from a more detailed analysis of the results, including error analysis and ablation studies, to better understand the strengths and weaknesses of the proposed approach.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10385v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10385v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10385v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10385v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7689</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/By_My_Eyes_Grounding_Multimodal_Large_Language_Models_with_Sensor_Data_via_Visual_Prompting/2024-07-15-By_My_Eyes_Grounding_Multimodal_Large_Language_Models_with_Sensor_Data_via_Visual_Prompting.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10385v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Mix-CPT: A Domain Adaptation Framework via Decoupling Knowledge Learning and Format Alignment</title>
  <dc:creator>Jinhao Jiang, Junyi Li, Wayne Xin Zhao, Yang Song, Tao Zhang, Ji-Rong Wen</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Mix_CPT_A_Domain_Adaptation_Framework_via_Decoupling_Knowledge_Learning_and_Format_Alignment/2024-07-15-Mix_CPT_A_Domain_Adaptation_Framework_via_Decoupling_Knowledge_Learning_and_Format_Alignment.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Mix_CPT_A_Domain_Adaptation_Framework_via_Decoupling_Knowledge_Learning_and_Format_Alignment/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10804v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper proposes a new domain adaptation framework called Mix-CPT for large language models (LLMs) to address the challenges of varied data distributions in specialized domains.</li>
<li>Mix-CPT includes two main stages: domain knowledge learning and general format alignment.</li>
<li>The domain knowledge learning stage involves knowledge mixture continual pre-training, which focuses on both knowledge memorization and utilization, and incorporates a logit swap self-distillation constraint to avoid catastrophic forgetting.</li>
<li>The general format alignment stage leverages the knowledge and capabilities acquired during continual pre-training to efficiently perform instruction tuning and alignment with a few general training samples for format alignment.</li>
<li>Extensive experiments demonstrate that Mix-CPT can improve the task-solving capabilities of LLMs on both target and general domains compared to traditional adaptation methods.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Mix-CPT enables LLMs to learn domain-specific knowledge and solve domain tasks with learned knowledge by disentangling domain adaptation into knowledge memorization and capability elicitation.</li>
<li>The use of token swap self-distillation in the knowledge mixture pre-training helps retain general knowledge and avoid catastrophic forgetting.</li>
<li>Mix-CPT outperforms traditional methods in both domain and general capabilities, as demonstrated by extensive experiments on three benchmark datasets.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper presents a novel approach to domain adaptation for LLMs, addressing the limitations of traditional methods that may result in inefficient knowledge memorization and substantial demands on LLMs.</li>
<li>The proposed Mix-CPT framework effectively improves the task-solving capabilities of LLMs on both target and general domains, as demonstrated by the experimental results.</li>
<li>However, the paper does not discuss the potential limitations or challenges of implementing Mix-CPT, such as the computational resources required for continual pre-training or the availability of high-quality domain-specific data.</li>
<li>Additionally, the paper does not provide a comparison of Mix-CPT with other recent domain adaptation methods, which could further validate its effectiveness and efficiency.</li>
<li>Future research could explore the application of Mix-CPT to other domains and investigate its performance in comparison to other state-of-the-art domain adaptation methods.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10804v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10804v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10804v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10804v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8459</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Mix_CPT_A_Domain_Adaptation_Framework_via_Decoupling_Knowledge_Learning_and_Format_Alignment/2024-07-15-Mix_CPT_A_Domain_Adaptation_Framework_via_Decoupling_Knowledge_Learning_and_Format_Alignment.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10804v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Hey, That’s My Model! Introducing Chain &amp; Hash, An LLM Fingerprinting Technique</title>
  <dc:creator>Mark Russinovich, Ahmed Salem</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Hey_Thats_My_Model!_Introducing_Chain__Hash_An_LLM_Fingerprinting_Technique/2024-07-15-Hey_Thats_My_Model!_Introducing_Chain__Hash_An_LLM_Fingerprinting_Technique.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Hey_Thats_My_Model!_Introducing_Chain__Hash_An_LLM_Fingerprinting_Technique/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10887v1/extracted/5732801/figs/chainAndHashOverview.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper introduces a new fingerprinting technique called Chain &amp; Hash for Large Language Models (LLMs) to protect their intellectual property (IP) and prevent misuse or theft. The technique involves generating a set of questions and potential answers, which are then hashed together using a secure hashing technique to select the value for each question. This approach provides an unforgeability property, preventing adversaries from claiming false ownership. The authors evaluate Chain &amp; Hash on multiple models and demonstrate its robustness against benign transformations and adversarial attempts to erase the fingerprint. The technique is efficient and maintains the performance of the fingerprinted models across different benchmarks.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Chain &amp; Hash is a new, simple fingerprinting approach that implements a fingerprint with a cryptographic flavor, achieving all the desired properties of a successful fingerprint, including transparency, efficiency, persistence, robustness, and unforgeability.</li>
<li>The technique involves generating a set of questions and potential answers, which are then hashed together using a secure hashing technique to select the value for each question, providing an unforgeability property.</li>
<li>The authors evaluate Chain &amp; Hash on multiple models and demonstrate its robustness against benign transformations, such as fine-tuning on different datasets, and adversarial attempts to erase the fingerprint.</li>
<li>The technique is efficient and maintains the performance of the fingerprinted models, which achieve almost the same performance as non-fingerprinted ones across different benchmarks.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The Chain &amp; Hash technique presents a promising approach to fingerprinting LLMs and protecting their IP. The use of a cryptographic hashing technique to select the value for each question provides a strong unforgeability property, making it difficult for adversaries to claim false ownership. The evaluation of the technique on multiple models and its demonstrated robustness against benign transformations and adversarial attempts to erase the fingerprint further support its effectiveness.</p>
<p>However, there are some potential limitations and areas for improvement. For instance, the technique’s reliance on a secure hashing technique may introduce computational overhead, which could impact the efficiency of the fingerprinting process. Additionally, the evaluation of the technique on multiple models is limited to a specific set of benchmarks,</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10887v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10887v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10887v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10887v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>11915</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Hey_Thats_My_Model!_Introducing_Chain__Hash_An_LLM_Fingerprinting_Technique/2024-07-15-Hey_Thats_My_Model!_Introducing_Chain__Hash_An_LLM_Fingerprinting_Technique.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10887v1/extracted/5732801/figs/chainAndHashOverview.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>CLAVE: An Adaptive Framework for Evaluating Values of LLM Generated Responses</title>
  <dc:creator>Jing Yao, Xiaoyuan Yi, Xing Xie</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/CLAVE_An_Adaptive_Framework_for_Evaluating_Values_of_LLM_Generated_Responses/2024-07-15-CLAVE_An_Adaptive_Framework_for_Evaluating_Values_of_LLM_Generated_Responses.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/CLAVE_An_Adaptive_Framework_for_Evaluating_Values_of_LLM_Generated_Responses/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10725v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper introduces CLAVE, a novel framework for evaluating the values of Large Language Models (LLMs) generated responses. The framework integrates two complementary LLMs: a large one for extracting high-level value concepts from a few human labels and a smaller one fine-tuned on these concepts to better align with human value understanding. This dual-model approach enables calibration with any value system using 100 human-labeled samples per value. The paper also presents ValEval, a comprehensive dataset comprising 13k+ text, value, label tuples across diverse domains and three major value systems. The authors benchmark the capabilities of 12+ popular LLM evaluators and analyze their strengths and weaknesses. The findings reveal that combining fine-tuned small models and prompt-based large ones serves as a superior balance in value evaluation.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The CLAVE framework integrates two complementary LLMs, a large one for extracting high-level value concepts and a smaller one fine-tuned on these concepts, to better align with human value understanding.</li>
<li>The dual-model approach enables calibration with any value system using 100 human-labeled samples per value.</li>
<li>The paper presents ValEval, a comprehensive dataset comprising 13k+ text, value, label tuples across diverse domains and three major value systems.</li>
<li>The authors benchmark the capabilities of 12+ popular LLM evaluators and analyze their strengths and weaknesses.</li>
<li>The findings reveal that combining fine-tuned small models and prompt-based large ones serves as a superior balance in value evaluation.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The paper presents a novel framework, CLAVE, for evaluating the values of LLMs generated responses. The framework addresses the challenges of adaptability and generalizability in LLM-based evaluators by integrating two complementary LLMs. The dual-model approach enables calibration with any value system using a relatively small number of human-labeled samples. The paper also presents a comprehensive dataset, ValEval, which covers diverse domains and three major value systems. The authors benchmark the capabilities of 12+ popular LLM evaluators and provide a detailed analysis of their strengths and weaknesses.</p>
<p>However</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10725v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10725v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10725v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10725v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>9188</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/CLAVE_An_Adaptive_Framework_for_Evaluating_Values_of_LLM_Generated_Responses/2024-07-15-CLAVE_An_Adaptive_Framework_for_Evaluating_Values_of_LLM_Generated_Responses.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10725v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>FinDKG: Dynamic Knowledge Graphs with Large Language Models for Detecting Global Trends in Financial Markets</title>
  <dc:creator>Xiaohui Victor Li, Francesco Sanna Passino</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/FinDKG_Dynamic_Knowledge_Graphs_with_Large_Language_Models_for_Detecting_Global_Trends_in_Financial_Markets/2024-07-15-FinDKG_Dynamic_Knowledge_Graphs_with_Large_Language_Models_for_Detecting_Global_Trends_in_Financial_Markets.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/FinDKG_Dynamic_Knowledge_Graphs_with_Large_Language_Models_for_Detecting_Global_Trends_in_Financial_Markets/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10909v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper explores the use of large language models (LLMs) as dynamic knowledge graph (DKG) generators, proposing a novel open-source fine-tuned LLM called the Integrated Contextual Knowledge Graph Generator (ICKG). The authors use ICKG to produce a novel open-source DKG from a corpus of financial news articles, called FinDKG, and propose an attention-based GNN architecture for analyzing it, called KGTransformer. The proposed model is tested on benchmark datasets and FinDKG, demonstrating superior performance on link prediction tasks. Additionally, the KGTransformer is evaluated on FinDKG for thematic investing, showing it can outperform existing thematic ETFs.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The proposed KGTransformer architecture improves the state-of-the-art link prediction performance on two benchmark datasets.</li>
<li>The KGTransformer achieves the best performance with over 10% uplift on FinDKG.</li>
<li>The ICKG LLM is used to create an open-source dataset from a corpus of financial news articles, called FinDKG.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper does not provide a detailed comparison of the proposed ICKG LLM with other existing LLMs for DKG generation.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the limitations and potential biases of the proposed ICKG LLM and KGTransformer.</li>
<li>The paper does not provide a detailed analysis of the computational complexity and scalability of the proposed methods.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential applications of the proposed methods beyond thematic investing.</li>
<li>The paper does not provide a detailed analysis of the quality and reliability of the generated FinDKG dataset.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential ethical implications of using LLMs for DKG generation and thematic investing.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10909v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10909v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10909v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10909v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6659</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/FinDKG_Dynamic_Knowledge_Graphs_with_Large_Language_Models_for_Detecting_Global_Trends_in_Financial_Markets/2024-07-15-FinDKG_Dynamic_Knowledge_Graphs_with_Large_Language_Models_for_Detecting_Global_Trends_in_Financial_Markets.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10909v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Cutting Through the Clutter: The Potential of LLMs for Efficient Filtration in Systematic Literature Reviews</title>
  <dc:creator>Lucas Joos, Daniel A. Keim, Maximilian T. Fischer</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Cutting_Through_the_Clutter_The_Potential_of_LLMs_for_Efficient_Filtration_in_Systematic_Literature_Reviews/2024-07-15-Cutting_Through_the_Clutter_The_Potential_of_LLMs_for_Efficient_Filtration_in_Systematic_Literature_Reviews.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Cutting_Through_the_Clutter_The_Potential_of_LLMs_for_Efficient_Filtration_in_Systematic_Literature_Reviews/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10652v1/x2.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article explores the potential of using Large Language Models (LLMs) to enhance the efficiency, speed, and precision of literature review filtering, reducing the amount of manual screening required.</li>
<li>The authors evaluate the real-world performance of LLMs during the construction of a recent literature survey paper with initially more than 8.3k potentially relevant articles and compare this with human performance on the same dataset.</li>
<li>The findings indicate that employing advanced LLMs like GPT-4o, Claude 3.5 Sonnet, Gemini 1.5 Flash, or Llama3 with simple prompting can significantly reduce the time required for literature filtering.</li>
<li>The study also shows that false negatives can be controlled through a consensus scheme, achieving recalls at or even beyond the typical human error threshold, thereby also providing for more accurate and relevant articles selected.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Efficient Literature Filtering</strong>: Employing advanced LLMs like GPT-4o, Claude 3.5 Sonnet, Gemini 1.5 Flash, or Llama3 with simple prompting can significantly reduce the time required for literature filtering.</li>
<li><strong>Controlling False Negatives</strong>: False negatives can be controlled through a consensus scheme, achieving recalls at or even beyond the typical human error threshold, thereby also providing for more accurate and relevant articles selected.</li>
<li><strong>Improved Methodology</strong>: The research demonstrates a substantial improvement in the methodology of literature reviews and sets the stage for further integration and extensive future applications of responsible AI in academic research practices.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study provides a promising approach to improving the efficiency and accuracy of literature review filtering using LLMs. However, it is important to note that the evaluation was conducted on a single large corpus and prompt, which may not generalize well to other research areas.</li>
<li>The study does not address the potential biases in the data, training, or Reinforcement Learning from Human Feedback (RLHF) process, which can lead to biased or incomplete results.</li>
<li>The SOTA commercial models have shown the highest performance but face access limitations through cost, availability, and rate limits, which might introduce an unfair advantage to established research groups, putting individual researchers or smaller groups at a disadvantage.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10652v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10652v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10652v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10652v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5541</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Cutting_Through_the_Clutter_The_Potential_of_LLMs_for_Efficient_Filtration_in_Systematic_Literature_Reviews/2024-07-15-Cutting_Through_the_Clutter_The_Potential_of_LLMs_for_Efficient_Filtration_in_Systematic_Literature_Reviews.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10652v1/x2.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>IDEAL: Leveraging Infinite and Dynamic Characterizations of Large Language Models for Query-focused Summarization</title>
  <dc:creator>Jie Cao, Dian Jiao, Qiang Yan, Wenqiao Zhang, Siliang Tang, Yueting Zhuang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/IDEAL_Leveraging_Infinite_and_Dynamic_Characterizations_of_Large_Language_Models_for_Query_focused_Summarization/2024-07-15-IDEAL_Leveraging_Infinite_and_Dynamic_Characterizations_of_Large_Language_Models_for_Query_focused_Summarization.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/IDEAL_Leveraging_Infinite_and_Dynamic_Characterizations_of_Large_Language_Models_for_Query_focused_Summarization/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10486v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper “IDEAL: Leveraging Infinite and Dynamic Characterizations of Large Language Models for Query-focused Summarization” explores the use of large language models (LLMs) for query-focused summarization (QFS). The authors propose two indispensable characteristics that LLMs-based QFS models should possess: Lengthy Document Summarization and Efficiently Fine-grained Query-LLM Alignment. To achieve these characteristics, the authors introduce two modules: Query-aware HyperExpert and Query-focused Infini-attention. The Query-aware HyperExpert module leverages parameter-efficient fine-tuning (PEFT) strategies to enable a model to perform new tasks with minimal parameter updates. The Query-focused Infini-attention module processes long documents under low memory resources for QFS tasks. The proposed approach, IDEAL, significantly outperforms other baselines in extensive and rigorous experiments across multiple QFS datasets.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The proposed IDEAL method tunes instance-level PEFT approaches according to query instructions, enhancing the model’s fine-grained instruction-following capabilities.</li>
<li>IDEAL incorporates a query-focused infini-attention module to process long text under low memory resources for QFS tasks. For example, IDEAL with the backbone model LLAMA2-7B can process datasets where the average length of input tokens is 13,000 on a single 24GB Nvidia GeForce RTX 3090.</li>
<li>IDEAL significantly outperforms other baselines in extensive and rigorous experiments across multiple QFS datasets.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The paper presents a novel approach to QFS using LLMs and introduces two modules to address the challenges of lengthy document summarization and efficient query-LLM alignment. The proposed method, IDEAL, demonstrates significant improvements over other baselines in experiments across multiple QFS datasets. However, the paper does not discuss the limitations of the proposed approach or potential biases that may have been introduced during the training stage. Additionally, the paper does not provide a detailed analysis of the method’s performance on different types of queries or the impact of the query length</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10486v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10486v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10486v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10486v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6156</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>programming</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/IDEAL_Leveraging_Infinite_and_Dynamic_Characterizations_of_Large_Language_Models_for_Query_focused_Summarization/2024-07-15-IDEAL_Leveraging_Infinite_and_Dynamic_Characterizations_of_Large_Language_Models_for_Query_focused_Summarization.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10486v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>LLM Circuit Analyses Are Consistent Across Training and Scale</title>
  <dc:creator>Curt Tigges, Michael Hanna, Qinan Yu, Stella Biderman</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLM_Circuit_Analyses_Are_Consistent_Across_Training_and_Scale/2024-07-15-LLM_Circuit_Analyses_Are_Consistent_Across_Training_and_Scale.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLM_Circuit_Analyses_Are_Consistent_Across_Training_and_Scale/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10827v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>This study explores the development and evolution of model mechanisms, operationalized as circuits, in decoder-only large language models (LLMs) across 300 billion tokens of training. The research focuses on models ranging from 70 million to 2.8 billion parameters, aiming to understand how task abilities and functional components emerge consistently at similar token counts across scale. The findings suggest that even when individual components change, the overall algorithm remains consistent, and these algorithms can replicate across model scale. This indicates that circuit analyses conducted on small models at the end of pre-training can provide insights applicable to additional pre-training and over model scale.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Task abilities and functional components emerge consistently at similar token counts across scale, even when implemented by different attention heads over time.</li>
<li>The overarching algorithm that the functional components implement remains consistent, despite changes in individual components.</li>
<li>Both the algorithms and the types of components involved in them can replicate across model scale.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>While the study provides valuable insights into the consistency of circuit analyses across training and scale, there are some potential limitations and areas for further research. The research focuses on a limited set of tasks, which may not be representative of more complex tasks that require larger models. Additionally, the study only examines models from one model family, which may not generalize to other model architectures or training setups. Furthermore, the research does not explore the impact of fine-tuning on circuit mechanisms, which could lead to different changes in model behavior. Future work should address these limitations and explore more complex phenomena, such as self-repair and load-balancing mechanisms in LLMs.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10827v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10827v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10827v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10827v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>11482</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLM_Circuit_Analyses_Are_Consistent_Across_Training_and_Scale/2024-07-15-LLM_Circuit_Analyses_Are_Consistent_Across_Training_and_Scale.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10827v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>MetaLLM: A High-performant and Cost-efficient Dynamic Framework for Wrapping LLMs</title>
  <dc:creator>Quang H. Nguyen, Duy C. Hoang, Juliette Decugis, Saurav Manchanda, Nitesh V. Chawla, Khoa D. Doan</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MetaLLM_A_High_performant_and_Cost_efficient_Dynamic_Framework_for_Wrapping_LLMs/2024-07-15-MetaLLM_A_High_performant_and_Cost_efficient_Dynamic_Framework_for_Wrapping_LLMs.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MetaLLM_A_High_performant_and_Cost_efficient_Dynamic_Framework_for_Wrapping_LLMs/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10834v1/extracted/5731237/figure/llmrouting-v2.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper introduces MetaLLM, a dynamic and intelligent framework that routes each query to the optimal large language model (LLM) for classification tasks. The framework aims to improve accuracy and cost-effectiveness by framing the selection problem as a multi-armed bandit. The experiments, conducted on popular LLM platforms such as OpenAI’s GPT models, Amazon’s Titan, Anthropic’s Claude, and Meta’s LLaMa, showcase MetaLLM’s efficacy in real-world scenarios.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>MetaLLM is a versatile wrapper around a suite of off-the-shelf LLMs, capable of intelligently choosing the target LLM for each query to achieve optimal performance and cost.</li>
<li>The framework employs an algorithm based on multi-armed bandit to tackle the routing problem in MetaLLM, which is efficient as it makes routing decisions without needing to query any LLMs.</li>
<li>Experimental results on benchmark datasets and popular API services, including OpenAI and Amazon’s Bedrock, demonstrate MetaLLM’s ability to identify the optimal LLM in terms of cost and performance. Specifically, MetaLLM improves the accuracy of the best model by around 10% while saving up to 50% and 70% of the total price on OpenAI and Bedrock APIs, respectively.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper focuses on zero-shot classification problems, but the MetaLLM framework can be extended to arbitrary language tasks by modifying the reward function to incorporate suitable metrics assessing the quality of the responses. However, this extension is left for future work.</li>
<li>The framework only trains a simple linear model, which may ignore more fine-grained features. Building a more complex reward model and utilizing other information from the query, such as the domain of the input and the demand of the user, may further facilitate better the needs of the applications and improve the performance of MetaLLM.</li>
<li>The framework optimizes MetaLLM with two values in the reward function: the performance and the cost of querying the API. However, several aspects to evaluate the model in practice could be incorporated into the reward, such as the inference time, the robustness of the model, emergent abilities</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10834v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10834v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10834v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10834v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5819</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MetaLLM_A_High_performant_and_Cost_efficient_Dynamic_Framework_for_Wrapping_LLMs/2024-07-15-MetaLLM_A_High_performant_and_Cost_efficient_Dynamic_Framework_for_Wrapping_LLMs.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10834v1/extracted/5731237/figure/llmrouting-v2.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Fast Matrix Multiplications for Lookup Table-Quantized LLMs</title>
  <dc:creator>Han Guo, William Brandon, Radostin Cholakov, Jonathan Ragan-Kelley, Eric P. Xing, Yoon Kim</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Fast_Matrix_Multiplications_for_Lookup_Table_Quantized_LLMs/2024-07-15-Fast_Matrix_Multiplications_for_Lookup_Table_Quantized_LLMs.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Fast_Matrix_Multiplications_for_Lookup_Table_Quantized_LLMs/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10960v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper presents FLUTE, a flexible lookup table engine for deploying weight-quantized LLMs, focusing on low-bit and non-uniform quantization settings.</li>
<li>FLUTE addresses challenges such as packing sub-8-bit matrices, unpacking during dequantization, and structuring unpacked data to match GPU-native matmul formats.</li>
<li>FLUTE uses offline weight restructuring, a shared-memory lookup table for efficient dequantization, and Stream-K partitioning for optimized workload distribution.</li>
<li>FLUTE outperforms existing non-uniform quantization kernels and matches simpler uniform-quantization kernels in some cases.</li>
<li>As an application of FLUTE, the paper explores a simple extension to lookup table-based NormalFloat quantization and applies it to quantize LLaMA3 to various configurations, obtaining competitive quantization performance against strong baselines while obtaining an end-to-end throughput increase of 1.5 to 2 times.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>FLUTE, a flexible lookup table engine, addresses challenges in deploying weight-quantized LLMs, such as packing sub-8-bit matrices, unpacking during dequantization, and structuring unpacked data to match GPU-native matmul formats.</li>
<li>FLUTE uses offline weight restructuring, a shared-memory lookup table for efficient dequantization, and Stream-K partitioning for optimized workload distribution.</li>
<li>FLUTE outperforms existing non-uniform quantization kernels and matches simpler uniform-quantization kernels in some cases.</li>
<li>As an application of FLUTE, the paper explores a simple extension to lookup table-based NormalFloat quantization and applies it to quantize LLaMA3 to various configurations, obtaining competitive quantization performance against strong baselines while obtaining an end-to-end throughput increase of 1.5 to 2 times.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper presents a promising approach to addressing the challenges of deploying weight-quantized LLMs, particularly in low-bit and non-uniform quantization settings.</li>
<li>The use of offline weight restructuring, a shared-memory lookup table, and Stream-K partitioning are effective strategies for optimizing workload distribution and improving performance</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10960v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.10960v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10960v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10960v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7852</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Fast_Matrix_Multiplications_for_Lookup_Table_Quantized_LLMs/2024-07-15-Fast_Matrix_Multiplications_for_Lookup_Table_Quantized_LLMs.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.10960v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
