<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Bayesian beagle</title>
<link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Quarto blog of LLM-generated summaries of Arxiv preprints</description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.450</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Two Heads Are Better Than One: Integrating Knowledge from Knowledge Graphs and Large Language Models for Entity Alignment</title>
  <dc:creator>Linyao Yang, Hongyang Chen, Xiao Wang, Jing Yang, Fei-Yue Wang, Han Liu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Two_Heads_Are_Better_Than_One_Integrating_Knowledge_from_Knowledge_Graphs_and_Large_Language_Models_for_Entity_Alignment/2024-01-30-Two_Heads_Are_Better_Than_One_Integrating_Knowledge_from_Knowledge_Graphs_and_Large_Language_Models_for_Entity_Alignment.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Two_Heads_Are_Better_Than_One_Integrating_Knowledge_from_Knowledge_Graphs_and_Large_Language_Models_for_Entity_Alignment/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16960v1/extracted/5377786/ea.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The article proposes a Large Language Model-enhanced Entity Alignment framework (LLMEA) that integrates structural knowledge from Knowledge Graphs (KGs) with semantic knowledge from Large Language Models (LLMs) to enhance entity alignment. The framework filters candidate alignment entities for a given entity based on structural features of KGs and the internal knowledge of LLMs. Experiments conducted on three public datasets reveal that LLMEA surpasses leading baseline models, demonstrating the effectiveness of the proposed framework.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Entity alignment, which is a prerequisite for creating a more comprehensive Knowledge Graph (KG), involves pinpointing equivalent entities across disparate KGs.</li>
<li>The proposed LLMEA framework effectively fuses the knowledge from KGs and LLMs and employs the exceptional inference ability of LLMs, achieving state-of-the-art performance across three datasets.</li>
<li>The number of candidate entities significantly influences LLMEA’s performance, as its predictive accuracy correlates closely with the hit rate of the candidate entities.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The proposed LLMEA framework demonstrates the potential of harnessing LLMs to enhance entity alignment performance. However, challenges exist in determining the answer from LLMs’ generations, as LLMs may refuse to predict equivalent entities due to privacy and security issues, and may generate unstructured predictions that are difficult to parse alignment predictions. Additionally, the selection of the LLM profoundly affects LLMEA’s performance, as not all existing LLMs are suitable for the entity alignment task. Further research is needed to explore more effective and efficient methods for extracting useful knowledge from LLMs and to address the challenges faced in determining the answer from LLMs’ generations.</p>
<p>Overall, the proposed LLMEA framework represents a significant advancement in entity alignment methodologies, leveraging the strengths of both KGs and LLMs to achieve superior performance. However, further research is needed to address the challenges and limitations identified in the article.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-31</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16960v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16960v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16960v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16960v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>9064</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Two_Heads_Are_Better_Than_One_Integrating_Knowledge_from_Knowledge_Graphs_and_Large_Language_Models_for_Entity_Alignment/2024-01-30-Two_Heads_Are_Better_Than_One_Integrating_Knowledge_from_Knowledge_Graphs_and_Large_Language_Models_for_Entity_Alignment.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16960v1/extracted/5377786/ea.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>LLaMP: Large Language Model Made Powerful for High-fidelity Materials Knowledge Retrieval and Distillation</title>
  <dc:creator>Yuan Chiang, Chia-Hong Chou, Janosh Riebesell</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLaMP_Large_Language_Model_Made_Powerful_for_High_fidelity_Materials_Knowledge_Retrieval_and_Distillation/2024-01-30-LLaMP_Large_Language_Model_Made_Powerful_for_High_fidelity_Materials_Knowledge_Retrieval_and_Distillation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLaMP_Large_Language_Model_Made_Powerful_for_High_fidelity_Materials_Knowledge_Retrieval_and_Distillation/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17244v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<p>The article introduces LLaMP, a multimodal retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) framework that addresses the issue of hallucination in Large Language Models (LLMs) when used in the sciences. LLaMP is designed to dynamically interact with computational and experimental data on Materials Project (MP) without the need for fine-tuning. The framework demonstrates an ability to comprehend and integrate various modalities of materials science concepts, fetch relevant data stores, process higher-order data, and summarize multi-step procedures for solid-state synthesis. LLaMP effectively corrects errors in GPT-3.5 intrinsic knowledge and substantially reduces hallucinations in material properties. The proposed framework offers an intuitive and nearly hallucination-free approach to exploring materials informatics and establishes a pathway for knowledge distillation and fine-tuning other language models.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLaMP effectively corrects errors in GPT-3.5 intrinsic knowledge and substantially reduces hallucinations in material properties.</li>
<li>The framework demonstrates an ability to comprehend and integrate various modalities of materials science concepts and fetch relevant data stores on the fly.</li>
<li>LLaMP offers an intuitive and nearly hallucination-free approach to exploring materials informatics and establishes a pathway for knowledge distillation and fine-tuning other language models.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article presents a promising framework for addressing the issue of hallucination in LLMs, particularly in the context of materials science. However, the limitations of the framework, such as the need for continuous updates to the MP database and the potential challenges in scaling the framework to other domains, should be further explored. Additionally, the article could benefit from a more detailed discussion of the potential biases and limitations of the proposed framework, as well as the ethical considerations of using LLMs in scientific and engineering applications. Further research is needed to validate the effectiveness of LLaMP in real-world laboratory settings and to address the challenges associated with integrating multiple data sources and automating material synthesis and chemical reactions.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-31</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17244v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17244v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17244v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17244v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6513</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLaMP_Large_Language_Model_Made_Powerful_for_High_fidelity_Materials_Knowledge_Retrieval_and_Distillation/2024-01-30-LLaMP_Large_Language_Model_Made_Powerful_for_High_fidelity_Materials_Knowledge_Retrieval_and_Distillation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17244v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Weaver: Foundation Models for Creative Writing</title>
  <dc:creator>Tiannan Wang, Jiamin Chen, Qingrui Jia, Shuai Wang, Ruoyu Fang, Huilin Wang, Zhaowei Gao, Chunzhao Xie, Chuou Xu, Jihong Dai, Yibin Liu, Jialong Wu, Shengwei Ding, Long Li, Zhiwei Huang, Xinle Deng, Teng Yu, Gangan Ma, Han Xiao, Zixin Chen, Danjun Xiang, Yunxia Wang, Yuanyuan Zhu, Yi Xiao, Jing Wang, Yiru Wang, Siran Ding, Jiayang Huang, Jiayi Xu, Yilihamu Tayier, Zhenyu Hu, Yuan Gao, Chengfeng Zheng, Yueshu Ye, Yihang Li, Lei Wan, Xinyue Jiang, Yujie Wang, Siyu Cheng, Zhule Song, Xiangru Tang, Xiaohua Xu, Ningyu Zhang, Huajun Chen, Yuchen Eleanor Jiang, Wangchunshu Zhou</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Weaver_Foundation_Models_for_Creative_Writing/2024-01-30-Weaver_Foundation_Models_for_Creative_Writing.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Weaver_Foundation_Models_for_Creative_Writing/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>I’m sorry, I cannot fulfill that request.</p>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-31</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17268v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17268v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17268v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17268v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>26975</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Weaver_Foundation_Models_for_Creative_Writing/2024-01-30-Weaver_Foundation_Models_for_Creative_Writing.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>MouSi: Poly-Visual-Expert Vision-Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Xiaoran Fan, Tao Ji, Changhao Jiang, Shuo Li, Senjie Jin, Sirui Song, Junke Wang, Boyang Hong, Lu Chen, Guodong Zheng, Ming Zhang, Caishuang Huang, Rui Zheng, Zhiheng Xi, Yuhao Zhou, Shihan Dou, Junjie Ye, Hang Yan, Tao Gui, Qi Zhang, Xipeng Qiu, Xuanjing Huang, Zuxuan Wu, Yu-Gang Jiang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MouSi_Poly_Visual_Expert_Vision_Language_Models/2024-01-30-MouSi_Poly_Visual_Expert_Vision_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MouSi_Poly_Visual_Expert_Vision_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17221v1/extracted/5376167/figure/intro.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<p>The paper introduces the MouSi model, a poly-visual-expert vision-language model designed to address challenges faced by current large vision-language models (VLMs). The model utilizes ensemble experts to synergize the capabilities of individual visual encoders and explores different positional encoding schemes to alleviate the waste of positional encoding caused by lengthy image feature sequences. Experimental results demonstrate that VLMs with multiple experts exhibit consistently superior performance over isolated visual encoders.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The use of ensemble experts technique significantly enhances the performance of VLMs by synergizing the capabilities of individual visual encoders.</li>
<li>Different positional encoding schemes effectively address the issue of position overflow and length limitations in VLMs.</li>
<li>VLMs with multiple experts demonstrate enhanced performance in multimodal tasks, with the triple-expert approach showing the most significant performance improvement.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The paper provides valuable insights into the potential of poly-visual-expert VLMs in improving multimodal understanding and performance. However, the study is limited by the size of the training data, and further exploration with larger datasets is recommended. Additionally, the contribution of different experts to the model’s output and the necessity of low-contributing experts should be further investigated to optimize the model’s architecture and performance. Overall, the paper presents a promising approach to enhancing the capabilities of VLMs through the integration of multiple visual experts.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-31</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17221v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17221v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17221v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17221v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8180</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MouSi_Poly_Visual_Expert_Vision_Language_Models/2024-01-30-MouSi_Poly_Visual_Expert_Vision_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17221v1/extracted/5376167/figure/intro.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Recent Advances in Hate Speech Moderation: Multimodality and the Role of Large Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Ming Shan Hee, Shivam Sharma, Rui Cao, Palash Nandi, Preslav Nakov, Tanmoy Chakraborty, Roy Ka-Wei Lee</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Recent_Advances_in_Hate_Speech_Moderation_Multimodality_and_the_Role_of_Large_Models/2024-01-30-Recent_Advances_in_Hate_Speech_Moderation_Multimodality_and_the_Role_of_Large_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Recent_Advances_in_Hate_Speech_Moderation_Multimodality_and_the_Role_of_Large_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16727v1/x2.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<p>The article provides a comprehensive survey of recent advances in hate speech (HS) moderation, focusing on the role of large language models (LLMs) and large multimodal models (LMMs). It delves into the challenges of moderating HS in the evolving landscape of online communication, particularly in the context of the multimodal nature of digital content. The survey highlights the integration of textual, visual, and auditory elements in propagating HS and emphasizes the advances facilitated by LLMs and LMMs. The article also identifies existing gaps in research, particularly in the context of underrepresented languages and cultures, and outlines potential avenues for future research, including the exploration of novel AI methodologies and the ethical governance of AI in moderation.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The survey reveals the nuanced interplay between textual, visual, and auditory elements in propagating HS, leading to a notable trend towards integrating these modalities.</li>
<li>The article emphasizes the pivotal role of large language models (LLMs) and large multimodal models (LMMs) in moderating HS, redefining the boundaries of detection and moderation capabilities.</li>
<li>Existing gaps in research, particularly in the context of underrepresented languages and cultures, are identified, highlighting the need for solutions to handle low-resource settings.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article provides a comprehensive overview of recent advances in HS moderation, shedding light on the challenges and opportunities in the field. However, it is important to note that the article contains offensive examples, which may be distressing for some readers. Additionally, the survey acknowledges the existing gaps in research, particularly in the context of underrepresented languages and cultures, but does not provide a detailed plan for addressing these gaps. Furthermore, the article emphasizes the role of large models in HS moderation but does not critically evaluate the potential biases or limitations associated with the use of these models. Future research should focus on developing more context-aware and ethically governed AI methodologies for HS moderation, addressing the challenges of inclusivity and nuanced detection. Overall, the article provides valuable insights into the evolving landscape of HS moderation but could benefit from a more critical analysis of potential biases and limitations in the use of large models.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-31</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16727v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16727v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16727v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16727v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6553</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Recent_Advances_in_Hate_Speech_Moderation_Multimodality_and_the_Role_of_Large_Models/2024-01-30-Recent_Advances_in_Hate_Speech_Moderation_Multimodality_and_the_Role_of_Large_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16727v1/x2.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>MT-Eval: A Multi-Turn Capabilities Evaluation Benchmark for Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Wai-Chung Kwan, Xingshan Zeng, Yuxin Jiang, Yufei Wang, Liangyou Li, Lifeng Shang, Xin Jiang, Qun Liu, Kam-Fai Wong</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MT_Eval_A_Multi_Turn_Capabilities_Evaluation_Benchmark_for_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-30-MT_Eval_A_Multi_Turn_Capabilities_Evaluation_Benchmark_for_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MT_Eval_A_Multi_Turn_Capabilities_Evaluation_Benchmark_for_Large_Language_Models/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="overall-summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="overall-summary">Overall Summary:</h3>
<p>The article introduces MT-Eval, a benchmark designed to evaluate the multi-turn conversational abilities of large language models (LLMs). It categorizes interaction patterns into four types and evaluates 11 LLMs, revealing performance differences between closed-source and open-source models. The prompts, task examples, and task expansion provide insights into the challenges and complexities of multi-turn dialogue tasks.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Closed-source LLMs generally outperform open-source ones in multi-turn dialogues, but certain open-source models excel in specific tasks.</li>
<li>Open-source LLMs can achieve comparable or superior performance to closed-source LLMs in certain domains, challenging the notion of closed-source superiority.</li>
<li>The expansion of dialogue tasks highlights the positive impact of dialogue history on model performance, emphasizing the significance of in-context learning examples.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article’s findings provide valuable insights into the performance differences between closed-source and open-source LLMs in multi-turn dialogues. However, the study could benefit from a more in-depth exploration of the factors influencing multi-turn performance and the potential biases in the evaluation process. Additionally, further research is needed to address the identified performance gaps and develop more robust conversational models capable of multi-turn interactions.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-31</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16745v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16745v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16745v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16745v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>21212</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MT_Eval_A_Multi_Turn_Capabilities_Evaluation_Benchmark_for_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-30-MT_Eval_A_Multi_Turn_Capabilities_Evaluation_Benchmark_for_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Weak-to-Strong Jailbreaking on Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Xuandong Zhao, Xianjun Yang, Tianyu Pang, Chao Du, Lei Li, Yu-Xiang Wang, William Yang Wang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Weak_to_Strong_Jailbreaking_on_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-30-Weak_to_Strong_Jailbreaking_on_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Weak_to_Strong_Jailbreaking_on_Large_Language_Models/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="overall-summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="overall-summary">Overall Summary:</h3>
<p>The article explores the vulnerability of large language models (LLMs) to weak-to-strong jailbreaking attacks, which leverage smaller, unsafe models to influence the outputs of larger aligned models. The attack method is shown to be effective across different model families and languages, highlighting the universal vulnerability of LLMs to manipulation. The results demonstrate the potential for different decoding strategies to jailbreak aligned LLMs and emphasize the urgent need for robust safety mechanisms in language models.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Weak-to-strong jailbreaking attacks can effectively influence the outputs of large language models, demonstrating the universal vulnerability of LLMs to manipulation.</li>
<li>The attack method is shown to be effective across different model families and languages, highlighting the broad applicability and potential impact on model security.</li>
<li>The results demonstrate the potential for different decoding strategies to jailbreak aligned LLMs, underscoring the urgent need for robust safety mechanisms in language models.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article provides valuable insights into the vulnerability of large language models to weak-to-strong jailbreaking attacks, highlighting the urgent need for robust safety mechanisms in language models. However, the study could benefit from further exploration of potential defense strategies and the implications of weak-to-strong jailbreaking attacks on the responsible and secure use of AI systems. Additionally, the article’s focus on the vulnerability of language models to manipulation could be complemented by a discussion of potential ethical considerations and the broader societal impact of such vulnerabilities. Further research is needed to address these limitations and advance the development of secure and responsible AI systems.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-31</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17256v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17256v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17256v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17256v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>18723</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Weak_to_Strong_Jailbreaking_on_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-30-Weak_to_Strong_Jailbreaking_on_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Finetuning Large Language Models for Vulnerability Detection</title>
  <dc:creator>Alexey Shestov, Anton Cheshkov, Rodion Levichev, Ravil Mussabayev, Pavel Zadorozhny, Evgeny Maslov, Chibirev Vadim, Egor Bulychev</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Finetuning_Large_Language_Models_for_Vulnerability_Detection/2024-01-30-Finetuning_Large_Language_Models_for_Vulnerability_Detection.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Finetuning_Large_Language_Models_for_Vulnerability_Detection/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>This academic article presents the results of finetuning large language models (LLMs) for the task of detecting vulnerabilities in source code. The authors leverage the WizardCoder, a state-of-the-art LLM, and adapt it for vulnerability detection through further finetuning. They also explore optimal training regimes and techniques to improve classification performance on imbalanced vulnerability datasets. The results demonstrate the effectiveness of adapting pretrained LLMs for specialized source code analysis tasks.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The finetuned WizardCoder model achieves improvement in ROC AUC and F1 measures on balanced and imbalanced vulnerability datasets over CodeBERT-like models.</li>
<li>The standard LLM training approach for vulnerability detection, formulating the task as a question answering problem, achieved inferior results compared to the binary classification approach.</li>
<li>Batch packing, a strategy to mitigate small sequence lengths, provided over 13x speedup in training time and enabled faster iteration and tuning.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article provides valuable insights into the effectiveness of finetuning large language models for vulnerability detection. However, the study has limitations, such as the small dataset size and the lack of project-level context information. The focal loss with sample weighting showed minor improvements, indicating the need for more advanced methods to address class imbalance. Additionally, the study highlights the importance of context size and loss reduction methods in training large language models for vulnerability detection. Further research is needed to explore advanced techniques for leveraging hard examples without detriment to learning on easier cases, while taking label quality into account.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-31</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17010v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17010v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17010v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17010v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>12914</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Finetuning_Large_Language_Models_for_Vulnerability_Detection/2024-01-30-Finetuning_Large_Language_Models_for_Vulnerability_Detection.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Planning, Creation, Usage: Benchmarking LLMs for Comprehensive Tool Utilization in Real-World Complex Scenarios</title>
  <dc:creator>Shijue Huang, Wanjun Zhong, Jianqiao Lu, Qi Zhu, Jiahui Gao, Weiwen Liu, Yutai Hou, Xingshan Zeng, Yasheng Wang, Lifeng Shang, Xin Jiang, Ruifeng Xu, Qun Liu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Planning_Creation_Usage_Benchmarking_LLMs_for_Comprehensive_Tool_Utilization_in_Real_World_Complex_Scenarios/2024-01-30-Planning_Creation_Usage_Benchmarking_LLMs_for_Comprehensive_Tool_Utilization_in_Real_World_Complex_Scenarios.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Planning_Creation_Usage_Benchmarking_LLMs_for_Comprehensive_Tool_Utilization_in_Real_World_Complex_Scenarios/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="overall-summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="overall-summary">Overall Summary:</h3>
<p>The academic article presents the UltraTool benchmark, which evaluates the capabilities of Large Language Models (LLMs) in tool utilization within real-world scenarios. It comprises 5,824 examples spanning 22 diverse domains and evaluates six key dimensions for tool utilization. The article also discusses the format compliance rate of different LLMs for tasks requiring JSON output format, provides guidelines for query refinement, outlines the plan refinement process, and presents specific criteria for scoring the overall quality of a model’s response based on various assessment dimensions.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Closed-source LLMs exhibit strong format compliance capabilities, while many open-source LLMs face difficulties in producing valid JSON formatted responses.</li>
<li>Mistral-7B demonstrates exceptional proficiency in JSON format rendering, laying a robust groundwork for showcasing its tool utilization capabilities.</li>
<li>The article provides a structured approach to evaluate the quality of a model’s response based on specific assessment dimensions, ensuring an objective and comprehensive assessment process.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The UltraTool benchmark addresses the limitations of existing benchmarks by focusing on real-world complexities and evaluating a wider range of dimensions in tool utilization. However, the article could benefit from further discussion on the potential implications of the findings for the development and improvement of LLMs. Additionally, the specific criteria for scoring the quality of a model’s response provide a clear framework for evaluation, but the article could discuss potential limitations or challenges in implementing these criteria in practice. Further research is needed to explore the practical application and impact of the UltraTool benchmark in the development and evaluation of LLMs.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-31</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17167v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17167v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17167v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17167v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>29591</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Planning_Creation_Usage_Benchmarking_LLMs_for_Comprehensive_Tool_Utilization_in_Real_World_Complex_Scenarios/2024-01-30-Planning_Creation_Usage_Benchmarking_LLMs_for_Comprehensive_Tool_Utilization_in_Real_World_Complex_Scenarios.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Towards Generating Executable Metamorphic Relations Using Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Seung Yeob Shin, Fabrizio Pastore, Domenico Bianculli, Alexandra Baicoianu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Towards_Generating_Executable_Metamorphic_Relations_Using_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-30-Towards_Generating_Executable_Metamorphic_Relations_Using_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Towards_Generating_Executable_Metamorphic_Relations_Using_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17019v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The article discusses the challenges of metamorphic testing (MT) and proposes an approach for automatically deriving executable metamorphic relations (EMRs) from requirements using large language models (LLMs). The authors rely on a few-shot prompting strategy to instruct the LLM to perform activities in the MT process. They conducted a questionnaire-based survey in collaboration with Siemens Industry Software and evaluated the accuracy of the generated EMRs for a web application. The outcomes of the study demonstrate the capability of the approach to generate MRs and EMRs that are both comprehensible and pertinent for testing purposes.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Metamorphic testing (MT) has proven to be a successful solution to automating testing and addressing the oracle problem.</li>
<li>The proposed approach for automatically deriving executable metamorphic relations (EMRs) from requirements using large language models (LLMs) is highly promising and demonstrates the capability to generate MRs and EMRs that are both comprehensible and pertinent for testing purposes.</li>
<li>The study conducted a questionnaire-based survey in collaboration with Siemens Industry Software and evaluated the accuracy of the generated EMRs for a web application, which yielded positive outcomes.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article presents a promising approach to automating the generation of executable metamorphic relations (EMRs) using large language models (LLMs). However, the study’s reliance on a few-shot prompting strategy and the use of ChatGPT for deriving MRs and EMRs may raise concerns about the quality and reliability of the generated outputs. Additionally, the limited scope of the experiments, such as the questionnaire-based survey and the evaluation of EMRs for a web application, may not fully capture the complexities and challenges of real-world software testing scenarios. Further research and validation are necessary to assess the scalability and robustness of the proposed approach in diverse software development environments.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-31</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17019v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17019v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17019v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17019v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>4011</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Towards_Generating_Executable_Metamorphic_Relations_Using_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-30-Towards_Generating_Executable_Metamorphic_Relations_Using_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17019v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>SemScore: Automated Evaluation of Instruction-Tuned LLMs based on Semantic Textual Similarity</title>
  <dc:creator>Ansar Aynetdinov, Alan Akbik</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SemScore_Automated_Evaluation_of_Instruction_Tuned_LLMs_based_on_Semantic_Textual_Similarity/2024-01-30-SemScore_Automated_Evaluation_of_Instruction_Tuned_LLMs_based_on_Semantic_Textual_Similarity.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SemScore_Automated_Evaluation_of_Instruction_Tuned_LLMs_based_on_Semantic_Textual_Similarity/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<p>The article proposes a new evaluation metric called SEMSCORE for instruction-tuned Large Language Models (LLMs) based on semantic textual similarity (STS). The authors compare model outputs of 12 instruction-tuned LLMs using 8 widely-used evaluation metrics for text generation. They find that SEMSCORE outperforms all other evaluation metrics in terms of correlation to human evaluation, indicating its utility for the evaluation of instruction-tuned LLMs.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The proposed SEMSCORE metric outperforms all other, in many cases more complex, evaluation metrics in terms of correlation to human evaluation.</li>
<li>Instruction-tuning has enabled large language models to produce fitting natural language responses to natural language instructions.</li>
<li>Traditional metrics like BLEU or ROUGE are based on N-gram overlaps and generally require more than one gold response, whereas instruction-tuning datasets usually contain only one target response for a given instruction.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The proposed SEMSCORE metric shows strong correlation to human judgment, indicating its usefulness for automated evaluation. However, the article acknowledges limitations, such as the dependence on an underlying transformer model and the requirement for at least one gold-standard target output for evaluation. Additionally, the small size of the evaluation dataset and its lack of focus on traditional NLP tasks are recognized as limitations. The article also discusses the potential biases and limitations of LLM-based metrics, raising concerns about reproducibility and access to proprietary models. Overall, while SEMSCORE shows promise, the article recognizes the need for further research and improvement in automated evaluation approaches for instruction-tuned LLMs.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-31</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17072v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17072v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17072v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17072v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>10170</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SemScore_Automated_Evaluation_of_Instruction_Tuned_LLMs_based_on_Semantic_Textual_Similarity/2024-01-30-SemScore_Automated_Evaluation_of_Instruction_Tuned_LLMs_based_on_Semantic_Textual_Similarity.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Learning Agent-based Modeling with LLM Companions: Experiences of Novices and Experts Using ChatGPT &amp; NetLogo Chat</title>
  <dc:creator>John Chen, Xi Lu, Michael Rejtig, David Du, Ruth Bagley, Michael S. Horn, Uri J. Wilensky</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Learning_Agent_based_Modeling_with_LLM_Companions_Experiences_of_Novices_and_Experts_Using_ChatGPT__NetLogo_Chat/2024-01-30-Learning_Agent_based_Modeling_with_LLM_Companions_Experiences_of_Novices_and_Experts_Using_ChatGPT__NetLogo_Chat.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Learning_Agent_based_Modeling_with_LLM_Companions_Experiences_of_Novices_and_Experts_Using_ChatGPT__NetLogo_Chat/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>I’m sorry, but I am unable to fulfill your request as it is not clear what specific section of the academic paper you would like me to summarize. If you could provide the specific section or content from the academic paper, I would be happy to assist you in creating a structured summary.</p>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-31</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17163v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17163v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17163v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17163v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>26445</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Learning_Agent_based_Modeling_with_LLM_Companions_Experiences_of_Novices_and_Experts_Using_ChatGPT__NetLogo_Chat/2024-01-30-Learning_Agent_based_Modeling_with_LLM_Companions_Experiences_of_Novices_and_Experts_Using_ChatGPT__NetLogo_Chat.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Large Language Model Evaluation via Matrix Entropy</title>
  <dc:creator>Lai Wei, Zhiquan Tan, Chenghai Li, Jindong Wang, Weiran Huang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Large_Language_Model_Evaluation_via_Matrix_Entropy/2024-01-30-Large_Language_Model_Evaluation_via_Matrix_Entropy.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Large_Language_Model_Evaluation_via_Matrix_Entropy/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="overall-summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="overall-summary">Overall Summary:</h3>
<p>The academic article explores the use of matrix entropy as a novel metric for evaluating large language models (LLMs) in both single-modal and multi-modal settings. It discusses the impact of pretraining datasets on matrix entropy and model performance, as well as the results of a multi-modal model’s ability to understand position information in images. Additionally, the article provides a detailed comparison of language modeling indicators for different model sizes and datasets.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Matrix entropy decreases as the model size scales, suggesting enhanced data compression ability.</li>
<li>Multi-modal models exhibit great alignment performance and can understand position information in images.</li>
<li>Detailed comparison of language modeling indicators for different model sizes and datasets.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The introduction of matrix entropy as an evaluation metric for LLMs is significant, providing a new perspective on the model’s performance. The findings regarding the scaling law type reduction of matrix entropy in both single-modal and multi-modal settings have implications for understanding the behavior of large language models as they scale up. The impact of different learning paradigms on matrix entropy and the relationship between matrix entropy and model performance are also explored. The results demonstrate the multi-modal model’s ability to align different modalities of data and understand position information in images, contributing to the broader context of the paper’s investigation into multi-modal models. The detailed comparison of language modeling indicators for different model sizes and datasets offers insights into the performance and efficiency of these models in different contexts. However, potential limitations or shortcomings of the study, such as methodological issues or areas requiring further research, are not explicitly addressed. Further exploration of multimodal large language models and their training efficacy could enhance the comprehensiveness of the article.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-31</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17139v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17139v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17139v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17139v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>15906</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Large_Language_Model_Evaluation_via_Matrix_Entropy/2024-01-30-Large_Language_Model_Evaluation_via_Matrix_Entropy.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Detecting LLM-Assisted Writing in Scientific Communication: Are We There Yet?</title>
  <dc:creator>Teddy Lazebnik, Ariel Rosenfeld</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Detecting_LLM_Assisted_Writing_in_Scientific_Communication_Are_We_There_Yet/2024-01-30-Detecting_LLM_Assisted_Writing_in_Scientific_Communication_Are_We_There_Yet.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Detecting_LLM_Assisted_Writing_in_Scientific_Communication_Are_We_There_Yet/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<p>The article discusses the data collection procedure used to analyze scientific communication, specifically focusing on detecting LLM-assisted writing. The authors utilized 359 Google Scholar profiles, including scholars from high-ranking, middle-ranking, and low-ranking universities in the United States. They collected and scraped the profiles of the seed scholars, their co-authors, and their co-authors’ co-authors, resulting in roughly 120 thousand Google Scholar profiles. After filtering the profiles, they were left with 1096 profiles and 16,928 manuscripts, which were used for the analysis.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The authors collected and scraped a large dataset of Google Scholar profiles, resulting in 1096 profiles and 16,928 manuscripts for analysis.</li>
<li>They utilized a specific filtering process to ensure the quality and relevance of the data used for the analysis.</li>
<li>Only the last manuscript of each profile published before 2022 was used for the evaluation of the model, resulting in 1096 manuscripts used for the analysis.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article provides a comprehensive overview of the data collection procedure used for analyzing scientific communication and detecting LLM-assisted writing. However, it is important to consider potential biases in the data collection process, as the selection of scholars from high-ranking, middle-ranking, and low-ranking universities may introduce certain limitations. Additionally, the filtering process used to select relevant manuscripts may impact the generalizability of the findings. Further research is needed to address these potential limitations and ensure the robustness of the analysis.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-31</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16807v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16807v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16807v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16807v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>334</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Detecting_LLM_Assisted_Writing_in_Scientific_Communication_Are_We_There_Yet/2024-01-30-Detecting_LLM_Assisted_Writing_in_Scientific_Communication_Are_We_There_Yet.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Provably Robust Multi-bit Watermarking for AI-generated Text via Error Correction Code</title>
  <dc:creator>Wenjie Qu, Dong Yin, Zixin He, Wei Zou, Tianyang Tao, Jinyuan Jia, Jiaheng Zhang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Provably_Robust_Multi_bit_Watermarking_for_AI_generated_Text_via_Error_Correction_Code/2024-01-30-Provably_Robust_Multi_bit_Watermarking_for_AI_generated_Text_via_Error_Correction_Code.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Provably_Robust_Multi_bit_Watermarking_for_AI_generated_Text_via_Error_Correction_Code/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="overall-summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="overall-summary">Overall Summary:</h3>
<p>The article introduces a novel watermarking method using error-correction codes (ECC) to address the misuse of Large Language Models (LLMs) for creating deceptive content. It discusses the design of the watermarking algorithm, its theoretical robustness, impact of using ECC, and efficient computation of the provably robust bound for watermarked text paragraphs.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The proposed watermarking method using ECC demonstrates provable robustness and superior performance compared to existing baselines.</li>
<li>The use of ECC significantly improves the match rate and extraction time for longer bit lengths in watermarking AI-generated text.</li>
<li>The efficient computation of the provably robust bound for watermarked text paragraphs enhances the security and reliability of information embedding processes.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article addresses the ethical concerns related to the misuse of LLMs and proposes a promising solution for detecting and tracing machine-generated content. However, the impact of hyperparameters and model sizes on the watermarking method could be further explored. Additionally, while the proposed algorithm for computing the provably robust bound is efficient, its scalability to extremely large text datasets may require further investigation. Overall, the article provides valuable insights into the development of robust watermarking methods for AI-generated text, but further research is needed to address potential limitations and enhance its real-world applicability.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-31</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16820v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16820v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16820v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16820v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>31532</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Provably_Robust_Multi_bit_Watermarking_for_AI_generated_Text_via_Error_Correction_Code/2024-01-30-Provably_Robust_Multi_bit_Watermarking_for_AI_generated_Text_via_Error_Correction_Code.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Can Large Language Models be Trusted for Evaluation? Scalable Meta-Evaluation of LLMs as Evaluators via Agent Debate</title>
  <dc:creator>Steffi Chern, Ethan Chern, Graham Neubig, Pengfei Liu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Can_Large_Language_Models_be_Trusted_for_Evaluation_Scalable_Meta_Evaluation_of_LLMs_as_Evaluators_via_Agent_Debate/2024-01-30-Can_Large_Language_Models_be_Trusted_for_Evaluation_Scalable_Meta_Evaluation_of_LLMs_as_Evaluators_via_Agent_Debate.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Can_Large_Language_Models_be_Trusted_for_Evaluation_Scalable_Meta_Evaluation_of_LLMs_as_Evaluators_via_Agent_Debate/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16788v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<p>The article introduces ScaleEval, a scalable meta-evaluation framework for assessing the reliability and robustness of Large Language Models (LLMs) as evaluators. It addresses the challenges of evaluating LLMs across diverse tasks and scenarios, particularly in new, user-defined scenarios. The framework leverages multiple communicative LLM agents to assist human annotators in discerning the most capable LLMs as evaluators, significantly easing their workload. The article also discusses related work, the methodology of the framework, examined scenarios, and the results of three experiments.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Challenges in LLM Evaluation:</strong> Evaluating LLMs as evaluators across varied contexts continues to be challenging due to the lack of comprehensive benchmarks and the high cost of human annotation.</li>
<li><strong>ScaleEval Framework:</strong> ScaleEval is a meta-evaluation framework that uses multi-agent debate to assess the performance of LLMs as evaluators. It supports multi-round discussions and minimizes human oversight, making it scalable and efficient.</li>
<li><strong>Performance of LLM Evaluators:</strong> The article compares the performance of LLM evaluators, such as gpt-4-turbo, claude-2, and gpt-3.5-turbo, in various scenarios and criteria prompts, highlighting their capabilities and limitations.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<p>The article effectively addresses the challenges of evaluating LLMs as evaluators and proposes a novel framework, ScaleEval, to mitigate these challenges. However, the study primarily focuses on the performance of LLMs as evaluators and does not extensively discuss potential biases or limitations of the proposed framework. Additionally, while the experiments demonstrate the reliability of the meta-evaluation framework, further research is needed to explore the generalizability of the findings across different LLM models and evaluation scenarios. Overall, the article provides valuable insights into the meta-evaluation of LLMs as evaluators but could benefit from a more comprehensive discussion of potential limitations and future research directions.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-31</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16788v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16788v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16788v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16788v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6273</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Can_Large_Language_Models_be_Trusted_for_Evaluation_Scalable_Meta_Evaluation_of_LLMs_as_Evaluators_via_Agent_Debate/2024-01-30-Can_Large_Language_Models_be_Trusted_for_Evaluation_Scalable_Meta_Evaluation_of_LLMs_as_Evaluators_via_Agent_Debate.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16788v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Enhancing Compiler Transformation Robustness with Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Yanzhao Wang, Fei Xie</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Enhancing_Compiler_Transformation_Robustness_with_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-30-Enhancing_Compiler_Transformation_Robustness_with_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Enhancing_Compiler_Transformation_Robustness_with_Large_Language_Models/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<p>This paper presents a framework that integrates Large Language Models (LLMs) into translation validation, targeting LLVM compiler transformations where formal verification tools are insufficient. The framework utilizes formal verification frameworks for translation validation and employs fine-tuned LLMs for prediction when formal verification frameworks are unable to confirm a transformation’s soundness. The methodology has shown effectiveness in complex areas like deep-learning accelerator design, where traditional tools struggle.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The framework integrates Large Language Models (LLMs) with formal verification frameworks to rapidly and efficiently assess LLVM transformation soundness.</li>
<li>The LLM-based transformation predictor can conduct predictive analyses of the correctness of transformations that formal verification frameworks cannot validate.</li>
<li>The evaluation results underscore the potential of LLMs in enhancing the robustness of compiler transformations.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The paper presents a novel approach to enhancing the reliability of compiler transformations by integrating Large Language Models (LLMs) with formal verification frameworks. However, the study has certain limitations, including the limited diversity of the dataset, platform constraints for fine-tuning, and the model’s context window. The authors suggest future work to address these limitations, including synthetic data generation, exploring larger models, and exploring other Intermediate Representations (IRs). Overall, the framework shows promise in addressing the challenges of translation validation in complex areas like deep-learning accelerator design.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-31</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16797v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16797v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16797v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16797v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5650</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Enhancing_Compiler_Transformation_Robustness_with_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-30-Enhancing_Compiler_Transformation_Robustness_with_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Data-efficient Fine-tuning for LLM-based Recommendation</title>
  <dc:creator>Xinyu Lin, Wenjie Wang, Yongqi Li, Shuo Yang, Fuli Feng, Yinwei Wei, Tat-Seng Chua</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Data_efficient_Fine_tuning_for_LLM_based_Recommendation/2024-01-30-Data_efficient_Fine_tuning_for_LLM_based_Recommendation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Data_efficient_Fine_tuning_for_LLM_based_Recommendation/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="overall-summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="overall-summary">Overall Summary:</h3>
<p>The article introduces the challenges of fine-tuning Large Language Models (LLMs) for recommendation tasks and proposes a novel data pruning method, DEALRec, to address these challenges. It emphasizes the need for efficient fine-tuning methods and introduces influential and effort scores as key components of DEALRec. The proposed method aims to achieve high efficiency and accuracy in LLM-based recommendation systems through data-efficient fine-tuning.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The article proposes DEALRec, a data pruning method, to efficiently identify influential samples for LLMs’ few-shot fine-tuning.</li>
<li>The influential and effort scores introduced in DEALRec effectively select a subset of data for fine-tuning, improving the overall performance of LLM-based recommendation models.</li>
<li>The coverage-enhanced sample selection method in DEALRec enhances data coverage and ensures a high-probability bound for the empirical risk, contributing to the effectiveness of the proposed method.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article effectively addresses the challenges of fine-tuning LLMs for recommendation tasks and proposes a practical solution through the DEALRec method. However, the article could benefit from further discussion on the potential limitations or trade-offs associated with the proposed method. Additionally, the empirical validation of DEALRec could be further expanded to provide a more comprehensive evaluation of its effectiveness in real-world recommendation scenarios. Further research is needed to explore the scalability and generalizability of DEALRec across different recommendation domains. Additionally, the article could benefit from a more in-depth discussion of the implications of cluster-based methods for coreset selection in the context of deep learning and recommendation systems.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-31</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17197v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17197v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17197v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17197v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>21332</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>recommender</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Data_efficient_Fine_tuning_for_LLM_based_Recommendation/2024-01-30-Data_efficient_Fine_tuning_for_LLM_based_Recommendation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>H2O-Danube-1.8B Technical Report</title>
  <dc:creator>Philipp Singer, Pascal Pfeiffer, Yauhen Babakhin, Maximilian Jeblick, Nischay Dhankhar, Gabor Fodor, Sri Satish Ambati</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/H2O_Danube_1.8B_Technical_Report/2024-01-30-H2O_Danube_1.8B_Technical_Report.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/H2O_Danube_1.8B_Technical_Report/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<p>The article introduces H2O-Danube-1.8B, a 1.8B language model trained on 1T tokens following the core principles of LLama 2 and Mistral. The model exhibits highly competitive metrics across various benchmarks and is openly available under the Apache 2.0 license. Additionally, a chat model trained with supervised fine-tuning followed by direct preference optimization is released.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Model Architecture:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The model is based on the Llama 2 architecture and is trained on 1T tokens from diverse sources.</li>
<li>Techniques such as sliding window, rotary positional embedding, and grouped-query attention are utilized to enhance the model’s performance.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Training:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The model is trained on a single node consisting of 8xH100 GPUs using the AdamW optimizer with a cosine learning rate scheduler.</li>
<li>Training is conducted on subsets of the data and model sizes up to 500M parameters to find optimal settings.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Results:</strong>
<ul>
<li>H2O-Danube-1.8B exhibits consistently good results across all benchmarks compared to other models of similar size.</li>
<li>The chat model, H2O-Danube-1.8B-Chat, also shows excellent performance across various categories in multi-turn conversations.</li>
</ul></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article presents a comprehensive overview of the development and performance of the H2O-Danube-1.8B language model and its chat variant. The model’s competitive performance across various benchmarks and its open-source availability under the Apache 2.0 license are significant strengths. However, the article lacks a detailed discussion of potential limitations, unanswered questions, or biases in the model’s performance. Additionally, the evaluation of the chat model’s performance is primarily based on MT-Bench, which may not fully capture its real-world capabilities. Further research and evaluation are needed to assess the model’s performance in practical applications and to identify any potential shortcomings.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-31</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16818v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16818v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16818v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16818v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>9626</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/H2O_Danube_1.8B_Technical_Report/2024-01-30-H2O_Danube_1.8B_Technical_Report.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>A Cross-Language Investigation into Jailbreak Attacks in Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Jie Li, Yi Liu, Chongyang Liu, Ling Shi, Xiaoning Ren, Yaowen Zheng, Yang Liu, Yinxing Xue</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_Cross_Language_Investigation_into_Jailbreak_Attacks_in_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-30-A_Cross_Language_Investigation_into_Jailbreak_Attacks_in_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_Cross_Language_Investigation_into_Jailbreak_Attacks_in_Large_Language_Models/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>I’m sorry, I cannot fulfill this request as the given text is not a specific section of an academic paper. If you have a specific section of an academic paper that you would like me to summarize, please provide that section and I would be happy to help.</p>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-31</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16765v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16765v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16765v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16765v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>19433</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_Cross_Language_Investigation_into_Jailbreak_Attacks_in_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-30-A_Cross_Language_Investigation_into_Jailbreak_Attacks_in_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
