<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Bayesian beagle</title>
<link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Quarto blog of LLM-generated summaries of Arxiv preprints</description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.450</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Molecular Graph Representation Learning Integrating Large Language Models with Domain-specific Small Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Tianyu Zhang, Yuxiang Ren, Chengbin Hou, Hairong Lv, Xuegong Zhang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Molecular_Graph_Representation_Learning_Integrating_Large_Language_Models_with_Domain_specific_Small_Models/2024-08-19-Molecular_Graph_Representation_Learning_Integrating_Large_Language_Models_with_Domain_specific_Small_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Molecular_Graph_Representation_Learning_Integrating_Large_Language_Models_with_Domain_specific_Small_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.10124v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article introduces a novel Molecular Graph representation learning framework called MolGraph-LarDo, which integrates Large Language Models (LLMs) and Domain-specific Small Models (DSMs) for molecular property prediction.</li>
<li>MolGraph-LarDo addresses the limitations of existing methods that rely on biochemical experts and vast amounts of domain knowledge literature, which are time-consuming and expensive.</li>
<li>The framework employs a two-stage prompt strategy where DSMs calibrate the knowledge provided by LLMs, enhancing the accuracy of domain-specific information and enabling LLMs to generate more precise textual descriptions for molecular samples.</li>
<li>A multi-modal alignment method is then used to coordinate various modalities, including molecular graphs and their corresponding descriptive texts, to guide the pre-training of molecular representations.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>MolGraph-LarDo leverages the retrieval and generation capabilities of LLMs to overcome the time-consuming and labor-intensive process of biomedical domain literature screening and pre-processing in molecular representation learning.</li>
<li>The proposed framework addresses the hallucination and precision issues of existing methods that integrate general LLMs into molecular tasks by introducing a novel framework for molecular graph representation learning which integrates LLMs and DSMs.</li>
<li>Extensive experiments demonstrate the effectiveness of MolGraph-LarDo in improving the performance of the downstream molecular property prediction while reducing the cost of obtaining specialized domain knowledge.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The proposed method effectively leverages the advantages of both LLMs and DSMs, providing a promising approach for molecular representation learning.</li>
<li>The two-stage prompt strategy and the use of DSMs for knowledge calibration are crucial components of the framework, ensuring the accuracy and relevance of the generated molecular descriptions.</li>
<li>The multi-modal alignment method employed in MolGraph-LarDo enables the integration of domain knowledge from LLMs and DSMs into the process of graph contrastive learning.</li>
<li>However, the method’s dependence on the quality and availability of LLMs and DSMs may pose challenges in terms of generalizability and scalability.</li>
<li>Future research could explore the application of MolGraph-LarDo to other domains and investigate ways to improve its robustness and adaptability to different</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-20</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.10124v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.10124v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.10124v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.10124v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5847</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Molecular_Graph_Representation_Learning_Integrating_Large_Language_Models_with_Domain_specific_Small_Models/2024-08-19-Molecular_Graph_Representation_Learning_Integrating_Large_Language_Models_with_Domain_specific_Small_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.10124v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Multilingual Needle in a Haystack: Investigating Long-Context Behavior of Multilingual Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Amey Hengle, Prasoon Bajpai, Soham Dan, Tanmoy Chakraborty</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Multilingual_Needle_in_a_Haystack_Investigating_Long_Context_Behavior_of_Multilingual_Large_Language_Models/2024-08-19-Multilingual_Needle_in_a_Haystack_Investigating_Long_Context_Behavior_of_Multilingual_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Multilingual_Needle_in_a_Haystack_Investigating_Long_Context_Behavior_of_Multilingual_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.10151v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level1">
<h1>Summary:</h1>
<p><strong>Summary:</strong></p>
<p>The paper introduces the MultiLingual Needle in a Haystack (MLNeedle) test, a new benchmark for evaluating the long-context capabilities of multilingual large language models (LLMs). The test assesses a model’s ability to retrieve relevant information (the needle) from a collection of multilingual distractor texts (the haystack). The authors evaluate four state-of-the-art LLMs on MLNeedle and find that model performance varies significantly with language and needle position. The lowest performance is observed when the needle is in a language outside the English language family and located in the middle of the input context. Additionally, none of the models demonstrate satisfactory cross-lingual retrieval performance as the context length increases.</p>
<p><strong>Major Findings:</strong></p>
<ol type="1">
<li>Model performance is highly sensitive to both the language and position of the needle in the haystack.</li>
<li>LLMs are relatively robust to variations in the language of distractor passages, indicating that the key challenges lie in how LLMs process and retrieve the needle from diverse linguistic environments.</li>
<li>Ablation studies reveal the role of temperature sampling, instruction tuning, and the choice of evaluation metric on performance.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The paper provides valuable insights into the long-context behavior of LLMs in multilingual settings, but it does not address the potential biases or limitations of the models themselves.</li>
<li>The study focuses on a specific task (multilingual question-answering) and does not explore other tasks that may be affected by long-context multilingual inputs.</li>
<li>The evaluation of models is limited to four state-of-the-art LLMs, and the results may not generalize to other models or architectures.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential implications of these findings for real-world applications, such as information retrieval or machine translation.</li>
<li>The study does not address the potential impact of the size and quality of the training data on the models’ performance in long-context multilingual tasks.</li>
<li>The paper does not provide a clear comparison between the performance of the evaluated models and that of other models or approaches in the literature.</li>
<li>The study does not discuss the potential impact of the evaluation metric on the results, and it does not explore alternative metrics that</li>
</ul>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-20</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.10151v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.10151v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.10151v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.10151v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6917</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Multilingual_Needle_in_a_Haystack_Investigating_Long_Context_Behavior_of_Multilingual_Large_Language_Models/2024-08-19-Multilingual_Needle_in_a_Haystack_Investigating_Long_Context_Behavior_of_Multilingual_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.10151v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Microscopic Analysis on LLM players via Social Deduction Game</title>
  <dc:creator>Byungjun Kim, Dayeon Seo, Bugeun Kim</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Microscopic_Analysis_on_LLM_players_via_Social_Deduction_Game/2024-08-19-Microscopic_Analysis_on_LLM_players_via_Social_Deduction_Game.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/../bayesian-beagle.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>This study focuses on the evaluation of large language models (LLMs) in the context of social deduction games (SDGs), specifically SpyGame, a variant of SpyFall. The authors propose an approach that utilizes microscopic event-level metrics to analyze the performance of LLMs in SDGs, demonstrating that these metrics offer a more detailed assessment than conventional macroscopic metrics. The study also conducts a qualitative analysis to identify categories of abnormal reasoning patterns in LLMs, discovering four main categories and five subcategories, including exposure, role ambiguity, memory distortion, and dissociation. The authors validate their quantitative findings by correlating them with the results of the qualitative analysis.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The study demonstrates the effectiveness of using microscopic event-level metrics to analyze the performance of LLMs in SDGs, showing that these metrics are more effective than conventional macroscopic metrics in evaluating gameplay skills in SpyGame.</li>
<li>The qualitative analysis identifies four main categories and five subcategories of abnormal reasoning patterns in LLMs, providing insights into the limitations and potential biases of LLMs in SDGs.</li>
<li>The study validates the quantitative findings by correlating them with the results of the qualitative analysis, highlighting the importance of a multifaceted approach to evaluating LLMs in SDGs.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The study provides a comprehensive evaluation of LLMs in SDGs, addressing the limitations of previous studies that relied on macroscopic quantitative evaluations and non-systematic qualitative analyses. The use of microscopic event-level metrics and thematic analysis offers a more detailed and nuanced understanding of LLMs’ performance in SDGs. However, the study has some limitations, such as the use of a simplified version of SpyGame and the focus on text-based LLMs. Future research should extend this work to multi-modal LLMs and explore the differences between human and LLM players in SDGs. Overall, the study provides valuable insights into the behavior of LLM-based players in SDGs and highlights the importance of a multifaceted approach to evaluating LLMs in such games.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-20</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.09946v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.09946v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09946v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09946v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>10720</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Microscopic_Analysis_on_LLM_players_via_Social_Deduction_Game/2024-08-19-Microscopic_Analysis_on_LLM_players_via_Social_Deduction_Game.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Strategic Demonstration Selection for Improved Fairness in LLM In-Context Learning</title>
  <dc:creator>Jingyu Hu, Weiru Liu, Mengnan Du</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Strategic_Demonstration_Selection_for_Improved_Fairness_in_LLM_In_Context_Learning/2024-08-19-Strategic_Demonstration_Selection_for_Improved_Fairness_in_LLM_In_Context_Learning.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Strategic_Demonstration_Selection_for_Improved_Fairness_in_LLM_In_Context_Learning/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09757v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>This study investigates the impact of varying demonstrations within in-context learning (ICL) prompts on the fairness outcomes of large language models (LLMs). The findings reveal that including minority group samples in prompts significantly improves fairness without compromising predictive accuracy. The proportion of minority to majority samples in demonstrations affects the trade-off between fairness and prediction accuracy. Based on these insights, a mitigation technique is introduced that employs clustering and evolutionary strategies to curate a diverse and representative sample set from the training data. This approach aims to enhance both predictive performance and fairness in ICL applications. Experimental results validate that the proposed method dramatically improves fairness across various metrics, demonstrating its efficacy in real-world scenarios.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Deliberately including minority group samples in ICL prompts significantly boosts fairness without sacrificing predictive accuracy.</li>
<li>The proportion of minority to majority samples in demonstrations affects the trade-off between fairness and prediction accuracy.</li>
<li>A mitigation technique that employs clustering and evolutionary strategies to curate a diverse and representative sample set from the training data enhances both predictive performance and fairness in ICL applications.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study provides valuable insights into the fairness implications of ICL in LLMs and introduces a novel mitigation technique to improve fairness.</li>
<li>However, the study focuses on binary classification with a single sensitive feature, which limits the broader applicability of the findings. Future research should explore LLM’s intersectional fairness and its performance in multi-classification tasks.</li>
<li>The study uses pre-trained models without fine-tuning. Investigating how fine-tuning on curated samples impacts fairness could provide deeper insights.</li>
<li>The proposed mitigation technique equally weighs fairness and prediction performance, which might not align with real-world applications that require a dynamic balance between these metrics.</li>
<li>The study does not address the potential biases in the training data, which could impact the fairness of the LLMs. Future research should consider methods to mitigate biases in the training data.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-20</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.09757v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.09757v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09757v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09757v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6909</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Strategic_Demonstration_Selection_for_Improved_Fairness_in_LLM_In_Context_Learning/2024-08-19-Strategic_Demonstration_Selection_for_Improved_Fairness_in_LLM_In_Context_Learning.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09757v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>MegaAgent: A Practical Framework for Autonomous Cooperation in Large-Scale LLM Agent Systems</title>
  <dc:creator>Qian Wang, Tianyu Wang, Qinbin Li, Jingsheng Liang, Bingsheng He</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MegaAgent_A_Practical_Framework_for_Autonomous_Cooperation_in_Large_Scale_LLM_Agent_Systems/2024-08-19-MegaAgent_A_Practical_Framework_for_Autonomous_Cooperation_in_Large_Scale_LLM_Agent_Systems.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MegaAgent_A_Practical_Framework_for_Autonomous_Cooperation_in_Large_Scale_LLM_Agent_Systems/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09955v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper introduces MegaAgent, a practical framework designed for autonomous cooperation in large-scale LLM Agent systems. MegaAgent addresses the limitations of current LLM-MA systems by enabling dynamic task splitting, systematic planning, and monitoring of agent activities, and managing concurrent operations. The framework is designed with a hierarchical structure and employs system-level parallelism to enhance performance and boost communication. The effectiveness of MegaAgent is demonstrated through Gobang game development and national policy simulation, outperforming popular LLM-MA systems and showcasing its high autonomy and potential to rapidly scale up to 590 agents while ensuring effective cooperation.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>MegaAgent is a practical framework designed for autonomous cooperation in large-scale LLM-MA systems, enabling dynamic task splitting and parallel communication among LLM agents.</li>
<li>The effectiveness of MegaAgent is validated through experiments in Gobang game development and national policy simulation, demonstrating its autonomy and scalability.</li>
<li>MegaAgent stands out for its high autonomy, multi-file support, parallelism, and scalability compared to current popular LLM-MA systems.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>While MegaAgent presents a promising solution for large-scale LLM-MA systems, there are potential limitations and areas for improvement. One concern is the reliance on a hierarchical structure, which may not be suitable for all types of tasks or environments. Additionally, the framework’s performance may be affected by the inherent instability of LLM agent outputs, necessitating the development of more robust control mechanisms. Furthermore, the scalability of MegaAgent may be limited by the computational resources required to manage a large number of agents, which could impact its applicability in resource-constrained scenarios. Future research should focus on addressing these challenges and exploring alternative approaches to enhance the effectiveness and efficiency of large-scale LLM-MA systems.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-20</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.09955v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.09955v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09955v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09955v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>10060</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MegaAgent_A_Practical_Framework_for_Autonomous_Cooperation_in_Large_Scale_LLM_Agent_Systems/2024-08-19-MegaAgent_A_Practical_Framework_for_Autonomous_Cooperation_in_Large_Scale_LLM_Agent_Systems.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09955v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>How to Make the Most of LLMs’ Grammatical Knowledge for Acceptability Judgments</title>
  <dc:creator>Yusuke Ide, Yuto Nishida, Miyu Oba, Yusuke Sakai, Justin Vasselli, Hidetaka Kamigaito, Taro Watanabe</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/How_to_Make_the_Most_of_LLMs_Grammatical_Knowledge_for_Acceptability_Judgments/2024-08-19-How_to_Make_the_Most_of_LLMs_Grammatical_Knowledge_for_Acceptability_Judgments.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/How_to_Make_the_Most_of_LLMs_Grammatical_Knowledge_for_Acceptability_Judgments/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09639v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The study investigates how to make the most of large language models (LLMs) for acceptability judgments, comparing conventional sentence probability readout methods, novel probability readout methods in in-template settings, and prompting-based methods. Through extensive experiments using six state-of-the-art LLMs and two minimal pair (MP) benchmarks (one for English and one for Chinese), the authors demonstrate that an in-template probability readout method, in-template LP, and a prompting-based method, Yes/No probability computing, achieve particularly high performance, surpassing the conventional approach. The analysis reveals their different strengths, with Yes/No probability computing being robust against token-length bias, suggesting that they harness different aspects of LLMs’ grammatical knowledge. The authors recommend using diverse judgment methods to evaluate LLMs comprehensively.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>In-template LP and Yes/No probability computing show top performance, surpassing the conventional methods.</li>
<li>In-template LP and Yes/No probability computing have different strengths; for example, Yes/No probability computing is robust against token-length bias, indicating that they harness different aspects of LLMs’ grammatical knowledge.</li>
<li>Ensembling the two methods further improves the accuracy, revealing their complementary capabilities. The highest score by Mix-P3 with Qwen2 is 1.6 percentage points higher than humans on the English benchmark.</li>
<li>Even with the top two methods, all the LLMs have trouble making correct judgments where the unacceptable sentence can be obtained by shuffling the words in the acceptable one.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The study provides a comprehensive comparison of various methods for extracting acceptability judgments from LLMs, highlighting the strengths and weaknesses of each approach. The authors’ recommendation to use diverse judgment methods for a more comprehensive and appropriate evaluation of LLMs is well-supported by their findings. However, the cause of the different strengths of in-template LP and Yes/No probability computing remains an open question, as the hypotheses examined in the study were not supported. Additionally, the focus on experiments in the zero-shot setting leaves room for further investigation into the potential benefits of providing few-shot examples in in-template LP and Yes/No probability computing. Overall, the study contributes valuable insights into</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-20</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.09639v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.09639v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09639v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09639v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5926</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/How_to_Make_the_Most_of_LLMs_Grammatical_Knowledge_for_Acceptability_Judgments/2024-08-19-How_to_Make_the_Most_of_LLMs_Grammatical_Knowledge_for_Acceptability_Judgments.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09639v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Importance Weighting Can Help Large Language Models Self-Improve</title>
  <dc:creator>Chunyang Jiang, Chi-min Chan, Wei Xue, Qifeng Liu, Yike Guo</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Importance_Weighting_Can_Help_Large_Language_Models_Self_Improve/2024-08-19-Importance_Weighting_Can_Help_Large_Language_Models_Self_Improve.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Importance_Weighting_Can_Help_Large_Language_Models_Self_Improve/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09849v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>This paper explores the impact of sample distribution shift extent (DSE) on Large Language Models (LLMs) self-improvement. The authors propose a novel metric called Distribution Shift Weight (DS weight) to approximate DSE, inspired by Importance Weighting methods. They then introduce a new self-improvement framework called Importance Weighting-based Self-Improvement (IWSI), which incorporates both answer correctness and DSE in its filtering strategy. The experiments conducted on six datasets show that IWSI significantly outperforms baseline self-improvement methods and rivals the enhancements achieved with supervision from a pre-trained reward model.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The proposed DS weight metric effectively approximates the DSE of LLM self-generated data, with the help of a tiny valid set.</li>
<li>The IWSI framework, which considers both answer correctness and DSE in its filtering strategy, significantly improves the performance of LLM self-improvement.</li>
<li>The performance of IWSI is comparable to that achieved with external supervision from a pre-trained reward model.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The paper presents a novel approach to LLM self-improvement by incorporating the DS weight metric to filter out high DSE samples. The proposed IWSI framework demonstrates significant improvements over baseline methods, and its performance is comparable to methods that rely on external supervision. However, the paper does not discuss the potential limitations or biases of the proposed method, nor does it address any methodological issues or conflicting evidence. Additionally, the paper does not provide any information on the computational cost or scalability of the proposed method. Further research is needed to evaluate the generalizability of the proposed method to other tasks and datasets, as well as its applicability in real-world scenarios.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-20</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.09849v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.09849v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09849v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09849v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7239</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Importance_Weighting_Can_Help_Large_Language_Models_Self_Improve/2024-08-19-Importance_Weighting_Can_Help_Large_Language_Models_Self_Improve.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09849v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Instruction Finetuning for Leaderboard Generation from Empirical AI Research</title>
  <dc:creator>Salomon Kabongo, Jennifer D&#39;Souza</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Instruction_Finetuning_for_Leaderboard_Generation_from_Empirical_AI_Research/2024-08-19-Instruction_Finetuning_for_Leaderboard_Generation_from_Empirical_AI_Research.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/../bayesian-beagle.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>This study explores the application of instruction finetuning of pretrained Large Language Models (LLMs) to automate the generation of AI research leaderboards. The authors utilize the FLAN-T5 model to enhance LLMs’ adaptability and reliability in information extraction, offering a novel method for structured knowledge representation. The research aims to streamline the dissemination of advancements in AI research by transitioning from traditional, manual community curation, or otherwise taxonomy-constrained natural language inference (NLI) models, to an automated, generative LLM-based approach.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The study introduces a novel objective: text generation within a given context, aiming to overcome the limitations of traditional NLI-based systems that rely on a predefined (T, D, M) taxonomy.</li>
<li>The authors adopt instruction fine-tuning to accomplish SOTA as a text generation task, enhancing the model’s adaptability to the domain-specific nuances of AI research.</li>
<li>The research employs the FLAN-T5 model, an instruction-tuned variant from the T5 model class, boasting 780M parameters and sourced from Google’s open-access repository on the Transformers library.</li>
<li>The authors demonstrate improvements in task performance, with their model surpassing previous NLI-based systems by nearly 10% in F1 scores, thereby validating the efficacy and feasibility of their approach.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>While the study presents a promising approach to automate the generation of AI research leaderboards, there are some potential limitations and areas for improvement:</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>The study focuses on the FLAN-T5 model, which may not generalize well to other LLMs or domains outside of AI research.</li>
<li>The authors acknowledge that their approach relies on the quality of data processing and the inherent limitations of the tools employed, such as Pandoc, for converting LaTeX documents to plain text. Errors introduced during this conversion can significantly affect the extraction accuracy of (Task, Dataset, Metric, Score) quadruples.</li>
<li>The model’s generalizability across various domains of academic research beyond computer science is not yet verified. The distinct formats and</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-20</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.10141v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.10141v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.10141v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.10141v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6247</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Instruction_Finetuning_for_Leaderboard_Generation_from_Empirical_AI_Research/2024-08-19-Instruction_Finetuning_for_Leaderboard_Generation_from_Empirical_AI_Research.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Ranking Generated Answers: On the Agreement of Retrieval Models with Humans on Consumer Health Questions</title>
  <dc:creator>Sebastian Heineking, Jonas Probst, Daniel Steinbach, Martin Potthast, Harrisen Scells</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Ranking_Generated_Answers_On_the_Agreement_of_Retrieval_Models_with_Humans_on_Consumer_Health_Questions/2024-08-19-Ranking_Generated_Answers_On_the_Agreement_of_Retrieval_Models_with_Humans_on_Consumer_Health_Questions.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Ranking_Generated_Answers_On_the_Agreement_of_Retrieval_Models_with_Humans_on_Consumer_Health_Questions/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09831v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper presents a method for evaluating the quality of answers generated by large language models (LLMs) using ranking signals as a substitute for explicit relevance judgments. The proposed method, called normalized rank position (NRP), measures the effectiveness of generated answers by ranking them alongside human-written documents using a retrieval model known to have high effectiveness in ranking documents with respect to their relevance judgments. The method is evaluated using the CLEF eHealth 2021 test data, which comprises 55 health-related queries obtained from medical experts and Reddit discussions. The results show that the choice of prompting strategy and model size have a large influence on the effectiveness of generated answers, and these effects are measurable with NRP. The paper also compares the preferences of the chosen ranking model with that of an expert annotator and shows a high agreement between the two.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The proposed NRP method can effectively evaluate the quality of answers generated by LLMs using ranking signals as a substitute for explicit relevance judgments.</li>
<li>The choice of prompting strategy and model size have a large influence on the effectiveness of generated answers, and these effects are measurable with NRP.</li>
<li>The proposed method shows a high agreement with the preferences of an expert annotator, indicating its validity in evaluating the quality of generated answers.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The proposed method provides a scalable and automatic way to evaluate the quality of generated answers to consumer health questions. However, the results of the experiments may be limited in their ability to discriminate highly effective LLMs as the dataset used was potentially too easy for these models. The paper also acknowledges the need for further research to extend the NRP method to assess retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) systems that ground their answers in documents by referring to them. Additionally, the paper focuses on evaluating generated answers for consumer health search questions, and future work is needed to develop and adapt test collections for other domains. Overall, the paper contributes a new way to automatically assess LLM capabilities by evaluating them in the context of human-annotated documents.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-20</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.09831v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.09831v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09831v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09831v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>3362</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Ranking_Generated_Answers_On_the_Agreement_of_Retrieval_Models_with_Humans_on_Consumer_Health_Questions/2024-08-19-Ranking_Generated_Answers_On_the_Agreement_of_Retrieval_Models_with_Humans_on_Consumer_Health_Questions.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09831v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Enhance Modality Robustness in Text-Centric Multimodal Alignment with Adversarial Prompting</title>
  <dc:creator>Yun-Da Tsai, Ting-Yu Yen, Keng-Te Liao, Shou-De Lin</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Enhance_Modality_Robustness_in_Text_Centric_Multimodal_Alignment_with_Adversarial_Prompting/2024-08-19-Enhance_Modality_Robustness_in_Text_Centric_Multimodal_Alignment_with_Adversarial_Prompting.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Enhance_Modality_Robustness_in_Text_Centric_Multimodal_Alignment_with_Adversarial_Prompting/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09798v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>This study evaluates the robustness of text-centric multimodal alignment methods, which convert diverse data types into text to facilitate the integration of various modalities. The authors reveal that current text-centric alignment methods can compromise downstream robustness due to the potential model collapse phenomenon, which can jeopardize the robustness of the aligned representation. To address this issue, the authors propose a new text-centric adversarial training approach that significantly enhances robustness compared to traditional robust training methods and pre-trained multimodal foundation models. The proposed method involves using a LLM-based perturbation module on top of the expert models to increase the diversity and robustness of text representations before converting different input modalities into text. The authors demonstrate that their enhancement can significantly improve the modality robustness through rigorous testing under various conditions, including missing or noisy data.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The study reveals that current text-centric alignment methods can compromise downstream robustness due to the potential model collapse phenomenon.</li>
<li>The authors propose a new text-centric adversarial training approach that significantly enhances robustness compared to traditional robust training methods and pre-trained multimodal foundation models.</li>
<li>The proposed method involves using a LLM-based perturbation module on top of the expert models to increase the diversity and robustness of text representations before converting different input modalities into text.</li>
<li>The authors demonstrate that their enhancement can significantly improve the modality robustness through rigorous testing under various conditions, including missing or noisy data.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The authors provide a comprehensive analysis of the robustness of text-centric multimodal alignment methods and propose a novel approach to enhance the robustness of these methods. However, the study does not provide a detailed comparison of the proposed method with other existing methods for improving the robustness of multimodal alignment. Additionally, the study does not discuss the potential limitations of the proposed method, such as the computational cost of using a LLM-based perturbation module or the impact of the perturbation module on the quality of the text representations. Further research is needed to address these limitations and evaluate the effectiveness of the proposed method in real-world applications.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-20</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.09798v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.09798v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09798v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09798v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5824</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Enhance_Modality_Robustness_in_Text_Centric_Multimodal_Alignment_with_Adversarial_Prompting/2024-08-19-Enhance_Modality_Robustness_in_Text_Centric_Multimodal_Alignment_with_Adversarial_Prompting.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09798v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Paired Completion: Flexible Quantification of Issue-framing at Scale with LLMs</title>
  <dc:creator>Simon D Angus, Lachlan O&#39;Neill</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Paired_Completion_Flexible_Quantification_of_Issue_framing_at_Scale_with_LLMs/2024-08-19-Paired_Completion_Flexible_Quantification_of_Issue_framing_at_Scale_with_LLMs.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Paired_Completion_Flexible_Quantification_of_Issue_framing_at_Scale_with_LLMs/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09742v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The study introduces a novel method called “paired completion” for detecting and quantifying issue framing in large text datasets. This method leverages next-token log probabilities derived from generative large language models (LLMs) to reliably and efficiently detect issue framing with only a few examples of either perspective on a given issue. The authors evaluate paired completion against prompt-based LLM methods and labeled methods using traditional NLP and recent LLM contextual embeddings. They also conduct a cost-based analysis and a model bias analysis. The results demonstrate a feasible path to scalable, accurate, and low-bias issue-framing in large corpora.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Paired completion method</strong>: The authors introduce a new method called paired completion, which is a low-resource, computationally efficient method that can accurately identify whether a target text aligns with one or other conceptual framing on a given issue.</li>
<li><strong>Empirical evaluation</strong>: The authors conduct rigorous evaluation of their proposed method across 192 independent experiments by comparing it to four framing classification approaches over four diverse, synthetic textual datasets. They demonstrate that the LLM-based approaches are, in general, far superior to the alternatives.</li>
<li><strong>Cost- and bias- comparison analyses</strong>: The authors conduct cost- and bias- comparison analyses at current gated API pricing to assess any trade-offs in performance. They demonstrate that paired completion with LLMs is generally superior to the LLM prompting approach.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The study presents a promising approach to detecting and quantifying issue framing in large text datasets. The paired completion method is a novel and efficient solution that can accurately identify conceptual framing with minimal examples. The authors provide a comprehensive evaluation of their method, demonstrating its superiority over existing approaches. However, the use of synthetic data for evaluation has some limitations, as it may not accurately reflect the performance of the method on human-labeled ground-truth data. Additionally, the study focuses on a traditional two-class classification paradigm, and further research is needed to explore the extension of paired completion to any number of framings on a given dimension of an issue. Finally, the study suggests that aligned models may be more prone to bias when performing framing alignment, but</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-20</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.09742v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.09742v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09742v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09742v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7395</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Paired_Completion_Flexible_Quantification_of_Issue_framing_at_Scale_with_LLMs/2024-08-19-Paired_Completion_Flexible_Quantification_of_Issue_framing_at_Scale_with_LLMs.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09742v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Are Large Language Models More Honest in Their Probabilistic or Verbalized Confidence?</title>
  <dc:creator>Shiyu Ni, Keping Bi, Lulu Yu, Jiafeng Guo</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Are_Large_Language_Models_More_Honest_in_Their_Probabilistic_or_Verbalized_Confidence/2024-08-19-Are_Large_Language_Models_More_Honest_in_Their_Probabilistic_or_Verbalized_Confidence.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Are_Large_Language_Models_More_Honest_in_Their_Probabilistic_or_Verbalized_Confidence/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09773v1/extracted/5799495/figs/thre.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level1">
<h1>Summary:</h1>
<p><strong>Summary:</strong> The paper investigates the perception of factual knowledge boundaries in large language models (LLMs) through probabilistic and verbalized confidence. The authors compare the strengths and weaknesses of these two perceptions, analyze their performance under varying question frequencies, and evaluate the correlation between LLMs’ probabilistic and verbalized confidence. The study reveals that LLMs’ probabilistic perception is generally more accurate than verbalized perception but requires an in-domain validation set to adjust the confidence threshold. Both perceptions perform better on less frequent questions, with probabilistic perception outperforming verbalized perception by a greater margin. However, LLMs struggle to accurately express their internal confidence in natural language.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs’ probabilistic perception of their knowledge boundaries is more accurate than their verbalized perception, but it necessitates the use of an in-domain dataset to determine an appropriate confidence threshold for binarizing continuous probabilistic confidence.</li>
<li>Both LLMs’ probabilistic perception and verbalized perception of their knowledge boundaries perform better on less common questions, indicating that LLMs’ perception levels decline on more familiar questions.</li>
<li>LLMs’ verbalized confidence is positively correlated with their probabilistic confidence, but the correlation is weak and varies significantly across different datasets, making it challenging for LLMs to accurately express their internal confidence in natural language.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h2>
<ul>
<li>The study provides valuable insights into the perception of factual knowledge boundaries in LLMs, highlighting the differences and connections between probabilistic and verbalized confidence.</li>
<li>The authors’ comprehensive analysis and comparison of LLMs’ perceptions under varying question frequencies and their correlation with QA performance offer a deeper understanding of LLMs’ capabilities and limitations.</li>
<li>However, the study could benefit from exploring additional factors that may influence LLMs’ perception of their knowledge boundaries, such as model size, training data, and prompting techniques.</li>
<li>Additionally, the study could investigate the potential applications of LLMs’ perception of their knowledge boundaries in real-world scenarios, such as safety and healthcare, to further demonstrate their practical implications.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-20</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.09773v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.09773v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09773v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09773v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>4282</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Are_Large_Language_Models_More_Honest_in_Their_Probabilistic_or_Verbalized_Confidence/2024-08-19-Are_Large_Language_Models_More_Honest_in_Their_Probabilistic_or_Verbalized_Confidence.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09773v1/extracted/5799495/figs/thre.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Minor DPO reject penalty to increase training robustness</title>
  <dc:creator>Shiming Xie, Hong Chen, Fred Yu, Zeye Sun, Xiuyu Wu, Yingfan Hu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Minor_DPO_reject_penalty_to_increase_training_robustness/2024-08-19-Minor_DPO_reject_penalty_to_increase_training_robustness.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/../bayesian-beagle.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The article discusses the use of Direct Preference Optimization (DPO) for aligning large-scale language models (LLMs) with human preferences. DPO is a simplified, RL-free method that models the relative log probability as an implicit reward function and optimizes the LLM policy using a simple binary cross-entropy objective. However, the authors identify a potential shortcoming in DPO: it is fragile in certain data distributions and may require careful tuning to avoid optimization crashes.</p>
<p>To address this issue, the authors propose MinorDPO, which is better aligned with the original RL algorithm and increases the stability of the preference optimization process. The main contribution of the article is a comprehensive analysis of the DPO mechanism and the proposal of an improved loss function, Minor DPO, based on this analysis.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>DPO is a simplified, RL-free method for aligning LLMs with human preferences, but it is fragile in certain data distributions and may require careful tuning.</li>
<li>The authors propose MinorDPO, which is better aligned with the original RL algorithm and increases the stability of the preference optimization process.</li>
<li>The main contribution of the article is a comprehensive analysis of the DPO mechanism and the proposal of an improved loss function, Minor DPO, based on this analysis.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article provides a valuable contribution to the field of LLM alignment with human preferences by proposing MinorDPO as a more stable and robust alternative to DPO. However, the article does not provide a detailed evaluation of MinorDPO’s performance compared to DPO or other alignment methods. Additionally, the authors do not discuss potential limitations or biases in the proposed method, such as the need for careful tuning or the potential for overfitting. Further research is needed to evaluate the effectiveness and limitations of MinorDPO in practical applications.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-20</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.09834v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.09834v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09834v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09834v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5014</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Minor_DPO_reject_penalty_to_increase_training_robustness/2024-08-19-Minor_DPO_reject_penalty_to_increase_training_robustness.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Harnessing Multimodal Large Language Models for Multimodal Sequential Recommendation</title>
  <dc:creator>Yuyang Ye, Zhi Zheng, Yishan Shen, Tianshu Wang, Hengruo Zhang, Peijun Zhu, Runlong Yu, Kai Zhang, Hui Xiong</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Harnessing_Multimodal_Large_Language_Models_for_Multimodal_Sequential_Recommendation/2024-08-19-Harnessing_Multimodal_Large_Language_Models_for_Multimodal_Sequential_Recommendation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Harnessing_Multimodal_Large_Language_Models_for_Multimodal_Sequential_Recommendation/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09698v1/extracted/5799202/figures/framework.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level1">
<h1>Summary</h1>
<p><strong>Summary:</strong> The paper introduces the Multimodal Large Language Model-enhanced Sequential Multimodal Recommendation (MLLM-MSR) model, which aims to capture dynamic user preferences in a two-stage user preference summarization method. The first stage involves an MLLM-based item-summarizer to extract image features and convert them into text. The second stage employs a recurrent user preference summarization generation paradigm to capture the dynamic changes in user preferences using an LLM-based user-summarizer. The MLLM-based recommender is then fine-tuned using Supervised Fine-Tuning (SFT) techniques. The proposed model is evaluated on various datasets, demonstrating its effectiveness in capturing and adapting to the evolving dynamics of user preferences.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li>The MLLM-MSR model is the first attempt to fine-tune multimodal large models for sequential multimodal recommendation, achieving significant improvements in recommendation performance.</li>
<li>The paper introduces a novel image summarizing method based on MLLMs to recurrently summarize user preferences on multi-modality, facilitating a deeper understanding of user interactions and interests over time.</li>
<li>The proposed approach is extensively validated across various datasets, demonstrating its effectiveness in enhancing the accuracy and interpretability of recommendations.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h2>
<ul>
<li>The paper presents an innovative approach to integrating MLLMs into multimodal sequential recommendation systems, addressing the challenges of processing sequential multimodal data.</li>
<li>The proposed two-stage user preference summarization method effectively captures dynamic user preferences, improving the interpretability of recommendations.</li>
<li>The paper demonstrates the effectiveness of the MLLM-MSR model through extensive evaluations on various datasets, showcasing its superior ability to adapt to evolving user preferences.</li>
<li>However, the paper does not discuss potential limitations or unanswered questions, such as the computational demands of processing sequential multimodal data or the generalizability of the fine-tuned MLLM-based recommender.</li>
<li>Future research could explore these aspects and investigate the applicability of the MLLM-MSR model in other recommendation domains.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-20</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.09698v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.09698v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09698v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09698v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6167</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>recommender</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Harnessing_Multimodal_Large_Language_Models_for_Multimodal_Sequential_Recommendation/2024-08-19-Harnessing_Multimodal_Large_Language_Models_for_Multimodal_Sequential_Recommendation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09698v1/extracted/5799202/figures/framework.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Application of Large Language Models in Automated Question Generation: A Case Study on ChatGLM’s Structured Questions for National Teacher Certification Exams</title>
  <dc:creator>Yanxin Chen, Ling He</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Application_of_Large_Language_Models_in_Automated_Question_Generation_A_Case_Study_on_ChatGLMs_Structured_Questions_for_National_Teacher_Certification_Exams/2024-08-19-Application_of_Large_Language_Models_in_Automated_Question_Generation_A_Case_Study_on_ChatGLMs_Structured_Questions_for_National_Teacher_Certification_Exams.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/../bayesian-beagle.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study explores the application potential of the large language model (LLM) ChatGLM in generating structured questions for National Teacher Certification Exams (NTCE).</li>
<li>Through prompt engineering, ChatGLM generated a series of simulated questions, which were compared with questions recollected from past examinees.</li>
<li>The study aimed to validate the application potential of LLMs in the simulation of question generation within the educational field.</li>
<li>The research results indicate that ChatGLM-generated questions exhibit a high level of rationality, scientificity, and practicality, similar to real exam questions across most evaluation criteria.</li>
<li>However, the study also reveals limitations in the model’s consideration of various rating criteria when generating questions, suggesting the need for further optimization and adjustment.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>ChatGLM-generated questions demonstrate high accuracy and reliability in simulating structured questions for teacher qualification exams, with close average scores and similar standard deviations to real exam questions in terms of the rationality of question design, balance of difficulty, logical coherence, and coverage of knowledge and abilities.</li>
<li>A significant difference (p &lt; 0.05, 3.51 &gt; 3.40) was observed under Evaluation Criterion 2 between real exam questions and those generated by ChatGLM, which may indicate that further optimization is needed in ChatGLM’s question generation for certain evaluation criteria.</li>
<li>LLMs like ChatGLM show significant potential in the automated generation of structured questions for teacher qualification exams, providing effective preparation materials for candidates and serving as a new automated tool for educational assessment.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study’s methodology and results are well-structured and provide valuable insights into the potential of LLMs in generating structured questions for NTCE.</li>
<li>The limitations of the study include the need for further optimization in ChatGLM’s question generation for certain evaluation criteria and the model’s performance being constrained by the quality and quantity of training data.</li>
<li>The study could have benefited from a more in-depth analysis of the specific areas where ChatGLM underperformed in generating practical questions compared to real exam questions.</li>
<li>Future research should continue to explore optimization strategies for the model to enhance its performance in generating complex and specialized questions, thereby better</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-20</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.09982v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.09982v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09982v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09982v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8304</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Application_of_Large_Language_Models_in_Automated_Question_Generation_A_Case_Study_on_ChatGLMs_Structured_Questions_for_National_Teacher_Certification_Exams/2024-08-19-Application_of_Large_Language_Models_in_Automated_Question_Generation_A_Case_Study_on_ChatGLMs_Structured_Questions_for_National_Teacher_Certification_Exams.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Edge-Cloud Collaborative Motion Planning for Autonomous Driving with Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Jiao Chen, Suyan Dai, Fangfang Chen, Zuohong Lv, Jianhua Tang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Edge_Cloud_Collaborative_Motion_Planning_for_Autonomous_Driving_with_Large_Language_Models/2024-08-19-Edge_Cloud_Collaborative_Motion_Planning_for_Autonomous_Driving_with_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Edge_Cloud_Collaborative_Motion_Planning_for_Autonomous_Driving_with_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09972v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study introduces EC-Drive, a novel edge-cloud collaborative autonomous driving system with data drift detection capabilities.</li>
<li>EC-Drive utilizes drift detection algorithms to selectively upload critical data to the cloud for processing by GPT-4, while routine data is managed by smaller LLMs on edge devices.</li>
<li>This approach reduces inference latency and improves system efficiency by optimizing communication resource use.</li>
<li>Experimental validation confirms the system’s robust processing capabilities and practical applicability in real-world driving conditions.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>EC-Drive, a novel edge-cloud collaborative autonomous driving system, ensures low inference latency while effectively addressing the challenges of complex environments.</li>
<li>The integration of linguistic features with traditional visual data enhances the interpretability and decision-making capabilities of autonomous driving systems.</li>
<li>Detailed experimental validation demonstrates the system’s robust processing capabilities and its potential applicability in real-world driving scenarios.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study does not provide a detailed comparison with other existing edge-cloud collaborative autonomous driving systems.</li>
<li>The experimental validation is limited to the EC-Drive system, and a more comprehensive evaluation involving other systems would provide a better understanding of its performance.</li>
<li>The study does not discuss the potential challenges and limitations of deploying such a system in real-world scenarios, such as network latency, data privacy, and security.</li>
<li>The study does not provide a detailed analysis of the computational overhead and resource requirements of the EC-Drive system.</li>
<li>The study does not discuss the potential impact of the system on the overall driving experience and user satisfaction.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-20</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.09972v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.09972v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09972v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09972v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>4056</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Edge_Cloud_Collaborative_Motion_Planning_for_Autonomous_Driving_with_Large_Language_Models/2024-08-19-Edge_Cloud_Collaborative_Motion_Planning_for_Autonomous_Driving_with_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09972v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>CMoralEval: A Moral Evaluation Benchmark for Chinese Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Linhao Yu, Yongqi Leng, Yufei Huang, Shang Wu, Haixin Liu, Xinmeng Ji, Jiahui Zhao, Jinwang Song, Tingting Cui, Xiaoqing Cheng, Tao Liu, Deyi Xiong</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/CMoralEval_A_Moral_Evaluation_Benchmark_for_Chinese_Large_Language_Models/2024-08-19-CMoralEval_A_Moral_Evaluation_Benchmark_for_Chinese_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/CMoralEval_A_Moral_Evaluation_Benchmark_for_Chinese_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09819v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper introduces CMoralEval, a large benchmark dataset for evaluating the morality of Chinese large language models (LLMs).</li>
<li>The dataset is derived from two sources: a Chinese TV program discussing moral norms and a collection of Chinese moral anomies from various newspapers and academic papers.</li>
<li>CMoralEval includes both explicit moral scenarios (14,964 instances) and moral dilemma scenarios (15,424 instances), each with instances from different data sources.</li>
<li>The dataset is categorized into five groups of morality: familial morality, social morality, professional ethics, Internet ethics, and personal morality.</li>
<li>The paper presents extensive experiments with CMoralEval to examine a variety of Chinese LLMs, demonstrating that it is a challenging benchmark.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>CMoralEval is the first Chinese dataset curated to evaluate Chinese LLMs on morality, covering two distinct scenarios designed to evaluate the performance of Chinese LLMs when confronted with various types of moral situations.</li>
<li>The paper develops a moral taxonomy and a set of fundamental moral principles that are rooted in traditional Chinese culture and consistent with contemporary societal norms.</li>
<li>The paper conducts extensive experiments on a wide range of Chinese LLMs under both zero- and few-shot settings, comprehensively evaluating Chinese LLMs in ethics and morality both horizontally and vertically across different models and model sizes.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper does not provide a detailed analysis of the performance of individual LLMs on the CMoralEval dataset, making it difficult to compare the strengths and weaknesses of different models.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential limitations of the CMoralEval dataset, such as the generalizability of the moral scenarios and the potential for cultural bias in the dataset.</li>
<li>The paper does not provide a clear definition of what constitutes a “correct” or “incorrect” response to a moral scenario, which could impact the validity of the evaluation results.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential implications of using a Chinese-specific dataset for evaluating LLMs, such as the potential for cultural bias in the evaluation results.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential for using the CMoralEval dataset to improve the moral reasoning capabilities of</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-20</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.09819v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.09819v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09819v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09819v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8745</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/CMoralEval_A_Moral_Evaluation_Benchmark_for_Chinese_Large_Language_Models/2024-08-19-CMoralEval_A_Moral_Evaluation_Benchmark_for_Chinese_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09819v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Privacy Checklist: Privacy Violation Detection Grounding on Contextual Integrity Theory</title>
  <dc:creator>Haoran Li, Wei Fan, Yulin Chen, Jiayang Cheng, Tianshu Chu, Xuebing Zhou, Peizhao Hu, Yangqiu Song</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Privacy_Checklist_Privacy_Violation_Detection_Grounding_on_Contextual_Integrity_Theory/2024-08-19-Privacy_Checklist_Privacy_Violation_Detection_Grounding_on_Contextual_Integrity_Theory.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Privacy_Checklist_Privacy_Violation_Detection_Grounding_on_Contextual_Integrity_Theory/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.10053v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>This paper proposes a novel approach to privacy research by formulating it as a reasoning problem rather than simple pattern matching. The authors ground their work on the Contextual Integrity (CI) theory, which posits that people’s perceptions of privacy are highly correlated with the corresponding social context. The paper introduces the first comprehensive checklist that covers social identities, private attributes, and existing privacy regulations. Unlike prior works, the proposed privacy checklist uses the whole Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (HIPAA) as an example to show that large language models (LLMs) can completely cover the HIPAA’s regulations. The checklist also gathers expert annotations across multiple ontologies to determine private information, including personally identifiable information (PII). The authors use their preliminary results on the HIPAA to shed light on future context-centric privacy research to cover more privacy regulations, social norms, and standards.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper extends prior works on CI to natural language and formulates the privacy research as an in-context reasoning problem with the help of large language models.</li>
<li>The authors propose Privacy Checklist, a first scalable knowledge base that can cover all norms of the HIPAA.</li>
<li>The paper considers various retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) pipelines for LLMs. To retrieve relevant legal documents, the authors implement term frequency, semantic similarity, and agent-based methodologies.</li>
<li>The authors conduct comprehensive experiments to demonstrate that their Privacy Checklist is effective in improving LLMs’ privacy judgment ability for real court cases.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The paper presents a promising approach to privacy research by grounding it in the CI theory and using LLMs for in-context reasoning. The proposed Privacy Checklist is a significant contribution to the field, as it provides a scalable knowledge base that can cover all norms of the HIPAA. The authors’ consideration of various RAG pipelines for LLMs is also noteworthy, as it highlights the importance of retrieving relevant legal documents for accurate privacy judgment.</p>
<p>However, the paper has some limitations. First, the proposed approach is only evaluated on the HIPAA, and its applicability to other privacy regulations and social norms is</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-20</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.10053v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.10053v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.10053v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.10053v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6383</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Privacy_Checklist_Privacy_Violation_Detection_Grounding_on_Contextual_Integrity_Theory/2024-08-19-Privacy_Checklist_Privacy_Violation_Detection_Grounding_on_Contextual_Integrity_Theory.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.10053v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>GoNoGo: An Efficient LLM-based Multi-Agent System for Streamlining Automotive Software Release Decision-Making</title>
  <dc:creator>Arsham Gholamzadeh Khoee, Yinan Yu, Robert Feldt, Andris Freimanis, Patrick Andersson, Dhasarathy Parthasarathy</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/GoNoGo_An_Efficient_LLM_based_Multi_Agent_System_for_Streamlining_Automotive_Software_Release_Decision_Making/2024-08-19-GoNoGo_An_Efficient_LLM_based_Multi_Agent_System_for_Streamlining_Automotive_Software_Release_Decision_Making.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/GoNoGo_An_Efficient_LLM_based_Multi_Agent_System_for_Streamlining_Automotive_Software_Release_Decision_Making/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09785v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper introduces GoNoGo, an LLM-based multi-agent system designed to streamline automotive software release decision-making. Unlike traditional methods, which rely on manual analysis of tabular software test data, GoNoGo leverages large language models (LLMs) to automate and improve the process. The system is specifically tailored to address domain-specific and risk-sensitive systems, and it has been evaluated using zero-shot and few-shot examples taken from industrial practice. The results show that GoNoGo achieves a 100% success rate for tasks up to Level 2 difficulty with 3-shot examples and maintains high performance even for more complex tasks.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>GoNoGo is an efficient and user-friendly LLM-based solution that assists with software release decision-making, supporting more informed and timely decisions in the release process for risk-sensitive vehicle systems.</li>
<li>The system achieves a 100% success rate for tasks up to Level 2 difficulty with 3-shot examples and maintains high performance even for more complex tasks.</li>
<li>GoNoGo effectively automates decision-making for simpler tasks, significantly reducing the need for manual intervention.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper does not provide a detailed comparison of GoNoGo’s performance with other existing methods or tools for automotive software release decision-making.</li>
<li>The evaluation of GoNoGo’s performance is based on a limited set of examples, which may not fully represent the complexity and diversity of real-world scenarios.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential limitations or challenges of using LLMs for automotive software release decision-making, such as the need for large amounts of training data, the risk of overfitting, or the potential for biases in the decision-making process.</li>
<li>The paper does not provide information on the scalability and adaptability of GoNoGo to different automotive software systems or the potential impact of changes in the software development process on the system’s performance.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential ethical implications of using LLMs for automotive software release decision-making, such as the potential for job displacement or the need for transparency and accountability in the decision-making process.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-20</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.09785v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.09785v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09785v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09785v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6011</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/GoNoGo_An_Efficient_LLM_based_Multi_Agent_System_for_Streamlining_Automotive_Software_Release_Decision_Making/2024-08-19-GoNoGo_An_Efficient_LLM_based_Multi_Agent_System_for_Streamlining_Automotive_Software_Release_Decision_Making.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09785v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>GANPrompt: Enhancing Robustness in LLM-Based Recommendations with GAN-Enhanced Diversity Prompts</title>
  <dc:creator>Xinyu Li, Chuang Zhao, Hongke Zhao, Likang Wu, Ming HE</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/GANPrompt_Enhancing_Robustness_in_LLM_Based_Recommendations_with_GAN_Enhanced_Diversity_Prompts/2024-08-19-GANPrompt_Enhancing_Robustness_in_LLM_Based_Recommendations_with_GAN_Enhanced_Diversity_Prompts.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/GANPrompt_Enhancing_Robustness_in_LLM_Based_Recommendations_with_GAN_Enhanced_Diversity_Prompts/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09671v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary:</strong></p>
<p>GANPrompt is a novel framework that enhances the robustness of Large Language Models (LLMs) in recommender systems using Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs). The framework addresses the challenge of LLMs being highly susceptible to the influence of prompt words by training a multidimensional prompt generator capable of producing diverse prompts based on user behavioral data. These diverse prompts are then used to train the LLM, improving its performance in the face of unseen prompts. A mathematical theory-based diversity constraint mechanism ensures that the generated prompts are both highly diverse and relevant, semantically covering a wide range of user intentions.</p>
<p><strong>Major Findings:</strong></p>
<ol type="1">
<li>GANPrompt effectively improves the adaptability and robustness of recommender systems in complex and dynamic environments.</li>
<li>The framework provides significant improvements in accuracy and robustness compared to existing state-of-the-art approaches.</li>
<li>The diversity constraint mechanism ensures that the generated prompts are both highly diverse and relevant, enhancing the model’s performance.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></p>
<p>While GANPrompt demonstrates promising results, there are potential limitations and areas for improvement. The framework’s reliance on GANs may introduce complexity and computational overhead. Additionally, the effectiveness of the diversity constraint mechanism may vary depending on the specific recommendation task and dataset. Future research could explore the applicability of GANPrompt to a wider range of recommendation tasks and investigate strategies to optimize the trade-off between diversity and relevance in prompt generation.</p>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-20</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.09671v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.09671v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09671v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09671v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>10110</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>recommender</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/GANPrompt_Enhancing_Robustness_in_LLM_Based_Recommendations_with_GAN_Enhanced_Diversity_Prompts/2024-08-19-GANPrompt_Enhancing_Robustness_in_LLM_Based_Recommendations_with_GAN_Enhanced_Diversity_Prompts.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.09671v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
