<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Bayesian beagle</title>
<link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Quarto blog of LLM-generated summaries of Arxiv preprints</description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.450</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>SWEA: Changing Factual Knowledge in Large Language Models via Subject Word Embedding Altering</title>
  <dc:creator>Xiaopeng Li, Shasha Li, Bin Ji, Shezheng Song, Xi Wang, Jun Ma, Jie Yu, Xiaodong Liu, Jing Wang, Weimin Zhang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SWEA_Changing_Factual_Knowledge_in_Large_Language_Models_via_Subject_Word_Embedding_Altering/2024-01-31-SWEA_Changing_Factual_Knowledge_in_Large_Language_Models_via_Subject_Word_Embedding_Altering.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SWEA_Changing_Factual_Knowledge_in_Large_Language_Models_via_Subject_Word_Embedding_Altering/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>17 return r</p>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-01</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17809v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17809v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17809v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17809v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>11646</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SWEA_Changing_Factual_Knowledge_in_Large_Language_Models_via_Subject_Word_Embedding_Altering/2024-01-31-SWEA_Changing_Factual_Knowledge_in_Large_Language_Models_via_Subject_Word_Embedding_Altering.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Global-Liar: Factuality of LLMs over Time and Geographic Regions</title>
  <dc:creator>Shujaat Mirza, Bruno Coelho, Yuyuan Cui, Christina Pöpper, Damon McCoy</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Global_Liar_Factuality_of_LLMs_over_Time_and_Geographic_Regions/2024-01-31-Global_Liar_Factuality_of_LLMs_over_Time_and_Geographic_Regions.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Global_Liar_Factuality_of_LLMs_over_Time_and_Geographic_Regions/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="overall-summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="overall-summary">Overall Summary:</h3>
<p>The article evaluates the fact-checking performance of GPT-3.5 and GPT-4 models using an evaluation framework that assesses stability and factuality. It discusses the impact of temperature settings, regional variations, and uncertain statements on model performance. The study highlights the importance of diverse datasets, continuous evaluation, and adaptation of AI models to ensure accuracy, relevance, and fairness across diverse global contexts. The findings emphasize the need for task-specific evaluations, iterative refinements, and the acknowledgment of the “unclear” label in fact-checking. The article also addresses the limitations of the study and the potential for biases in datasets, emphasizing the need for future research to improve the effectiveness and fairness of language models in combating misinformation.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The stability and factuality of GPT-3.5 and GPT-4 models vary based on temperature settings, regional variations, and uncertain statements.</li>
<li>Model performance is better in Global North regions compared to Global South regions, highlighting disparities in factuality across geographic regions.</li>
<li>The study underscores the importance of diverse datasets, continuous evaluation, and adaptation of AI models to ensure accuracy, relevance, and fairness across diverse global contexts.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article provides valuable insights into the stability and factuality of GPT-3.5 and GPT-4 models, highlighting the need for diverse datasets, continuous evaluation, and adaptation of AI models to ensure accuracy, relevance, and fairness across diverse global contexts. However, the study is limited to specific language models, and the challenges faced in extending the research to a broader range of models are acknowledged. The findings also emphasize the need for future research to address biases in datasets and the democratization of fact-checking across diverse regions and languages. Additionally, the study’s implications for future research include the need to explore the performance of other LLM series and further investigate the impact of regional and temporal variations on model accuracy.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-01</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17839v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17839v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17839v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17839v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>17374</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Global_Liar_Factuality_of_LLMs_over_Time_and_Geographic_Regions/2024-01-31-Global_Liar_Factuality_of_LLMs_over_Time_and_Geographic_Regions.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>LoRec: Large Language Model for Robust Sequential Recommendation against Poisoning Attacks</title>
  <dc:creator>Kaike Zhang, Qi Cao, Yunfan Wu, Fei Sun, Huawei Shen, Xueqi Cheng</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LoRec_Large_Language_Model_for_Robust_Sequential_Recommendation_against_Poisoning_Attacks/2024-01-31-LoRec_Large_Language_Model_for_Robust_Sequential_Recommendation_against_Poisoning_Attacks.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LoRec_Large_Language_Model_for_Robust_Sequential_Recommendation_against_Poisoning_Attacks/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="overall-summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="overall-summary">Overall Summary:</h3>
<p>The article introduces two frameworks, LLM4Dec and LoRec, designed to enhance the robustness of sequential recommender systems against fraudulent activities and poisoning attacks. LLM4Dec leverages Large Language Models (LLMs) to detect fraudulent activities by transforming user interaction data into prompts to query LLMs’ knowledge. It utilizes a two-layer perceptron and an Entropy Regularization term to compute the probability that a user is fraudulent. On the other hand, LoRec integrates an LLM-enhanced Calibrator to estimate the likelihood of users being fraudsters and calibrate user weights during the training phase of the recommender system. Both frameworks demonstrate the potential to generalize across different types of attacks, including unknown ones, and enhance the robustness of recommender systems.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLM4Dec and LoRec demonstrate the potential to generalize across different types of fraudulent activities and poisoning attacks, including unknown ones.</li>
<li>The frameworks effectively enhance the robustness of sequential recommender systems against poisoning attacks while preserving recommendation performance.</li>
<li>The LLM4Dec framework’s loss function, including a regularization term, prevents extreme predictions, contributing to its overall effectiveness.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article represents a significant advancement in the detection of fraudulent activities and the mitigation of poisoning attacks in sequential recommender systems. However, potential limitations or areas for further research include the need for more extensive real-world testing and the exploration of the frameworks’ adaptability to diverse recommendation settings and backbone models. Additionally, the impact of hyperparameters and the size of the LLM on the frameworks’ performance could be further investigated. Overall, the frameworks show promise in enhancing the security and reliability of recommender systems, but further research is needed to fully understand their real-world applicability and potential limitations.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-01</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17723v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17723v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17723v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17723v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>17835</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>recommender</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LoRec_Large_Language_Model_for_Robust_Sequential_Recommendation_against_Poisoning_Attacks/2024-01-31-LoRec_Large_Language_Model_for_Robust_Sequential_Recommendation_against_Poisoning_Attacks.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Supporting Anticipatory Governance using LLMs: Evaluating and Aligning Large Language Models with the News Media to Anticipate the Negative Impacts of AI</title>
  <dc:creator>Mowafak Allaham, Nicholas Diakopoulos</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Supporting_Anticipatory_Governance_using_LLMs_Evaluating_and_Aligning_Large_Language_Models_with_the_News_Media_to_Anticipate_the_Negative_Impacts_of_AI/2024-01-31-Supporting_Anticipatory_Governance_using_LLMs_Evaluating_and_Aligning_Large_Language_Models_with_the_News_Media_to_Anticipate_the_Negative_Impacts_of_AI.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Supporting_Anticipatory_Governance_using_LLMs_Evaluating_and_Aligning_Large_Language_Models_with_the_News_Media_to_Anticipate_the_Negative_Impacts_of_AI/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="overall-summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="overall-summary">Overall Summary:</h3>
<p>The article presents a comprehensive approach to extracting, categorizing, and anticipating negative impacts of AI from news media using large language models (LLMs). The authors developed a taxonomy of negative impacts, refined a dataset of negative impact descriptions, and evaluated the performance of different models in generating negative impacts. They also discussed the challenges of AI-generated content and security, research ethics, and social impact, as well as the use of LLMs to anticipate impacts.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The development of a taxonomy of negative impacts provides a comprehensive framework for evaluating and comparing the generated impacts from different models.</li>
<li>The challenges and potential impacts of AI-generated content and security vulnerabilities in AI technologies are significant considerations for anticipatory governance.</li>
<li>The ethical considerations and potential challenges in using AI technologies for anticipatory governance underscore the need for a nuanced and cautious approach.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article’s approach to extracting and categorizing negative impacts of AI from news media using LLMs is rigorous and provides a foundation for further analysis and evaluation. However, potential biases, limitations, and ethical considerations associated with the use of LLMs for anticipatory governance should be carefully considered. The challenges and limitations in accurately anticipating impacts using LLMs highlight the need for a cautious approach to leveraging AI for anticipatory governance and the responsible development and deployment of AI technologies. Further research is needed to address these potential problems and shortcomings.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-01</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.18028v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.18028v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.18028v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.18028v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>22355</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Supporting_Anticipatory_Governance_using_LLMs_Evaluating_and_Aligning_Large_Language_Models_with_the_News_Media_to_Anticipate_the_Negative_Impacts_of_AI/2024-01-31-Supporting_Anticipatory_Governance_using_LLMs_Evaluating_and_Aligning_Large_Language_Models_with_the_News_Media_to_Anticipate_the_Negative_Impacts_of_AI.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>KVQuant: Towards 10 Million Context Length LLM Inference with KV Cache Quantization</title>
  <dc:creator>Coleman Hooper, Sehoon Kim, Hiva Mohammadzadeh, Michael W. Mahoney, Yakun Sophia Shao, Kurt Keutzer, Amir Gholami</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/KVQuant_Towards_10_Million_Context_Length_LLM_Inference_with_KV_Cache_Quantization/2024-01-31-KVQuant_Towards_10_Million_Context_Length_LLM_Inference_with_KV_Cache_Quantization.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/KVQuant_Towards_10_Million_Context_Length_LLM_Inference_with_KV_Cache_Quantization/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="overall-summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="overall-summary">Overall Summary:</h3>
<p>The academic article explores various methods and techniques for quantizing and compressing Key and Value (KV) cache activations in large language models (LLMs) to enable efficient long-sequence length inference. It introduces the Per-Channel Key Quantization method, which significantly improves the quantization of cached Key activations, resulting in a 3.88 perplexity improvement on Wikitext-2 for 3-bit LLaMA-7B quantization. The article also discusses the challenges of caching Key vectors after applying Relative Positional Encoding (RoPE) and proposes pre-RoPE Key quantization as a solution. Additionally, it presents the nuqX datatype for non-uniform KV cache quantization and explores the benefits of per-channel and per-token quantization. The article also delves into the mathematical formulation and practical implementation of the RoPE embedding, the distribution of the magnitude of elements in Keys and Value activations, and the quantization error for 2-bit quantization with and without Q-Norm. Furthermore, it evaluates the LongLoRA model on the Wikitext-2 dataset using 2-bit quantization with varying amounts of input context, highlighting the advantages of mixed-precision quantization for memory reduction and perplexity evaluation.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Per-Channel Key Quantization significantly improves the quantization of cached Key activations, resulting in a 3.88 perplexity improvement on Wikitext-2 for 3-bit LLaMA-7B quantization.</li>
<li>Pre-RoPE Key quantization addresses the challenges of caching Key vectors after applying RoPE, leading to improved perplexity for 3-bit LLaMA-7B quantization.</li>
<li>The use of Q-Norm improves quantization error, especially for later layers, and the calibration step does not require a large number of samples to attain high accuracy.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article provides valuable insights into the development of efficient methods for compressing the KV cache to enable efficient long-sequence length inference in large language models. However, it would benefit from further exploration of the practical implementation challenges and potential trade-offs associated with the proposed quantization methods. Additionally, the article could address the generalizability of the findings to other language models and datasets, as well as the potential impact on real-world applications of natural language processing tasks. Further research is needed to validate the scalability and robustness of the proposed methods across different LLM architectures and datasets.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-01</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.18079v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.18079v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.18079v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.18079v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>25178</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/KVQuant_Towards_10_Million_Context_Length_LLM_Inference_with_KV_Cache_Quantization/2024-01-31-KVQuant_Towards_10_Million_Context_Length_LLM_Inference_with_KV_Cache_Quantization.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Contextual Feature Extraction Hierarchies Converge in Large Language Models and the Brain</title>
  <dc:creator>Gavin Mischler, Yinghao Aaron Li, Stephan Bickel, Ashesh D. Mehta, Nima Mesgarani</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Contextual_Feature_Extraction_Hierarchies_Converge_in_Large_Language_Models_and_the_Brain/2024-01-31-Contextual_Feature_Extraction_Hierarchies_Converge_in_Large_Language_Models_and_the_Brain.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Contextual_Feature_Extraction_Hierarchies_Converge_in_Large_Language_Models_and_the_Brain/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="overall-summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="overall-summary">Overall Summary:</h3>
<p>The article investigates the alignment between large language models (LLMs) and the human brain’s language processing mechanisms. It explores the impact of contextual information on brain similarity, evidence of a predictive coding hierarchy in the human brain when listening to speech, and provides visual representations of the data and analyses.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Higher-performing LLMs achieved higher brain similarity scores.</li>
<li>Contextual information significantly improved similarity scores with electrodes in higher-level language processing areas.</li>
<li>Evidence supports the existence of a predictive coding hierarchy in the human brain when listening to speech.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The findings of the study provide valuable insights into the convergence of LLMs with the brain’s language processing mechanisms, highlighting the significance of contextual information in enabling brain hierarchy alignment in LLMs. The evidence of a predictive coding hierarchy in the human brain when listening to speech has implications for understanding language comprehension and the development of neural models for speech processing. The visual representations in the supplementary figures enhance the comprehensibility and interpretability of the research outcomes. However, potential limitations or methodological issues were not discussed in the individual section summaries, and further research may be needed to address these aspects.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-01</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17671v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17671v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17671v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17671v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>15192</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Contextual_Feature_Extraction_Hierarchies_Converge_in_Large_Language_Models_and_the_Brain/2024-01-31-Contextual_Feature_Extraction_Hierarchies_Converge_in_Large_Language_Models_and_the_Brain.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Do Language Models Exhibit the Same Cognitive Biases in Problem Solving as Human Learners?</title>
  <dc:creator>Andreas Opedal, Alessandro Stolfo, Haruki Shirakami, Ying Jiao, Ryan Cotterell, Bernhard Schölkopf, Abulhair Saparov, Mrinmaya Sachan</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Do_Language_Models_Exhibit_the_Same_Cognitive_Biases_in_Problem_Solving_as_Human_Learners/2024-01-31-Do_Language_Models_Exhibit_the_Same_Cognitive_Biases_in_Problem_Solving_as_Human_Learners.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Do_Language_Models_Exhibit_the_Same_Cognitive_Biases_in_Problem_Solving_as_Human_Learners/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="overall-summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="overall-summary">Overall Summary:</h3>
<p>The article explores the cognitive modeling of the problem-solving process, focusing on math word problems. It delves into the generation of problem structures, the performance of language models in solving transfer-type and comparison problems, and the details of linguistic error correction using GPT-3.5 Turbo. The study aims to identify biases in language models’ problem-solving capabilities and their implications for cognitive modeling.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Language models exhibit biases in solving transfer-type problems over comparison problems.</li>
<li>The process of generating problem structures and instantiating them with properties is crucial for creating math word problems.</li>
<li>Linguistic error correction using GPT-3.5 Turbo is effective in ensuring the accuracy and coherence of generated problems.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article provides a comprehensive understanding of the cognitive biases exhibited by language models in problem-solving. It highlights the importance of understanding the human problem-solving process and the implications for the development and deployment of cognitive models. The study’s findings shed light on the need for further research in this area and the potential limitations of the research methodology. The detailed evaluation of biases and error rates enhances the transparency and reliability of the study’s findings.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-01</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.18070v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.18070v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.18070v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.18070v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>18759</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Do_Language_Models_Exhibit_the_Same_Cognitive_Biases_in_Problem_Solving_as_Human_Learners/2024-01-31-Do_Language_Models_Exhibit_the_Same_Cognitive_Biases_in_Problem_Solving_as_Human_Learners.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Deductive Beam Search: Decoding Deducible Rationale for Chain-of-Thought Reasoning</title>
  <dc:creator>Tinghui Zhu, Kai Zhang, Jian Xie, Yu Su</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Deductive_Beam_Search_Decoding_Deducible_Rationale_for_Chain_of_Thought_Reasoning/2024-01-31-Deductive_Beam_Search_Decoding_Deducible_Rationale_for_Chain_of_Thought_Reasoning.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Deductive_Beam_Search_Decoding_Deducible_Rationale_for_Chain_of_Thought_Reasoning/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="overall-summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="overall-summary">Overall Summary:</h3>
<p>The article introduces Deductive Beam Search (DBS) as a method to integrate chain-of-thought (CoT) reasoning and deductive reasoning with step-wise beam search for Large Language Models (LLMs). The approach includes a verifier to verify the deducibility of a reasoning step and its premises, thus reducing error accumulation. Additionally, a scalable and labor-free data construction method is introduced to enhance the model’s verification capabilities. The proposed DBS significantly enhances the performance of LLMs across various reasoning datasets and genres. Challenges in introducing deductive reasoning into CoT reasoning are discussed, and the process of training a deductive verifier is outlined. The article also details the process of using margin ranking to model the task of providing fine-grained supervision for error detection and the methodology for improving reasoning paths generated by LLMs using DBS. Furthermore, the experimental details section outlines the training data and process for the deductive verifier, emphasizing the importance of training data and prompts in developing and evaluating reasoning capabilities.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Deductive Beam Search (DBS) significantly enhances the performance of Large Language Models (LLMs) across various reasoning datasets and genres.</li>
<li>The use of margin ranking to model the task of providing fine-grained supervision for error detection is crucial for training the general deductive verifier and detecting false reasoning steps.</li>
<li>The DBS method improves reasoning paths generated by LLMs and steadily enhances performance as the beam size increases.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The introduction of Deductive Beam Search addresses the limitations of previous methods in handling reasoning errors in intermediate steps, leading to accumulative errors. The proposed approach not only enhances the performance of LLMs but also demonstrates the capability of detecting diverse and subtle reasoning errors. The challenges and solutions presented in the article lay the foundation for the subsequent discussions on the implementation and evaluation of DBS. However, potential limitations or biases in the experimental setup and the generalizability of the findings to real-world applications should be further explored. Additionally, the article could benefit from discussing potential ethical implications of integrating deductive reasoning into machine learning models.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-01</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17686v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17686v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17686v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17686v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>15955</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Deductive_Beam_Search_Decoding_Deducible_Rationale_for_Chain_of_Thought_Reasoning/2024-01-31-Deductive_Beam_Search_Decoding_Deducible_Rationale_for_Chain_of_Thought_Reasoning.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Multipath parsing in the brain</title>
  <dc:creator>Berta Franzluebbers, Donald Dunagan, Miloš Stanojević, Jan Buys, John T. Hale</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Multipath_parsing_in_the_brain/2024-01-31-Multipath_parsing_in_the_brain.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Multipath_parsing_in_the_brain/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The study investigates how humans process syntactic ambiguities by correlating predictions from incremental generative dependency parsers with time-course data from people undergoing functional neuroimaging while listening to an audiobook. The study finds evidence for multipath parsing in both English and Chinese data, with brain regions associated with this multipath effect including bilateral superior temporal gyrus.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The study finds evidence for multipath parsing in both English and Chinese data.</li>
<li>Brain regions associated with this multipath effect include bilateral superior temporal gyrus.</li>
<li>The study compares competing hypotheses regarding the number of developing syntactic analyses in play during word-by-word comprehension and finds evidence for multipath parsing.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The study provides valuable insights into how humans process syntactic ambiguities during sentence comprehension. However, the study is limited by the particularities of the parsing system and the training data, which may affect the generalizability of the findings. Additionally, the study does not address the interaction between disambiguation and memory, which could be an important direction for future work. Further research is needed to confirm or refute the findings in other languages and genres. Additionally, using brain data with higher temporal resolution, such as MEG, may provide a benefit given the temporary nature of the syntactic ambiguities included in the model.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-01</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.18046v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.18046v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.18046v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.18046v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>13665</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Multipath_parsing_in_the_brain/2024-01-31-Multipath_parsing_in_the_brain.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Towards Efficient and Reliable LLM Serving: A Real-World Workload Study</title>
  <dc:creator>Yuxin Wang, Yuhan Chen, Zeyu Li, Zhenheng Tang, Rui Guo, Xin Wang, Qiang Wang, Amelie Chi Zhou, Xiaowen Chu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Towards_Efficient_and_Reliable_LLM_Serving_A_Real_World_Workload_Study/2024-01-31-Towards_Efficient_and_Reliable_LLM_Serving_A_Real_World_Workload_Study.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Towards_Efficient_and_Reliable_LLM_Serving_A_Real_World_Workload_Study/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<p>The article introduces BurstGPT, a real-world trace dataset of large language model (LLM) serving workloads, and analyzes the characteristics of these workloads. The study focuses on the impact of burstiness on LLM serving systems and aims to improve the reliability and performance of these systems. The authors also develop a benchmark suite based on BurstGPT to evaluate LLM serving systems.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The absence of reliable workload data for evaluating LLM serving systems impacts the quality of service (QoS) and reliability in industrial deployments.</li>
<li>BurstGPT provides insights into the characteristics of LLM serving workloads, including burstiness, request and response distributions, and the reliability of GPT services.</li>
<li>The evaluation uncovers a previously unrecognized vulnerability of LLM serving systems to short-term burstiness, particularly in common workload scenarios.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article provides a comprehensive analysis of real-world LLM serving workloads and introduces a benchmark suite based on BurstGPT to evaluate LLM serving systems. The study highlights the impact of burstiness on the reliability and performance of LLM serving systems, emphasizing the need for real-world workload data in optimizing and evaluating these systems. However, the article could benefit from a more detailed discussion of potential solutions or strategies to address the challenges identified in the study. Additionally, further research is needed to explore the practical implications of the findings and to develop effective strategies for optimizing LLM serving systems based on BurstGPT data.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-01</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17644v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17644v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17644v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17644v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>14587</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Towards_Efficient_and_Reliable_LLM_Serving_A_Real_World_Workload_Study/2024-01-31-Towards_Efficient_and_Reliable_LLM_Serving_A_Real_World_Workload_Study.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>WSC+: Enhancing The Winograd Schema Challenge Using Tree-of-Experts</title>
  <dc:creator>Pardis Sadat Zahraei, Ali Emami</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/WSC+_Enhancing_The_Winograd_Schema_Challenge_Using_Tree_of_Experts/2024-01-31-WSC+_Enhancing_The_Winograd_Schema_Challenge_Using_Tree_of_Experts.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/WSC+_Enhancing_The_Winograd_Schema_Challenge_Using_Tree_of_Experts/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="overall-summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="overall-summary">Overall Summary:</h3>
<p>The academic article introduces the WSC+ dataset as an extension of the Winograd Schema Challenge (WSC) to evaluate the common-sense reasoning capabilities of Large Language Models (LLMs). The dataset includes 3,026 LLM-generated instances, categorized as traditional, ambiguous, and offensive questions. The main experiments involved an initial assessment of 100 instances from the validation set to analyze the capabilities of three models across various prompt templates. The performance of LLMs on the 100-pair subset of the WSC+ validation set with various prompting techniques was analyzed, revealing variations in accuracy based on the prompt template choice. Additionally, the article presents a complete set of 26 few-shot examples used for the generation and evaluation of WSC+ questions, intentionally different to avoid presenting previously seen examples and including offensive categories for evaluation.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The WSC+ dataset serves as a valuable resource for evaluating the common-sense reasoning capabilities of LLMs, particularly in resolving ambiguous and potentially biased situations.</li>
<li>The performance of LLMs varied based on prompt template choice, highlighting the influence of prompt strategies and variations in accuracy across different instance types.</li>
<li>The intentional selection of diverse few-shot examples for the generation and evaluation of WSC+ questions ensures a comprehensive and robust evaluation process.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article provides valuable insights into the biases exhibited by large language models, the influence of prompt strategies on model performance, and the intentional selection of diverse examples for evaluation. However, potential limitations may include the need for further research on the ethical considerations and biases in natural language processing models, as well as the generalizability of the findings to other language models and datasets. Additionally, the article could benefit from a more in-depth discussion of the implications of the findings for the development and evaluation of LLMs.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-01</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17703v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17703v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17703v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17703v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>17528</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/WSC+_Enhancing_The_Winograd_Schema_Challenge_Using_Tree_of_Experts/2024-01-31-WSC+_Enhancing_The_Winograd_Schema_Challenge_Using_Tree_of_Experts.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Enhancing Large Language Model with Decomposed Reasoning for Emotion Cause Pair Extraction</title>
  <dc:creator>Jialiang Wu, Yi Shen, Ziheng Zhang, Longjun Cai</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Enhancing_Large_Language_Model_with_Decomposed_Reasoning_for_Emotion_Cause_Pair_Extraction/2024-01-31-Enhancing_Large_Language_Model_with_Decomposed_Reasoning_for_Emotion_Cause_Pair_Extraction.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Enhancing_Large_Language_Model_with_Decomposed_Reasoning_for_Emotion_Cause_Pair_Extraction/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17716v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<p>The article introduces the Decomposed Emotion-Cause Chain (DECC) framework, which leverages large language models (LLMs) to address the Emotion-Cause Pair Extraction (ECPE) task. The DECC framework aims to guide LLMs to tackle the ECPE task by inducing inference and logical pruning, mimicking human cognitive processes. The article presents experiment results demonstrating the strength of DECC compared to state-of-the-art supervised fine-tuning methods. It also analyzes the effectiveness of each component and the robustness of the method in various scenarios, including different LLM bases, rebalanced datasets, and multi-pair extraction.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The DECC framework significantly enhances the reasoning ability of large language models on the ECPE task, resulting in improved precision and recall compared to naive prompting methods.</li>
<li>DECC demonstrates robust performance across different LLMs and datasets, including traditional benchmark datasets and rebalanced datasets, showcasing its generalizing ability.</li>
<li>The DECC framework outperforms state-of-the-art supervised fine-tuning methods, especially on multi-pair extraction scenarios, indicating its compatibility with both multi-pair and single-pair extraction scenarios.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The DECC framework presents a novel approach to addressing the ECPE task by decomposing it into a series of sub-problems and solving them in sequence. The article provides comprehensive experimental results and analysis, demonstrating the effectiveness and robustness of DECC. However, the article acknowledges that DECC may increase the inference time of large language models and did not test DECC on GPT4 due to cost constraints. Additionally, the article highlights the limitations of current benchmark datasets and the potential for further research in efficient and robust demonstration selection methods to enhance DECC’s performance. Overall, the article provides valuable insights into leveraging large language models for emotion-cause pair extraction and opens avenues for future research in this area.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-01</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17716v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17716v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17716v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17716v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6121</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Enhancing_Large_Language_Model_with_Decomposed_Reasoning_for_Emotion_Cause_Pair_Extraction/2024-01-31-Enhancing_Large_Language_Model_with_Decomposed_Reasoning_for_Emotion_Cause_Pair_Extraction.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17716v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>ReSLLM: Large Language Models are Strong Resource Selectors for Federated Search</title>
  <dc:creator>Shuai Wang, Shengyao Zhuang, Bevan Koopman, Guido Zuccon</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ReSLLM_Large_Language_Models_are_Strong_Resource_Selectors_for_Federated_Search/2024-01-31-ReSLLM_Large_Language_Models_are_Strong_Resource_Selectors_for_Federated_Search.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ReSLLM_Large_Language_Models_are_Strong_Resource_Selectors_for_Federated_Search/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17645v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<p>The article discusses the use of Large Language Models (LLMs) for resource selection in federated search. It introduces ReSLLM, a zero-shot LLM-based method for resource selection, and the Synthetic Label Augmentation Tuning (SLAT) protocol, a fine-tuning approach that leverages LLM-generated synthetic labels. The study demonstrates that both ReSLLM and SLAT+ReSLLM can effectively select resources in a federated search environment, outperforming several baseline methods and matching the efficacy of supervised models in certain scenarios.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>ReSLLM Method:</strong> ReSLLM is a zero-shot LLM-based method for resource selection that operates without the need for human-labeled data.</li>
<li><strong>SLAT Protocol:</strong> The Synthetic Label Augmentation Tuning (SLAT) protocol is a fine-tuning approach that leverages LLM-generated synthetic labels, providing an effective means of tuning ReSLLM without human intervention.</li>
<li><strong>Effectiveness:</strong> Both ReSLLM and SLAT+ReSLLM can effectively select resources in a federated search environment, outperforming several baseline methods and matching the efficacy of supervised models in certain scenarios.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<p>The study demonstrates the potential benefits of using LLMs for resource selection in federated search. It highlights the effectiveness of ReSLLM and SLAT+ReSLLM, especially in scenarios where human-annotated data is limited or unavailable. The study also identifies the impact of LLM size, architecture, and resource representation on the effectiveness of resource selection. However, the study acknowledges limitations in fine-tuning for conversational queries and the need for further research in this area. Overall, the article provides valuable insights into the use of LLMs for resource selection and highlights the potential for future research in this domain.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-01</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17645v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17645v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17645v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17645v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>10157</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ReSLLM_Large_Language_Models_are_Strong_Resource_Selectors_for_Federated_Search/2024-01-31-ReSLLM_Large_Language_Models_are_Strong_Resource_Selectors_for_Federated_Search.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17645v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Evaluating the Effectiveness of GPT-4 Turbo in Creating Defeaters for Assurance Cases</title>
  <dc:creator>Kimya Khakzad Shahandashti, Mithila Sivakumar, Mohammad Mahdi Mohajer, Alvine B. Belle, Song Wang, Timothy C. Lethbridge</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Evaluating_the_Effectiveness_of_GPT_4_Turbo_in_Creating_Defeaters_for_Assurance_Cases/2024-01-31-Evaluating_the_Effectiveness_of_GPT_4_Turbo_in_Creating_Defeaters_for_Assurance_Cases.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Evaluating_the_Effectiveness_of_GPT_4_Turbo_in_Creating_Defeaters_for_Assurance_Cases/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<p>The article evaluates the effectiveness of GPT-4 Turbo in creating defeaters for assurance cases, which are structured arguments used to verify the correct implementation of non-functional requirements in systems. The study proposes a novel approach using GPT-4 Turbo to identify defeaters within assurance cases formalized using Eliminative Argumentation (EA) notation. The preliminary evaluation shows that GPT-4 Turbo is proficient in understanding and generating arguments in this context.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>GPT-4 Turbo is proficient in understanding and generating arguments in EA notation.</li>
<li>The model is capable of generating different types of defeaters within assurance cases.</li>
<li>GPT-4 Turbo shows strong proficiency in creating EA elements, particularly various types of defeaters.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<p>The preliminary study reveals that GPT-4 Turbo demonstrates excellent proficiency in understanding and applying EA notation, particularly in generating different types of defeaters within assurance cases. However, the model’s understanding of the semantics of EA elements was found to be less robust. This suggests the need for specific prompting techniques to enhance its comprehension of EA semantics. Overall, the study highlights the potential of GPT-4 Turbo as a valuable tool for identifying and mitigating defeaters within assurance cases, particularly in mission-critical systems. However, further research is needed to enhance the model’s semantic understanding and to validate its effectiveness in identifying and mitigating defeaters in real-world scenarios.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-01</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17991v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17991v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17991v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17991v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7310</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Evaluating_the_Effectiveness_of_GPT_4_Turbo_in_Creating_Defeaters_for_Assurance_Cases/2024-01-31-Evaluating_the_Effectiveness_of_GPT_4_Turbo_in_Creating_Defeaters_for_Assurance_Cases.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Probing Language Models’ Gesture Understanding for Enhanced Human-AI Interaction</title>
  <dc:creator>Philipp Wicke</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Probing_Language_Models_Gesture_Understanding_for_Enhanced_Human_AI_Interaction/2024-01-31-Probing_Language_Models_Gesture_Understanding_for_Enhanced_Human_AI_Interaction.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Probing_Language_Models_Gesture_Understanding_for_Enhanced_Human_AI_Interaction/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17858v1/extracted/5380014/images/page01.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<p>The proposal aims to investigate the interaction between Large Language Models (LLMs) and non-verbal communication, specifically focusing on gestures. It sets out a plan to examine the proficiency of LLMs in deciphering both explicit and implicit non-verbal cues within textual prompts and their ability to associate these gestures with various contextual factors. The research proposes to test established psycholinguistic study designs to construct a comprehensive dataset that pairs textual prompts with detailed gesture descriptions, encompassing diverse regional variations, and semantic labels. To assess LLMs’ comprehension of gestures, experiments are planned, evaluating their ability to simulate human behavior in order to replicate psycholinguistic experiments. These experiments consider cultural dimensions and measure the agreement between LLM-identified gestures and the dataset, shedding light on the models’ contextual interpretation of non-verbal cues (e.g.&nbsp;gestures).</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The proposal aims to investigate the proficiency of LLMs in deciphering both explicit and implicit non-verbal cues within textual prompts and their ability to associate these gestures with various contextual factors.</li>
<li>The research proposes to test established psycholinguistic study designs to construct a comprehensive dataset that pairs textual prompts with detailed gesture descriptions, encompassing diverse regional variations, and semantic labels.</li>
<li>Experiments are planned to evaluate LLMs’ ability to simulate human behavior and replicate psycholinguistic experiments, considering cultural dimensions and measuring the agreement between LLM-identified gestures and the dataset.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The proposal presents a comprehensive plan to investigate the interaction between LLMs and non-verbal communication, particularly focusing on gestures. However, it is important to note that the research has not been conducted, and the strengths and weaknesses outlined are based on anticipated outcomes. The reliance on open-source models may introduce limitations in terms of model complexity compared to proprietary counterparts like GPT-3, raising questions about the generalizability of the findings to models with different architectures and scales. Future research directions could include extending the study to multimodal models and exploring the impact of gesture-based communication on user experience and engagement with conversational AI systems.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-01</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17858v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17858v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17858v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17858v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>3310</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>programming</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Probing_Language_Models_Gesture_Understanding_for_Enhanced_Human_AI_Interaction/2024-01-31-Probing_Language_Models_Gesture_Understanding_for_Enhanced_Human_AI_Interaction.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17858v1/extracted/5380014/images/page01.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Paramanu: A Family of Novel Efficient Indic Generative Foundation Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Mitodru Niyogi, Arnab Bhattacharya</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Paramanu_A_Family_of_Novel_Efficient_Indic_Generative_Foundation_Language_Models/2024-01-31-Paramanu_A_Family_of_Novel_Efficient_Indic_Generative_Foundation_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Paramanu_A_Family_of_Novel_Efficient_Indic_Generative_Foundation_Language_Models/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>Thank you for providing the individual section summaries. Based on the information provided, here is the structured summary of the academic articles:</p>
<section id="overall-summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="overall-summary">Overall Summary:</h3>
<p>The first article discusses the development and evaluation of Gyan AI Paramanu, a family of novel language models for Indian languages. It covers data cleaning and pre-processing, evaluation of language models for Sanskrit text generation, human evaluation results for open-end text generation, and the writing skills of the Bangla model. The article also highlights the Paramanu models’ inference speed, open-end text generation performance, and future work.</p>
<p>The second article covers a range of topics, including the concept of devotion and spiritual connection, the financial performance of the film “Don” featuring Shah Rukh Khan, the controversies surrounding the actor, and the enduring legacy of Mahatma Gandhi. It delves into the philosophical and spiritual aspects of devotion, the influence of celebrity star power on film earnings, the public’s fascination with celebrity controversies, and the ongoing relevance of Gandhi’s principles in Indian society.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><p>The Gyan AI Paramanu language models demonstrate efficient and powerful performance for Indian languages, outperforming larger language models.</p></li>
<li><p>The mParamanu-162M model exhibits superior text generation capabilities for Sanskrit, addressing the limitations of existing language models for less commonly studied languages.</p></li>
<li><p>The Bangla model showcases diverse writing capabilities, despite its relatively small size, and is the first of its kind exclusively pretrained on Bangla corpus.</p></li>
<li><p>The essence of devotion lies in the devotee’s feelings and spiritual connection with the divine, as highlighted in the Vedas.</p></li>
<li><p>The financial success of the film “Don” is influenced by Shah Rukh Khan’s fan base and star power.</p></li>
<li><p>Mahatma Gandhi’s principles continue to have a lasting impact on Indian society and politics, even after his death.</p></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The first article’s strengths lie in addressing the need for high-quality language models for Indian languages, the development of efficient and powerful models, and the evaluation of text generation capabilities. However, the article could benefit from further context and explanation of the presented text generations. Additionally, the article’s focus on Indian languages and the planned release of API access indicate potential widespread impact. Further research is needed to address limitations and scale up the models for broader applications and evaluation on new benchmarks.</p>
<p>The second article provides valuable insights into the philosophical, financial, and historical aspects of devotion, celebrity influence on film success, and the enduring legacy of Mahatma Gandhi. However, the inclusion of text in different languages may pose challenges for readers who are not familiar with those languages. Additionally, further research could explore the contemporary relevance of devotion and the impact of celebrity controversies on public perception.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-01</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.18034v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.18034v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.18034v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.18034v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>100343</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Paramanu_A_Family_of_Novel_Efficient_Indic_Generative_Foundation_Language_Models/2024-01-31-Paramanu_A_Family_of_Novel_Efficient_Indic_Generative_Foundation_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>I Think, Therefore I am: Awareness in Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Yuan Li, Yue Huang, Yuli Lin, Siyuan Wu, Yao Wan, Lichao Sun</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/I_Think_Therefore_I_am_Awareness_in_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-31-I_Think_Therefore_I_am_Awareness_in_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/I_Think_Therefore_I_am_Awareness_in_Large_Language_Models/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<p>In “I Think, Therefore I am: Awareness in Large Language Models,” the authors introduce the concept of awareness to large language models (LLMs) and argue that it is essential for LLMs to enhance their interaction with humans and ensure ethical responses. They define awareness in LLMs as the ability to perceive and understand themselves as AI models and to exhibit social intelligence. The authors identify four key dimensions of awareness: capability, mission, emotion, and perspective. To assess LLMs on these dimensions, they introduce a specialized dataset, AWARELLM dataset. The findings reveal that LLMs demonstrate a decent degree of awareness, though they still lack substantial capability awareness.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs demonstrate a decent degree of awareness, though they still lack substantial capability awareness.</li>
<li>The dataset and code for assessing LLMs on awareness dimensions are available at https://github.com/HowieHwong/Awareness-in-LLM.</li>
<li>The study emphasizes the importance of awareness in LLMs for enhancing their interaction with humans and ensuring ethical responses.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article provides valuable insights into the concept of awareness in LLMs and introduces a specialized dataset for assessing LLMs on different dimensions of awareness. However, the study has limitations in terms of the performance of LLMs on capability awareness, which indicates a need for further research and improvement in this area. Additionally, the study focuses on the positive aspects of awareness in LLMs and does not thoroughly address potential biases or limitations in the assessment of LLMs’ awareness. Further research is needed to address these shortcomings and provide a more comprehensive understanding of awareness in LLMs.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-01</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17882v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17882v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17882v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17882v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>11352</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/I_Think_Therefore_I_am_Awareness_in_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-31-I_Think_Therefore_I_am_Awareness_in_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Generative AI to Generate Test Data Generators</title>
  <dc:creator>Benoit Baudry, Khashayar Etemadi, Sen Fang, Yogya Gamage, Yi Liu, Yuxin Liu, Martin Monperrus, Javier Ron, André Silva, Deepika Tiwari</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Generative_AI_to_Generate_Test_Data_Generators/2024-01-31-Generative_AI_to_Generate_Test_Data_Generators.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Generative_AI_to_Generate_Test_Data_Generators/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<p>The article discusses the use of Large Language Models (LLMs) to generate fake test data for software testing. It highlights the challenges of generating realistic test data and the potential of LLMs to address these challenges. The authors present a study where they prompt LLMs to generate test data and evaluate the results based on domain adequacy, executability, and compatibility with existing faking libraries.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Domain Adequacy:</strong>
<ul>
<li>LLMs are able to generate high-quality test data that is appropriate for the specified application domain.</li>
<li>The study shows strong domain adequacy for high-resource languages such as Chinese, French, Hindi, Portuguese, and Spanish.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Executability:</strong>
<ul>
<li>LLMs are capable of synthesizing executable code that generates fake data, including data constraints related to cultural contexts such as wine-pairing conventions in Portuguese cuisine.</li>
<li>The study demonstrates the successful execution of LLM-generated code for generating Farsi poetry in right-to-left script.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Compatibility with Existing Faking Libraries:</strong>
<ul>
<li>LLMs can generate new fakers that are directly interoperable with existing test suites, as demonstrated by the successful integration of an LLM-generated faker into a mature Java project’s test suite.</li>
<li>The study shows that LLM-generated fakers can seamlessly replace conventional fakers in real-world test suites.</li>
</ul></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article provides valuable insights into the potential of LLMs for generating test data, addressing the challenges of domain adequacy, executability, and compatibility with existing faking libraries. However, the study primarily focuses on high-resource languages, and the limitations of LLMs for low-resource languages are acknowledged. Additionally, the article could benefit from discussing potential ethical considerations and biases associated with using LLMs for generating culturally relevant test data. Further research is needed to explore the generalizability of the findings to a wider range of application domains and cultural contexts.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-01</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17626v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17626v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17626v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.17626v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>9452</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Generative_AI_to_Generate_Test_Data_Generators/2024-01-31-Generative_AI_to_Generate_Test_Data_Generators.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Prompt-Driven LLM Safeguarding via Directed Representation Optimization</title>
  <dc:creator>Chujie Zheng, Fan Yin, Hao Zhou, Fandong Meng, Jie Zhou, Kai-Wei Chang, Minlie Huang, Nanyun Peng</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Prompt_Driven_LLM_Safeguarding_via_Directed_Representation_Optimization/2024-01-31-Prompt_Driven_LLM_Safeguarding_via_Directed_Representation_Optimization.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Prompt_Driven_LLM_Safeguarding_via_Directed_Representation_Optimization/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="overall-summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="overall-summary">Overall Summary:</h3>
<p>The article investigates the impact of safety prompts on large language models (LLMs) and proposes a method called Directed Representation Optimization (DRO) for automatic safety prompt optimization. The study finds that safety prompts do not significantly enhance the distinction between harmful and harmless queries in the models’ representation space. However, the DRO method shows promising results in improving LLM safety by optimizing safety prompts. The paper also discusses previous research on LLM safety and prompt optimization, providing important context for the proposed method. Visualization results and interpretability analysis are presented to demonstrate the effectiveness of safety prompts and the impact of DRO on model representations.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Safety prompts do not noticeably enhance the distinction between harmful and harmless queries in LLMs’ representation space.</li>
<li>Directed Representation Optimization (DRO) offers a promising solution for automatically optimizing safety prompts and improving LLM safety.</li>
<li>The proposed DRO method outperforms strong baselines and has implications for enhancing the safety and reliability of LLMs in real-world applications.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The findings of the article provide valuable insights into the intrinsic working mechanisms of prompt-driven LLM safeguarding and the potential of the DRO method for optimizing safety prompts. However, the visualization results suggest that safety prompts may not be as effective in distinguishing between harmful and harmless queries as initially anticipated. Additionally, while the DRO method shows promising results, further research is needed to address potential limitations and ensure the robustness of LLM safety. The interpretability analysis contributes to a better understanding of the impact of DRO on model representations and the variations in optimized safety prompts across different models. Overall, the article makes a significant contribution to the field of LLM safety and prompts optimization, but further research is required to address potential shortcomings and ensure the practical applicability of the proposed method.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-01</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.18018v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.18018v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.18018v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.18018v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>21383</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Prompt_Driven_LLM_Safeguarding_via_Directed_Representation_Optimization/2024-01-31-Prompt_Driven_LLM_Safeguarding_via_Directed_Representation_Optimization.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>EEG-GPT: Exploring Capabilities of Large Language Models for EEG Classification and Interpretation</title>
  <dc:creator>Jonathan W. Kim, Ahmed Alaa, Danilo Bernardo</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/EEG_GPT_Exploring_Capabilities_of_Large_Language_Models_for_EEG_Classification_and_Interpretation/2024-01-31-EEG_GPT_Exploring_Capabilities_of_Large_Language_Models_for_EEG_Classification_and_Interpretation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/EEG_GPT_Exploring_Capabilities_of_Large_Language_Models_for_EEG_Classification_and_Interpretation/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<p>The article introduces EEG-GPT, a new approach to EEG classification that leverages large language models (LLMs) to achieve multi-scale electrophysiological understanding and classification capabilities. The proposed method demonstrates excellent performance in classifying normal from abnormal EEG, utilizing only 2% of training data. Furthermore, it offers transparent and interpretable reasoning steps, promoting trustworthiness in clinical contexts.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>EEG-GPT achieves excellent performance comparable to current state-of-the-art deep learning methods in classifying normal from abnormal EEG in a few-shot learning paradigm utilizing only 2% of training data.</li>
<li>The approach provides intermediate reasoning steps and coordinates specialist EEG tools across multiple scales, offering transparent and interpretable step-by-step verification, thereby promoting trustworthiness in clinical contexts.</li>
<li>LLMs demonstrate the ability to plan and carry out intermediate reasoning steps when asked to solve complex problems, as well as synergize inputs from other computational “experts” to solve complex tasks.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article presents a promising approach for EEG interpretation and classification using LLMs. However, it is crucial to address the limitations of LLMs, such as their tendency to generate non-factual or “hallucinated” information, which limits their reliability and trustworthiness in clinical settings. Future work should focus on further optimizing performance, evaluating reasoning capabilities, and addressing the potential failure modes of LLMs. Additionally, a step-by-step verifiability with human oversight is recommended to enhance the reliability and interpretability of LLMs in clinical applications.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-01</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.18006v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.18006v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.18006v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.18006v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5965</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/EEG_GPT_Exploring_Capabilities_of_Large_Language_Models_for_EEG_Classification_and_Interpretation/2024-01-31-EEG_GPT_Exploring_Capabilities_of_Large_Language_Models_for_EEG_Classification_and_Interpretation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
