<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Bayesian beagle</title>
<link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Quarto blog of LLM-generated summaries of Arxiv preprints</description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.450</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Why Are My Prompts Leaked? Unraveling Prompt Extraction Threats in Customized Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Zi Liang, Haibo Hu, Qingqing Ye, Yaxin Xiao, Haoyang Li</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Why_Are_My_Prompts_Leaked_Unraveling_Prompt_Extraction_Threats_in_Customized_Large_Language_Models/2024-08-05-Why_Are_My_Prompts_Leaked_Unraveling_Prompt_Extraction_Threats_in_Customized_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Why_Are_My_Prompts_Leaked_Unraveling_Prompt_Extraction_Threats_in_Customized_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02416v1/x2.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level1">
<h1>Summary:</h1>
<p>The paper “Why Are My Prompts Leaked? Unraveling Prompt Extraction Threats in Customized Large Language Models” explores the issue of prompt leakage in customized large language models (LLMs). The authors investigate the factors that influence prompt leakage, including model sizes, prompt lengths, and types of prompts. They propose two hypotheses to explain how LLMs expose their prompts: perplexity (familiarity of LLMs to texts) and straightforward token translation paths in attention matrices. The authors also evaluate the effectiveness of alignments in defending against prompt extraction attacks (PEA) and propose several defense strategies.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Scaling Laws in Prompt Extraction</strong>: The authors analyze the scaling laws in prompt extraction and find that larger LLMs exhibit similar extraction rates to smaller LLMs under explicit intent-based attacks. However, larger LLMs are more vulnerable to implicit attacks.</li>
<li><strong>Prompt Memorization</strong>: The authors observe that LLMs can memorize and transcribe some long prompts accurately and verbatim, a phenomenon they refer to as prompt memorization. This occurs due to the perplexity of prompts and the parallel translation of prompts in attention matrices.</li>
<li><strong>Defense Strategies</strong>: The authors propose several defense strategies against PEA, including alignments and prompt engineering-based methods. They find that these methods can significantly reduce the prompt extraction rate for Llama2-7B and GPT-3.5.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h2>
<p>The paper provides a comprehensive analysis of prompt extraction threats in customized LLMs and proposes several defense strategies. However, the paper does not discuss the potential impact of prompt leakage on the performance of LLMs or the potential risks associated with using leaked prompts. Additionally, the paper does not provide a detailed comparison of the proposed defense strategies with existing methods.</p>
<p>Further research is needed to evaluate the effectiveness of the proposed defense strategies in real-world scenarios and to explore the potential risks associated with prompt leakage. Additionally, future work could focus on developing more robust defense strategies that can effectively prevent prompt leakage in customized LLMs.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02416v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02416v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02416v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02416v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>10615</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Why_Are_My_Prompts_Leaked_Unraveling_Prompt_Extraction_Threats_in_Customized_Large_Language_Models/2024-08-05-Why_Are_My_Prompts_Leaked_Unraveling_Prompt_Extraction_Threats_in_Customized_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02416v1/x2.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>SpecRover: Code Intent Extraction via LLMs</title>
  <dc:creator>Haifeng Ruan, Yuntong Zhang, Abhik Roychoudhury</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SpecRover_Code_Intent_Extraction_via_LLMs/2024-08-05-SpecRover_Code_Intent_Extraction_via_LLMs.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SpecRover_Code_Intent_Extraction_via_LLMs/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02232v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper presents SpecRover, an LLM-guided autonomous software engineering workflow that focuses on the role of program specifications in iterative specification inference. The goal is to automatically derive a patch for a software codebase based on a natural language problem description. SpecRover conducts code search guided by program structure and calculates specifications of the classes/methods to capture intended program behavior. The specifications are then deposited along with generated tests to a reviewer agent, which studies the specifications, generated tests, and natural language requirements to guide the patching. The reviewer agent also produces evidence of confidence in the reported patch.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>SpecRover shows more than 50% improvement in efficacy over AutoCodeRover in resolving GitHub issues in the full SWE-Bench.</li>
<li>SpecRover demonstrates modest cost ($0.65 per issue) in resolving an average GitHub issue in SWE-Bench lite compared to open-source agents available.</li>
<li>The production of explanation by SpecRover allows for a better “signal” to be given to the developer, on when the suggested patches can be accepted with confidence.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper does not provide a detailed comparison of SpecRover with other state-of-the-art systems that target the repository-level issue solving task.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the limitations and potential biases of the proposed approach, such as the reliance on the quality of the input issue statement and the potential for overfitting to the specific codebase.</li>
<li>The paper does not provide a clear evaluation of the scalability and generalizability of SpecRover to other programming languages and domains.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential ethical implications of using LLMs for automated program repair, such as the potential for introducing new vulnerabilities or perpetuating existing biases in the codebase.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02232v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02232v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02232v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02232v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>10030</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>programming</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SpecRover_Code_Intent_Extraction_via_LLMs/2024-08-05-SpecRover_Code_Intent_Extraction_via_LLMs.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02232v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Long Input Benchmark for Russian Analysis</title>
  <dc:creator>Igor Churin, Murat Apishev, Maria Tikhonova, Denis Shevelev, Aydar Bulatov, Yuri Kuratov, Sergej Averkiev, Alena Fenogenova</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Long_Input_Benchmark_for_Russian_Analysis/2024-08-05-Long_Input_Benchmark_for_Russian_Analysis.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/../bayesian-beagle.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level1">
<h1>Summary:</h1>
<p><strong>Summary:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The paper introduces LIBRA, a new benchmark for long context understanding in Russian, which includes 21 tasks for LLM evaluation.</li>
<li>LIBRA aims to evaluate a large scope of LLMs, including pretrain models and models with supervised finetuning (SFT) with any system prompt.</li>
<li>The tasks in LIBRA are divided into 4 complexity groups, and the datasets have several subsets of various context lengths ranging from 4k up to 128k tokens.</li>
<li>The main purpose of the benchmark is to create a reliable instrument for the long context understanding evaluation, enabling the study of the model’s ability to solve various tasks of different complexity with respect to the input context length.</li>
<li>The paper also presents a methodology for the evaluation of long-context abilities of LLMs for the Russian language and publicly releases a set of 21 datasets of various skills and complexities in Russian which form the LIBRA benchmark.</li>
<li>The paper also provides a codebase and public leaderboard for LIBRA to guide forthcoming research.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Major Findings:</strong></p>
<ol type="1">
<li>LIBRA is a new benchmark for long context understanding in Russian, which includes 21 tasks for LLM evaluation.</li>
<li>The tasks in LIBRA are divided into 4 complexity groups, and the datasets have several subsets of various context lengths ranging from 4k up to 128k tokens.</li>
<li>The main purpose of the benchmark is to create a reliable instrument for the long context understanding evaluation, enabling the study of the model’s ability to solve various tasks of different complexity with respect to the input context length.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The paper presents a new benchmark for long context understanding in Russian, which is a significant contribution to the field.</li>
<li>The division of tasks into 4 complexity groups and the use of datasets with various context lengths ranging from 4k up to 128k tokens is a well-thought-out approach to evaluate the model’s ability to solve various tasks of different complexity with respect to the input context length.</li>
<li>The paper also provides a codebase and public leaderboard for LIBRA, which is a valuable resource for researchers and practitioners in the field.</li>
<li>However, the</li>
</ul>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02439v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02439v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02439v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02439v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8590</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Long_Input_Benchmark_for_Russian_Analysis/2024-08-05-Long_Input_Benchmark_for_Russian_Analysis.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Is Large Language Model Good at Database Knob Tuning? A Comprehensive Experimental Evaluation</title>
  <dc:creator>Yiyan Li, Haoyang Li, Zhao Pu, Jing Zhang, Xinyi Zhang, Tao Ji, Luming Sun, Cuiping Li, Hong Chen</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Is_Large_Language_Model_Good_at_Database_Knob_Tuning_A_Comprehensive_Experimental_Evaluation/2024-08-05-Is_Large_Language_Model_Good_at_Database_Knob_Tuning_A_Comprehensive_Experimental_Evaluation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/../bayesian-beagle.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study compares the performance of different large language models (LLMs) in knob tuning tasks, focusing on ChatGPT-3.5, ChatGPT-4, Kimi, and LLaMA.</li>
<li>The models are categorized based on scale (tens of billions vs.&nbsp;hundreds of billions of parameters) and usage (publicly accessible vs.&nbsp;closed-source).</li>
<li>The results show that GPT-4 outperforms other models, with better performance attributed to its larger scale, comprehensive corpus, and stronger ability to solve complex tasks.</li>
<li>The study also finds that closed-source LLMs generally perform better than open-source models, and larger models tend to have better performance.</li>
<li>The superior performance of closed-source models is attributed to factors such as more abundant and high-quality corpus, sufficient resources for training, and high-quality human feedback for fine-tuning.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>GPT-4 outperforms other LLMs in knob tuning tasks</strong>: The study shows that GPT-4 achieves the best results among all tested models, with its larger scale, comprehensive corpus, and strong ability to solve complex tasks contributing to its superior performance.</li>
<li><strong>Closed-source LLMs outperform open-source models</strong>: The study finds that closed-source models, such as GPT-4, generally perform better than open-source models, with factors such as more abundant and high-quality corpus, sufficient resources for training, and high-quality human feedback for fine-tuning contributing to their superior performance.</li>
<li><strong>Larger models tend to have better performance</strong>: The study finds that larger LLMs, such as GPT-4, tend to have better performance than smaller models, with the number of parameters in the model being a significant factor in determining its performance.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study provides valuable insights into the performance of different LLMs in knob tuning tasks, highlighting the superior performance of GPT-4 and the advantages of closed-source models.</li>
<li>However, the study does not provide a detailed comparison of the performance of different LLMs in specific knob tuning tasks, which could be useful for practitioners looking to choose the appropriate LLM for their specific needs.</li>
<li>Additionally, the study does</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02213v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02213v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02213v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02213v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>866</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Is_Large_Language_Model_Good_at_Database_Knob_Tuning_A_Comprehensive_Experimental_Evaluation/2024-08-05-Is_Large_Language_Model_Good_at_Database_Knob_Tuning_A_Comprehensive_Experimental_Evaluation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Let Me Speak Freely? A Study on the Impact of Format Restrictions on Performance of Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Zhi Rui Tam, Cheng-Kuang Wu, Yi-Lin Tsai, Chieh-Yen Lin, Hung-yi Lee, Yun-Nung Chen</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Let_Me_Speak_Freely_A_Study_on_the_Impact_of_Format_Restrictions_on_Performance_of_Large_Language_Models/2024-08-05-Let_Me_Speak_Freely_A_Study_on_the_Impact_of_Format_Restrictions_on_Performance_of_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Let_Me_Speak_Freely_A_Study_on_the_Impact_of_Format_Restrictions_on_Performance_of_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02442v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The study investigates the impact of format restrictions on the performance of large language models (LLMs) in generating structured outputs. The authors evaluate LLMs’ performance when restricted to adhere to structured formats versus generating free-form responses across various common tasks. Surprisingly, they observe a significant decline in LLMs’ reasoning abilities under format restrictions, with stricter constraints generally leading to greater performance degradation in reasoning tasks.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs’ reasoning abilities decline under format restrictions, with stricter constraints leading to greater performance degradation in reasoning tasks.</li>
<li>The study presents a comprehensive analysis of the potential impacts of format-restricting instructions on LLMs’ performance across a wide range of tasks.</li>
<li>The authors propose simple approaches to mitigate performance degradation due to format constraints, achieving both consistent formats and optimal performance.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The study does not address the potential impact of format restrictions on LLMs’ performance in tasks other than reasoning, such as classification tasks.</li>
<li>The authors do not explore the potential benefits of format restrictions, such as improved output parsing and reliability, which could be valuable in industrial applications.</li>
<li>The study does not consider the potential impact of format restrictions on the interpretability and explainability of LLMs’ outputs, which could be important for ensuring the trustworthiness of these models.</li>
<li>The authors do not discuss the potential implications of their findings for the design and development of LLMs, such as the need to incorporate format-following capabilities into these models.</li>
<li>The study does not consider the potential impact of format restrictions on the scalability and efficiency of LLMs, which could be important for deploying these models in real-world applications.</li>
<li>The authors do not discuss the potential impact of their findings on the broader field of natural language processing, such as the implications for the development of other types of language models.</li>
<li>The study does not consider the potential impact of format restrictions on the fairness and bias of LLMs, which could be important for ensuring the ethical use of these models.</li>
<li>The authors do not discuss the potential impact of their findings on the evaluation and benchmarking of LLMs, such as the need to develop new metrics and benchmarks that take into account format restrictions.</li>
<li></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02442v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02442v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02442v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02442v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7522</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Let_Me_Speak_Freely_A_Study_on_the_Impact_of_Format_Restrictions_on_Performance_of_Large_Language_Models/2024-08-05-Let_Me_Speak_Freely_A_Study_on_the_Impact_of_Format_Restrictions_on_Performance_of_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02442v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>An investigation on the use of Large Language Models for hyperparameter tuning in Evolutionary Algorithms</title>
  <dc:creator>Leonardo Lucio Custode, Fabio Caraffini, Anil Yaman, Giovanni Iacca</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/An_investigation_on_the_use_of_Large_Language_Models_for_hyperparameter_tuning_in_Evolutionary_Algorithms/2024-08-05-An_investigation_on_the_use_of_Large_Language_Models_for_hyperparameter_tuning_in_Evolutionary_Algorithms.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/An_investigation_on_the_use_of_Large_Language_Models_for_hyperparameter_tuning_in_Evolutionary_Algorithms/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02451v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article explores the use of Large Language Models (LLMs) for hyperparameter tuning in Evolutionary Algorithms (EAs), specifically focusing on step-size adaptation for -ES.</li>
<li>LLMs have been successfully applied to various domains, including chemistry, protein design, robotics, and urban delivery route optimization.</li>
<li>The authors conduct a preliminary investigation on the possibility of automating “empirical” step-size adaptation in Evolution Strategies (ES) using LLMs, specifically Llama2-70b and Mixtral.</li>
<li>The results show that LLMs can compete with well-known traditional mechanisms for step-size adaptation.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs can be an effective method for optimizing hyperparameters in Evolution Strategies, encouraging further research in this direction.</li>
<li>The study focuses on the case of tuning the step-size for -ES using state-of-the-art LLMs, namely Llama2-70b and Mixtral.</li>
<li>The results suggest that LLMs can compete with well-known traditional mechanisms for step-size adaptation.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides a promising direction for using LLMs in hyperparameter optimization for EAs.</li>
<li>However, the study is preliminary and focuses on a specific case of step-size adaptation for -ES. Further research is needed to explore the potential of LLMs in other hyperparameter optimization scenarios.</li>
<li>The study does not discuss the computational cost of using LLMs for hyperparameter optimization, which could be a significant limitation.</li>
<li>The authors acknowledge that current LLMs are not well-suited for low-level (i.e., numerical) continuous optimization tasks due to the inference cost of querying LLMs and their limited mathematical reasoning capabilities. This could be a potential problem when applying LLMs to other hyperparameter optimization tasks.</li>
<li>The study does not compare the performance of LLMs with other hyperparameter optimization methods, which could provide a more comprehensive evaluation of the proposed approach.</li>
<li>The authors do not discuss the potential biases or limitations of the LLMs used in the study, which could impact the generalizability of the findings.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02451v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02451v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02451v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02451v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5174</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/An_investigation_on_the_use_of_Large_Language_Models_for_hyperparameter_tuning_in_Evolutionary_Algorithms/2024-08-05-An_investigation_on_the_use_of_Large_Language_Models_for_hyperparameter_tuning_in_Evolutionary_Algorithms.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02451v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>DanModCap: Designing a Danmaku Moderation Tool for Video-Sharing Platforms that Leverages Impact Captions</title>
  <dc:creator>Siying Hu, Huanchen Wang, Yu Zhang, Piaohong Wang, Zhicong Lu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/DanModCap_Designing_a_Danmaku_Moderation_Tool_for_Video_Sharing_Platforms_that_Leverages_Impact_Captions/2024-08-05-DanModCap_Designing_a_Danmaku_Moderation_Tool_for_Video_Sharing_Platforms_that_Leverages_Impact_Captions.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/DanModCap_Designing_a_Danmaku_Moderation_Tool_for_Video_Sharing_Platforms_that_Leverages_Impact_Captions/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02574v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The article presents a novel approach to moderating Danmaku comments on video-sharing platforms using a tool called DanModCap. DanModCap leverages Impact Captions, a concept inspired by East Asian variety shows, to guide viewers towards positive Danmaku-related activities and elicit prosocial behaviors. The tool collects and analyzes Danmaku comments and uses them as input to large generative language models to produce Impact Captions. The evaluation of DanModCap demonstrated that Impact Captions reduced negative antagonistic emotions, increased users’ desire to share positive content, and elicited self-control in Danmaku social action to foster proactive community maintenance behaviors. The approach highlights the benefits of using LLM-supported content moderation methods for proactive moderation in large-scale live content contexts.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Impact Captions, inspired by East Asian variety shows, can be used to guide viewers towards positive Danmaku-related activities and elicit prosocial behaviors.</li>
<li>DanModCap, a tool for Danmaku content moderation, uses generative AI to create Impact Captions that can reduce negative antagonistic emotions, increase users’ desire to share positive content, and elicit self-control in Danmaku social action.</li>
<li>The use of LLM-supported content moderation methods for proactive moderation in large-scale live content contexts can be beneficial.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article presents an innovative approach to moderating Danmaku comments on video-sharing platforms using Impact Captions. The use of Impact Captions to guide viewers towards positive Danmaku-related activities and elicit prosocial behaviors is a novel concept that has the potential to improve the user experience on these platforms. The evaluation of DanModCap demonstrated positive results, indicating that the tool can effectively reduce negative antagonistic emotions, increase users’ desire to share positive content, and elicit self-control in Danmaku social action.</p>
<p>However, there are some potential limitations and areas for further research. The article does not provide a detailed description of the methodology used to evaluate DanModCap, making it difficult to assess the validity of the findings. Additionally, the use of LLM-supported content moderation methods for proactive moderation in large-scale live content contexts is a relatively new approach</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02574v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02574v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02574v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02574v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>14165</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/DanModCap_Designing_a_Danmaku_Moderation_Tool_for_Video_Sharing_Platforms_that_Leverages_Impact_Captions/2024-08-05-DanModCap_Designing_a_Danmaku_Moderation_Tool_for_Video_Sharing_Platforms_that_Leverages_Impact_Captions.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02574v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Evaluating and Enhancing LLMs Agent based on Theory of Mind in Guandan: A Multi-Player Cooperative Game under Imperfect Information</title>
  <dc:creator>Yauwai Yim, Chunkit Chan, Tianyu Shi, Zheye Deng, Wei Fan, Tianshi Zheng, Yangqiu Song</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Evaluating_and_Enhancing_LLMs_Agent_based_on_Theory_of_Mind_in_Guandan_A_Multi_Player_Cooperative_Game_under_Imperfect_Information/2024-08-05-Evaluating_and_Enhancing_LLMs_Agent_based_on_Theory_of_Mind_in_Guandan_A_Multi_Player_Cooperative_Game_under_Imperfect_Information.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2408.02559v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary:</strong></p>
<p>This study evaluates the performance of open-source and closed-source Large Language Models (LLMs) in a complex card game, Guandan, which involves imperfect information and requires collaboration among agents. The research aims to explore the applicability of knowledge acquired by these models in sophisticated text-based games and compare their performance to established baselines using other types of agents. The study proposes a Theory of Mind (ToM) planning technique that allows LLM agents to adapt their strategy against various adversaries using only game rules, current state, and historical context as input. An external tool was incorporated to mitigate the challenge of dynamic and extensive action spaces in this card game. The results show that while a performance gap exists between current LLMs and state-of-the-art reinforcement learning (RL) models, LLMs demonstrate ToM capabilities in this game setting and consistently improve their performance against opposing agents.</p>
<p><strong>Major Findings:</strong></p>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs exhibit subpar performance compared to RL-based approaches in intricate and realistic scenarios, such as the Guandan card game.</li>
<li>The proposed ToM planning method optimizes LLM-agent’s decision-making and collaboration in multi-agent gaming environments.</li>
<li>An RL-based model was developed to address LLMs’ challenges in adapting to dynamic changes and extensive legal action lists.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></p>
<p>The study provides valuable insights into the performance of LLMs in complex, multi-agent gaming environments. However, it is essential to acknowledge the limitations of LLMs without fine-tuning when faced with cooperative tasks involving imperfect information. The research highlights the significant limitations of most models in addressing such challenges effectively. Additionally, the study’s focus on the Guandan card game may limit the generalizability of the findings to other complex social interactions and strategic thinking tasks. Future research should explore the potential of LLMs in a broader range of real-world tasks and address the identified limitations.</p>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02559v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02559v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02559v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02559v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>23008</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Evaluating_and_Enhancing_LLMs_Agent_based_on_Theory_of_Mind_in_Guandan_A_Multi_Player_Cooperative_Game_under_Imperfect_Information/2024-08-05-Evaluating_and_Enhancing_LLMs_Agent_based_on_Theory_of_Mind_in_Guandan_A_Multi_Player_Cooperative_Game_under_Imperfect_Information.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2408.02559v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Leveraging the Power of LLMs: A Fine-Tuning Approach for High-Quality Aspect-Based Summarization</title>
  <dc:creator>Ankan Mullick, Sombit Bose, Rounak Saha, Ayan Kumar Bhowmick, Aditya Vempaty, Pawan Goyal, Niloy Ganguly, Prasenjit Dey, Ravi Kokku</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Leveraging_the_Power_of_LLMs_A_Fine_Tuning_Approach_for_High_Quality_Aspect_Based_Summarization/2024-08-05-Leveraging_the_Power_of_LLMs_A_Fine_Tuning_Approach_for_High_Quality_Aspect_Based_Summarization.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Leveraging_the_Power_of_LLMs_A_Fine_Tuning_Approach_for_High_Quality_Aspect_Based_Summarization/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02584v1/extracted/5732566/R1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper explores the potential of fine-tuning large language models (LLMs) for the task of aspect-based summarization. The authors evaluate the impact of fine-tuning open-source foundation LLMs, including Llama2, Mistral, Gemma, and Aya, on a publicly available domain-specific aspect-based summary dataset. The goal is to enable these models to effectively identify and extract aspect-related information, leading to superior quality aspect-based summaries compared to the state-of-the-art. The authors establish a comprehensive evaluation framework to compare the performance of fine-tuned LLMs against competing aspect-based summarization methods and vanilla counterparts of the fine-tuned LLMs.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Fine-tuning LLMs for aspect-based summarization significantly improves the quality of generated summaries compared to vanilla counterparts and state-of-the-art methods.</li>
<li>The effectiveness of fine-tuning LLMs varies depending on the base model architecture, with some models showing significant improvement while others do not.</li>
<li>The robustness of fine-tuned LLMs for variations in dataset and domains for aspect-based summarization is demonstrated through experiments on different types of OASUM data and evaluations for different domains.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper provides a comprehensive evaluation of fine-tuned LLMs for aspect-based summarization, but the results are limited to a single dataset and may not generalize to other datasets or domains.</li>
<li>The evaluation metrics used in the paper, such as ROUGE and BERTScore, may not fully capture the quality of generated summaries, and alternative evaluation methods, such as human evaluation, could provide additional insights.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the computational cost of fine-tuning LLMs for aspect-based summarization, which could be a significant limitation for practical applications.</li>
<li>The paper does not explore the potential of using LLMs for other tasks in NLP, such as question answering or sentiment analysis, which could provide additional insights into the capabilities of LLMs for targeted information extraction tasks.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential ethical implications of using LLMs for aspect-based summarization, such as the risk of generating biased or inaccurate</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02584v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02584v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02584v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02584v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6967</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Leveraging_the_Power_of_LLMs_A_Fine_Tuning_Approach_for_High_Quality_Aspect_Based_Summarization/2024-08-05-Leveraging_the_Power_of_LLMs_A_Fine_Tuning_Approach_for_High_Quality_Aspect_Based_Summarization.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02584v1/extracted/5732566/R1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>A Multi-Source Heterogeneous Knowledge Injected Prompt Learning Method for Legal Charge Prediction</title>
  <dc:creator>Jingyun Sun, Chi Wei, Yang Li</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_Multi_Source_Heterogeneous_Knowledge_Injected_Prompt_Learning_Method_for_Legal_Charge_Prediction/2024-08-05-A_Multi_Source_Heterogeneous_Knowledge_Injected_Prompt_Learning_Method_for_Legal_Charge_Prediction.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2408.02233v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary:</strong></p>
<p>The paper presents a prompt learning framework-based method for legal charge prediction that leverages multi-source heterogeneous external knowledge from a legal knowledge base, a conversational LLM, and related legal articles. The method matches knowledge snippets in case descriptions via the legal knowledge base and encapsulates them into the input through a hard prompt template. It also retrieves legal articles related to a given case description through contrastive learning and obtains factual elements within the case description through a conversational LLM. The method fuses the embedding vectors of soft prompt tokens with the encoding vector of factual elements to achieve knowledge-enhanced model forward inference. The proposed method achieved state-of-the-art results on CAIL-2018, the largest legal charge prediction dataset, and has lower data dependency.</p>
<p><strong>Major Findings:</strong></p>
<ol type="1">
<li>The proposed method achieved state-of-the-art results on CAIL-2018, the largest legal charge prediction dataset, with a macro F1 score of 0.84.</li>
<li>The method has lower data dependency, as its performance remains high even with a reduced training data size.</li>
<li>The method demonstrates strong interpretability, as shown in case studies.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></p>
<p>The paper presents a novel approach to legal charge prediction that leverages multi-source heterogeneous external knowledge. The method’s ability to achieve state-of-the-art results on the largest legal charge prediction dataset and its lower data dependency are significant contributions. However, the paper does not explore situations where a single case description may correspond to multiple legal charges, which could be a limitation. Additionally, the paper does not provide a detailed comparison with other methods that also use external knowledge, such as knowledge graphs or ontologies. The paper could also benefit from a more in-depth analysis of the interpretability of the method, as this is a crucial aspect in the legal domain.</p>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02233v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02233v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02233v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02233v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>15870</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_Multi_Source_Heterogeneous_Knowledge_Injected_Prompt_Learning_Method_for_Legal_Charge_Prediction/2024-08-05-A_Multi_Source_Heterogeneous_Knowledge_Injected_Prompt_Learning_Method_for_Legal_Charge_Prediction.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2408.02233v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Context Conquers Parameters: Outperforming Proprietary LLM in Commit Message Generation</title>
  <dc:creator>Aaron Imani, Iftekhar Ahmed, Mohammad Moshirpour</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Context_Conquers_Parameters_Outperforming_Proprietary_LLM_in_Commit_Message_Generation/2024-08-05-Context_Conquers_Parameters_Outperforming_Proprietary_LLM_in_Commit_Message_Generation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Context_Conquers_Parameters_Outperforming_Proprietary_LLM_in_Commit_Message_Generation/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02502v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The study investigates the use of open-source large language models (OLLMs) for generating commit messages (CMs) that are comparable to those produced by the state-of-the-art Omniscient Message Generator (OMG), which uses GPT-4. The authors propose a new approach called lOcal MessagE GenerAtor (OMEGA) that employs a 4-bit quantized 8B OLLM. The study demonstrates that OMEGA can generate CMs that surpass the performance of GPT-4 in practitioners’ preference.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>An OLLM can generate CMs that are comparable to those produced by OMG, but with a gap in comprehensiveness.</li>
<li>The study introduces a new method summarization approach called Change-based Multi-Intent Method Summarization (CMMS) for software engineering tasks that rely on code changes.</li>
<li>The study proposes two augmentation techniques for commit diff, Diff Narrator and Fine-grained Interactive Diff EXplainer (FIDEX), that boost SLM’s performance in CMG.</li>
<li>OMEGA, a 4-bit quantized SLM with 8B trained parameters, can generate CMs that are preferred by practitioners over those generated by OMG.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The study provides a well-structured and coherent summary of the research, highlighting the major findings and contributions. The use of open-source LLMs for generating CMs is a significant contribution, as it addresses privacy and sustainability concerns associated with proprietary LLMs. The proposed OMEGA approach shows promising results in generating CMs that are preferred by practitioners over those generated by OMG.</p>
<p>However, the study has some limitations. The evaluation of the proposed approach is based on a single dataset, and the results may not generalize to other datasets or programming languages. Additionally, the study does not provide a detailed comparison of the proposed approach with other state-of-the-art CMG methods. The study also does not discuss the potential impact of the proposed approach on the quality of the generated CMs, such as their accuracy, completeness, and relevance.</p>
<p>Overall, the study provides a valuable contribution to the field of CMG by</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02502v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02502v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02502v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02502v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>10845</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Context_Conquers_Parameters_Outperforming_Proprietary_LLM_in_Commit_Message_Generation/2024-08-05-Context_Conquers_Parameters_Outperforming_Proprietary_LLM_in_Commit_Message_Generation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02502v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Large Language Model Aided QoS Prediction for Service Recommendation</title>
  <dc:creator>Huiying Liu, Zekun Zhang, Qilin Wu, Yiwen Zhang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Large_Language_Model_Aided_QoS_Prediction_for_Service_Recommendation/2024-08-05-Large_Language_Model_Aided_QoS_Prediction_for_Service_Recommendation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Large_Language_Model_Aided_QoS_Prediction_for_Service_Recommendation/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02223v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper introduces a novel approach called large language model aided QoS prediction (llmQoS) for web service recommendation. This method combines collaborative filtering and natural language processing to overcome the data sparsity issue in QoS prediction. The proposed model uses large language models (LLMs) to extract useful information from attributes of web users and services via descriptive sentences. This information is then used in combination with the QoS values of historical interactions of users and services to predict QoS values for any given user-service pair. The paper demonstrates that llmQoS can predict QoS values accurately under different data sparsity levels and outperforms several existing QoS prediction models consistently on the WSDream dataset.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper introduces the use of large language models (LLMs) for the web service recommendation task, proposing the large language model aided QoS prediction (llmQoS) model.</li>
<li>The llmQoS model effectively mitigates the data sparsity issue inherent to the QoS prediction problem by combining collaborative filtering and nature language processing.</li>
<li>The llmQoS model is shown to predict QoS values accurately under different data sparsity levels and outperforms several existing QoS prediction models consistently on the WSDream dataset.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The paper presents an innovative approach to the QoS prediction problem by utilizing large language models (LLMs) to extract useful information from attributes of web users and services. The proposed model, llmQoS, effectively mitigates the data sparsity issue and demonstrates superior performance compared to existing QoS prediction models. However, the paper does not discuss the potential limitations or biases of the proposed model, nor does it address any methodological issues or conflicting evidence. Additionally, the paper does not provide any information on the computational cost or scalability of the proposed model, which could be important considerations for practical implementation. Further research is needed to address these potential shortcomings and evaluate the performance of the llmQoS model in real-world scenarios.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02223v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02223v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02223v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02223v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6778</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>recommender</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Large_Language_Model_Aided_QoS_Prediction_for_Service_Recommendation/2024-08-05-Large_Language_Model_Aided_QoS_Prediction_for_Service_Recommendation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02223v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>A First Look at License Compliance Capability of LLMs in Code Generation</title>
  <dc:creator>Weiwei Xu, Kai Gao, Hao He, Minghui Zhou</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_First_Look_at_License_Compliance_Capability_of_LLMs_in_Code_Generation/2024-08-05-A_First_Look_at_License_Compliance_Capability_of_LLMs_in_Code_Generation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_First_Look_at_License_Compliance_Capability_of_LLMs_in_Code_Generation/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02487v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>This paper addresses the issue of license compliance in LLM-generated code by establishing a benchmark to evaluate the ability of LLMs to provide accurate license information for their generated code. The authors conduct an empirical study to identify a reasonable standard for “striking similarity” that excludes the possibility of independent creation, indicating a copy relationship between the LLM output and certain open-source code. Based on this standard, they propose an evaluation benchmark, LiCoEval, to evaluate the license compliance capabilities of LLMs. Using LiCoEval, the authors evaluate 14 popular LLMs and find that even top-performing LLMs produce a non-negligible proportion (0.88% to 2.01%) of code strikingly similar to existing open-source implementations. Most models fail to provide accurate license information, particularly for code under copyleft licenses. These findings underscore the urgent need to enhance LLM compliance capabilities in code generation tasks.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The authors establish a benchmark, LiCoEval, to evaluate the license compliance capabilities of LLMs in code generation.</li>
<li>The authors find that even top-performing LLMs produce a non-negligible proportion (0.88% to 2.01%) of code strikingly similar to existing open-source implementations.</li>
<li>Most LLMs fail to provide accurate license information, particularly for code under copyleft licenses.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The authors’ work is a significant contribution to the field of LLM-generated code and its compliance with open-source licenses. The establishment of a benchmark for evaluating LLMs’ license compliance capabilities is a crucial step towards ensuring the ethical and legal use of LLMs in code generation. However, the authors acknowledge that their striking similarity standard focuses on precision, potentially overlooking cases where LLMs generate code derived from open-source code but fall below their threshold. Additionally, the authors note that their evaluation is limited to Python code and function-level code completion, which may not fully represent the vast diversity of real-world code and potentially more severe compliance issues at class or project levels. Despite these limitations, the authors’ work provides valuable insights for improving license compliance in AI-assisted software development and protecting open-source developers’ IP rights.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02487v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02487v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02487v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02487v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>9790</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_First_Look_at_License_Compliance_Capability_of_LLMs_in_Code_Generation/2024-08-05-A_First_Look_at_License_Compliance_Capability_of_LLMs_in_Code_Generation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02487v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>SEAS: Self-Evolving Adversarial Safety Optimization for Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Muxi Diao, Rumei Li, Shiyang Liu, Guogang Liao, Jingang Wang, Xunliang Cai, Weiran Xu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SEAS_Self_Evolving_Adversarial_Safety_Optimization_for_Large_Language_Models/2024-08-05-SEAS_Self_Evolving_Adversarial_Safety_Optimization_for_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SEAS_Self_Evolving_Adversarial_Safety_Optimization_for_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02632v1/extracted/5774252/Main.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level1">
<h1>Summary:</h1>
<p><strong>Summary:</strong></p>
<p>The paper introduces the Self-Evolving Adversarial Safety (SEAS) optimization framework, which aims to enhance the security of large language models (LLMs) by leveraging data generated by the models themselves. The framework operates through three iterative stages: Initialization, Attack, and Adversarial Optimization. The SEAS framework reduces reliance on manual testing and significantly improves the security capabilities of LLMs. The contributions of this work include a novel adversarial framework, a comprehensive safety dataset, and improved performance of the Target model, comparable to GPT-4, and a marked increase in the attack success rate (ASR) of the Red Team model against advanced models.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li>The SEAS framework enhances the security of LLMs by iteratively improving the capabilities of the Red Team model and the safety of the Target model without requiring manual annotation.</li>
<li>The SEAS dataset, which includes various harmful, adversarial, and ambiguous harmless prompts, provides tools for the secure development and deployment of LLMs.</li>
<li>After three iterations, the Target model achieves a security level close to that of GPT-4 while maintaining its general ability, and the Red Team model shows a 50.66% increase in ASR against Llama3-70B.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper does not provide a detailed comparison of the SEAS framework with other existing adversarial frameworks, which could help to better understand its advantages and limitations.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential risks associated with the use of the SEAS framework, such as the possibility of generating harmful content or the misuse of the generated data.</li>
<li>The paper does not provide a detailed analysis of the computational resources required to implement the SEAS framework, which could be a limiting factor for its adoption in resource-constrained environments.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential impact of the SEAS framework on the fairness and bias of LLMs, which is an important consideration in the development of safe and reliable AI systems.</li>
<li>The paper does not provide a detailed analysis of the potential limitations of the SEAS dataset, such as the coverage of different types of adversarial attacks and the diversity of the generated</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02632v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02632v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02632v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02632v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8981</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SEAS_Self_Evolving_Adversarial_Safety_Optimization_for_Large_Language_Models/2024-08-05-SEAS_Self_Evolving_Adversarial_Safety_Optimization_for_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02632v1/extracted/5774252/Main.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Developing PUGG for Polish: A Modern Approach to KBQA, MRC, and IR Dataset Construction</title>
  <dc:creator>Albert Sawczyn, Katsiaryna Viarenich, Konrad Wojtasik, Aleksandra Domogała, Marcin Oleksy, Maciej Piasecki, Tomasz Kajdanowicz</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Developing_PUGG_for_Polish_A_Modern_Approach_to_KBQA_MRC_and_IR_Dataset_Construction/2024-08-05-Developing_PUGG_for_Polish_A_Modern_Approach_to_KBQA_MRC_and_IR_Dataset_Construction.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Developing_PUGG_for_Polish_A_Modern_Approach_to_KBQA_MRC_and_IR_Dataset_Construction/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02337v1/extracted/5774485/plots/pipeline.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper introduces a modern, semi-automated approach for creating datasets for tasks such as KBQA, MRC, and IR, tailored explicitly for low-resource environments.</li>
<li>The authors executed this pipeline and introduced the PUGG dataset, the first Polish KBQA dataset, and novel datasets for MRC and IR.</li>
<li>The paper provides a comprehensive implementation, insightful findings, detailed statistics, and evaluation of baseline models.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The proposed pipeline generates natural and factoid questions in a semi-automated manner, significantly reducing the workload of human annotators.</li>
<li>The pipeline results in the creation of KBQA, MRC, and IR datasets while drastically reducing the labor of human annotators.</li>
<li>The paper introduces the PUGG dataset, which encompasses three tasks — KBQA, MRC, and IR. This dataset features natural factoid questions in Polish and stands out as the first Polish KBQA resource.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper does not provide a detailed comparison with existing KBQA datasets, which could help to understand the advantages and limitations of the proposed approach.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential biases in the generated datasets, which could be introduced by the LLMs and pre-existing datasets used in the pipeline.</li>
<li>The paper does not provide a detailed analysis of the performance of the baseline models on the PUGG dataset, which could help to understand the strengths and weaknesses of the proposed approach.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential applications of the proposed approach in other low-resource languages, which could help to understand the generalizability of the proposed approach.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02337v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02337v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02337v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02337v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7039</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Developing_PUGG_for_Polish_A_Modern_Approach_to_KBQA_MRC_and_IR_Dataset_Construction/2024-08-05-Developing_PUGG_for_Polish_A_Modern_Approach_to_KBQA_MRC_and_IR_Dataset_Construction.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02337v1/extracted/5774485/plots/pipeline.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>An Evaluation of Requirements Modeling for Cyber-Physical Systems via LLMs</title>
  <dc:creator>Dongming Jin, Shengxin Zhao, Zhi Jin, Xiaohong Chen, Chunhui Wang, Zheng Fang, Hongbin Xiao</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/An_Evaluation_of_Requirements_Modeling_for_Cyber_Physical_Systems_via_LLMs/2024-08-05-An_Evaluation_of_Requirements_Modeling_for_Cyber_Physical_Systems_via_LLMs.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/An_Evaluation_of_Requirements_Modeling_for_Cyber_Physical_Systems_via_LLMs/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02450v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary:</strong></p>
<p>This paper evaluates the performance of large language models (LLMs) in modeling cyber-physical systems (CPSs) requirements using problem diagrams. The authors propose a benchmark called CPSBench, which consists of 12 enterprise-level requirements documents and 30 tutorial cases. They apply a few-shot reasoning strategy to evaluate the capabilities and limitations of seven advanced LLMs. The evaluation reveals that LLMs have limited effectiveness in modeling CPSs requirements using problem diagrams for practical applications, with a recall rate of only around 60%. LLMs have a better understanding of general requirements concepts than specialized concepts, and their performance can be improved with more shots in the prompt. The authors also establish a taxonomy of LLMs hallucinations in CPSs requirements modeling.</p>
<p><strong>Major Findings:</strong></p>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs have limited ability to model the requirements for CPSs using problem diagrams, with a recall rate of only around 60%.</li>
<li>LLMs have a better understanding of general concepts than specialized concepts in CPSs requirements modeling.</li>
<li>LLMs can improve their performance with more shots in the prompt.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></p>
<p>The paper provides a comprehensive evaluation of the capabilities and limitations of LLMs in CPSs requirements modeling using problem diagrams. However, the evaluation is limited to seven advanced LLMs, and the results may not generalize to other LLMs. Additionally, the authors do not discuss the potential impact of the quality and complexity of the requirements documents on the performance of LLMs. The paper also does not provide a detailed comparison of the performance of LLMs with other approaches for CPSs requirements modeling. Finally, the authors do not discuss the potential ethical implications of using LLMs for CPSs requirements modeling, such as the risk of introducing biases or errors in the requirements.</p>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02450v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02450v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02450v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02450v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8576</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/An_Evaluation_of_Requirements_Modeling_for_Cyber_Physical_Systems_via_LLMs/2024-08-05-An_Evaluation_of_Requirements_Modeling_for_Cyber_Physical_Systems_via_LLMs.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02450v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>From LLMs to LLM-based Agents for Software Engineering: A Survey of Current, Challenges and Future</title>
  <dc:creator>Haolin Jin, Linghan Huang, Haipeng Cai, Jun Yan, Bo Li, Huaming Chen</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/From_LLMs_to_LLM_based_Agents_for_Software_Engineering_A_Survey_of_Current_Challenges_and_Future/2024-08-05-From_LLMs_to_LLM_based_Agents_for_Software_Engineering_A_Survey_of_Current_Challenges_and_Future.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/From_LLMs_to_LLM_based_Agents_for_Software_Engineering_A_Survey_of_Current_Challenges_and_Future/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02479v1/extracted/5774653/year.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary:</strong></p>
<p>This paper provides a comprehensive survey of the current practice and solutions for Large Language Models (LLMs) and LLM-based agents in software engineering. LLMs, such as GPT and Codex, have shown remarkable capabilities in handling downstream tasks in SE, including code generation, debugging, and documentation. However, they also exhibit limitations, such as limited context length and hallucinations. To address these challenges, LLM-based agents have emerged, combining LLMs with external tools and resources to enable more dynamic and autonomous operations. These agents can perform a wide range of tasks, such as autonomous debugging, code refactoring, and adaptive test generation, demonstrating capabilities that approach artificial general intelligence (AGI).</p>
<p>The paper covers six key topics: requirement engineering, code generation, autonomous decision-making, software design and evaluation, software test generation, and software security and maintenance. LLMs and LLM-based agents</p>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02479v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02479v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02479v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02479v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>34830</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/From_LLMs_to_LLM_based_Agents_for_Software_Engineering_A_Survey_of_Current_Challenges_and_Future/2024-08-05-From_LLMs_to_LLM_based_Agents_for_Software_Engineering_A_Survey_of_Current_Challenges_and_Future.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02479v1/extracted/5774653/year.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Self-Taught Evaluators</title>
  <dc:creator>Tianlu Wang, Ilia Kulikov, Olga Golovneva, Ping Yu, Weizhe Yuan, Jane Dwivedi-Yu, Richard Yuanzhe Pang, Maryam Fazel-Zarandi, Jason Weston, Xian Li</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Self_Taught_Evaluators/2024-08-05-Self_Taught_Evaluators.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Self_Taught_Evaluators/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02666v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level1">
<h1>Summary:</h1>
<p>The paper presents a novel approach to improve evaluators for large language models (LLMs) without relying on human annotations. The proposed method, called Self-Taught Evaluator, uses synthetic training data and an iterative self-improvement scheme to generate contrasting model outputs and train an LLM-as-a-Judge to produce reasoning traces and final judgments. The approach is demonstrated to improve a strong LLM (Llama3-70B-Instruct) from 75.4 to 88.3 (88.7 with majority vote) on RewardBench, outperforming commonly used LLM judges such as GPT-4 and matching the performance of top-performing reward models trained with labeled examples.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level1">
<h1>Major Findings:</h1>
<ol type="1">
<li>The Self-Taught Evaluator method significantly improves the performance of a strong LLM (Llama3-70B-Instruct) on RewardBench, from 75.4 to 88.3 (88.7 with majority vote), without using any labeled preference data.</li>
<li>The proposed approach outperforms commonly used LLM judges such as GPT-4 and matches the performance of the top-performing reward models trained with labeled examples.</li>
<li>The iterative training scheme used in the Self-Taught Evaluator method allows for continuous improvement of the LLM-as-a-Judge model, as it is trained on its own predictions and the generated synthetic data.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level1">
<h1>Analysis and Critique:</h1>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper presents an innovative approach to improving evaluators for LLMs, addressing the limitations of relying on human annotations and the cost and time associated with collecting them.</li>
<li>The proposed method demonstrates promising results, outperforming commonly used LLM judges and matching the performance of top-performing reward models trained with labeled examples.</li>
<li>However, the paper does not provide a detailed comparison of the proposed approach with other methods that use synthetic data or unsupervised learning for improving evaluators.</li>
<li>The paper also does not discuss the potential limitations or biases introduced by using synthetic data and the iterative self-improvement scheme, which could be a topic for future research.</li>
<li>The proposed method is demonstrated to work well for a specific LLM</li>
</ol>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02666v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02666v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02666v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02666v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5749</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Self_Taught_Evaluators/2024-08-05-Self_Taught_Evaluators.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02666v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>SceneMotifCoder: Example-driven Visual Program Learning for Generating 3D Object Arrangements</title>
  <dc:creator>Hou In Ivan Tam, Hou In Derek Pun, Austin T. Wang, Angel X. Chang, Manolis Savva</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SceneMotifCoder_Example_driven_Visual_Program_Learning_for_Generating_3D_Object_Arrangements/2024-08-05-SceneMotifCoder_Example_driven_Visual_Program_Learning_for_Generating_3D_Object_Arrangements.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2408.02211v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper introduces SceneMotifCoder (SMC), a novel approach for generating 3D object arrangements using visual program learning. SMC leverages large language models (LLMs) and program synthesis to learn visual programs from example arrangements, which are then generalized into compact, editable meta-programs. These meta-programs, combined with 3D object retrieval and geometry-aware optimization, can create object arrangements with varying structures and contained objects. The paper claims that SMC generates high-quality arrangements using meta-programs learned from few examples, outperforming state-of-the-art text-to-3D generation and layout methods in terms of conformity to user-specified text descriptions and physical plausibility.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>SMC outperforms state-of-the-art text-to-3D generation and layout methods in terms of conformity to</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02211v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02211v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02211v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02211v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>37815</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>programming</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SceneMotifCoder_Example_driven_Visual_Program_Learning_for_Generating_3D_Object_Arrangements/2024-08-05-SceneMotifCoder_Example_driven_Visual_Program_Learning_for_Generating_3D_Object_Arrangements.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2408.02211v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>From Generalist to Specialist: Exploring CWE-Specific Vulnerability Detection</title>
  <dc:creator>Syafiq Al Atiiq, Christian Gehrmann, Kevin Dahlén, Karim Khalil</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/From_Generalist_to_Specialist_Exploring_CWE_Specific_Vulnerability_Detection/2024-08-05-From_Generalist_to_Specialist_Exploring_CWE_Specific_Vulnerability_Detection.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/From_Generalist_to_Specialist_Exploring_CWE_Specific_Vulnerability_Detection/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02329v1/extracted/5772338/figs/label_distribution.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level1">
<h1>Summary:</h1>
<p>The paper explores the use of CWE-specific classifiers for vulnerability detection, hypothesizing that training separate classifiers for each CWE will enable models to capture the unique characteristics and code semantics associated with each vulnerability category. The authors conduct an ablation study by training individual classifiers for each CWE and evaluating their performance independently. The results demonstrate that CWE-specific classifiers outperform a single binary classifier trained on all vulnerabilities. The paper also discusses the potential of using a multiclass approach to combine CWE-specific classifiers into a unified vulnerability detection system.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li>CWE-specific classifiers outperform a single binary classifier in detecting vulnerabilities, as they can capture the unique characteristics and code semantics associated with each vulnerability category.</li>
<li>The lack of large and high-quality datasets for vulnerability detection is still a major obstacle, but multiclass detection can be a better path toward practical vulnerability detection in the future.</li>
<li>The authors’ models and code to produce their results are open-sourced, allowing for further research and development in the field.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h2>
<p>The paper presents a novel approach to vulnerability detection by focusing on CWE-specific classifiers. This approach addresses the limitations of traditional binary classifiers, which may oversimplify the problem by treating all vulnerabilities as a single label. The use of CWE-specific classifiers allows for a more nuanced understanding of vulnerabilities and their unique characteristics.</p>
<p>However, the paper acknowledges that the lack of large and high-quality datasets for vulnerability detection remains a significant challenge. The authors’ findings are based on their own dataset, and it is unclear how well their approach would generalize to other datasets or real-world scenarios. Additionally, the paper does not discuss potential biases or limitations in the dataset used, which could impact the validity of their findings.</p>
<p>Overall, the paper provides a valuable contribution to the field of vulnerability detection by introducing a new approach to classifying vulnerabilities. However, further research is needed to validate the effectiveness of this approach in different contexts and to address the ongoing challenge of limited datasets for vulnerability detection.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02329v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02329v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02329v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02329v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>10425</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/From_Generalist_to_Specialist_Exploring_CWE_Specific_Vulnerability_Detection/2024-08-05-From_Generalist_to_Specialist_Exploring_CWE_Specific_Vulnerability_Detection.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.02329v1/extracted/5772338/figs/label_distribution.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
