<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Bayesian beagle</title>
<link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Quarto blog of LLM-generated summaries of Arxiv preprints</description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.450</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>BibSonomy Meets ChatLLMs for Publication Management: From Chat to Publication Management: Organizing your related work using BibSonomy &amp; LLMs</title>
  <dc:creator>Tom Völker, Jan Pfister, Tobias Koopmann, Andreas Hotho</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/BibSonomy_Meets_ChatLLMs_for_Publication_Management_From_Chat_to_Publication_Management_Organizing_your_related_work_using_BibSonomy__LLMs/2024-01-17-BibSonomy_Meets_ChatLLMs_for_Publication_Management_From_Chat_to_Publication_Management_Organizing_your_related_work_using_BibSonomy__LLMs.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/BibSonomy_Meets_ChatLLMs_for_Publication_Management_From_Chat_to_Publication_Management_Organizing_your_related_work_using_BibSonomy__LLMs/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-the-article" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-of-the-article">Summary of the Article:</h3>
<p>The article introduces a retrieval augmented generation system that utilizes chat-based large language models (LLMs) to simplify and enhance the process of scientific publication management. This system provides a unified chat-based interface, allowing interactions with backends like Semantic Scholar, BibSonomy, and the Zotero Webscraper. It addresses two main use-cases: (1) Explorative Search &amp; Retrieval, and (2) Cataloguing &amp; Management. Evaluation of the system against different LLM models in three settings, including a user study, demonstrates its advantages.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Chat-based Large Language Models for Publication Management:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Introducing a novel retrieval augmented generation system leveraging chat-based LLMs to streamline and enhance the process of publication management.</li>
<li>Provides a unified chat-based interface, enabling intuitive interactions with various backends including Semantic Scholar, BibSonomy, and the Zotero Webscraper.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Use-Cases of the System:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Explorative Search &amp; Retrieval: Utilizes LLMs to search for specific and general scientific publications, addressing challenges of content hallucination and data obsolescence through querying different knowledge bases.</li>
<li>Cataloguing &amp; Management: Aids in the organization of personal publication libraries by automating the addition of metadata and tags, while facilitating manual edits and updates.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Evaluation and Comparison:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The system is evaluated qualitatively and quantitatively against similar tools, showing advantages in user opinion, determinism of query results, and inference time.</li>
</ul></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article effectively presents a novel approach using chat-based LLMs for streamlining publication management. However, it mainly focuses on the system’s capabilities and benefits with limited discussion on potential limitations or challenges. Additionally, while the evaluation demonstrates the system’s advantages, it would be beneficial to include a more comprehensive comparison with existing literature management tools. Further discussion on the scalability, potential biases, and the generalizability of the findings would enhance the article’s overall credibility and contribution to the field.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-18</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09092v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09092v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09092v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09092v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8708</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/BibSonomy_Meets_ChatLLMs_for_Publication_Management_From_Chat_to_Publication_Management_Organizing_your_related_work_using_BibSonomy__LLMs/2024-01-17-BibSonomy_Meets_ChatLLMs_for_Publication_Management_From_Chat_to_Publication_Management_Organizing_your_related_work_using_BibSonomy__LLMs.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Large Language Models Are Neurosymbolic Reasoners</title>
  <dc:creator>Meng Fang, Shilong Deng, Yudi Zhang, Zijing Shi, Ling Chen, Mykola Pechenizkiy, Jun Wang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Large_Language_Models_Are_Neurosymbolic_Reasoners/2024-01-17-Large_Language_Models_Are_Neurosymbolic_Reasoners.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Large_Language_Models_Are_Neurosymbolic_Reasoners/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09334v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong></p>
<p>The article investigates the potential application of Large Language Models (LLMs) as symbolic reasoners in text-based games. The LLM agent is designed to tackle symbolic tasks, including math, map reading, sorting, and applying common sense in text-based worlds. The experimental results demonstrate that the LLM agent significantly enhances the capability of LLMs as automated agents for symbolic reasoning, achieving an average performance of 88% across all tasks.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Text-based games serve as significant benchmarks for agents with natural language capabilities and have garnered substantial attention in the realm of language-centric machine learning research.</li>
<li>The challenges in text-based games involving symbolic tasks necessitate interactive multi-step reasoning, and the proposed LLM agent demonstrates superior performance compared to strong baselines, achieving an average performance of 88% across all tasks.</li>
<li>The incorporation of external symbolic modules by the LLM agent leads to enhanced average accuracy compared to other baselines, demonstrating the potential of LLMs in performing symbolic reasoning tasks.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article provides valuable insights into the effective application of LLMs as neurosymbolic reasoners in text-based games involving symbolic tasks. However, several limitations and areas for further exploration can be identified:</p>
<ol type="1">
<li><p><strong>Complexity of Tasks:</strong> While the LLM agent demonstrates strong performance, it faces challenges in certain tasks such as MapReader and Sorting, indicating limitations in its understanding and memory capacity. This highlights the need for further development to address the complexities of diverse scenarios.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Methodological Limitations:</strong> The article acknowledges the need for more detailed prompts to offer greater control over the actions of the LLM agent. This limitation suggests a potential area for improvement in the prompting approach to enhance the system’s performance.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Generalization and Uncertainty:</strong> The LLM agent’s capability to connect with a symbolic module for specific tasks still exhibits uncertainty and is prone to making mistakes, indicating the need for further exploration to improve its generalization and decision-making abilities.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Scope for Future Research:</strong> Integrating more sophisticated symbolic modules and extending the model’s application to more complex domains are highlighted as potential areas for future research to enhance the LLM agent’s problem-solving approach.</p></li>
</ol>
<p>In conclusion, while the article presents promising findings regarding the application of LLMs as neurosymbolic reasoners, it also underscores the need for addressing the limitations identified and conducting further research to fully leverage the potential of LLMs in performing symbolic reasoning tasks in real-world applications.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-18</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09334v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09334v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09334v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09334v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7175</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Large_Language_Models_Are_Neurosymbolic_Reasoners/2024-01-17-Large_Language_Models_Are_Neurosymbolic_Reasoners.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09334v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Material Informatics through Neural Networks on Ab-Initio Electron Charge Densities: the Role of Transfer Learning</title>
  <dc:creator>Dario Massa, Stefanos Papanikolaou, Piotr Sankowski</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Material_Informatics_through_Neural_Networks_on_Ab_Initio_Electron_Charge_Densities_the_Role_of_Transfer_Learning/2024-01-17-Material_Informatics_through_Neural_Networks_on_Ab_Initio_Electron_Charge_Densities_the_Role_of_Transfer_Learning.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Material_Informatics_through_Neural_Networks_on_Ab_Initio_Electron_Charge_Densities_the_Role_of_Transfer_Learning/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09301v1/extracted/5344758/figures/originaldata.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-the-article" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-of-the-article"><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong></h3>
<p>The article explores the role of transfer learning in extracting representations from ab-initio differential electron charge density (ECD) profiles using Neural Networks, particularly in Materials Science. The study demonstrates significant improvements in regression of defected-materials properties through transfer learning techniques and explores the insufficiency of open-models like GPT-4 in achieving similar performances as the proposed domain-specific models. The work also proposes a multimodal approach, combining ECD images and text data for regression tasks on undefected systems, and provides insights into the limitations and potential of transfer learning in complex physical systems.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Transfer Learning: The study highlights the pivotal role of transfer learning in improving the regression of specific defected-materials properties, demonstrating significant enhancements in predictions and reproducibilities by considering pre-trained Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs) and fine-tuning.</li>
<li>Multimodal Approach: The article introduces a multimodal model combining ECD images with text data, showcasing promising performances in regression tasks on a variety of undefected crystals, particularly emphasizing the significance of textual information in enhancing model performances.</li>
<li>Inadequacy of Open-Models: The research provides evidence of the inadequacy of open-models like GPT-4 in performing zero-shot predictions on the multimodal datasets provided to domain-specific multimodal models, emphasizing the need for domain-specific models and benchmarking.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article effectively demonstrates the potential of transfer learning and a multimodal approach in enhancing materials informatics, shedding light on efficient representations extraction without ad-hoc functional building. The critical exploration of open-models’ inadequacy provides valuable insights into the limitations of general-purpose models in domain-specific tasks. However, the article could benefit from clearer explanations of the datasets used and the specific limitations of the open-models. Additionally, while the research methodology is robust, the lack of a comparative analysis with existing literature on similar topics limits the broader context of the findings. Furthermore, the article could have delved deeper into the implications of the study’s findings for future applications and research directions within Materials Science and Machine Learning.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-18</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09301v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09301v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09301v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09301v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7615</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Material_Informatics_through_Neural_Networks_on_Ab_Initio_Electron_Charge_Densities_the_Role_of_Transfer_Learning/2024-01-17-Material_Informatics_through_Neural_Networks_on_Ab_Initio_Electron_Charge_Densities_the_Role_of_Transfer_Learning.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09301v1/extracted/5344758/figures/originaldata.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>AttackEval: How to Evaluate the Effectiveness of Jailbreak Attacking on Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Dong shu, Mingyu Jin, Suiyuan Zhu, Beichen Wang, Zihao Zhou, Chong Zhang, Yongfeng Zhang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/AttackEval_How_to_Evaluate_the_Effectiveness_of_Jailbreak_Attacking_on_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-17-AttackEval_How_to_Evaluate_the_Effectiveness_of_Jailbreak_Attacking_on_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/AttackEval_How_to_Evaluate_the_Effectiveness_of_Jailbreak_Attacking_on_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09002v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-the-article" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-of-the-article">Summary of the Article:</h3>
<p>The research paper explores a new method for evaluating the effectiveness of jailbreak attacks on Large Language Models (LLMs). The authors introduce two novel evaluation frameworks, a coarse-grained evaluation, and a fine-grained evaluation, which provide a more comprehensive and nuanced assessment of attack prompts, using a scoring range from 0 to 1. Additionally, the study presents a ground truth dataset specifically tailored for jailbreak tasks, offering a benchmark for consistent and comparative analysis. The authors compare their evaluation method with traditional approaches and identify a more in-depth analysis without deviating from the baseline trend. The study concludes that their work lays a solid foundation for assessing a wider array of similar or more complex tasks in the realm of prompt injection, potentially revolutionizing this field.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The research pioneers two innovative evaluation frameworks for assessing attack prompts in jailbreak tasks, marking a significant shift from binary robustness evaluations to a more focused analysis of prompt effectiveness.</li>
<li>The study introduces a comprehensive ground truth dataset that serves as a benchmark, enabling researchers to systematically compare LLM responses across different models.</li>
<li>The evaluation method aligns with traditional binary methods, but offers a more detailed and profound analysis, indicating the importance of nuanced assessment in evaluating attack prompts.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article effectively introduces innovative approaches for evaluating jailbreak attacks on Large Language Models and provides a critical benchmark for analysis. However, the paper might overlook emerging or less common attack vectors and the ground truth dataset possibly does not encompass the full spectrum of LLM responses. Additionally, while the study compares its evaluation methods with traditional binary approaches, it would be valuable to delve into the potential limitations and biases associated with the development and implementation of the ground truth dataset and evaluation frameworks. Further research is required to address these limitations and assess the applicability of the presented methodology to a broader range of attack scenarios.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-18</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09002v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09002v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09002v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09002v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8735</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/AttackEval_How_to_Evaluate_the_Effectiveness_of_Jailbreak_Attacking_on_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-17-AttackEval_How_to_Evaluate_the_Effectiveness_of_Jailbreak_Attacking_on_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09002v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Canvil: Designerly Adaptation for LLM-Powered User Experiences</title>
  <dc:creator>K. J. Kevin Feng, Q. Vera Liao, Ziang Xiao, Jennifer Wortman Vaughan, Amy X. Zhang, David W. McDonald</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Canvil_Designerly_Adaptation_for_LLM_Powered_User_Experiences/2024-01-17-Canvil_Designerly_Adaptation_for_LLM_Powered_User_Experiences.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Canvil_Designerly_Adaptation_for_LLM_Powered_User_Experiences/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09051v1/extracted/5352340/canvil-overview.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong></p>
<p>The article discusses the growing role of large language models (LLMs) in shaping user experiences and the need for designers to actively engage with LLMs to ensure responsible and effective user-centered designs. To address this, the practice of “designerly adaptation” is introduced, emphasizing the low technical barrier, leveraging designers’ perspectives, and encouraging iterative model tinkering. The authors present Canvil, a Figma widget that facilitates designerly adaptation by supporting the structured authoring of system prompts, testing adapted models, and integrating model outputs into interface designs. Canvil was utilized in a group-based design study to explore the implications and opportunities of integrating designerly adaptation into design workflows.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Characteristics of Designerly Adaptation:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Low Technical Barrier to Entry:</strong> Designerly adaptation emphasizes the need for a low technical barrier, allowing designers without extensive technical expertise to engage effectively.</li>
<li><strong>Leveraging Designers’ Perspectives:</strong> The practice encourages leveraging designers’ unique viewpoints to bridge user needs and technology and inform model behavior.</li>
<li><strong>Encouraging Model Tinkering:</strong> The adaptation process supports iterative tinkering with models to enhance user interaction and align with user needs.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Canvil as a Technology Probe:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Canvil operationalizes designerly adaptation, allowing for structured authoring of system prompts, model testing, and seamless integration into design workflows.</li>
<li>The tool facilitates collaboration and is designed to align with designers’ mental models and existing design environments.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Implications of Designerly Adaptation:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Through the design study, it was found that designers could effectively steer LLM behavior to align with user needs, derive interface affordances, and collaborate to enhance user interactions.</li>
<li>The study also highlighted the potential for integrating designerly adaptation into design workflows, emphasizing the need for tools that support collaborative AI tinkering and material understanding for designers.</li>
</ul></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article effectively introduces the concept of designerly adaptation and presents Canvil as a practical implementation of this concept. The structured formative study and the subsequent design study provide empirical support for the effectiveness and potential of integrating designerly adaptation into design workflows. However, the article lacks a comprehensive discussion of potential limitations or challenges in implementing designerly adaptation, and it would benefit from addressing ethical considerations and potential biases that may arise from designers’ involvement in model adaptation. Additionally, the generalizability of the findings from the design study to various design contexts and industries could be further explored.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-18</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09051v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09051v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09051v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09051v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>24911</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Canvil_Designerly_Adaptation_for_LLM_Powered_User_Experiences/2024-01-17-Canvil_Designerly_Adaptation_for_LLM_Powered_User_Experiences.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09051v1/extracted/5352340/canvil-overview.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Code Simulation Challenges for Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Emanuele La Malfa, Christoph Weinhuber, Orazio Torre, Fangru Lin, Anthony Cohn, Nigel Shadbolt, Michael Wooldridge</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Code_Simulation_Challenges_for_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-17-Code_Simulation_Challenges_for_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Code_Simulation_Challenges_for_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09074v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong> The article investigates the capabilities of Large Language Models (LLMs) to simulate the execution of computer code and algorithms. It demonstrates that current LLMs struggle to effectively simulate the execution of complex computer code, including straight line programs, algorithms with critical paths and redundant instructions, sorting algorithms, and routines with nested loops. Additionally, it addresses the tension between memorization and code simulation, proposing a novel prompting method, Chain of Simulation (CoSm), to improve code execution simulation when memorization is detrimental.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs struggle with simulating code execution, particularly with longer and more complex programs, demonstrating poor performance with straight line programs and algorithms with critical paths and redundant instructions.</li>
<li>The computational complexity of a routine directly affects an LLM’s ability to simulate its execution, showing a consistent program trace only for short programs and standard procedures.</li>
<li>The proposed Chain of Simulation (CoSm) method improves the standard Chain of Thought prompting approach by avoiding memorization pitfalls and enhancing code execution simulation.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article provides valuable insights into the limitations of LLMs in simulating code execution. However, it does not discuss potential solutions to improve LLMs’ code simulation capabilities, such as advancements in model architecture or training strategies. Additionally, the study primarily focuses on evaluation without proposing methods to enhance LLMs’ performance in code simulation. Further research could explore techniques to mitigate the identified limitations, paving the way for more effective code simulation by LLMs.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-18</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09074v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09074v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09074v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09074v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>9323</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Code_Simulation_Challenges_for_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-17-Code_Simulation_Challenges_for_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09074v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>InternEvo: Efficient Long-sequence Large Language Model Training via Hybrid Parallelism and Redundant Sharding</title>
  <dc:creator>Qiaoling Chen, Diandian Gu, Guoteng Wang, Xun Chen, YingTong Xiong, Ting Huang, Qinghao Hu, Xin Jin, Yonggang Wen, Tianwei Zhang, Peng Sun</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/InternEvo_Efficient_Long_sequence_Large_Language_Model_Training_via_Hybrid_Parallelism_and_Redundant_Sharding/2024-01-17-InternEvo_Efficient_Long_sequence_Large_Language_Model_Training_via_Hybrid_Parallelism_and_Redundant_Sharding.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/InternEvo_Efficient_Long_sequence_Large_Language_Model_Training_via_Hybrid_Parallelism_and_Redundant_Sharding/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09149v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong></p>
<p>The article introduces InternEvo as an efficient framework for training Transformer-based large language models (LLMs) with long sequences, addressing the inefficiency and compatibility issues of existing methods. The framework utilizes a hybrid parallelism strategy, and memory management techniques to optimize training performance, minimize communication overhead, and reduce GPU memory fragmentation.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><p>Large language models (LLMs) with long sequences have become crucial in powering new applications, such as generative AI, long-context understanding, computer vision, and AI for science.</p></li>
<li><p>Existing methods for training LLMs with long sequences, such as 3D parallelism and automatic parallelization frameworks, are inefficient for long-sequence LLM training due to communication overload and memory fragmentation.</p></li>
<li><p>InternEvo effectively addresses these issues by introducing a hierarchical space with four parallel dimensions and three sharding dimensions, enabling efficient parallelization and communication strategies that outperform existing methods in model FLOPs utilization.</p></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article presents a comprehensive and well-structured approach to addressing the challenges associated with training long-sequence LLMs, filling a crucial gap in current methodologies. The proposed InternEvo framework introduces novel strategies, such as hybrid parallelism, selective overlap mechanism, and memory management techniques, which significantly improve training performance and model FLOPs utilization.</p>
<p>However, while the article highlights the successful implementation of the InternEvo framework and provides evidence of its superior performance, it may benefit from a deeper exploration of potential limitations and challenges. For instance, a critical analysis of the scalability and generalizability of the InternEvo framework across different hardware configurations, model sizes, and types of large language models could provide valuable insights. Additionally, further discussion on potential trade-offs and trade-offs of the proposed strategies, as well as comparison with other state-of-the-art frameworks, could enhance the understanding of the framework’s strengths and limitations.</p>
<p>Overall, the article provides a valuable contribution to the field of large language model training and offers a promising framework in InternEvo. However, a more comprehensive assessment of potential limitations and broader applicability could further strengthen the credibility and applicability of the proposed framework.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-18</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09149v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09149v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09149v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09149v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>16209</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/InternEvo_Efficient_Long_sequence_Large_Language_Model_Training_via_Hybrid_Parallelism_and_Redundant_Sharding/2024-01-17-InternEvo_Efficient_Long_sequence_Large_Language_Model_Training_via_Hybrid_Parallelism_and_Redundant_Sharding.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09149v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Understanding the concerns and choices of public when using large language models for healthcare</title>
  <dc:creator>Yunpeng Xiao, Kyrie Zhixuan Zhou, Yueqing Liang, Kai Shu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Understanding_the_concerns_and_choices_of_public_when_using_large_language_models_for_healthcare/2024-01-17-Understanding_the_concerns_and_choices_of_public_when_using_large_language_models_for_healthcare.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Understanding_the_concerns_and_choices_of_public_when_using_large_language_models_for_healthcare/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09090v1/extracted/5352531/images/searchLLM.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-the-article" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-of-the-article">Summary of the Article:</h3>
<p>The article examines the public’s use of Large Language Models (LLMs) for healthcare purposes and investigates their motivations, concerns, and choices regarding obtaining healthcare information. It utilizes a mixed-methods approach, including surveys and interviews, to understand how LLMs are being used and the impact they have on public health and doctor-patient relationships.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Use of LLMs for Healthcare Purposes</strong>:
<ul>
<li>LLMs, such as ChatGPT, have gained popularity and are used for medical Q&amp;A, self-diagnosis, and daily healthcare information seeking.</li>
<li>LLMs are often used in combination with other information channels such as search engines and online health communities to optimize information quality.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Advantages of LLMs</strong>:
<ul>
<li>LLMs provide more accurate and convenient healthcare information compared to traditional channels.</li>
<li>LLMs are perceived to reduce misinformation, especially in daily healthcare questions.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Doctor-Patient Relationship</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Public acceptance of doctors using LLMs for diagnosis is less compared to using LLMs for auxiliary work such as writing medical records.</li>
</ul></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article successfully sheds light on the public’s use of LLMs for healthcare, uncovering motivations, concerns, and choices. However, some limitations should be noted: - The study primarily includes a younger demographic and is limited to specific racial groups, potentially overlooking diverse needs and challenges in healthcare information seeking. - The qualitative analysis of the survey data might benefit from more rigorous quantitative analysis to uncover correlations and patterns. - The article’s recommendations emphasize the need for transparency and accountability when using LLMs for healthcare, but it may not fully address the potential biases or ethical considerations involved in the use of AI-driven healthcare solutions.</p>
<p>This article provides valuable insights into the public’s interaction with LLMs for healthcare. A more comprehensive understanding of the demographic and ethical implications, along with a deeper quantitative analysis, would further enhance the study’s significance.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-18</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09090v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09090v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09090v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09090v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>11252</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Understanding_the_concerns_and_choices_of_public_when_using_large_language_models_for_healthcare/2024-01-17-Understanding_the_concerns_and_choices_of_public_when_using_large_language_models_for_healthcare.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09090v1/extracted/5352531/images/searchLLM.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Stuck in the Quicksand of Numeracy, Far from AGI Summit: Evaluating LLMs’ Mathematical Competency through Ontology-guided Perturbations</title>
  <dc:creator>Pengfei Hong, Deepanway Ghosal, Navonil Majumder, Somak Aditya, Rada Mihalcea, Soujanya Poria</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Stuck_in_the_Quicksand_of_Numeracy_Far_from_AGI_Summit_Evaluating_LLMs_Mathematical_Competency_through_Ontology_guided_Perturbations/2024-01-17-Stuck_in_the_Quicksand_of_Numeracy_Far_from_AGI_Summit_Evaluating_LLMs_Mathematical_Competency_through_Ontology_guided_Perturbations.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Stuck_in_the_Quicksand_of_Numeracy_Far_from_AGI_Summit_Evaluating_LLMs_Mathematical_Competency_through_Ontology_guided_Perturbations/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09395v1/x2.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-the-article" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-of-the-article">Summary of the Article:</h3>
<p>The article evaluates the mathematical competency of Large Language Models (LLMs) by developing an ontology of perturbations for math questions, using the GPT-4 model to generate a dataset of 216 perturbed math problems, and conducting a comprehensive evaluation of LLMs on these perturbed questions. The results reveal a significant performance drop across all LLM models, suggesting their lack of robust mathematical skills and deep reasoning abilities. The researchers propose a novel extensive extensible ontology of perturbation operations and provide a way to semi-automatically create such perturbations. They benchmark five state-of-the-art LLMs’ numeracy abilities on the dataset and observe how these models can be fragile, exposing their limitations in reasoning. The article emphasizes the importance of assessing the mathematical problem-solving and analytical capabilities of LLMs beyond conventional leaderboard performance metrics.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Controlled perturbations of math questions using the ontology resulted in a dataset of 216 perturbed math problems.</li>
<li>Comprehensive evaluation of LLMs on the perturbed questions showed a significant performance drop across all models, indicating their lack of robust mathematical skills and deep reasoning abilities.</li>
<li>The proposed ontology of perturbation operations and the dataset pave the way for a fresh perspective in assessing the mathematical problem-solving and analytical capabilities of LLMs.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article effectively addresses the limitations of current LLMs’ mathematical reasoning abilities through a well-structured methodology. However, the reliance on GPT-4 for generating perturbed questions raises concerns about the quality and accuracy of the perturbations, which are acknowledged in the filtering and validation process. The human verification process ensures improved quality and relevance of the perturbed questions, but the potential impact of human bias in rephrasing or rewriting the questions should be considered. Additionally, the article lacks information about the specific limitations and weaknesses observed in different LLM models, which could provide more insights into their mathematical reasoning capabilities. Further research could focus on refining the perturbation process and exploring alternative methods for evaluating LLMs’ mathematical competencies to enhance the validity of the findings.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-18</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09395v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09395v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09395v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09395v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>17363</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Stuck_in_the_Quicksand_of_Numeracy_Far_from_AGI_Summit_Evaluating_LLMs_Mathematical_Competency_through_Ontology_guided_Perturbations/2024-01-17-Stuck_in_the_Quicksand_of_Numeracy_Far_from_AGI_Summit_Evaluating_LLMs_Mathematical_Competency_through_Ontology_guided_Perturbations.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09395v1/x2.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Vlogger: Make Your Dream A Vlog</title>
  <dc:creator>Shaobin Zhuang, Kunchang Li, Xinyuan Chen, Yaohui Wang, Ziwei Liu, Yu Qiao, Yali Wang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Vlogger_Make_Your_Dream_A_Vlog/2024-01-17-Vlogger_Make_Your_Dream_A_Vlog.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Vlogger_Make_Your_Dream_A_Vlog/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09414v1/x2.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="section" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section"></h3>
<p><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong> The article presents Vlogger, an AI system designed to generate minute-level video blogs (vlogs) from user descriptions. Vlogger utilizes a Large Language Model (LLM) to decompose the vlog generation task into four key stages: Script, Actor, ShowMaker, and Voicer. The system uses a top-down planning approach with the LLM Director to convert user stories into scripts, designs actors, and generates video snippets for each shooting scene. Vlogger incorporates a novel video diffusion model, ShowMaker, to enhance spatial-temporal coherence in each snippet. The extensive experiments demonstrate that Vlogger achieves state-of-the-art performance on zero-shot T2V generation and prediction tasks, and it can generate over 5-minute vlogs without losing video coherence.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Vlogger leverages LLM as Director to decompose vlog generation into four key stages: Script, Actor, ShowMaker, and Voicer.</li>
<li>The system uses a top-down planning approach and a novel video diffusion model, ShowMaker, to enhance spatial-temporal coherence in each video snippet.</li>
<li>Extensive experiments show that Vlogger achieves state-of-the-art performance on zero-shot T2V generation and prediction tasks and can generate over 5-minute vlogs without losing video coherence.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article presents an innovative approach to AI-based vlog generation, showcasing impressive results in state-of-the-art performance and the capability to generate coherent vlogs from open-world descriptions. However, several potential concerns or limitations can be identified:</p>
<ul>
<li><p>Data and Model Availability: Although the article claims that the code and model will be made available, the availability and accessibility of the resources are crucial for the reproducibility and applicability of Vlogger in various domains. It is essential to ensure that the code and models are well-documented and easily accessible for broader adoption and research purposes.</p></li>
<li><p>Evaluation Considerations: While the extensive experiments show promising results, it is important to consider the diversity of user stories and content types when evaluating the performance of Vlogger. The robustness and generalizability of the system across various vlog genres and user demographics should be further explored.</p></li>
<li><p>Ethical Considerations: The use of AI systems for content generation raises ethical considerations, especially regarding the potential for misuse, misinformation, or deepfakes. The article could benefit from discussing the ethical implications of automated vlog generation and addressing potential safeguards against misuse.</p></li>
<li><p>Interpretability and Bias: As the system leverages LLM and various foundation models, it is crucial to consider the interpretability of the generated vlogs and potential biases in script creation, actor design, and video generation. Transparency and fairness in the content generation process are essential for maintaining trust and credibility.</p></li>
</ul>
<p>In conclusion, while Vlogger demonstrates significant advancements in AI-based vlog generation, addressing the potential limitations and ethical considerations will be crucial for the responsible development and deployment of such systems. Further research and development in these areas will be beneficial for realizing the full potential of AI systems in content creation.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-18</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09414v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09414v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09414v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09414v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8506</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Vlogger_Make_Your_Dream_A_Vlog/2024-01-17-Vlogger_Make_Your_Dream_A_Vlog.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09414v1/x2.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Augmenting Math Word Problems via Iterative Question Composing</title>
  <dc:creator>Haoxiong Liu, Andrew Chi-Chih Yao</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Augmenting_Math_Word_Problems_via_Iterative_Question_Composing/2024-01-17-Augmenting_Math_Word_Problems_via_Iterative_Question_Composing.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Augmenting_Math_Word_Problems_via_Iterative_Question_Composing/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09003v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong> The article introduces the MMIQC dataset and the IQC (Iterative Question Composing) method to equip large language models with improved mathematical reasoning skills. It highlights the Mistral-7B-MMIQC model’s achievement of 36.0% accuracy on the MATH benchmark, which is 5.8% higher than the previous state-of-the-art (SOTA) model. The paper combines high-quality corpora used in pre-training and synthetic question-response pairs to improve model performance. The IQC method, which iteratively asks language models to compose new questions from seed problems and uses rejection sampling, contributes significantly to this improvement.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Mistral-7B-MMIQC achieved 36.0% accuracy on MATH, surpassing the previous SOTA model by 5.8%.</li>
<li>The novel augmentation method IQC, which iteratively asks language models to compose new questions from seed problems and uses rejection sampling, significantly improves the model’s performance.</li>
<li>The article demonstrates that using multiple augmentation methods to construct datasets for fine-tuning is an efficient way to boost the performance of large language models.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article makes significant contributions by introducing the MMIQC dataset and the IQC method, resulting in improved mathematical reasoning skills for large language models. However, the evaluation focuses solely on the MATH benchmark, raising questions about the generalizability of the findings to other mathematical problem-solving tasks. Additionally, the potential algorithmic biases or limitations of relying on large language models for mathematical problem-solving should be addressed, especially with regard to diverse representation and interpretability issues. Further research could explore the potential ethical implications and societal impacts of using such models for complex reasoning tasks. Moreover, the article acknowledges the performance gap between open-source models and advanced close-source models, but a deeper exploration of the reasons and implications of this gap would enhance the article’s critical analysis.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-18</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09003v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09003v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09003v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09003v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>4740</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Augmenting_Math_Word_Problems_via_Iterative_Question_Composing/2024-01-17-Augmenting_Math_Word_Problems_via_Iterative_Question_Composing.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09003v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Whispering Pixels: Exploiting Uninitialized Register Accesses in Modern GPUs</title>
  <dc:creator>Frederik Dermot Pustelnik, Xhani Marvin Saß, Jean-Pierre Seifert</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Whispering_Pixels_Exploiting_Uninitialized_Register_Accesses_in_Modern_GPUs/2024-01-16-Whispering_Pixels_Exploiting_Uninitialized_Register_Accesses_in_Modern_GPUs.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Whispering_Pixels_Exploiting_Uninitialized_Register_Accesses_in_Modern_GPUs/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.08881v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-the-article" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-of-the-article"><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong></h3>
<p>The article discusses a new vulnerability class in Graphic Processing Units (GPUs) that allows leaked data from previously executed shader kernels due to improper register initialization routines. The vulnerability affects products from major vendors such as Apple, NVIDIA, and Qualcomm. The paper showcases the real-world impact of the flaw, including leaking arbitrary pixel data in fragment shaders and attacking Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs) and Large Language Models (LLMs).</p>
<p>The article also provides insights into GPU architectures, the rendering pipeline, General Purpose Computation for GPUs (GPGPU), vendor differences, and discusses the threat model. Additionally, it presents the attack procedure, challenges, and evaluation of the attack performance for various scenarios, including leaking fragment shader data, Convolutional Neural Networks, and Large Language Models. Countermeasures to mitigate the vulnerability are also proposed.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The discovery of a vulnerability in GPUs that leads to unintended register content leakage of previously executed shader kernels.</li>
<li>Showcasing the real-world impact of the vulnerability, including leaking pixel data, attacking CNNs, and extracting information from Large Language Models.</li>
<li>Proposal of multiple countermeasures against the presented attacks.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article provides comprehensive insights into the vulnerability of uninitialized register access in GPUs and its real-world implications. However, the paper focuses primarily on demonstrating the exploitation of the vulnerability and proposes countermeasures without delving deeply into the practical implementation of the suggested solutions. Additionally, the article lacks a thorough discussion of the potential implications of the vulnerability on data privacy and security, such as specific examples of how private user data could be compromised. Furthermore, the article does not provide empirical evidence of the success of the proposed countermeasures, and further evaluation is necessary to ascertain their effectiveness.</p>
<p>The article would benefit from a more detailed analysis of the potential impact of the vulnerability on end-users and recommendations for mitigating its effects, especially from a practical implementation standpoint. Additionally, further research is needed to evaluate the proposed countermeasures in real-world scenarios to provide a comprehensive understanding of their practical implications.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-18</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.08881v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.08881v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.08881v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.08881v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>15852</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Whispering_Pixels_Exploiting_Uninitialized_Register_Accesses_in_Modern_GPUs/2024-01-16-Whispering_Pixels_Exploiting_Uninitialized_Register_Accesses_in_Modern_GPUs.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.08881v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>HuixiangDou: Overcoming Group Chat Scenarios with LLM-based Technical Assistance</title>
  <dc:creator>Huanjun Kong, Songyang Zhang, Kai Chen</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/HuixiangDou_Overcoming_Group_Chat_Scenarios_with_LLM_based_Technical_Assistance/2024-01-16-HuixiangDou_Overcoming_Group_Chat_Scenarios_with_LLM_based_Technical_Assistance.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/HuixiangDou_Overcoming_Group_Chat_Scenarios_with_LLM_based_Technical_Assistance/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.08772v1/extracted/5318483/baseline.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-the-article" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-of-the-article">Summary of the Article:</h3>
<p>This article presents HuixiangDou, a technical assistant powered by Large Language Models (LLM), designed to assist with open-source algorithm projects such as computer vision and deep learning projects from OpenMMLab. The article outlines the challenges of integrating such assistants into instant messaging group chats and discusses the evolution of the approach, from the baseline version to the improved and final versions. It also details the experiments conducted to fine-tune the models and evaluate their performance in group chat scenarios.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The Evolution of Approach
<ul>
<li>Baseline version suffered from hallucination issues, which led to the development of improved and final versions to address this challenge.</li>
<li>The improved version focused on refuse-to-answer scenarios, utilizing Reject and Response Pipelines to filter out non-technical content and improve precision in answering technical queries.</li>
<li>The final version enhanced the long context capability of the chat model, extended the Response Pipeline, and incorporated security measures to ensure safe and reliable interactions.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Experiments Conducted
<ul>
<li>Baseline fine-tuned models experienced issues with hallucinations, leading to insights on data quality issues and challenges in achieving accurate domain-specific responses.</li>
<li>RAG in Reject Pipeline and LLM Scoring were utilized to determine the likelihood of a query being a question, refine refusal response precision, and evaluate the relevance between questions and background.</li>
<li>Long Context and LLM Paging experiments focused on maximizing the capability of models to handle extensive and complex queries in group chat scenarios.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Limitations and Future Work
<ul>
<li>Identified limitations include difficulties in understanding professional user queries, the need for further pretraining, the loss of contextual information through message division, and the inability to support multimodal queries with images.</li>
</ul></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article provides a comprehensive overview of the challenges and iterative improvements in developing a technical assistant for group chat scenarios. However, it does not extensively discuss the ethical implications and user perspective of integrating such assistants into instant messaging platforms. Additionally, the experiments and solutions presented are primarily focused on technical aspects, with limited discussion on user experience and potential biases that could arise from the use of such assistants. The article also lacks a comparative analysis with existing solutions, which could provide a clearer understanding of the novel contributions of HuixiangDou. Further research is needed to address the identified limitations and improve the usability and reliability of the technical assistant in real-world group chat settings.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-18</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.08772v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.08772v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.08772v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.08772v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5437</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/HuixiangDou_Overcoming_Group_Chat_Scenarios_with_LLM_based_Technical_Assistance/2024-01-16-HuixiangDou_Overcoming_Group_Chat_Scenarios_with_LLM_based_Technical_Assistance.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.08772v1/extracted/5318483/baseline.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Segment Anything Model Can Not Segment Anything: Assessing AI Foundation Model’s Generalizability in Permafrost Mapping</title>
  <dc:creator>Wenwen Li, Chia-Yu Hsu, Sizhe Wang, Yezhou Yang, Hyunho Lee, Anna Liljedahl, Chandi Witharana, Yili Yang, Brendan M. Rogers, Samantha T. Arundel, Matthew B. Jones, Kenton McHenry, Patricia Solis</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Segment_Anything_Model_Can_Not_Segment_Anything_Assessing_AI_Foundation_Models_Generalizability_in_Permafrost_Mapping/2024-01-16-Segment_Anything_Model_Can_Not_Segment_Anything_Assessing_AI_Foundation_Models_Generalizability_in_Permafrost_Mapping.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Segment_Anything_Model_Can_Not_Segment_Anything_Assessing_AI_Foundation_Models_Generalizability_in_Permafrost_Mapping/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.08787v1/extracted/5351243/figures/fig_sam_clip_arch.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-the-article" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-of-the-article">Summary of the Article:</h3>
<p>This paper evaluates the performance of a trending AI foundation model, Segment Anything Model (SAM), in the context of natural landscape feature segmentation, specifically in permafrost mapping. SAM, designed for image segmentation, is assessed using instance segmentation pipelines and a series of prompt strategies to minimize changes to the model. The evaluation is conducted using challenging permafrost feature datasets, ice-wedge polygons, and retrogressive thaw slumps. The findings indicate that while SAM shows promise, there is room for improvement to support AI-augmented terrain mapping, especially for challenging natural features. The paper also discusses the spatial and domain generalizability of the findings and presents future research directions to enhance SAM’s applicability in challenging geospatial domains.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>SAM’s Zero-shot Performance: SAM’s performance in zero-shot prediction, knowledge-embedded learning, and instance segmentation is evaluated. The results show a relatively low performance when no prior knowledge is provided, indicating the need for domain-specific adaptation.</li>
<li>Strengths in Domain Adaptation: SAM demonstrates strong domain adaptation capabilities through fine-tuning, showcasing potential for improved performance with additional training on domain datasets. However, the performance gap between SAM and supervised learning models is more prominent when dealing with challenging natural features.</li>
<li>Evaluation on General Datasets: The performance of SAM is also assessed using EuroCrop dataset for agricultural field mapping. While SAM’s performance is relatively low when used alone, integrating SAM with CLIP and providing prior knowledge, such as ground truth BBOX, demonstrates significant improvements in segmentation accuracy.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article provides a thorough evaluation of SAM’s performance in geospatial vision tasks, emphasizing its potential for domain adaptation through fine-tuning and prior knowledge. However, the paper acknowledges limitations in SAM’s zero-shot learning and instance segmentation capabilities for challenging natural features. The article presents meaningful insights and practical experimentation, but it would benefit from a more comprehensive discussion of potential biases, limitations in data representation, and the applicability of SAM in diverse geographical contexts. Additionally, expanding SAM’s representations through inclusion of benchmark natural feature datasets and further enhancing its data modalities may improve its performance in geospatial applications.</p>
<p>The critical analysis could have been further strengthened by acknowledging potential biases in data representation, issues related to data collection, and limitations in the proposed framework. Furthermore, a comparative analysis with other vision foundation models and a detailed exploration of SAM’s generalizability to different geospatial problems would enhance the article.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-18</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.08787v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.08787v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.08787v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.08787v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>11457</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Segment_Anything_Model_Can_Not_Segment_Anything_Assessing_AI_Foundation_Models_Generalizability_in_Permafrost_Mapping/2024-01-16-Segment_Anything_Model_Can_Not_Segment_Anything_Assessing_AI_Foundation_Models_Generalizability_in_Permafrost_Mapping.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.08787v1/extracted/5351243/figures/fig_sam_clip_arch.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>SpecGen: Automated Generation of Formal Program Specifications via Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Lezhi Ma, Shangqing Liu, Yi Li, Xiaofei Xie, Lei Bu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SpecGen_Automated_Generation_of_Formal_Program_Specifications_via_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-16-SpecGen_Automated_Generation_of_Formal_Program_Specifications_via_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SpecGen_Automated_Generation_of_Formal_Program_Specifications_via_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.08807v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-the-article" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-of-the-article"><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong></h3>
<p>In “SpecGen: Automated Generation of Formal Program Specifications via Large Language Models,” the authors address the challenge of manually crafting formal program specifications, which is labor-intensive and often results in simplistic specifications that struggle to accurately capture complex program behaviors. To alleviate this burden, they introduce SpecGen, a novel technique for formal program specification generation based on Large Language Models (LLMs). SpecGen aims to leverage LLMs’ code comprehension capabilities to overcome the limitations of existing methods. The process of SpecGen consists of two phases: the conversational approach, which guides the LLM to generate appropriate specifications, and the mutation-based approach, which applies mutation operators to model-generated specifications and employs a heuristic selection strategy to obtain verified specifications. The authors evaluate the effectiveness of SpecGen using a dataset of 120 Java programs. The experimental results demonstrate that SpecGen outperforms existing approaches in generating verifiable specifications for complex programs by achieving a success rate of 100 out of 120 programs.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>SpecGen successfully generated verifiable specifications for 100 out of 120 Java programs, outperforming existing purely LLM-based approaches and conventional specification generation tools like Houdini and Daikon.</li>
<li>The conversational approach effectively guides LLMs to generate accurate and comprehensive specifications, which contributes to the improvement of success probability.</li>
<li>Mutation-based specification generation, coupled with a heuristic selection strategy, significantly improves the efficiency of generating and verifying specifications, particularly for complex programs with loop structures.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<p>The article presents an innovative approach, SpecGen, that addresses the challenges of manual formal program specification generation by leveraging Large Language Models. The use of LLMs to automate the generation of formal program specifications represents a significant advancement in the field of software engineering. The experimental results demonstrate the effectiveness of SpecGen in generating accurate and comprehensive specifications for complex Java programs. However, the article could benefit from a more in-depth discussion of potential limitations or challenges associated with the use of LLMs in program specification generation. One potential challenge is the interpretability and explainability of the specifications generated by LLMs, which could be crucial for ensuring trustworthiness and usability in practical software development scenarios. Additionally, the article does not address potential ethical considerations or biases in the LLMs’ training data, which could impact the quality and fairness of the generated specifications. Further research and discussion on these areas would enhance the completeness of the article.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-18</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.08807v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.08807v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.08807v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.08807v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>13756</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>programming</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SpecGen_Automated_Generation_of_Formal_Program_Specifications_via_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-16-SpecGen_Automated_Generation_of_Formal_Program_Specifications_via_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.08807v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Stability Analysis of ChatGPT-based Sentiment Analysis in AI Quality Assurance</title>
  <dc:creator>Tinghui Ouyang, AprilPyone MaungMaung, Koichi Konishi, Yoshiki Seo, Isao Echizen</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Stability_Analysis_of_ChatGPT_based_Sentiment_Analysis_in_AI_Quality_Assurance/2024-01-15-Stability_Analysis_of_ChatGPT_based_Sentiment_Analysis_in_AI_Quality_Assurance.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Stability_Analysis_of_ChatGPT_based_Sentiment_Analysis_in_AI_Quality_Assurance/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.07441v1/extracted/5347321/fig11.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong></p>
<p>The paper delves into the quality assurance of a large language model (LLM) – specifically, a ChatGPT-based sentiment analysis system. It discusses the challenges posed by the complex architecture and vast parameters of LLM-based AI products, such as ChatGPT, and emphasizes the importance of AI quality management (AIQM) in ensuring the reliability and effectiveness of such products. The study comprises stability and robustness analyses, focusing on the uncertainty and operational factors, as well as the robustness of the ChatGPT-based sentiment analysis system against four types of perturbations. Experimental analysis using benchmark sentiment analysis datasets reveals uncertainty in the operation of ChatGPT and demonstrates its stability issues in handling conventional attacks.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><p><strong>Uncertainty in Operation:</strong> The study identifies uncertainty issues in the running of ChatGPT, attributed to factors such as non-deterministic responses, differences between using ChatGPT on the web and using the ChatGPT API, variance due to timing, and prompt engineering. These operational factors contribute to the instability of the system.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Robustness Analysis:</strong> The paper evaluates the robustness of the ChatGPT-based sentiment analysis system against four types of perturbations – typo, synonym, homoglyph, and homophone. The results demonstrate the system’s relatively good robustness against these perturbations, with synonym perturbation posing the strongest attack.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Quality Assurance Conclusions:</strong> The study concludes that the ChatGPT-based sentiment analysis system is robust against adversarial text perturbations, albeit exhibiting uncertainty due to continuous updates, timing differences, and other operational factors.</p></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article provides valuable insights into the stability and robustness of the ChatGPT-based sentiment analysis system. However, it focuses primarily on specific operational and robustness issues without deeply exploring potential solutions or mitigation strategies for the identified problems. Furthermore, while the study offers essential findings for AI quality management, it could benefit from discussing the broader implications of these stability and robustness issues for AI-based products and potential strategies to address them. Additionally, the limitations of the study, such as the specific focus on the ChatGPT-based sentiment analysis system and the need for broader applicability, require further consideration. While the study raises critical points relevant to AIQM, it would benefit from addressing these potential shortcomings and providing a more comprehensive outlook on the topic.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-17</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.07441v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.07441v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.07441v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.07441v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7475</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Stability_Analysis_of_ChatGPT_based_Sentiment_Analysis_in_AI_Quality_Assurance/2024-01-15-Stability_Analysis_of_ChatGPT_based_Sentiment_Analysis_in_AI_Quality_Assurance.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.07441v1/extracted/5347321/fig11.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Active Learning for NLP with Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Xuesong Wang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Active_Learning_for_NLP_with_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-14-Active_Learning_for_NLP_with_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Active_Learning_for_NLP_with_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.07367v1/extracted/5347142/cost_by_gpt_3.5.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-the-article" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-of-the-article">Summary of the Article:</h3>
<p>The article explores the use of Large Language Models (LLMs) for annotating samples in Active Learning (AL) to reduce labeling costs and enhance sample efficiency, particularly for Natural Language Processing (NLP) tasks. The study investigates the accuracy and cost of using LLMs, specifically GPT-3.5 and GPT-4, to label samples on different datasets. A mixed annotation strategy is proposed, combining LLM and human annotations, and its performance under various AL settings is evaluated. The results suggest that using LLMs as annotators in AL settings can be cost-efficient while maintaining high accuracy levels, showing potential for reducing annotation costs.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs, particularly GPT-3.5 and GPT-4, demonstrate cost efficiency and reasonable accuracy when used for annotating samples in AL, offering potential for reducing labeling costs.</li>
<li>A mixed annotation strategy, combining LLM and human annotations, yields similar or better results compared to using human annotations only, particularly on tasks such as news topic and movie review classifications.</li>
<li>The proposed consistency-based label fixing strategy shows potential for improving the accuracy of AL models by utilizing LLM annotations and correcting incorrectly labeled samples with human annotations.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article provides valuable insights into the potential of LLMs for annotating samples in AL, offering cost efficiency and maintaining accuracy. However, there are some limitations and potential areas for further investigation: - It’s important to acknowledge that the study is based on a limited number of experiments and runs, potentially requiring further validation and replication to ensure the generalizability of the findings. - The potential biases or limitations associated with using GPT-3.5 and GPT-4, such as their performance on new datasets and their behavior on specific tasks like question classification, deserve further investigation to ensure the robustness of the proposed approach. - The article does not address the ethical implications of relying on LLMs for annotation, including concerns related to bias, fairness, and transparency in the labeling process. Further research should consider addressing these ethical considerations when implementing LLMs in AL settings.</p>
<p>Overall, while the article presents promising findings regarding the use of LLMs in AL for NLP tasks, further research and comprehensive validation are necessary to fully assess the effectiveness and potential limitations of this approach.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-17</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.07367v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.07367v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.07367v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.07367v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>4673</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Active_Learning_for_NLP_with_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-14-Active_Learning_for_NLP_with_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.07367v1/extracted/5347142/cost_by_gpt_3.5.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>PersonalityChat: Conversation Distillation for Personalized Dialog Modeling with Facts and Traits</title>
  <dc:creator>Ehsan Lotfi, Maxime De Bruyn, Jeska Buhmann, Walter Daelemans</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/PersonalityChat_Conversation_Distillation_for_Personalized_Dialog_Modeling_with_Facts_and_Traits/2024-01-14-PersonalityChat_Conversation_Distillation_for_Personalized_Dialog_Modeling_with_Facts_and_Traits.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/PersonalityChat_Conversation_Distillation_for_Personalized_Dialog_Modeling_with_Facts_and_Traits/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.07363v1/extracted/5347114/imgs/personalitychat-pipe.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong> The article explores the use of Large Language Models (LLMs) to create a synthetic conversational dataset, PersonalityChat, personalized with both personas and Big-5 personality traits. The paper highlights the potential of LLMs in refining conversation datasets for personalized dialog models, demonstrating that personality traits can be utilized for personalized dialog modeling. Furthermore, the study compares the performance of models trained on the distilled PersonalityChat dataset with those trained on the crowd-sourced PersonaChat dataset, showing improved fluency and coherence in the small-model regime.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Creation of PersonalityChat Dataset:</strong>
<ul>
<li>PersonalityChat is a synthetic conversational dataset based on the popular PersonaChat dataset, conditioned on both personas and Big-5 personality traits.</li>
<li>The use of LLMs to predict personality traits for personas enables the curation of a dataset explicitly grounded in personality characteristics.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Trait-Based Personalization:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The study demonstrates that personality trait labels can influence and modify the ‘attitude’ of a dialog agent, showing the potential for trait-based personalization of generative dialogue models.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Performance Comparison:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Training on the distilled PersonalityChat dataset results in more fluent and coherent dialog agents in the small-model regime compared to training on the crowd-sourced PersonaChat dataset.</li>
</ul></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article effectively demonstrates the value of using LLMs to create a personalized conversational dataset and highlights the potential for utilizing personality traits in dialog modeling, offering insights into improving the performance of dialogue agents. However, some limitations should be considered, such as: 1. <strong>Biases and Limitations in Data Curation:</strong> The use of LLMs for dataset curation introduces potential biases, leading to less diverse and more predictable language distribution, which could affect the quality and diversity of the generated conversations. 2. <strong>Model Behavior and Trait Incorporation:</strong> The article acknowledges that while the models’ behavior can be influenced by trait labels, there is still room for improvement in incorporating traits into the generated dialogs, suggesting a need for further research and refinement. 3. <strong>Evaluation Limitations:</strong> The evaluation process, mainly relying on automatic metrics and single-trait labels, may not fully capture the models’ real-world conversational behavior and their responses to multiple trait labels.</p>
<p>In conclusion, while the article presents valuable findings, the study acknowledges certain shortcomings and areas for further development, including addressing biases in dataset curation and improving the incorporation of personality traits into the dialog agents’ responses. Future research could focus on refining dialog modeling techniques and enhancing the naturalness and coherence of personalized dialogue generation.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-17</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.07363v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.07363v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.07363v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.07363v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7867</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/PersonalityChat_Conversation_Distillation_for_Personalized_Dialog_Modeling_with_Facts_and_Traits/2024-01-14-PersonalityChat_Conversation_Distillation_for_Personalized_Dialog_Modeling_with_Facts_and_Traits.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.07363v1/extracted/5347114/imgs/personalitychat-pipe.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Towards Conversational Diagnostic AI</title>
  <dc:creator>Tao Tu, Anil Palepu, Mike Schaekermann, Khaled Saab, Jan Freyberg, Ryutaro Tanno, Amy Wang, Brenna Li, Mohamed Amin, Nenad Tomasev, Shekoofeh Azizi, Karan Singhal, Yong Cheng, Le Hou, Albert Webson, Kavita Kulkarni, S Sara Mahdavi, Christopher Semturs, Juraj Gottweis, Joelle Barral, Katherine Chou, Greg S Corrado, Yossi Matias, Alan Karthikesalingam, Vivek Natarajan</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Towards_Conversational_Diagnostic_AI/2024-01-11-Towards_Conversational_Diagnostic_AI.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Towards_Conversational_Diagnostic_AI/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05654v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary</h3>
<p>In the paper “Towards Conversational Diagnostic AI,” the authors introduce AMIE, an AI system optimized for diagnostic dialogue. They compare AMIE’s performance to that of primary care physicians (PCPs) in a study of text-based consultations with simulated patient actors. The study finds that AMIE demonstrated greater diagnostic accuracy and superior performance on several axes according to specialist physicians and patient actors. The evaluation framework encompasses history-taking, diagnostic accuracy, management reasoning, communication skills, and empathy. Additionally, the authors detail the datasets used to develop AMIE, including medical reasoning, long-form medical question answering, medical summarization, and real-world dialogue datasets. They describe a simulated learning environment for diagnostic dialogues, a self-play framework for iterative improvement, instruction fine-tuning, and a chain-of-reasoning strategy for online inference.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The AI system, AMIE, showed greater <strong>diagnostic accuracy</strong> and <strong>superior performance</strong> in multiple axes compared to primary care physicians in simulated text-based consultations.</li>
<li>AMIE was able to achieve higher conversation quality by surpassing PCPs in patient actor and specialist physician evaluations for various axes, including communication skills and empathy.</li>
<li>The study introduced a novel self-play environment for learning, and a chain-of-reasoning strategy for online inference, which significantly contributed to AMIE’s performance and capabilities.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="methods-and-results" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="methods-and-results">Methods and Results</h3>
<section id="amie-an-llm-based-ai-system-for-diagnostic-dialogue" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="amie-an-llm-based-ai-system-for-diagnostic-dialogue">AMIE: An LLM based AI System for Diagnostic Dialogue</h4>
<ul>
<li>The authors used diverse real-world datasets for training AMIE, including medical reasoning, long-form medical question answering, medical summarization, and real-world dialogue datasets.</li>
<li>They developed a simulated dialogue learning environment with a self-play framework for iterative improvement, an instruction fine-tuning process, and a chain-of-reasoning strategy for online inference.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="objective-structured-clinical-examination" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="objective-structured-clinical-examination">Objective Structured Clinical Examination</h4>
<ul>
<li>The study involved 20 PCPs and 20 validated patient actors in a randomized, double-blind crossover study with 149 case scenarios.</li>
<li>AMIE’s consultations outperformed PCPs in terms of <strong>conversation quality</strong> across multiple axes, as assessed by both patient actors and specialist physicians.</li>
</ul>
</section>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<p>The study has several limitations, including the use of a text-chat interface, which may not be representative of usual clinical consultation settings. The simulated patient actors may not fully reflect the complexity and nuances of real patients, and the study design may not fully capture the challenges of real-world clinical dialogue. Future research should aim to address these limitations and further validate AMIE’s performance in real-world clinical practice.</p>
<p>Overall, the paper contributes to the development of conversational diagnostic AI systems and highlights the potential of AI in improving the quality and accuracy of medical consultations. However, it is important to consider the limitations and contextual factors related to the study design and evaluation. More research is needed to translate AMIE to real-world clinical settings and to validate its performance in diverse healthcare contexts.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-12</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05654v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05654v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05654v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05654v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>18673</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Towards_Conversational_Diagnostic_AI/2024-01-11-Towards_Conversational_Diagnostic_AI.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05654v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Mutation-based Consistency Testing for Evaluating the Code Understanding Capability of LLMs</title>
  <dc:creator>Ziyu Li, Donghwan Shin</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Mutation_based_Consistency_Testing_for_Evaluating_the_Code_Understanding_Capability_of_LLMs/2024-01-11-Mutation_based_Consistency_Testing_for_Evaluating_the_Code_Understanding_Capability_of_LLMs.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Mutation_based_Consistency_Testing_for_Evaluating_the_Code_Understanding_Capability_of_LLMs/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05940v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-mutation-based-consistency-testing-for-evaluating-the-code-understanding-capability-of-llms" class="level1">
<h1>Summary of “Mutation-based Consistency Testing for Evaluating the Code Understanding Capability of LLMs”</h1>
<section id="overall-findings" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="overall-findings">Overall Findings</h2>
<ul>
<li>The study proposed a novel method called <em>Mutation-based Consistency Testing (MCT)</em> to evaluate the code understanding performance of Large Language Models (LLMs) by introducing code <em>mutations</em> to create mismatches between code and its natural language descriptions.</li>
<li>The study conducted a case study on popular LLMs, GPT-3.5 and GPT-4, using the HumanEval-X benchmark and found significant variation in their code understanding performance, with the models showing different strengths and weaknesses depending on the mutation type and programming language.</li>
<li>The results demonstrated the importance of prompt engineering, with one-shot prompts significantly improving the performance of LLMs in identifying subtle inconsistencies between code and its descriptions.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">1. Introduction</h2>
<ul>
<li>Large Language Models (LLMs) have gained attention in software engineering, yet existing benchmarks do not thoroughly assess the code understanding performance of LLMs, especially for subtle inconsistencies between code and its natural language descriptions.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="background" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="background">2. Background</h2>
<ul>
<li>Large Language Models (LLMs) are advanced Deep Learning systems that comprehend natural and programming languages. They have been used in various software engineering applications.</li>
<li>Existing benchmarks such as HumanEval-X assess the code generation ability of LLMs, but do not focus on code understanding, syntax, and semantics.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="approach" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="approach">3. Approach</h2>
<ul>
<li>The study proposed <em>Mutation-based Consistency Testing (MCT)</em> to assess the code understanding capability of LLMs using code mutations to create inconsistencies between code and its descriptions.</li>
<li>Details on prompt engineering and mutant generation were provided.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="case-study-design" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="case-study-design">4. Case Study Design</h2>
<ul>
<li>The case study aimed to evaluate the ability of different LLMs to detect inconsistencies between code and its descriptions, assess their performance across different programming languages, and investigate the impact of one-shot prompt engineering on their performance.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="case-study-results" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="case-study-results">5. Case Study Results</h2>
<ul>
<li>Findings included the impact of mutation operators and programming languages on LLM performance, the explanation of test results, and the impact of prompt engineering.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="threats-to-validity" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="threats-to-validity">5.5. Threats to Validity</h2>
<ul>
<li>Potential threats to validity included implementation bugs and the impact of input understanding on model performance.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="data-availability" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="data-availability">6. Data Availability</h2>
<ul>
<li>The replication package, including the MCT method implementation and execution results, is available for public access.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="related-work" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="related-work">7. Related Work</h2>
<ul>
<li>The study highlighted the existing literature on LLM testing, focusing on code generation and code understanding.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="conclusion" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="conclusion">8. Conclusion</h2>
<ul>
<li>The study concluded that MCT can effectively assess the code understanding capability of LLMs and offered suggestions for future research in this area.</li>
</ul>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper provides a comprehensive exploration of MCT for evaluating LLMs, but potential limitations include the small scale of the case study and reliance on GPT-3.5 and GPT-4, which may not fully represent all LLMs.</li>
</ul>
<p>The paper provides valuable insights into evaluating LLMs’ code understanding capability and introduces a novel method, MCT, to assess LLM performance in identifying subtle code inconsistencies. The findings have implications for future research and development of LLM-based software engineering, with potential for further exploration and refinement of the MCT approach.</p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-12</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05940v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05940v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05940v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05940v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>11106</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Mutation_based_Consistency_Testing_for_Evaluating_the_Code_Understanding_Capability_of_LLMs/2024-01-11-Mutation_based_Consistency_Testing_for_Evaluating_the_Code_Understanding_Capability_of_LLMs.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05940v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
