<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Bayesian beagle</title>
<link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Quarto blog of LLM-generated summaries of Arxiv preprints</description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.450</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>ChatQA: Building GPT-4 Level Conversational QA Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Zihan Liu, Wei Ping, Rajarshi Roy, Peng Xu, Mohammad Shoeybi, Bryan Catanzaro</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ChatQA_Building_GPT_4_Level_Conversational_QA_Models/2024-01-18-ChatQA_Building_GPT_4_Level_Conversational_QA_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ChatQA_Building_GPT_4_Level_Conversational_QA_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.10225v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong></p>
<p>The article introduces ChatQA, a series of conversational question answering (QA) models designed to achieve GPT-4 level accuracies. The authors propose a two-stage instruction tuning method and a dense retriever for retrieval-augmented generation in conversational QA. They demonstrate superior performance of ChatQA-70B compared to GPT-4 on 10 conversational QA datasets. Additionally, the article discusses the importance of conversational QA in real-world applications and the challenges involved in building conversational QA models.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><p><strong>ChatQA Models:</strong> ChatQA-70B outperforms GPT-4 in terms of average score on 10 conversational QA datasets.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Fine-Tuning and Retrieval:</strong> The proposed two-stage instruction tuning method and dense retriever significantly enhance the models’ capability for zero-shot conversational QA tasks, outperforming regular instruction tuning or RLHF-based recipes.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Unanswerable Scenario:</strong> Adding “unanswerable” samples in instruction tuning reduces model hallucination, improving the model’s performance in handling scenarios where answers are unavailable.</p></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article provided valuable insights into the development of ChatQA models. However, it lacked a detailed comparison with other existing conversational QA models, which could have further strengthened the findings. Additionally, the article focused on the model’s technical aspects but did not extensively discuss potential ethical implications or biases that might arise from the deployment of ChatQA models. Moreover, while the results are promising, further external validation and testing are necessary to establish the generalizability of the ChatQA models across diverse conversational QA tasks and datasets.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-19</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.10225v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.10225v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.10225v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.10225v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>18597</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ChatQA_Building_GPT_4_Level_Conversational_QA_Models/2024-01-18-ChatQA_Building_GPT_4_Level_Conversational_QA_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.10225v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>A Comparative Study on Annotation Quality of Crowdsourcing and LLM via Label Aggregation</title>
  <dc:creator>Jiyi Li</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_Comparative_Study_on_Annotation_Quality_of_Crowdsourcing_and_LLM_via_Label_Aggregation/2024-01-18-A_Comparative_Study_on_Annotation_Quality_of_Crowdsourcing_and_LLM_via_Label_Aggregation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_Comparative_Study_on_Annotation_Quality_of_Crowdsourcing_and_LLM_via_Label_Aggregation/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong> The article explores the comparative annotation quality of crowdsourcing and Large Language Models (LLMs) by aggregating labels. It investigates the use of existing crowdsourcing datasets, compares the quality of individual crowd and LLM labels, and evaluates the aggregated labels. Additionally, it proposes a Crowd-LLM hybrid label aggregation method and finds that adding LLM labels to existing crowdsourcing datasets enhances the quality of the aggregated labels, surpassing the quality of LLM labels themselves.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Existing Crowdsourcing Datasets for Comparative Study:
<ul>
<li>The article addresses the underutilization of existing crowdsourcing datasets in evaluating the annotation quality, aiming to provide reliable evaluations from a different viewpoint.</li>
<li>It investigates which datasets can be used for comparative studies, creating a benchmark for reliable evaluations.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Quality Comparison between Crowd and LLM Labels:
<ul>
<li>The study compares the quality of individual crowd labels and LLM labels, finding that good LLM labels enhance the quality of aggregated labels, surpassing the quality of LLM labels themselves.</li>
<li>It also examines the performance of LLM workers, proposing a hybrid label aggregation method utilizing both crowd and LLM labels.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Label Aggregation Evaluation:
<ul>
<li>The article evaluates the quality of label aggregation using traditional crowd label aggregation models and proposes a Crowd-LLM hybrid label aggregation method.</li>
<li>It demonstrates that adding good LLM labels to existing crowdsourcing datasets enhances the quality of the aggregated labels, outperforming the quality of LLM labels alone. It also suggests that collecting more crowd labels can further improve the quality of aggregated labels.</li>
</ul></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article provides valuable insights into the comparison of annotation quality between crowdsourcing and LLMs. However, it is limited to categorical labels, excluding other types of labels like numerical and textual labels. Additionally, while the study highlights the enhanced quality of aggregated labels with LLM inputs, it does not address potential biases in the LLM-generated labels or the impact of dataset characteristics on the LLM’s performance. Further research is needed to explore these aspects and expand the comparative studies to include other types of labels for a comprehensive understanding of annotation quality.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-19</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09760v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09760v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09760v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09760v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>4581</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_Comparative_Study_on_Annotation_Quality_of_Crowdsourcing_and_LLM_via_Label_Aggregation/2024-01-18-A_Comparative_Study_on_Annotation_Quality_of_Crowdsourcing_and_LLM_via_Label_Aggregation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Advancing Large Multi-modal Models with Explicit Chain-of-Reasoning and Visual Question Generation</title>
  <dc:creator>Kohei Uehara, Nabarun Goswami, Hanqin Wang, Toshiaki Baba, Kohtaro Tanaka, Tomohiro Hashimoto, Kai Wang, Rei Ito, Takagi Naoya, Ryo Umagami, Yingyi Wen, Tanachai Anakewat, Tatsuya Harada</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Advancing_Large_Multi_modal_Models_with_Explicit_Chain_of_Reasoning_and_Visual_Question_Generation/2024-01-18-Advancing_Large_Multi_modal_Models_with_Explicit_Chain_of_Reasoning_and_Visual_Question_Generation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Advancing_Large_Multi_modal_Models_with_Explicit_Chain_of_Reasoning_and_Visual_Question_Generation/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.10005v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-the-article" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-of-the-article">Summary of the Article:</h3>
<p>The article introduces a novel approach to enhance Large Multi-Modal Models (LMMs) by integrating explicit reasoning capabilities and visual question generation. It outlines the development of a new dataset aimed at promoting chain-of-thought reasoning combined with question-asking mechanisms. The authors also introduce a three-stage training process focusing on image-text alignment, instruction tuning, and fine-tuning for chain-of-thought reasoning. The results demonstrate the potential of the proposed approach in improving the robustness and interpretability of LMMs, enabling them to reason explicitly and proactively seek information when faced with ambiguous visual input.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The Introduction of Explicit Reasoning: The article underscores the significance of explicitly incorporating reasoning processes into Large Multi-Modal Models (LMMs) to enhance their interpretability and the accuracy of their inferences.</li>
<li>Importance of Question-Asking Mechanism: The integration of a question-generation step into the reasoning process is shown to facilitate the acquisition of necessary knowledge, highlighting the value of proactively seeking information during ambiguous reasoning situations.</li>
<li>Model Training and Dataset Creation: The article presents a novel dataset designed to promote chain-of-thought reasoning and question generation, and outlines a three-stage training process aimed at fine-tuning LMMs for explicit reasoning.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article effectively addresses the growing demand for LMMs with enhanced reasoning capabilities. However, it also highlights challenges in generating coherent and consistent long reasoning steps, leading to a decrease in evaluation scores for models using explicit reasoning processes. This suggests the need for further research to improve LMMs’ ability to produce coherent and consistent long reasoning steps in line with the given tasks. Moreover, while the proposed approach shows promise, the study could benefit from a more comprehensive analysis of the limitations and potential areas for further refinement. Additionally, the authors could consider exploring potential biases in the dataset creation and model training, providing a more critical evaluation of the proposed approach’s limitations.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-19</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.10005v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.10005v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.10005v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.10005v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7853</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Advancing_Large_Multi_modal_Models_with_Explicit_Chain_of_Reasoning_and_Visual_Question_Generation/2024-01-18-Advancing_Large_Multi_modal_Models_with_Explicit_Chain_of_Reasoning_and_Visual_Question_Generation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.10005v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>DiffusionGPT: LLM-Driven Text-to-Image Generation System</title>
  <dc:creator>Jie Qin, Jie Wu, Weifeng Chen, Yuxi Ren, Huixia Li, Hefeng Wu, Xuefeng Xiao, Rui Wang, Shilei Wen</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/DiffusionGPT_LLM_Driven_Text_to_Image_Generation_System/2024-01-18-DiffusionGPT_LLM_Driven_Text_to_Image_Generation_System.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/DiffusionGPT_LLM_Driven_Text_to_Image_Generation_System/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.10061v1/x2.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong> The article introduces DiffusionGPT, a unified text-to-image generation system that leverages Large Language Models (LLMs) and domain-expert models. It addresses the challenges faced by current text-to-image systems by proposing a method to handle diverse inputs and integrate domain expert models. The system is capable of parsing diverse input prompts, facilitating model selection, and ensuring exceptional performance across different domains. The article highlights the contributions of DiffusionGPT, its all-in-one system, training-free nature, and high effectiveness in pushing the boundaries of image synthesis.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>DiffusionGPT as a Unified System</strong>
<ul>
<li>DiffusionGPT seamlessly accommodates various types of input prompts, including prompt-based, instruction-based, inspiration-based, and hypothesis-based input types.</li>
<li>The system is capable of generating outputs of superior quality, showcasing its ability to integrate diverse generative models.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Efficiency and Adaptability</strong>
<ul>
<li>DiffusionGPT is a training-free system, allowing for easy integration as a plug-and-play solution.</li>
<li>The system’s versatility and professional solution enable it to handle various prompt types, expanding its applicability.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Effectiveness in Image Generation</strong>
<ul>
<li>DiffusionGPT outperforms traditional stable diffusion models, demonstrating significant advancements in image generation, offering an efficient and effective pathway for community development.</li>
</ul></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article presents a promising approach to text-to-image generation, addressing the limitations of current models. By leveraging LLMs and domain-expert models, DiffusionGPT offers a comprehensive and adaptable solution. However, the article lacks a detailed comparison with existing state-of-the-art methods, and the evaluation mainly focuses on qualitative and user preference aspects, with limited analysis of quantitative metrics. Additionally, the article should provide more insight into potential limitations, unbiased user studies, and real-world applications to strengthen the proposed approach. Further research is warranted to address the limitations, including incorporating feedback-driven optimization, expanding model candidates, and extending the application of the system to broader tasks beyond text-to-image.</p>
<p>The proposed system shows promise, but the article would benefit from a more thorough analysis and critical evaluation of the limitations and future research directions. Additionally, a more comprehensive comparison with existing methods and a broader range of evaluation metrics would provide a clearer understanding of the system’s effectiveness.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-19</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.10061v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.10061v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.10061v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.10061v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6954</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/DiffusionGPT_LLM_Driven_Text_to_Image_Generation_System/2024-01-18-DiffusionGPT_LLM_Driven_Text_to_Image_Generation_System.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.10061v1/x2.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Leveraging Biases in Large Language Models: bias-kNN’’ for Effective Few-Shot Learning</title>
  <dc:creator>Yong Zhang, Hanzhang Li, Zhitao Li, Ning Cheng, Ming Li, Jing Xiao, Jianzong Wang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Leveraging_Biases_in_Large_Language_Models_bias_kNN_for_Effective_Few_Shot_Learning/2024-01-18-Leveraging_Biases_in_Large_Language_Models_bias_kNN_for_Effective_Few_Shot_Learning.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Leveraging_Biases_in_Large_Language_Models_bias_kNN_for_Effective_Few_Shot_Learning/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09783v1/extracted/5354115/analysis.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong> The article discusses the challenges posed by biases in Large Language Models (LLMs) and introduces a novel methodology called “bias-kNN” aimed at leveraging biases to enhance few-shot learning in text classification tasks. The study demonstrates the adaptability and efficacy of the “bias-kNN” method across diverse domain text classification datasets and different GPT-2 model sizes. It outperforms conventional in-context learning in few-shot scenarios and exhibits robustness across a spectrum of samples, templates, and verbalizers, presenting biases as assets for improved model performance.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The “bias-kNN” approach capitalizes on biased outputs by utilizing them as primary features for kNN and supplementing with gold labels, consistently outperforming traditional in-context learning in few-shot scenarios.</li>
<li>The method exhibits enhanced stability and adaptability across diverse templates and verbalizers, highlighting its resilience and broad applicability.</li>
<li>Rigorous evaluations across various domain text classification datasets and GPT-2 model sizes demonstrate the effectiveness and versatility of the “bias-kNN” approach in leveraging biases for improved model performance in text classification tasks.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article’s “bias-kNN” methodology presents an intriguing perspective on addressing biases in Large Language Models (LLMs), demonstrating its effectiveness in enhancing few-shot learning in text classification tasks. However, the study predominantly focuses on the efficacy of the proposed method and lacks a detailed exploration of potential limitations or challenges. It would be beneficial to consider the ethical implications of leveraging biases and the potential risks associated with relying on biased outputs for model enhancement. Additionally, while the results are promising, the article could benefit from a more critical discussion of the potential shortcomings or scenarios where the “bias-kNN” approach might not be as effective. Further research and exploration of the ethical considerations and potential drawbacks of leveraging biases in LLMs would contribute to a more comprehensive understanding of the proposed methodology.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-19</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09783v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09783v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09783v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09783v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>3552</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Leveraging_Biases_in_Large_Language_Models_bias_kNN_for_Effective_Few_Shot_Learning/2024-01-18-Leveraging_Biases_in_Large_Language_Models_bias_kNN_for_Effective_Few_Shot_Learning.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09783v1/extracted/5354115/analysis.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Comparing Traditional and LLM-based Search for Image Geolocation</title>
  <dc:creator>Albatool Wazzan, Stephen MacNeil, Richard Souvenir</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Comparing_Traditional_and_LLM_based_Search_for_Image_Geolocation/2024-01-18-Comparing_Traditional_and_LLM_based_Search_for_Image_Geolocation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Comparing_Traditional_and_LLM_based_Search_for_Image_Geolocation/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.10184v1/extracted/5353910/figs/paris.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong></p>
<p>The study compared traditional and Large Language Model (LLM)-based search for image geolocation tasks, assessing user interactions and query formulation strategies. In a user study with 60 participants, those using traditional search engines outperformed those using LLM-based search. Participants using LLM-based search issued longer, more conversational queries, but had shorter search sessions. Conversely, traditional search users tended to add more terms to their initial queries when reformulating.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Participants using traditional search outperformed those using LLM-based search in accurately predicting image locations.</li>
<li>Participants using LLM-based search issued longer, more natural language queries, but had shorter search sessions compared to traditional search participants.</li>
<li>Distinct query formulation strategies emerged between users, with traditional search users adding more terms to their initial queries, while LLM-based search users consistently rephrased their initial queries.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article provides valuable insights into the differences in strategies and user behaviors when using traditional and LLM-based search for image geolocation tasks. However, the study has several limitations and potential biases: 1. The sample size of the user study was relatively small (60 participants) and may not be representative of a larger population. 2. The study did not explicitly categorize participants based on their expertise in geolocation, which could have influenced their performance and interactions with the search tools. 3. The study did not assess specific metrics, such as search engine result pages (SERPs) or clicks, which could have provided a more comprehensive view of the effectiveness of LLM-based search in image geolocation tasks. 4. The article discusses the challenges faced by participants using LLM-based search, including difficulties in query formulation, suggesting potential issues with LLM interface usability and user understanding of LLM capabilities. 5. The study raises questions about the perceived affordances of LLMs compared to traditional search engines, as the integration of similar features in LLMs may not be as intuitive as in traditional search engines. 6. The study identifies a need for more research on human-centered design of LLM interfaces and understanding how users form mental models of LLMs. Additionally, the study emphasizes the importance of teaching novices how to prompt effectively when using LLMs.</p>
<p>In conclusion, while the article provides important insights into user behaviors and performance differences between traditional and LLM-based search for image geolocation, further research is needed to address the limitations and biases of the study and explore the potential usability challenges of LLM interfaces and user understanding of LLM capabilities.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-19</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.10184v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.10184v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.10184v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.10184v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>11450</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Comparing_Traditional_and_LLM_based_Search_for_Image_Geolocation/2024-01-18-Comparing_Traditional_and_LLM_based_Search_for_Image_Geolocation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.10184v1/extracted/5353910/figs/paris.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Evolutionary Multi-Objective Optimization of Large Language Model Prompts for Balancing Sentiments</title>
  <dc:creator>Jill Baumann, Oliver Kramer</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Evolutionary_Multi_Objective_Optimization_of_Large_Language_Model_Prompts_for_Balancing_Sentiments/2024-01-18-Evolutionary_Multi_Objective_Optimization_of_Large_Language_Model_Prompts_for_Balancing_Sentiments.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Evolutionary_Multi_Objective_Optimization_of_Large_Language_Model_Prompts_for_Balancing_Sentiments/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09862v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong> The article discusses the importance of prompt optimization for large language models (LLMs) and proposes an evolutionary multi-objective approach called EMO-Prompts to address this challenge. The authors showcase its effectiveness through experiments focused on sentiment analysis, demonstrating that EMO-Prompts can generate prompts guiding the LLM to produce texts embodying conflicting emotions simultaneously.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Significance of Prompt Optimization:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The effectiveness of LLMs heavily relies on the quality of input prompts, making prompt optimization a crucial area of research.</li>
<li>Previous studies have explored various strategies for prompt optimization, emphasizing its importance in leveraging the full potential of LLMs.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Evolutionary Multi-Objective Approach (EMO-Prompts):</strong>
<ul>
<li>EMO-Prompts uses evolutionary algorithms to navigate the vast prompt space and concurrently fulfill dual objectives in the LLM’s response, in this case, conflicting emotions in sentiment analysis.</li>
<li>The proposed approach showcases its ability to generate prompts capable of guiding the LLM to produce texts embodying two conflicting emotions simultaneously.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Experimental Validation:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Experiments focused on sentiment analysis demonstrate the efficiency of EMO-Prompts in producing texts with balanced sentiments, as evidenced by the achievement of peak fitness values in various scenarios.</li>
<li>Specific methods, such as NSGA-II and SMS-EMOA, are integrated with EMO-Prompts to optimize prompt mutation and crossover, resulting in the successful generation of balanced sentiment texts.</li>
</ul></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article effectively addresses the critical area of prompt optimization for LLMs and presents a novel approach, EMO-Prompts, showcasing its effectiveness in generating prompts for balanced sentiment texts. The integration of evolutionary algorithms with prompt optimization strategies demonstrates promising results. However, the article could benefit from a more detailed discussion on the limitations or potential challenges of the proposed approach, such as the scalability of the method to more complex tasks or the generalizability of the findings across different LLMs. Additionally, further elaboration on the potential biases or limitations of using sentiment analysis as the primary case study could enhance the article’s comprehensiveness. Overall, the article effectively contributes to the field of natural language processing and prompt engineering, opening avenues for future research in text generation technology.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-19</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09862v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09862v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09862v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09862v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6061</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Evolutionary_Multi_Objective_Optimization_of_Large_Language_Model_Prompts_for_Balancing_Sentiments/2024-01-18-Evolutionary_Multi_Objective_Optimization_of_Large_Language_Model_Prompts_for_Balancing_Sentiments.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09862v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Large Language Model Lateral Spear Phishing: A Comparative Study in Large-Scale Organizational Settings</title>
  <dc:creator>Mazal Bethany, Athanasios Galiopoulos, Emet Bethany, Mohammad Bahrami Karkevandi, Nishant Vishwamitra, Peyman Najafirad</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Large_Language_Model_Lateral_Spear_Phishing_A_Comparative_Study_in_Large_Scale_Organizational_Settings/2024-01-18-Large_Language_Model_Lateral_Spear_Phishing_A_Comparative_Study_in_Large_Scale_Organizational_Settings.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Large_Language_Model_Lateral_Spear_Phishing_A_Comparative_Study_in_Large_Scale_Organizational_Settings/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09727v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-the-article" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-of-the-article"><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong></h3>
<p>The article explores the heightened threat of large language model (LLM) facilitated phishing in large-scale organizational settings and emphasizes the importance of investigating the integration of LLMs for large-scale attacks targeting entire organizations. The study investigates a large tier 1 university’s operation and workforce of approximately 9,000 individuals over an 11-month period. The research evaluates the capability of email filtering infrastructure to detect LLM-generated phishing attempts and proposes machine learning-based detection techniques for such emails. The findings underscore the urgent need for integrating existing anti-phishing infrastructure with LLM-generated phishing email detection methods and point out the need for updated organizational policies towards mitigating LLM-driven phishing threats.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The study proposes machine learning-based detection techniques for LLM-generated phishing emails which achieved an F1-score of 98.96.</li>
<li>LLM-generated phishing emails were found to have a persuasive effectiveness, with about 10% of email recipients at the university being compelled to input their login credentials.</li>
<li>The research highlights the urgent need for integrating existing anti-phishing infrastructure with LLM-generated phishing email detection methods and emphasizes the requirement for updated organizational policies towards mitigating LLM-driven phishing threats.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<p>The article provides crucial insights into the emerging threat of LLM-facilitated phishing and its potential impact on large organizations. However, the study primarily focuses on investigating the effectiveness of detection techniques for LLM-generated phishing emails, overlooking the broader implications and potential countermeasures that organizations can employ. Additionally, while the study proposes machine learning-based detection techniques for LLM-generated phishing emails, the article lacks a detailed discussion on the limitations and potential biases of these proposed techniques.</p>
<p>Furthermore, the study emphasizes the need for updated organizational policies towards mitigating LLM-driven phishing threats, but it does not delve into the specific aspects of these policies or provide practical recommendations for organizations to address this issue. Therefore, the article could benefit from a more comprehensive analysis of potential countermeasures and policy recommendations to effectively combat LLM-facilitated phishing in large-scale organizational settings.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-19</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09727v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09727v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09727v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09727v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>17156</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Large_Language_Model_Lateral_Spear_Phishing_A_Comparative_Study_in_Large_Scale_Organizational_Settings/2024-01-18-Large_Language_Model_Lateral_Spear_Phishing_A_Comparative_Study_in_Large_Scale_Organizational_Settings.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09727v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>A Fast, Performant, Secure Distributed Training Framework For Large Language Model</title>
  <dc:creator>Wei Huang, Yinggui Wang, Anda Cheng, Aihui Zhou, Chaofan Yu, Lei Wang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_Fast_Performant_Secure_Distributed_Training_Framework_For_Large_Language_Model/2024-01-18-A_Fast_Performant_Secure_Distributed_Training_Framework_For_Large_Language_Model.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_Fast_Performant_Secure_Distributed_Training_Framework_For_Large_Language_Model/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09796v1/extracted/5354499/feature2.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong> The article introduces a secure distributed framework for training Large Language Models (LLMs) to address the problem of maliciously stealing model parameters and data during the distributed training process. The framework is based on model slicing and employs Trusted Execution Environments (TEE) and lightweight encryption to ensure security. The proposed method involves deploying TEE on both the client and server sides, splitting the LLM by layers, and combining Sparsification Parameter Fine-tuning (SPF) with certain model components to improve accuracy while maintaining security.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Security Challenges in Distributed Learning</strong>:
<ul>
<li>The article addresses the security challenges in distributed LLM training, including the risk of malicious servers stealing model parameters and data and the potential for clients to infer data from other clients via model parameters and intermediate embedding.</li>
<li>Previous work focused on server-side threats but did not adequately consider the leakage of parameters and data on the client side.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Proposed Secure Distributed Training Framework</strong>:
<ul>
<li>The proposed framework involves model slicing, TEE deployment, and lightweight encryption to prevent data and parameter leakage. It includes an approach for split fine-tuning, where the LLM is divided by layers, and certain components are placed in the server-side TEE, with the client not requiring a TEE.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Experimental Evaluation</strong>:
<ul>
<li>The experimental results demonstrate that the proposed method ensures security while maintaining high efficiency and accuracy, even with security measures in place. Method1 and Method2 are compared, with Method2 showing significantly higher accuracy, albeit with a larger number of fine-tuned parameters.</li>
</ul></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article presents an innovative approach to addressing security concerns in distributed LLM training by leveraging TEE and lightweight encryption. However, the use of TEE and encryption introduces overhead, impacting the training time, particularly in Method1. Additionally, the article lacks a detailed discussion on potential limitations or challenges associated with TEE deployment, such as overhead and resource constraints. Furthermore, the article could benefit from providing a more comprehensive comparison with existing security measures in federated learning to highlight the novelty and effectiveness of the proposed framework. Additional research could focus on further optimizing the proposed methods to minimize overhead and resource requirements associated with TEE deployment in distributed LLM training.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-19</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09796v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09796v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09796v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09796v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>3880</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_Fast_Performant_Secure_Distributed_Training_Framework_For_Large_Language_Model/2024-01-18-A_Fast_Performant_Secure_Distributed_Training_Framework_For_Large_Language_Model.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09796v1/extracted/5354499/feature2.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>LOCALINTEL: Generating Organizational Threat Intelligence from Global and Local Cyber Knowledge</title>
  <dc:creator>Shaswata Mitra, Subash Neupane, Trisha Chakraborty, Sudip Mittal, Aritran Piplai, Manas Gaur, Shahram Rahimi</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LOCALINTEL_Generating_Organizational_Threat_Intelligence_from_Global_and_Local_Cyber_Knowledge/2024-01-18-LOCALINTEL_Generating_Organizational_Threat_Intelligence_from_Global_and_Local_Cyber_Knowledge.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LOCALINTEL_Generating_Organizational_Threat_Intelligence_from_Global_and_Local_Cyber_Knowledge/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.10036v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-the-article" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-of-the-article"><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong></h3>
<p>The article discusses the development of LocalIntel, an automated system designed to generate organization-specific threat intelligence by contextualizing global and local knowledge. The system aims to assist Security Operations Center (SoC) analysts in efficiently processing and utilizing threat reports from global repositories and private local knowledge databases to automate organization-specific threat response and mitigation strategies. It presents a three-phase process involved in retrieving global threat intelligence, local knowledge, and generating contextualized completions. The article also describes the theoretical foundation, system approach, background, related work, system implementation, experiments, and results of LocalIntel.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Automation of Threat Intelligence Generation:</strong>
<ul>
<li>LocalIntel automates the generation of organization-specific threat intelligence by leveraging large language models to process global and local knowledge databases, alleviating the labor-intensive and time-consuming task previously undertaken by SoC analysts.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Efficient Contextualization of Threat Intelligence:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The system effectively contextualizes global threat reports for a specific organization by retrieving relevant global and local knowledge and producing a contextualized completion specific to the organization’s unique operating conditions.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Performance and Reliability of LocalIntel:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The article presents qualitative and quantitative evaluations of LocalIntel’s performance, demonstrating its capability to generate accurate and contextually relevant responses consistently, making it a reliable tool for SoC analysts.</li>
</ul></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article effectively addresses the significant challenge faced by SoC analysts in manually tailoring global threat intelligence to suit an organization’s specific context. However, while the system’s performance is showcased through qualitative and quantitative evaluations, potential limitations in real-world scenarios are not thoroughly discussed. The effectiveness of LocalIntel in handling diverse and real-time cyber threats, potential biases in the curation of global threat reports, and the system’s adaptability to varying organizational contexts could benefit from further exploration. Additionally, the use of a specific language model and vector database in experiments might limit the generalizability of the results. It would be valuable for future research to provide a more comprehensive analysis of the system’s robustness, limitations, and its adaptability to different organizational settings and evolving cyber threats. Furthermore, addressing the privacy and security concerns associated with utilizing private local knowledge databases and ensuring the accuracy and reliability of the system in safeguarding sensitive organizational information are important aspects that could be explored further.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-19</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.10036v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.10036v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.10036v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.10036v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7977</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LOCALINTEL_Generating_Organizational_Threat_Intelligence_from_Global_and_Local_Cyber_Knowledge/2024-01-18-LOCALINTEL_Generating_Organizational_Threat_Intelligence_from_Global_and_Local_Cyber_Knowledge.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.10036v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Beyond Reference-Based Metrics: Analyzing Behaviors of Open LLMs on Data-to-Text Generation</title>
  <dc:creator>Zdeněk Kasner, Ondřej Dušek</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Beyond_Reference_Based_Metrics_Analyzing_Behaviors_of_Open_LLMs_on_Data_to_Text_Generation/2024-01-18-Beyond_Reference_Based_Metrics_Analyzing_Behaviors_of_Open_LLMs_on_Data_to_Text_Generation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Beyond_Reference_Based_Metrics_Analyzing_Behaviors_of_Open_LLMs_on_Data_to_Text_Generation/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.10186v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-the-article" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-of-the-article">Summary of the Article:</h3>
<p>The article explores the use of open large language models (LLMs) in generating coherent and relevant text from structured data in data-to-text (D2T) generation tasks. The authors introduce Quintd-1, a benchmark for five D2T generation tasks using structured data records from public APIs and leverage reference-free evaluation metrics and LLMs’ in-context learning capabilities. The findings suggest that open LLMs with 7B parameters can generate fluent and coherent text from various standard data formats in zero-shot settings. However, semantic accuracy of the outputs remains a major issue, with 80% of outputs containing a semantic error according to human annotators. The authors also provide insights into experimental processes, model selection, observations from preliminary experiments, final experiments, and evaluation strategies.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Open LLMs with 7B parameters can generate fluent and coherent text from various standard data formats in zero-shot settings.</li>
<li>Semantic accuracy is a major obstacle, with 80% of LLM outputs containing a semantic error according to human annotators and 91% according to the GPT-4-based metric.</li>
<li>Long data inputs cause practical issues, including the need for long-context models, increased GPU memory requirements, and unavailability of few-shot approaches.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article provides valuable insights into the use of open LLMs for D2T generation but has some limitations. The study focuses on open LLMs with 7B parameters, potentially overlooking the performance of models with different capacities. Additionally, the evaluation metrics, although innovative, may not fully capture the complexities of D2T generation tasks. The use of human annotators from crowdsourcing platforms may introduce biases, and the reliance on GPT-4 for automatic evaluation may not be universally applicable. Further research is needed to understand the generalizability of the findings and the reproducibility of the experimental setup.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-19</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.10186v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.10186v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.10186v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.10186v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>4624</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Beyond_Reference_Based_Metrics_Analyzing_Behaviors_of_Open_LLMs_on_Data_to_Text_Generation/2024-01-18-Beyond_Reference_Based_Metrics_Analyzing_Behaviors_of_Open_LLMs_on_Data_to_Text_Generation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.10186v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Evolutionary Computation in the Era of Large Language Model: Survey and Roadmap</title>
  <dc:creator>Xingyu Wu, Sheng-hao Wu, Jibin Wu, Liang Feng, Kay Chen Tan</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Evolutionary_Computation_in_the_Era_of_Large_Language_Model_Survey_and_Roadmap/2024-01-18-Evolutionary_Computation_in_the_Era_of_Large_Language_Model_Survey_and_Roadmap.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Evolutionary_Computation_in_the_Era_of_Large_Language_Model_Survey_and_Roadmap/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.10034v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-the-article" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-of-the-article"><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong></h3>
<p>The article explores the integration of Large Language Models (LLMs) with Evolutionary Algorithms (EAs) and identifies their shared optimization nature, black-box characteristics, and proficiency in handling complex problems. It presents a comprehensive review and roadmap for their mutual collaboration and provides insight into specific areas of synergy, such as LLM-enhanced evolutionary optimization and EA-enhanced LLM. The paper categorizes their collaboration into discrete sections, covering topics like neural architecture search, code generation, software engineering, and text generation. Furthermore, it identifies challenges and future directions for leveraging the collaborative potential of LLMs and EAs, aiming to unlock their combined power in tackling complex optimization problems to advance artificial intelligence.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Shared Optimization Nature:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Both LLMs and EAs are considered as optimization methods, aiming to achieve optimal solutions within a given search space.</li>
<li>They both balance exploration and exploitation, influencing the trade-off between innovation and stability in their optimization processes.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Complementary Advantages:</strong>
<ul>
<li>EAs provide flexibility, global search capability, and iterative optimization mechanisms to compensate for the limitations of LLMs in terms of search capabilities and result progression.</li>
<li>LLMs offer rich domain knowledge, text processing capabilities, and guidance in search spaces, compensating for some limitations of EAs, particularly in the early stages of search processes.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Integrated Synergy and Applications:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The integrated collaboration between LLMs and EAs is observed in various applications, including neural architecture search, code generation, software engineering, and text generation, demonstrating the potential of their combined strengths in addressing complex problems.</li>
</ul></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<p>The article effectively highlights the synergistic potential of integrating LLMs and EAs in addressing complex optimization problems across various domains. However, some limitations and potential biases should be noted, such as the reliance on commercially viable LLMs with proprietary model parameters, which may limit the reproducibility and transparency of the research findings. Additionally, the article could benefit from further exploration of ethical considerations and potential biases in the practical implementation of the collaborative approaches proposed. It is essential to address these limitations and engage in transparent discussions to ensure the ethical and unbiased deployment of LLMs with EAs in various application scenarios. Moreover, the article is heavily focused on highlighting the benefits of integrating LLMs and EAs, and it could benefit from a more balanced discussion of potential drawbacks or challenges associated with their collaboration.</p>
<p>Overall, the article effectively provides a comprehensive overview of the collaborative potential of LLMs and EAs, but it would benefit from a more nuanced discussion of potential limitations, ethical considerations, and biases associated with their integrated synergy.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-19</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.10034v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.10034v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.10034v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.10034v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>18593</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Evolutionary_Computation_in_the_Era_of_Large_Language_Model_Survey_and_Roadmap/2024-01-18-Evolutionary_Computation_in_the_Era_of_Large_Language_Model_Survey_and_Roadmap.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.10034v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>SkyEyeGPT: Unifying Remote Sensing Vision-Language Tasks via Instruction Tuning with Large Language Model</title>
  <dc:creator>Yang Zhan, Zhitong Xiong, Yuan Yuan</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SkyEyeGPT_Unifying_Remote_Sensing_Vision_Language_Tasks_via_Instruction_Tuning_with_Large_Language_Model/2024-01-18-SkyEyeGPT_Unifying_Remote_Sensing_Vision_Language_Tasks_via_Instruction_Tuning_with_Large_Language_Model.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SkyEyeGPT_Unifying_Remote_Sensing_Vision_Language_Tasks_via_Instruction_Tuning_with_Large_Language_Model/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09712v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-the-article" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-of-the-article">Summary of the Article:</h3>
<p>The article introduces SkyEyeGPT, a multi-modal large language model specifically designed for remote sensing (RS) vision-language understanding, addressing the lack of satisfactory performance in this domain. SkyEyeGPT demonstrates impressive performance on different RS vision-language tasks without requiring extra encoding modules. The model’s architecture consists of a visual encoder, an alignment layer, and an LLM-based decoder for RS open-ended tasks. Additionally, the article presents a meticulous curation of an RS multi-modal instruction tuning dataset and a two-stage tuning method to enhance instruction-following and multi-turn dialogue ability.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Unified Model for RS Vision-Language Tasks:</strong>
<ul>
<li>SkyEyeGPT works surprisingly well on considerably different tasks without the need for extra encoding modules, demonstrating a unified and efficient model for RS vision-language tasks.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>RS Vision-Language Instruction Dataset:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The construction of the SkyEye-968k dataset, including single-task image-text instruction and multi-task conversation instruction, fills the gap of the lack of large-scale RS multimodal instruction-following data.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Superior Performance:</strong>
<ul>
<li>SkyEyeGPT exhibits superior performance in image-level and region-level RS vision-language tasks, such as captioning, visual grounding, and VQA, outperforming existing models such as GPT-4V in some tests.</li>
</ul></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article offers valuable contributions to the field of multi-modal large language models for remote sensing vision-language tasks. However, some potential limitations and areas of further research include: - Clear Evaluation Methods: The article highlights the challenge of evaluating model performance accurately, especially in image captioning. While introducing a novel evaluation method using ChatGPT, relying on a single evaluation metric could be limited. Additional robust evaluation methods may be required. - Generalization and Modality Difference: The model’s performance is affected by modality differences between satellite imagery and aerial images in different tasks. Addressing this difference and ensuring generalization across diverse RS imagery sources should be a focus of future research.</p>
<p>The article effectively presents SkyEyeGPT’s architecture, dataset creation, and the model’s performance on various RS vision-language tasks, but further investigation is needed to ensure its robustness and generalizability across different modalities within the RS domain.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-19</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09712v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09712v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09712v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09712v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8815</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SkyEyeGPT_Unifying_Remote_Sensing_Vision_Language_Tasks_via_Instruction_Tuning_with_Large_Language_Model/2024-01-18-SkyEyeGPT_Unifying_Remote_Sensing_Vision_Language_Tasks_via_Instruction_Tuning_with_Large_Language_Model.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09712v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Self-Rewarding Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Weizhe Yuan, Richard Yuanzhe Pang, Kyunghyun Cho, Sainbayar Sukhbaatar, Jing Xu, Jason Weston</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Self_Rewarding_Language_Models/2024-01-18-Self_Rewarding_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Self_Rewarding_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.10020v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong> The article discusses the concept of Self-Rewarding Language Models (SRLMs) and their ability to continually improve in both instruction following and reward modeling through iterative training. The authors propose a method where SRLMs generate their own rewards during training via an iterative procedure, and they demonstrate that this approach leads to improved performance in instruction following tasks and reward modeling ability. The study focuses on fine-tuning a Llama 2 70B model using three iterations of the proposed approach and shows that the model outperforms existing systems on the AlpacaEval 2.0 leaderboard.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Self-Rewarding Language Models (SRLMs):</strong>
<ul>
<li>The study introduces Self-Rewarding Language Models, which can act as both instruction following models and as generators and evaluators of new instruction-following examples. These models are trained using an iterative DPO framework, allowing them to update their reward model continually during alignment.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Improved Instruction Following and Reward Modeling Ability:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Through iterative training, the SRLMs demonstrate improved instruction following ability and the ability to provide high-quality rewards to themselves. The findings show that the reward modeling ability of the model dynamically improves during training, deviating from standard practices where the reward model is fixed.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Performance on AlpacaEval 2.0 Leaderboard:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The SRLM, after three iterations of training, outperforms existing systems on the AlpacaEval 2.0 leaderboard, including Claude 2, Gemini Pro, and GPT-4 0613. The preliminary study suggests the possibility of models continually improving in both instruction following and reward modeling.</li>
</ul></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article presents an innovative approach to self-rewarding language models and demonstrates promising findings. However, the study is limited in several ways: - Lack of In-depth Evaluation: While the authors conducted head-to-head evaluations and reported performance on the AlpacaEval 2.0 leaderboard, there is a lack of in-depth evaluation using other benchmarks or comprehensive human evaluations. - Limited Iterations: The study conducted only three iterations of training, leaving open questions about the scalability and long-term effectiveness of the proposed approach. - Safety Evaluation: The article acknowledges the need for safety evaluations but does not provide an in-depth analysis of potential safety issues or the model’s capability to improve in safety over time. - Methodological Limitations: The study lacks a critical analysis of potential biases or limitations with the proposed approach, such as reward-hacking or unforeseen challenges in iterative training.</p>
<p>In conclusion, while the concept of Self-Rewarding Language Models shows promise, further research is necessary to address the limitations and evaluate the long-term effectiveness and safety implications of this approach.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-19</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.10020v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.10020v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.10020v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.10020v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7958</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Self_Rewarding_Language_Models/2024-01-18-Self_Rewarding_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.10020v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Sketch-Guided Constrained Decoding for Boosting Blackbox Large Language Models without Logit Access</title>
  <dc:creator>Saibo Geng, Berkay Döner, Chris Wendler, Martin Josifoski, Robert West</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Sketch_Guided_Constrained_Decoding_for_Boosting_Blackbox_Large_Language_Models_without_Logit_Access/2024-01-18-Sketch_Guided_Constrained_Decoding_for_Boosting_Blackbox_Large_Language_Models_without_Logit_Access.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Sketch_Guided_Constrained_Decoding_for_Boosting_Blackbox_Large_Language_Models_without_Logit_Access/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09967v1/extracted/5355273/figures/overview.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong></p>
<p>The article introduces “Sketch-Guided Constrained Decoding” (SGCD) as a new approach to constrained decoding for blackbox Large Language Models (LLMs), which does not rely on direct logit access. The SGCD method utilizes a locally hosted auxiliary model to refine the outputs of a blackbox LLM while respecting specified constraints. The article demonstrates the efficacy of SGCD through experiments in closed information extraction and constituency parsing, highlighting its ability to enhance the utility and flexibility of blackbox LLMs for complex Natural Language Processing (NLP) tasks.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Constrained decoding offers a solution to restrict model outputs without necessitating model retraining or architectural modifications, but existing methods require access to the model’s logits during inference, posing limitations with blackbox LLMs.</li>
<li>SGCD splits the constrained decoding task into two phases: sketching and constrained generation. It employs a sketcher, typically a powerful blackbox LLM, for the sketching phase and a constrained generator, a smaller-scale locally hosted LLM, for the constrained generation phase.</li>
<li>The experimental evaluation of SGCD in closed information extraction and constituency parsing tasks demonstrates its ability to significantly enhance the performance of blackbox LLMs, particularly in terms of precision, recall, and F1-score.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article presents a novel method, SGCD, addressing the limitations of constrained decoding with blackbox LLMs, showcasing its effectiveness through experimental comparisons. However, the study acknowledges the “degeneration” issue where the constrained generator may produce outputs of inferior quality, and highlights potential data contamination risks in evaluating LLMs on downstream tasks. Further research is recommended to address the degeneration problem and to assess the impact of data contamination on the validity of conclusions drawn from LLM evaluations. Additionally, the article acknowledges that as LLMs continue to improve, the benefits of SGCD might diminish on some tasks, emphasizing the need for ongoing assessment and adaptation of methods in response to advancements in LLM technology.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-19</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09967v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09967v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09967v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09967v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6507</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Sketch_Guided_Constrained_Decoding_for_Boosting_Blackbox_Large_Language_Models_without_Logit_Access/2024-01-18-Sketch_Guided_Constrained_Decoding_for_Boosting_Blackbox_Large_Language_Models_without_Logit_Access.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09967v1/extracted/5355273/figures/overview.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Spatial-Temporal Large Language Model for Traffic Prediction</title>
  <dc:creator>Chenxi Liu, Sun Yang, Qianxiong Xu, Zhishuai Li, Cheng Long, Ziyue Li, Rui Zhao</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Spatial_Temporal_Large_Language_Model_for_Traffic_Prediction/2024-01-18-Spatial_Temporal_Large_Language_Model_for_Traffic_Prediction.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Spatial_Temporal_Large_Language_Model_for_Traffic_Prediction/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.10134v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong> The article introduces a novel Spatial-Temporal Large Language Model (ST-LLM) for traffic prediction, focusing on the representation of spatial-temporal dependencies in traffic data. The ST-LLM incorporates a spatial-temporal embedding layer, a fusion convolution layer, and a partially frozen attention strategy to enhance prediction accuracy. Extensive experiments on real traffic datasets confirm the superior performance of the ST-LLM over state-of-the-art models, particularly in both few-shot and zero-shot prediction scenarios.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Large Language Models (LLMs) have shown outstanding capabilities in time series analysis, and the proposed ST-LLM leverages LLMs to redefine timesteps at each location as tokens, emphasizing spatial and temporal aspects.</li>
<li>The partially frozen attention strategy within the ST-LLM enhances the model’s ability to capture global spatial-temporal dependencies for different traffic prediction tasks.</li>
<li>The ST-LLM outperforms existing models across various settings, demonstrating robust performance in both few-shot and zero-shot prediction scenarios, highlighting its capability for intra-domain and inter-domain knowledge transfer.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article presents a comprehensive and innovative approach to traffic prediction using the ST-LLM, addressing the limitations of existing models by focusing on spatial-temporal dependencies. However, limitations include the extensive computational requirements for the proposed ST-LLM and the lack of comparison with more traditional time series models. Additionally, while the ST-LLM shows promising results, further research is needed to explore its applicability in other domains beyond traffic prediction. Despite these shortcomings, the ST-LLM represents a significant advancement in the field of traffic prediction and warrants further investigation and development.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-19</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.10134v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.10134v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.10134v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.10134v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7755</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Spatial_Temporal_Large_Language_Model_for_Traffic_Prediction/2024-01-18-Spatial_Temporal_Large_Language_Model_for_Traffic_Prediction.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.10134v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>All in How You Ask for It: Simple Black-Box Method for Jailbreak Attacks</title>
  <dc:creator>Kazuhiro Takemoto</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/All_in_How_You_Ask_for_It_Simple_Black_Box_Method_for_Jailbreak_Attacks/2024-01-18-All_in_How_You_Ask_for_It_Simple_Black_Box_Method_for_Jailbreak_Attacks.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/All_in_How_You_Ask_for_It_Simple_Black_Box_Method_for_Jailbreak_Attacks/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09798v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong> This study introduces a simple black-box method for generating jailbreak prompts to bypass safeguards and create ethically harmful content using Large Language Models (LLMs) like ChatGPT and Gemini-Pro. The proposed method iteratively rewrites harmful prompts into non-harmful expressions using the target LLM itself. The results show that this method achieved an attack success rate of over 80% within an average of 5 iterations, remained effective despite model updates, and produced naturally-worded and concise jailbreak prompts. The study challenges the existing belief that jailbreak attacks are complex and not easily executable, emphasizing the simplicity and effectiveness of black-box jailbreak attacks.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Jailbreak prompts can be generated with remarkable ease: The proposed simple black-box method achieved an attack success rate of over 80% within an average of 5 iterations, challenging the belief that jailbreak attacks are complex and not easily executable.</li>
<li>Effective natural language jailbreak prompts: The generated jailbreak prompts were naturally-worded, concise, and less detectable, posing a serious security threat to LLMs. This contradicts the assumption that creating effective jailbreak prompts is difficult.</li>
<li>Simple method with high efficiency: The proposed method is extremely easy to implement, requires no sophisticated prompts or high-spec computing environments, and demonstrates high attack performance against a wide range of ethically harmful questions in various scenarios. The average number of iterations required for jailbreaking was fewer than expected.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article effectively highlights the simplicity and high effectiveness of the proposed black-box method for jailbreak attacks against LLMs. The study challenges existing assumptions about the complexity of jailbreak attacks and convincingly demonstrates the ease with which harmful prompts can be generated. However, the article solely focuses on the effectiveness of the proposed method and does not adequately address potential ethical concerns regarding the generation of harmful content. The impacts of such attacks on society, individuals, and the integrity of LLMs are not thoroughly discussed. Additionally, the article lacks a comprehensive discussion of potential countermeasures and defense strategies to protect LLMs against such attacks. Further research should include a more in-depth analysis of the ethical implications, societal impacts, and defensive measures related to jailbreak attacks on LLMs. Additionally, a broader evaluation using questions with more pronounced ethical harmfulness and the examination of new LLMs are essential for advancing the understanding of jailbreak attacks.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-19</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09798v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09798v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09798v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09798v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7140</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/All_in_How_You_Ask_for_It_Simple_Black_Box_Method_for_Jailbreak_Attacks/2024-01-18-All_in_How_You_Ask_for_It_Simple_Black_Box_Method_for_Jailbreak_Attacks.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09798v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Large Language Models for Scientific Information Extraction: An Empirical Study for Virology</title>
  <dc:creator>Mahsa Shamsabadi, Jennifer D&#39;Souza, Sören Auer</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Large_Language_Models_for_Scientific_Information_Extraction_An_Empirical_Study_for_Virology/2024-01-18-Large_Language_Models_for_Scientific_Information_Extraction_An_Empirical_Study_for_Virology.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Large_Language_Models_for_Scientific_Information_Extraction_An_Empirical_Study_for_Virology/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.10040v1/extracted/5354967/images/orkg-comparison.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong></p>
<p>The article proposes the use of structured and semantic content representation for scholarly communication, specifically focusing on virology. The paper suggests the integration of large language models (LLMs) to generate structured scholarly contribution summaries using automated techniques, and presents a novel automated approach using LLMs for information extraction (IE) in scientific domains. The study aims to replace traditional modular approaches with a model that offers a practical solution for complex IE tasks, particularly related to estimating the basic reproduction number of infectious diseases. The authors introduce the complex IE task for estimating the basic reproduction number of infectious diseases, present the orkg-R0 model, and suggest the use of instruction-based finetuning for LLMs to enhance their performance in a unique domain.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper demonstrates that the finetuned FLAN-T5 model, with 1000x fewer parameters than the state-of-the-art GPT-davinci model, delivers competitive results for the task of information extraction in virology.</li>
<li>The study showcases the effectiveness of instruction-based finetuning in enhancing LLM performance in specialized scientific fields, particularly virology, supporting the use of LLMs for complex IE tasks.</li>
<li>The results indicate that the single-task instruction-finetuned orkg-FLAN-T5 780M model outperforms other models, including pretrained T5, instruction-tuned FLAN-T5, and GPT3.5-davinci 175B, for the complex IE task of orkg-R0 extraction.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article effectively addresses the need for structured and semantic content representation in scholarly communication and presents a novel approach for information extraction in the domain of virology. The use of LLMs, particularly the finetuned FLAN-T5 model, demonstrates promising results in addressing complex IE tasks, showcasing the potential of instruction-based finetuning in enhancing LLM performance in specialized scientific domains.</p>
<p>However, the article has several limitations and areas for improvement: 1. Lack of Standardization: The lack of standardization in semantic scholarly knowledge publishing models like ORKG may hinder interoperability and limit accessibility across different platforms and communities, requiring more collaborative efforts and community-building to adopt and streamline these models. 2. Technical Complexity: Implementing and maintaining the infrastructure required for semantic publishing models like ORKG can be technically complex and resource-intensive, requiring expertise in semantic technologies and ontological engineering. 3. Model Scaling: While the study focuses on the moderate-sized FLAN-T5 model with 780M parameters, there is potential for further investigation into larger-scale models and model distillation, which could be explored in future research.</p>
<p>Overall, the study provides valuable insights into the use of LLMs for scientific information extraction but would benefit from addressing the aforementioned limitations and facilitating more widespread adoption of structured and semantic content representation in scholarly communication.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-19</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.10040v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.10040v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.10040v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.10040v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>13676</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Large_Language_Models_for_Scientific_Information_Extraction_An_Empirical_Study_for_Virology/2024-01-18-Large_Language_Models_for_Scientific_Information_Extraction_An_Empirical_Study_for_Virology.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.10040v1/extracted/5354967/images/orkg-comparison.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>A Survey on Hardware Accelerators for Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Christoforos Kachris</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_Survey_on_Hardware_Accelerators_for_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-18-A_Survey_on_Hardware_Accelerators_for_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_Survey_on_Hardware_Accelerators_for_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09890v1/extracted/5354953/survey.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-the-article" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-of-the-article"><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong></h3>
<p>The paper surveys hardware accelerators designed to optimize the performance and energy efficiency of Large Language Models (LLMs). These models have revolutionized natural language processing, creating a growing need for computational solutions to address their scale and complexity. The article examines various accelerators, including GPUs, FPGAs, custom architectures, and in-memory computing, showcasing a comprehensive analysis of architecture, performance metrics, and energy efficiency considerations.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Computational and Energy Requirements:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Large language models are computationally intensive due to their architecture, scale of training data, and depth of neural networks, requiring substantial computational resources.</li>
<li>Both the training and inference stages of LLMs demand significant computational complexity and translate to considerable energy consumption, raising concerns about their environmental impact.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>FPGA-based Accelerators:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Several FPGA-based accelerators, such as MNNFast, FTRANS, Multi-Head Attention, and others, have been proposed to improve the throughput and energy efficiency of LLMs, achieving speedups ranging from 2.01x to 27x and energy efficiency improvements of up to 81x over CPUs and GPUs.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>ASIC Accelerators:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Approaches such as A3, ELSA, SpAtten, and Sanger have demonstrated significant speedup ranging from 7x to 157x and energy efficiency improvements of 1000x over GPUs, showcasing potential for highly efficient custom hardware solutions.</li>
</ul></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The comprehensive survey provides valuable insights into the landscape of hardware accelerators for LLMs and their potential impact on improving performance and energy efficiency. However, the lack of a standardized reference platform for comparison poses challenges in evaluating the absolute performance and energy efficiency across different accelerators. Additionally, while ASIC and in-memory-based solutions exhibit impressive results, their high development costs and longer time-to-market may limit their immediate practicality. Nonetheless, the article effectively highlights the promising potential of hardware accelerators in optimizing the deployment of LLMs, indicating a need for continued research and development to address the computational challenges associated with these models.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-19</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09890v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09890v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09890v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09890v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>12244</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_Survey_on_Hardware_Accelerators_for_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-18-A_Survey_on_Hardware_Accelerators_for_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09890v1/extracted/5354953/survey.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>DistServe: Disaggregating Prefill and Decoding for Goodput-optimized Large Language Model Serving</title>
  <dc:creator>Yinmin Zhong, Shengyu Liu, Junda Chen, Jianbo Hu, Yibo Zhu, Xuanzhe Liu, Xin Jin, Hao Zhang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/DistServe_Disaggregating_Prefill_and_Decoding_for_Goodput_optimized_Large_Language_Model_Serving/2024-01-18-DistServe_Disaggregating_Prefill_and_Decoding_for_Goodput_optimized_Large_Language_Model_Serving.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/DistServe_Disaggregating_Prefill_and_Decoding_for_Goodput_optimized_Large_Language_Model_Serving/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09670v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-the-article" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-of-the-article">Summary of the Article:</h3>
<p>The article presents DistServe, an approach that aims to improve the performance of large language models (LLMs) serving by disaggregating the prefill and decoding computation. Existing LLM serving systems batch the computation of prefill and decoding across all users and requests, leading to strong prefill-decoding interferences and coupling of resource allocation and parallelism plans for both phases. DistServe assigns prefill and decoding computation to different GPUs, eliminating interferences, and co-optimizes the resource allocation and parallelism strategy tailored for each phase. The approach significantly improves LLM serving performance in terms of the maximum request rate that can be served within both time to first token (TTFT) and time per output token (TPOT) constraints on each GPU.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Disaggregation of Prefill and Decoding</strong>: DistServe addresses the interference between prefill and decoding computation in LLM serving systems by assigning them to separate GPUs, thereby eliminating interference and improving system performance.</li>
<li><strong>Co-Optimized Resource Allocation and Parallelism</strong>: The approach co-optimizes the resource allocation and parallelism strategy tailored for each phase, leading to improved performance within TTFT and TPOT constraints on each GPU.</li>
<li><strong>Performance Improvement</strong>: DistServe outperforms state-of-the-art systems, serving up to 4.48 times more requests under latency constraints, while staying within latency constraints for over 90% of requests.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article provides a comprehensive and innovative approach to addressing the challenges in LLM serving systems, particularly in improving the performance and managing latency constraints. By disaggregating the prefill and decoding computation and co-optimizing resource allocation and parallelism, DistServe demonstrates significant performance improvements. The latency breakdown and ablation studies serve to verify the effectiveness of the proposed approach.</p>
<p>However, the article lacks a detailed analysis of potential drawbacks or limitations of the DistServe approach. Further exploration of potential issues, such as scalability, practical implementation complexities, or cost implications, could provide a more balanced view of the effectiveness and applicability of the proposed approach. Additionally, the article could benefit from a more detailed discussion of potential deployment challenges and adaptation to real-world production settings.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-19</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09670v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09670v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09670v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09670v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>15168</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/DistServe_Disaggregating_Prefill_and_Decoding_for_Goodput_optimized_Large_Language_Model_Serving/2024-01-18-DistServe_Disaggregating_Prefill_and_Decoding_for_Goodput_optimized_Large_Language_Model_Serving.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.09670v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
