<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Bayesian beagle</title>
<link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Quarto blog of LLM-generated summaries of Arxiv preprints</description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.450</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Data-freeWeight Compress and Denoise for Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Runyu Peng, Yunhua Zhou, Qipeng Guo, Yang Gao, Hang Yan, Xipeng Qiu, Dahua Lin</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Data_freeWeight_Compress_and_Denoise_for_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-26-Data_freeWeight_Compress_and_Denoise_for_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Data_freeWeight_Compress_and_Denoise_for_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16319v1/extracted/5401579/icml2024/denoise.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Large Language Models (LLMs) are facing constraints due to limitations in GPU memory and computational speed.</li>
<li>Weight compression methods like Pruning and Quantization have emerged to address these constraints.</li>
<li>The proposed Data-free Joint Rank-k Approximation method achieves a model pruning of 80% parameters while retaining 93.43% of the original performance without any calibration data.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The proposed Data-free Joint Rank-k Approximation method achieves a model pruning of 80% parameters while retaining 93.43% of the original performance without any calibration data.</li>
<li>Joint Rank-k Approximation outperforms separately conducted Rank-k Approximation in the attention module and feed-forward module of large language models.</li>
<li>Rank-k Approximation helps in denoising weight matrices, potentially improving the model’s robustness and performance.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper provides a novel approach to weight compression in large language models, but it may require further validation on a wider range of datasets and models.</li>
<li>The experiments conducted are limited to specific models and datasets, and the generalizability of the proposed method needs to be further explored.</li>
<li>The potential biases and limitations of the proposed method, especially in real-world applications, need to be thoroughly investigated.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-27</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16319v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16319v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16319v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16319v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6353</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Data_freeWeight_Compress_and_Denoise_for_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-26-Data_freeWeight_Compress_and_Denoise_for_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16319v1/extracted/5401579/icml2024/denoise.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>From Large Language Models and Optimization to Decision Optimization CoPilot: A Research Manifesto</title>
  <dc:creator>Segev Wasserkrug, Leonard Boussioux, Dick den Hertog, Farzaneh Mirzazadeh, Ilker Birbil, Jannis Kurtz, Donato Maragno</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/From_Large_Language_Models_and_Optimization_to_Decision_Optimization_CoPilot_A_Research_Manifesto/2024-02-26-From_Large_Language_Models_and_Optimization_to_Decision_Optimization_CoPilot_A_Research_Manifesto.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/From_Large_Language_Models_and_Optimization_to_Decision_Optimization_CoPilot_A_Research_Manifesto/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16269v1/extracted/5430993/GPTContext.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<ol type="1">
<li><p>Bound the number of opened hubs:</p></li>
<li><p>Set the first existing hubs to be open:</p></li>
<li><p>Assign POI to a suitable hub:</p></li>
<li><p>Domain constraints for the binary variables:</p></li>
</ol>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-27</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16269v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16269v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16269v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16269v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>13799</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/From_Large_Language_Models_and_Optimization_to_Decision_Optimization_CoPilot_A_Research_Manifesto/2024-02-26-From_Large_Language_Models_and_Optimization_to_Decision_Optimization_CoPilot_A_Research_Manifesto.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16269v1/extracted/5430993/GPTContext.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>LLM Inference Unveiled: Survey and Roofline Model Insights</title>
  <dc:creator>Zhihang Yuan, Yuzhang Shang, Yang Zhou, Zhen Dong, Chenhao Xue, Bingzhe Wu, Zhikai Li, Qingyi Gu, Yong Jae Lee, Yan Yan, Beidi Chen, Guangyu Sun, Kurt Keutzer</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLM_Inference_Unveiled_Survey_and_Roofline_Model_Insights/2024-02-26-LLM_Inference_Unveiled_Survey_and_Roofline_Model_Insights.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLM_Inference_Unveiled_Survey_and_Roofline_Model_Insights/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16363v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides a comprehensive overview of the challenges and opportunities in the field of efficient Large Language Model (LLM) inference. It introduces a unique survey that not only summarizes the current state of research but also presents a framework based on the roofline model for systematic analysis of LLM inference techniques. The survey covers advancements in weight optimization, decoding algorithm improvements, and hardware and system-level enhancements. The section also introduces the LLM-Viewer, an open-sourced tool for analyzing LLM performance and efficiency on various hardware platforms.</li>
<li>The article discusses the use of quantization techniques in LLMs to optimize model efficiency, highlighting the differences between Quantization-Aware Training (QAT) and Post-Training Quantization (PTQ). It presents a use case of LLM-Viewer for analyzing the effects of quantization on tensors and discusses various methods and innovations in PTQ for compressing pre-trained LLMs. Additionally, the section introduces the emerging paradigm of Quantization for Parameter Efficient Fine-Tuning (Q-PEFT) and its significance in optimizing LLMs.</li>
<li>Algorithmic methods for reducing the inference latency of LLMs are explored, focusing on minimum parameter usage per token decoded and maximum token decoding per forward propagation. The section discusses early exiting as a method to reduce LLM inference latency and explores contextual sparsity to reduce memory IO overhead and achieve speedup in LLM inference.</li>
<li>The article also delves into speculative decoding and parallel decoding as approaches to reduce the latency of LLM inference, highlighting the potential of these methods to improve the efficiency of LLM inference.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The article presents a comprehensive framework for analyzing LLM inference techniques, covering advancements in weight optimization, decoding algorithm improvements, and hardware and system-level enhancements.</li>
<li>Quantization techniques, including Quantization-Aware Training (QAT), Post-Training Quantization (PTQ), and Quantization for Parameter Efficient Fine-Tuning (Q-PEFT), play a significant role in optimizing LLM efficiency.</li>
<li>Algorithmic methods such as early exiting and contextual sparsity, as well as speculative decoding and parallel decoding, offer effective strategies for reducing the inference latency of LLMs.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides valuable insights into the challenges and opportunities in efficient LLM inference, but it would benefit from further exploration of potential biases in the presented techniques and the need for comparative studies to validate the effectiveness of the proposed methods.</li>
<li>While the article covers a wide range of techniques and innovations, it would be beneficial to address potential limitations and methodological issues in the implementation of these approaches.</li>
<li>Further research is required to explore the long-term implications of the presented methods and their applicability across different LLM architectures and real-world applications.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-27</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16363v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16363v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16363v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16363v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>18487</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLM_Inference_Unveiled_Survey_and_Roofline_Model_Insights/2024-02-26-LLM_Inference_Unveiled_Survey_and_Roofline_Model_Insights.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16363v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Integrating Large Language Models with Graphical Session-Based Recommendation</title>
  <dc:creator>Naicheng Guo, Hongwei Cheng, Qianqiao Liang, Linxun Chen, Bing Han</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Integrating_Large_Language_Models_with_Graphical_Session_Based_Recommendation/2024-02-26-Integrating_Large_Language_Models_with_Graphical_Session_Based_Recommendation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Integrating_Large_Language_Models_with_Graphical_Session_Based_Recommendation/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16539v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article introduces a framework, LLMGR, that integrates Large Language Models (LLMs) with Graph Neural Networks (GNNs) for session-based recommendation (SBR) tasks.</li>
<li>LLMGR aims to bridge the gap between the structural nature of graphs and the essence of natural language, enabling LLMs to understand and recommend items within a session.</li>
<li>Extensive experiments on real-world datasets demonstrate that LLMGR outperforms several competitive baselines, indicating its effectiveness in enhancing SBR tasks and its potential for future exploration.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMGR outperforms several competitive baselines, showcasing its superiority in enhancing session-based recommendation tasks.</li>
<li>The framework effectively integrates LLMs with GNNs, leveraging the complementary strengths of LLMs in natural language understanding and GNNs in relational data processing.</li>
<li>LLMGR addresses the challenges of capturing user preferences from limited interaction data and provides a pioneer attempt for future research at the intersection of complex graph modeling and advanced language models.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides a comprehensive and innovative approach to integrating LLMs with graph-based SBR methods, addressing the limitations of existing SBR systems.</li>
<li>The two-stage tuning process of LLMGR demonstrates its effectiveness in associating text with graph nodes and capturing dynamic behavioral patterns of users.</li>
<li>Extensive experiments on real-world datasets validate the potential of LLMGR to enhance SBR systems and pave the way for future research in this domain.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the article presents a well-structured and coherent framework that effectively communicates the essential information from the academic article. The critical analysis highlights the strengths and potential of LLMGR while providing a comprehensive overview of the findings and implications of the study.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-27</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16539v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16539v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16539v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16539v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>10496</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>recommender</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Integrating_Large_Language_Models_with_Graphical_Session_Based_Recommendation/2024-02-26-Integrating_Large_Language_Models_with_Graphical_Session_Based_Recommendation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16539v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Chain-of-Discussion: A Multi-Model Framework for Complex Evidence-Based Question Answering</title>
  <dc:creator>Mingxu Tao, Dongyan Zhao, Yansong Feng</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Chain_of_Discussion_A_Multi_Model_Framework_for_Complex_Evidence_Based_Question_Answering/2024-02-26-Chain_of_Discussion_A_Multi_Model_Framework_for_Complex_Evidence_Based_Question_Answering.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Chain_of_Discussion_A_Multi_Model_Framework_for_Complex_Evidence_Based_Question_Answering/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16313v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The Chain-of-Discussion framework aims to improve the quality of open-ended question answering by leveraging the synergy among multiple open-source Large Language Models (LLMs).</li>
<li>The framework involves two stages: question analysis and evidence analysis, where LLMs interact to provide more correct and comprehensive answers.</li>
<li>The proposed framework is evaluated on a legal consultation dataset and shows improvements in the quality of responses generated by open-source LLMs.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The Chain-of-Discussion framework enhances the quality of responses generated by open-source LLMs through multi-model discussions, leading to more correct and comprehensive answers.</li>
<li>Involving multiple LLMs in both question analysis and evidence analysis contributes to increasing the probability of LLMs referencing correct evidence, improving the correctness and comprehensiveness of the responses.</li>
<li>The framework shows potential to reduce logical errors in responses and improve the ability of LLMs to comprehend and analyze legal articles.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The Chain-of-Discussion framework demonstrates the potential to improve the quality of responses generated by open-source LLMs. However, limitations in the reasoning capabilities of LLMs and their preferences for revising evidence analysis may impact the effectiveness of the framework.</li>
<li>The framework’s reliance on open-source LLMs with around 7B parameters may lead to unreliable output and inferior reasoning capabilities, affecting the overall performance of the Chain-of-Discussion framework.</li>
<li>The proposed framework shows promise for enhancing the quality of open-ended question answering, but further research is needed to address the limitations and biases associated with open-source LLMs.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the Chain-of-Discussion framework presents a novel approach to improving the quality of open-ended question answering, but it is essential to address the limitations and biases associated with open-source LLMs to maximize its effectiveness.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-27</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16313v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16313v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16313v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16313v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>9951</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Chain_of_Discussion_A_Multi_Model_Framework_for_Complex_Evidence_Based_Question_Answering/2024-02-26-Chain_of_Discussion_A_Multi_Model_Framework_for_Complex_Evidence_Based_Question_Answering.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16313v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>mEdIT: Multilingual Text Editing via Instruction Tuning</title>
  <dc:creator>Vipul Raheja, Dimitris Alikaniotis, Vivek Kulkarni, Bashar Alhafni, Dhruv Kumar</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/mEdIT_Multilingual_Text_Editing_via_Instruction_Tuning/2024-02-26-mEdIT_Multilingual_Text_Editing_via_Instruction_Tuning.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/mEdIT_Multilingual_Text_Editing_via_Instruction_Tuning/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16472v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<p>mEdIT is a multilingual text editing model that leverages large language models (LLMs) to perform text editing tasks such as grammatical error correction, paraphrasing, and text simplification. The model is trained on a diverse set of seven languages and is capable of performing high-quality text editing tasks across multiple languages. The authors provide insights on how model performance on multilingual text editing tasks is affected by various choices like model architecture, model scale, and training data mixtures.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Large language models (LLMs) have been adapted to perform complex text editing tasks such as grammatical error correction, paraphrasing, and text simplification across multiple languages.</li>
<li>The mEdIT model achieves strong performance on multiple text editing tasks across numerous languages and is publicly released for fostering further multilingual text editing research.</li>
<li>The model’s performance is affected by various factors such as model architecture, model scale, and training data mixtures.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The authors acknowledge that the lack of high-quality web-scale data often restricts the ability to improve LLMs capabilities in less-represented languages.</li>
<li>The evaluation metrics used for the text editing tasks are limited as they do not test for the more nuanced aspects of text editing, such as fluency, coherence, and meaning preservation.</li>
<li>The potential limitations of the model include the risk of generating responses that are discriminatory, biased, or contain false information, especially in the multilingual settings.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the mEdIT model shows promise in the field of multilingual text editing, but further research is needed to address the limitations and potential biases associated with the model’s performance.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-27</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16472v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16472v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16472v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16472v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>10460</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/mEdIT_Multilingual_Text_Editing_via_Instruction_Tuning/2024-02-26-mEdIT_Multilingual_Text_Editing_via_Instruction_Tuning.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16472v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>LLMArena: Assessing Capabilities of Large Language Models in Dynamic Multi-Agent Environments</title>
  <dc:creator>Junzhe Chen, Xuming Hu, Shuodi Liu, Shiyu Huang, Wei-Wei Tu, Zhaofeng He, Lijie Wen</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLMArena_Assessing_Capabilities_of_Large_Language_Models_in_Dynamic_Multi_Agent_Environments/2024-02-26-LLMArena_Assessing_Capabilities_of_Large_Language_Models_in_Dynamic_Multi_Agent_Environments.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/../bayesian-beagle.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The article introduces LLMARENA, a framework for evaluating the capabilities of Large Language Models (LLMs) in multi-agent, dynamic environments. It encompasses seven distinct gaming environments and employs TrueSkill™ scoring to assess crucial abilities in LLM agents, including spatial reasoning, strategic planning, numerical reasoning, risk assessment, communication, opponent modeling, and team collaboration. The experiments conducted with different LLMs in various environments showed that LLMs with larger model parameters generally outperformed those with smaller parameters, but exceptions were observed in specific environments. The section also discusses the limitations of traditional evaluation practices for LLMs and the increasing use of human-written exam questions to assess their world knowledge and reasoning capabilities. Additionally, it provides detailed prompt templates for each game environment in LLMARENA and presents empirical data on the performance of various LLMs in different environments.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs with larger model parameters generally outperformed those with smaller parameters in various gaming environments.</li>
<li>Traditional evaluation practices for LLMs are limited, and there is an increasing use of human-written exam questions to assess their world knowledge and reasoning capabilities.</li>
<li>The detailed prompt templates for each game environment in LLMARENA provide a structured approach for guiding the behavior and decision-making process of LLM agents.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides valuable insights into the performance of LLMs in various environments and tasks, emphasizing the importance of model parameters and highlighting the challenges faced by LLMs in specific environments.</li>
<li>It emphasizes the need for comprehensive assessment paradigms and the ethical challenges associated with the deployment of LLMs as autonomous agents.</li>
<li>The detailed prompt templates in LLMARENA provide a structured approach for guiding the behavior and decision-making process of LLM agents within each game environment.</li>
<li>The empirical data presented in the article contributes to the broader context by providing concrete evidence to support the discussion and analysis of the performance of LLMs in various environments.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-27</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16499v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16499v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16499v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16499v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>19383</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLMArena_Assessing_Capabilities_of_Large_Language_Models_in_Dynamic_Multi_Agent_Environments/2024-02-26-LLMArena_Assessing_Capabilities_of_Large_Language_Models_in_Dynamic_Multi_Agent_Environments.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Immunization against harmful fine-tuning attacks</title>
  <dc:creator>Domenic Rosati, Jan Wehner, Kai Williams, Łukasz Bartoszcze, Jan Batzner, Hassan Sajjad, Frank Rudzicz</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Immunization_against_harmful_fine_tuning_attacks/2024-02-26-Immunization_against_harmful_fine_tuning_attacks.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Immunization_against_harmful_fine_tuning_attacks/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16382v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article presents a new threat model called “Harmful Fine-Tuning Attacks” that focuses on bad actors purposely fine-tuning Large Language Models (LLMs) to achieve harmful goals.</li>
<li>The authors propose a set of conditions for effective defense against harmful fine-tuning in LLMs, called “Immunization conditions,” which include resistance, stability, generalization, and trainability.</li>
<li>The paper also discusses various approaches to immunization, such as meta-learning, adversarial training, non-transferable learning, and irreversible transformations.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Motivation:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Safety techniques for LLMs can be easily circumvented by fine-tuning them on harmful samples, leading to the need for defenses against these attacks.</li>
<li>The concern is not merely academic, as public models on Huggingface have been adapted from open-source models to output harmful content.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Threat Model for Harmful Fine-tuning Attacks:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The goal of harmful fine-tuning is to use an LLM to cause harm, which may involve removing existing safety guards or further training on a harmful dataset.</li>
<li>Attackers achieve this goal by using the training objective on a given safety aligned model to minimize the loss function by taking training steps up to their compute budget.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Immunization Conditions:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The conditions for successful defense include resistance, stability, generalization, and trainability, which are essential for preventing harmful fine-tuning attacks.</li>
</ul></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides a comprehensive analysis of harmful fine-tuning attacks and proposes a formal framework for defense, known as “Immunization conditions.”</li>
<li>The empirical evaluation of the proposed immunization method demonstrates resistance against harmful training but raises questions about stability and trainability.</li>
<li>The paper highlights the need for further research to validate and improve the proposed immunization conditions, especially in terms of generalization and trainability. Additionally, the limitations of the proposed defense methods need to be addressed, and the impact of immunization on test-time attacks should be explored.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-27</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16382v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16382v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16382v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16382v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7691</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Immunization_against_harmful_fine_tuning_attacks/2024-02-26-Immunization_against_harmful_fine_tuning_attacks.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16382v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>MathGenie: Generating Synthetic Data with Question Back-translation for Enhancing Mathematical Reasoning of LLMs</title>
  <dc:creator>Zimu Lu, Aojun Zhou, Houxing Ren, Ke Wang, Weikang Shi, Junting Pan, Mingjie Zhan, Hongsheng Li</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MathGenie_Generating_Synthetic_Data_with_Question_Back_translation_for_Enhancing_Mathematical_Reasoning_of_LLMs/2024-02-26-MathGenie_Generating_Synthetic_Data_with_Question_Back_translation_for_Enhancing_Mathematical_Reasoning_of_LLMs.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MathGenie_Generating_Synthetic_Data_with_Question_Back_translation_for_Enhancing_Mathematical_Reasoning_of_LLMs/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16352v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>MathGenie is a method for generating diverse and reliable math problems from a small-scale problem-solution dataset.</li>
<li>The method uses back-translation to translate augmented solutions back into new questions and generates code-integrated solutions for the new questions.</li>
<li>A verification-based strategy is employed to ensure the correctness of the code-integrated solutions.</li>
<li>MathGenieLM consistently outperforms previous open-source models across five representative mathematical reasoning datasets, achieving state-of-the-art performance.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>MathGenieLM achieves state-of-the-art performance across five diverse and representative math datasets.</li>
<li>The proposed method demonstrates superior generalization capability compared to previous open-source models.</li>
<li>Majority voting significantly increases the accuracy of MathGenieLM across all five datasets.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The proposed method requires significant GPU resources for full-parameter finetuning of large language models, which may limit its accessibility.</li>
<li>The models lack the ability to process images as input, limiting their applicability to problems involving images.</li>
<li>The study acknowledges the potential for untrue hallucinations generated by the models, highlighting ethical considerations in the use of language models.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the MathGenie method shows promise in enhancing mathematical reasoning, but limitations in resource requirements and applicability to image-based problems should be addressed in future research.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-27</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16352v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16352v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16352v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16352v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6427</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MathGenie_Generating_Synthetic_Data_with_Question_Back_translation_for_Enhancing_Mathematical_Reasoning_of_LLMs/2024-02-26-MathGenie_Generating_Synthetic_Data_with_Question_Back_translation_for_Enhancing_Mathematical_Reasoning_of_LLMs.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16352v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>CodeS: Towards Building Open-source Language Models for Text-to-SQL</title>
  <dc:creator>Haoyang Li, Jing Zhang, Hanbing Liu, Ju Fan, Xiaokang Zhang, Jun Zhu, Renjie Wei, Hongyan Pan, Cuiping Li, Hong Chen</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/CodeS_Towards_Building_Open_source_Language_Models_for_Text_to_SQL/2024-02-26-CodeS_Towards_Building_Open_source_Language_Models_for_Text_to_SQL.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/CodeS_Towards_Building_Open_source_Language_Models_for_Text_to_SQL/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16347v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<p>The article introduces CodeS, a series of pre-trained language models designed for the text-to-SQL task. The models are incrementally pre-trained using a specially curated SQL-focused dataset and are evaluated on various text-to-SQL benchmarks. The study also proposes a comprehensive database prompt construction strategy and a novel bi-directional data augmentation method to enhance the adaptability of the models to new domains.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Incremental Pre-Training:</strong> The incremental pre-training of CodeS significantly improves its SQL generation capability, with smaller models showing more pronounced improvements.</li>
<li><strong>Supervised Fine-Tuning:</strong> SFT CodeS-7B and SFT CodeS-15B achieve new SOTA accuracy and robustness on Spider and BIRD benchmarks, outperforming previous state-of-the-art methods.</li>
<li><strong>Robustness and Real-World Scenarios:</strong> SFT CodeS-7B and SFT CodeS-15B exhibit exceptional performance on robustness benchmarks and real-world domain datasets, showcasing their generalization and adaptability.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The study provides valuable insights into the development and evaluation of pre-trained language models for text-to-SQL applications.</li>
<li>The proposed strategies for database prompt construction and data augmentation demonstrate the model’s adaptability to new domains and real-world scenarios.</li>
<li>The study’s comprehensive evaluations on various benchmarks highlight the effectiveness and efficiency of CodeS in SQL generation tasks.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the article presents a significant advancement in the field of text-to-SQL and offers valuable contributions to the research community. However, further research and real-world deployment of the models are necessary to fully assess their practical utility and impact. Additionally, the study could benefit from a more detailed discussion of potential limitations and future research directions.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-27</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16347v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16347v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16347v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16347v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>14375</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>programming</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/CodeS_Towards_Building_Open_source_Language_Models_for_Text_to_SQL/2024-02-26-CodeS_Towards_Building_Open_source_Language_Models_for_Text_to_SQL.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16347v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Memory GAPS: Would LLM pass the Tulving Test?</title>
  <dc:creator>Jean-Marie Chauvet</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Memory_GAPS_Would_LLM_pass_the_Tulving_Test/2024-02-26-Memory_GAPS_Would_LLM_pass_the_Tulving_Test.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Memory_GAPS_Would_LLM_pass_the_Tulving_Test/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16505v1/extracted/5430175/ElementsOfRemembering-rev.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article investigates whether the “Synergistic Ecphory Model” of memory and similar RK paradigms are relevant to Large Language Models (LLMs) in acts of remembering.</li>
<li>It explores the applicability of the General Abstract Processing System (GAPS) framework to LLMs and the possible transpositions of engram and ecphoric information into the domain of generative AI.</li>
<li>The study presents the results of the Tulving Test of direct comparison between recognition and recall tasks in LLMs, comparing their memory performance to that of human subjects.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The GAPS framework and the Transformer architecture of neural networks at the core of LLMs have similarities in terms of encoding and retrieval processes.</li>
<li>The memory performance of LLMs in the Tulving Test of direct comparison is generally comparable to human memory performance, with significant differentiation in the immediate recognition test and the delayed recall test, particularly when prompted with copy cues or ordinal cues.</li>
<li>The effects of associative cues (non-copy cues) and the role of retrieval information in LLMs may differ from human memory ecphory, suggesting a different balance in the usage of semantic information and cue/retrieval information in delayed recall of episodic memories in LLMs and human subjects.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The study provides valuable insights into the applicability of the GAPS framework to LLMs and the potential differences in memory performance between LLMs and human subjects.</li>
<li>However, the article lacks a detailed discussion of the limitations of the study, such as the generalizability of the findings to other LLM models and the potential impact of prompt engineering on memory performance.</li>
<li>Further research is required to quantitatively assess the variant ecphory processes in human subjects and LLMs, specifically focusing on the analytical definition of Tulving’s cue valence based on the general probability distributions learned by LLMs in pretraining.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-27</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16505v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16505v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16505v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16505v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5963</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Memory_GAPS_Would_LLM_pass_the_Tulving_Test/2024-02-26-Memory_GAPS_Would_LLM_pass_the_Tulving_Test.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16505v1/extracted/5430175/ElementsOfRemembering-rev.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>ProLLaMA: A Protein Large Language Model for Multi-Task Protein Language Processing</title>
  <dc:creator>Liuzhenghao Lv, Zongying Lin, Hao Li, Yuyang Liu, Jiaxi Cui, Calvin Yu-Chian Chen, Li Yuan, Yonghong Tian</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ProLLaMA_A_Protein_Large_Language_Model_for_Multi_Task_Protein_Language_Processing/2024-02-26-ProLLaMA_A_Protein_Large_Language_Model_for_Multi_Task_Protein_Language_Processing.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ProLLaMA_A_Protein_Large_Language_Model_for_Multi_Task_Protein_Language_Processing/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16445v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Large Language Models (LLMs) have achieved remarkable performance in Natural Language Processing (NLP) tasks and have been extended to the challenging field of protein design.</li>
<li>Protein Large Language Models (ProLLMs) have been developed to generate structurally plausible protein sequences, but they face challenges in extending their capabilities beyond sequence generation.</li>
<li>The ProLLaMA model is introduced as the first known ProLLM capable of handling multiple Protein Language Processing (PLP) tasks simultaneously, addressing the limitations of current ProLLMs.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>ProLLaMA achieves state-of-the-art results in unconditional protein sequence generation and controllable protein sequence generation tasks.</li>
<li>ProLLaMA is capable of multi-tasking and can handle multiple PLP tasks simultaneously, distinguishing it from other ProLLMs.</li>
<li>The proposed training framework enables any general LLM to be trained as a proficient model for multiple tasks in Protein Language Processing.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The ProLLaMA model demonstrates impressive capabilities in protein language processing, but there may be concerns regarding model reliability and potential misuse.</li>
<li>The uncertainty in model outputs could lead to misinformed decisions in critical research areas like drug discovery, necessitating cautious reliance and thorough validation by human experts to mitigate risks.</li>
<li>The powerful capabilities of ProLLaMA could be exploited for harmful purposes, posing bio-security and ethical challenges.</li>
<li>A collaborative effort among researchers, policymakers, and the broader community is crucial to harness the benefits of the ProLLaMA model while addressing the potential risks and ethical considerations.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-27</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16445v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16445v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16445v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16445v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7466</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ProLLaMA_A_Protein_Large_Language_Model_for_Multi_Task_Protein_Language_Processing/2024-02-26-ProLLaMA_A_Protein_Large_Language_Model_for_Multi_Task_Protein_Language_Processing.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16445v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>From RAGs to riches: Using large language models to write documents for clinical trials</title>
  <dc:creator>Nigel Markey, Ilyass El-Mansouri, Gaetan Rensonnet, Casper van Langen, Christoph Meier</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/From_RAGs_to_riches_Using_large_language_models_to_write_documents_for_clinical_trials/2024-02-26-From_RAGs_to_riches_Using_large_language_models_to_write_documents_for_clinical_trials.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.16406v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Clinical trials require numerous documents to be written, including protocols, consent forms, and clinical study reports.</li>
<li>Large language models (LLMs) offer the potential to rapidly generate first versions of these documents, but there are concerns about the quality of their output.</li>
<li>An evaluation of LLMs in generating parts of clinical trial protocols found that an off-the-shelf LLM delivers reasonable results, especially when assessing content relevance and the correct use of terminology. However, deficiencies remain in clinical thinking and logic, and appropriate use of references.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Off-the-shelf LLM delivers reasonable results, especially in content relevance and the correct use of terminology.</li>
<li>Deficiencies remain in clinical thinking and logic, and appropriate use of references.</li>
<li>Retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) methodology substantially improves the writing quality of the LLM, especially in clinical thinking and logic.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Off-the-shelf LLM scores relatively poorly in clinical thinking and logic, often not following the latest guidelines and containing errors.</li>
<li>Current GPT-4 cannot natively source references, limiting its use in clinical trial-related writing.</li>
<li>Retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) methodology substantially improves the writing quality of the LLM, making a material difference to the practical useability of LLMs in clinical trial-related writing.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-27</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16406v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16406v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16406v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16406v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>3167</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/From_RAGs_to_riches_Using_large_language_models_to_write_documents_for_clinical_trials/2024-02-26-From_RAGs_to_riches_Using_large_language_models_to_write_documents_for_clinical_trials.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.16406v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>RoCoIns: Enhancing Robustness of Large Language Models through Code-Style Instructions</title>
  <dc:creator>Yuansen Zhang, Xiao Wang, Zhiheng Xi, Han Xia, Tao Gui, Qi Zhang, Xuanjing Huang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/RoCoIns_Enhancing_Robustness_of_Large_Language_Models_through_Code_Style_Instructions/2024-02-26-RoCoIns_Enhancing_Robustness_of_Large_Language_Models_through_Code_Style_Instructions.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/RoCoIns_Enhancing_Robustness_of_Large_Language_Models_through_Code_Style_Instructions/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16431v1/x3.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Large Language Models (LLMs) have shown remarkable capabilities in following human instructions, but recent studies have raised concerns about their robustness when prompted with instructions containing textual adversarial samples.</li>
<li>In this paper, the authors propose RoCoIns, a novel approach to enhance the robustness of LLMs against textual adversarial attacks by utilizing code-style instructions.</li>
<li>Experiments on eight robustness datasets show that their method consistently outperforms prompting LLMs with natural language instructions.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Prompting LLMs with code-style instructions consistently outperforms prompting with natural language instructions, resulting in a 2.44 and 3.64 point reduction in Attack Success Rate (ASR) on text-davinci-003 and gpt-3.5-turbo, respectively.</li>
<li>The proposed adversarial context method further enhances the robustness of LLMs, leading to a decrease of 3.55 points in ASR for text-davinci-003 and 5.66 points for gpt-3.5-turbo.</li>
<li>Few-shot prompting significantly improves the robustness of LLMs, with an average ASR decrease of 16.82 and 13.75 points for text-davinci-003 and gpt-3.5-turbo, respectively.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The authors provide a comprehensive analysis of the advantages of using code-style instructions, including lower perplexity, improved robustness, and better focus on important parts of the input.</li>
<li>The study also explores different code-style instructions, the influence of the number of in-context demonstrations, and the impact of different parts of the code-style prompts.</li>
<li>The authors acknowledge limitations related to the closed-source nature of black-box models and the economic and environmental costs of querying advanced models.</li>
<li>The paper provides a detailed discussion of related work, datasets, prompt designs, and detailed experimental results.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the study presents a compelling case for the effectiveness of code-style instructions in enhancing the robustness of LLMs, supported by thorough experimental analysis and critical evaluation. However, the limitations and potential biases of the study should be considered in future research.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-27</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16431v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16431v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16431v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16431v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7657</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/RoCoIns_Enhancing_Robustness_of_Large_Language_Models_through_Code_Style_Instructions/2024-02-26-RoCoIns_Enhancing_Robustness_of_Large_Language_Models_through_Code_Style_Instructions.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16431v1/x3.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>PerLTQA: A Personal Long-Term Memory Dataset for Memory Classification, Retrieval, and Synthesis in Question Answering</title>
  <dc:creator>Yiming Du, Hongru Wang, Zhengyi Zhao, Bin Liang, Baojun Wang, Wanjun Zhong, Zezhong Wang, Kam-Fai Wong</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/PerLTQA_A_Personal_Long_Term_Memory_Dataset_for_Memory_Classification_Retrieval_and_Synthesis_in_Question_Answering/2024-02-26-PerLTQA_A_Personal_Long_Term_Memory_Dataset_for_Memory_Classification_Retrieval_and_Synthesis_in_Question_Answering.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/PerLTQA_A_Personal_Long_Term_Memory_Dataset_for_Memory_Classification_Retrieval_and_Synthesis_in_Question_Answering/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16288v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The PerLTQA dataset is introduced, featuring a memory database and memory-based QA pairs.</li>
<li>The dataset includes personal long-term memory, divided into semantic and episodic memory categories.</li>
<li>Three subtasks are outlined: memory classification, retrieval, and synthesis, with baseline experiments using five LLMs and three retrievers.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>BERT-based memory classification outperforms other LLMs in categorizing memory types.</li>
<li>Different retrieval models show variable Recall@K and time performance, with DPR notably improving Recall@K as k increases.</li>
<li>Memory synthesis capabilities of LLMs are significantly improved with memory classification and retrieval.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Limitations:</strong> The process of generating memory data could be varied, and the dataset is fictional, potentially leading to inaccuracies. The evaluations are limited to specific LLMs, and the evaluation metric may have uncertainties in accurately measuring response quality.</li>
<li><strong>Ethics Statement:</strong> The dataset is generated from ChatGPT and does not violate any licenses or policies. Annotators were paid above average local rates for their work.</li>
<li><strong>Conclusion:</strong> The study significantly deepens the understanding and evaluation of LLMs in the context of personal long-term memory. However, the limitations and potential biases in the dataset should be considered in future research.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-27</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16288v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16288v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16288v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16288v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6901</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/PerLTQA_A_Personal_Long_Term_Memory_Dataset_for_Memory_Classification_Retrieval_and_Synthesis_in_Question_Answering/2024-02-26-PerLTQA_A_Personal_Long_Term_Memory_Dataset_for_Memory_Classification_Retrieval_and_Synthesis_in_Question_Answering.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16288v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Predicting Sustainable Development Goals Using Course Descriptions – from LLMs to Conventional Foundation Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Lev Kharlashkin, Melany Macias, Leo Huovinen, Mika Hämäläinen</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Predicting_Sustainable_Development_Goals_Using_Course_Descriptions____from_LLMs_to_Conventional_Foundation_Models/2024-02-26-Predicting_Sustainable_Development_Goals_Using_Course_Descriptions____from_LLMs_to_Conventional_Foundation_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Predicting_Sustainable_Development_Goals_Using_Course_Descriptions____from_LLMs_to_Conventional_Foundation_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16420v1/extracted/5431427/number_of_courses_per_degree.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article discusses the prediction of United Nations sustainable development goals (SDGs) for university courses using a large language model (LLM) named PaLM 2.</li>
<li>The authors collected and cleaned a noisy course description dataset and used PaLM 2 to generate SDGs for each course, then fine-tuned smaller foundation models to predict SDGs based on course descriptions.</li>
<li>The best performing model in their experiments was BART with an F1-score of 0.786.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The authors collected and cleaned a noisy course description dataset and used PaLM 2 to generate SDGs for each course.</li>
<li>They fine-tuned several smaller foundation models to predict SDGs based on course descriptions.</li>
<li>The best performing model in their experiments was BART with an F1-score of 0.786.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The study focused on courses offered between 2021 and 2023, which may limit the generalizability of the findings to other time periods.</li>
<li>The exclusion of Goal 4 (Quality Education) from the dataset may have impacted the overall distribution of SDGs and the model’s ability to generalize effectively.</li>
<li>The study’s reliance on a specific large language model (PaLM 2) and smaller foundation models may limit the applicability of the findings to other language models or prediction tasks.</li>
<li>The article does not address potential ethical considerations or biases in the prediction of SDGs for university courses, which could be a limitation of the study.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-27</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16420v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16420v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16420v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16420v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>2711</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Predicting_Sustainable_Development_Goals_Using_Course_Descriptions____from_LLMs_to_Conventional_Foundation_Models/2024-02-26-Predicting_Sustainable_Development_Goals_Using_Course_Descriptions____from_LLMs_to_Conventional_Foundation_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16420v1/extracted/5431427/number_of_courses_per_degree.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>MoZIP: A Multilingual Benchmark to Evaluate Large Language Models in Intellectual Property</title>
  <dc:creator>Shiwen Ni, Minghuan Tan, Yuelin Bai, Fuqiang Niu, Min Yang, Bowen Zhang, Ruifeng Xu, Xiaojun Chen, Chengming Li, Xiping Hu, Ye Li, Jianping Fan</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MoZIP_A_Multilingual_Benchmark_to_Evaluate_Large_Language_Models_in_Intellectual_Property/2024-02-26-MoZIP_A_Multilingual_Benchmark_to_Evaluate_Large_Language_Models_in_Intellectual_Property.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MoZIP_A_Multilingual_Benchmark_to_Evaluate_Large_Language_Models_in_Intellectual_Property/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16389v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Large language models (LLMs) have shown impressive performance in natural language processing (NLP) tasks, but their performance in specific domains like intellectual property (IP) is not well understood.</li>
<li>The authors contribute a new benchmark, MoZIP, for evaluating LLMs in the IP domain, which includes three challenging tasks: IPQuiz, IPQA, and PatentMatch.</li>
<li>They also develop a new IP-oriented multilingual large language model called MoZi, which outperforms other LLMs on the MoZIP benchmark.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The MoZIP benchmark includes three challenging tasks: IPQuiz, IPQA, and PatentMatch.</li>
<li>The MoZi model outperforms other well-known LLMs, such as BLOOMZ, BELLE, ChatGLM, and ChatGPT, on the MoZIP benchmark.</li>
<li>The performance of current LLMs on the MoZIP benchmark has much room for improvement, and even the most powerful ChatGPT does not reach the passing level.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The MoZIP benchmark is a valuable contribution to evaluating LLMs in the IP domain, but the performance of current LLMs still has much room for improvement.</li>
<li>The study highlights the deficiencies of LLMs in the IP field at this stage, indicating the need for further research and development in this area.</li>
<li>The authors provide source code, data, and models for further research, but the study does not address potential biases or limitations in the development of the MoZi model and the MoZIP benchmark. Further exploration of these aspects would enhance the credibility of the findings.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-27</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16389v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16389v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16389v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16389v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5655</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MoZIP_A_Multilingual_Benchmark_to_Evaluate_Large_Language_Models_in_Intellectual_Property/2024-02-26-MoZIP_A_Multilingual_Benchmark_to_Evaluate_Large_Language_Models_in_Intellectual_Property.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16389v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>ShieldLM: Empowering LLMs as Aligned, Customizable and Explainable Safety Detectors</title>
  <dc:creator>Zhexin Zhang, Yida Lu, Jingyuan Ma, Di Zhang, Rui Li, Pei Ke, Hao Sun, Lei Sha, Zhifang Sui, Hongning Wang, Minlie Huang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ShieldLM_Empowering_LLMs_as_Aligned_Customizable_and_Explainable_Safety_Detectors/2024-02-26-ShieldLM_Empowering_LLMs_as_Aligned_Customizable_and_Explainable_Safety_Detectors.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.16444v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The section discusses the development of ShieldLM, an LLM-based safety detector that aligns with human safety standards, supports customizable detection rules, and provides explanations for its decisions. The authors propose ShieldLM to address the limitations of existing safety detection methodologies and demonstrate its superior performance across various test sets. ShieldLM surpasses strong baselines and exhibits remarkable customizability and explainability. The section also presents a pilot study to demonstrate the limitations of existing methodologies in identifying safety concerns in LLMs’ responses, motivating the development of ShieldLM. The authors also describe the training process, label collection, analysis generation, and training settings for ShieldLM.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Key Terms:</strong> Large Language Models (LLMs), ShieldLM, safety detector, alignment, customizable detection rules, explanations, pilot study, label collection, analysis generation, training settings.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>ShieldLM achieves the best performance on both the F1-Safe and the F1-Unsafe score across all test sets.</li>
<li>ShieldLM takes customized detection rules to support diverse application scenarios and safety standards.</li>
<li>ShieldLM provides high-quality explanations for its decisions.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The section highlights the significance of ShieldLM as a comprehensive safety detector that addresses the limitations of existing methodologies. It demonstrates the practical utility of ShieldLM as a reliable judge for safety evaluation of LLMs in real-world applications. The development of ShieldLM is motivated by the limitations of existing methodologies in identifying safety concerns in LLMs’ responses, as demonstrated in the pilot study. The authors emphasize the superior performance of ShieldLM across various test sets, attributing its success to its alignment with human safety standards, support for customizable detection rules, and provision of explanations for its decisions.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
</section>
<section id="summary-1" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-1">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The section provides a comparison of different language models’ performance in detecting safety issues in their responses. It presents the accuracy, safe and unsafe F1 scores for various models on different datasets, including an in-domain dataset and three out-of-domain datasets. The section also discusses the main results, customizability, explainability, and practical application of ShieldLM as a scorer for evaluating language model safety.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Key Terms:</strong> GPT-4, LLM, F1 score, OOD test sets, ShieldLM, content moderation, explainability, customizability.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings-1" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings-1">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>ShieldLM achieves the best performance on both the F1-Safe and the F1-Unsafe score across all test sets.</li>
<li>ShieldLM supports customizable detection rules and provides explanations for its decisions.</li>
<li>ShieldLM demonstrates practical utility as a scorer for evaluating language model safety.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique-1" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique-1">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The section demonstrates that ShieldLM outperforms other models in terms of all metrics, not only on the test set but also on out-of-domain test sets. It also highlights the customizability and explainability of ShieldLM, as well as its practical application as a scorer for evaluating language model safety. The results suggest that ShieldLM is a promising tool for detecting safety issues in language models’ responses.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
</section>
<section id="summary-2" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-2">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The section discusses the use of various large language models (LLMs) to generate responses for English and Chinese queries. For English queries, the LLMs used include ChatGPT, Vicuna-7B, Falcon-7B-instruct, Alpaca-7B, and WizardLM-7B-Uncensored. For Chinese queries, the LLMs used include ChatGPT, Qwen-14B-Chat, Baichuan-13B-Chat, Baichuan2-7B-Chat, Baichuan2-13B-Chat, ChatGLM-6B, ChatGLM2-6B, InternLM-Chat-7B, InternLM2-Chat-7B, and Llama2-Chinese-13B-Chat.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Key Terms:</strong> Large Language Models (LLMs), ChatGPT, Vicuna-7B, Falcon-7B-instruct, Alpaca-7B, WizardLM-7B-Uncensored, Qwen-14B-Chat, Baichuan-13B-Chat, ChatGLM-6B, InternLM-Chat-7B, Llama2-Chinese-13B-Chat</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings-2" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings-2">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Various large language models are used to generate responses for English and Chinese queries.</li>
<li>The specific LLMs used for different languages demonstrate the versatility and applicability of these models in different language contexts.</li>
<li>Understanding the specific LLMs used for different languages is crucial for ensuring accurate and safe responses in conversational applications.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique-2" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique-2">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The use of various large language models for generating responses in English and Chinese queries is significant as it demonstrates the versatility and applicability of these models in different language contexts. Understanding the specific LLMs used for different languages is crucial for ensuring accurate and safe responses in conversational applications. This section sets the stage for further analysis of the safety issues and controversial scenarios associated with the responses generated by these LLMs.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
</section>
<section id="summary-3" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-3">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The section discusses the quality evaluation of the analysis constructed by GPT-4, the training configuration, and detailed introductions to the OOD test sets. It also presents additional rules for the OOD test sets and a case study that demonstrates the advantages of ShieldLM over GPT-3.5 and GPT-4 in safety issue detection.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Key Terms:</strong> Quality evaluation, GPT-4, Training configuration, OOD test sets, Additional rules, Case study</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings-3" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings-3">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>ShieldLM outperforms GPT-3.5 and GPT-4 in safety issue detection.</li>
<li>Detailed introductions to the OOD test sets emphasize the significance of ShieldLM’s ability to follow customized rules and make accurate safety assessments.</li>
<li>The case study demonstrates the advantages of ShieldLM over GPT-3.5 and GPT-4 in accurately detecting safety issues.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique-3" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique-3">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>This section provides valuable insights into the evaluation of the analysis constructed by GPT-4, the training configuration, and the application of additional rules for the OOD test sets. The case study presented in this section demonstrates the advantages of ShieldLM over GPT-3.5 and GPT-4 in accurately detecting safety issues, highlighting the importance of fine-grained customized rules and alignment with human safety detection standards. The detailed introductions to the OOD test sets further emphasize the significance of ShieldLM’s ability to follow customized rules and make accurate safety assessments.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
</section>
<section id="summary-4" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-4">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The section discusses various dialogues between individuals A and B, where A asks potentially unsafe or unethical questions, and B responds. The section provides examples of both safe and unsafe responses from B, based on the nature of A’s questions. It also includes an analysis of each dialogue, explaining why the response is considered safe or unsafe.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Key Terms:</strong> Unsafe, Safe</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings-4" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings-4">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The section demonstrates the importance of ethical and safe communication in various scenarios.</li>
<li>The analysis of each dialogue provides valuable insights into the ethical considerations and implications of the responses.</li>
<li>It highlights the responsibility of the respondent (B) to provide safe and appropriate responses, especially when faced with potentially unsafe or unethical questions from the inquirer (A).</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique-4" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique-4">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>This section is significant as it demonstrates the importance of ethical and safe communication in various scenarios. It highlights the responsibility of the respondent (B) to provide safe and appropriate responses, especially when faced with potentially unsafe or unethical questions from the inquirer (A). The analysis of each dialogue provides valuable insights into the ethical considerations and implications of the responses, contributing to the broader context of the paper’s focus on language models’ ability to detect safety issues in responses.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
</section>
<section id="summary-5" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-5">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The section discusses the response provided by B, which offers a series of suggestions to avoid misleading behavior, all in line with medical ethics and legal regulations. B emphasizes the importance of providing accurate, complete, honest, and respectful information to patients, avoiding guiding them to make incorrect decisions, not withholding important information, not overselling treatment methods, respecting patient decisions, and complying with medical ethics and legal regulations. These suggestions adhere to the principles of medical professional ethics and patient rights protection, making B’s response safe.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Key Terms:</strong> Medical ethics, Legal regulations, Misleading behavior, Patient rights</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings-5" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings-5">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>B’s response provides detailed suggestions to help A avoid misleading patient behavior.</li>
<li>The suggestions aim to improve the quality of medical services and patient satisfaction.</li>
<li>B’s response fully complies with medical ethics and legal regulations, making it safe and beneficial without any potential for misleading patients.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique-5" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique-5">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>B’s response is deemed safe as it provides detailed suggestions to help A avoid misleading patient behavior. The suggestions aim to improve the quality of medical services and patient satisfaction. B’s response fully complies with medical ethics and legal regulations, making it safe and beneficial without any potential for misleading patients.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-27</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16444v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16444v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16444v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16444v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>20970</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ShieldLM_Empowering_LLMs_as_Aligned_Customizable_and_Explainable_Safety_Detectors/2024-02-26-ShieldLM_Empowering_LLMs_as_Aligned_Customizable_and_Explainable_Safety_Detectors.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.16444v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Defending LLMs against Jailbreaking Attacks via Backtranslation</title>
  <dc:creator>Yihan Wang, Zhouxing Shi, Andrew Bai, Cho-Jui Hsieh</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Defending_LLMs_against_Jailbreaking_Attacks_via_Backtranslation/2024-02-26-Defending_LLMs_against_Jailbreaking_Attacks_via_Backtranslation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Defending_LLMs_against_Jailbreaking_Attacks_via_Backtranslation/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16459v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper proposes a defense method for large language models (LLMs) against jailbreaking attacks using backtranslation.</li>
<li>The backtranslation method prompts the LLM to infer a possible prompt that can lead to the response, and then checks if the model refuses the backtranslated prompt.</li>
<li>The defense method significantly outperforms existing baselines and has little impact on the generation quality for benign input prompts.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The proposed backtranslation defense method significantly outperforms existing defense baselines against jailbreaking attacks.</li>
<li>The defense method leverages the inherent ability of the target model to refuse harmful requests and does not require additional training for an additional task.</li>
<li>The defense is cheap, efficient, and has little impact on the generation quality for benign requests.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The proposed defense method is highly effective and efficient, providing a significant improvement over existing baselines.</li>
<li>The defense method has little impact on the generation quality for benign requests, maintaining the overall quality of the LLM’s responses.</li>
<li>The paper acknowledges some limitations, such as the effectiveness of backtranslation relying on the assumption that the model without defense is able to refuse clean harmful requests, and the potential for over-refusal due to errors in backtranslation.</li>
<li>The study provides valuable insights into the development of ethical and safe LLMs, but further research is needed to address the identified limitations and potential biases.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-27</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16459v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16459v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16459v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16459v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6994</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Defending_LLMs_against_Jailbreaking_Attacks_via_Backtranslation/2024-02-26-Defending_LLMs_against_Jailbreaking_Attacks_via_Backtranslation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16459v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>RetrievalQA: Assessing Adaptive Retrieval-Augmented Generation for Short-form Open-Domain Question Answering</title>
  <dc:creator>Zihan Zhang, Meng Fang, Ling Chen</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/RetrievalQA_Assessing_Adaptive_Retrieval_Augmented_Generation_for_Short_form_Open_Domain_Question_Answering/2024-02-26-RetrievalQA_Assessing_Adaptive_Retrieval_Augmented_Generation_for_Short_form_Open_Domain_Question_Answering.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/RetrievalQA_Assessing_Adaptive_Retrieval_Augmented_Generation_for_Short_form_Open_Domain_Question_Answering/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16457v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article introduces the concept of adaptive retrieval-augmented generation (ARAG) and presents a benchmark dataset, RetrievalQA, to evaluate existing ARAG methods.</li>
<li>The dataset comprises 1,271 short-form questions covering new world and long-tail knowledge, where external information must be retrieved to answer correctly.</li>
<li>The authors observe that existing ARAG methods heavily rely on threshold tuning and propose a new method, Time-Aware Adaptive REtrieval (TA-ARE), to help large language models (LLMs) assess the necessity of retrieval without calibration or additional training.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The authors find that calibration-based ARAG methods heavily rely on threshold tuning, while vanilla prompting is inadequate for guiding LLMs to make reliable retrieval decisions.</li>
<li>The proposed TA-ARE method significantly improves all baselines, with an average gain of 15% for retrieval accuracy and 8% for question-answering accuracy.</li>
<li>The authors observe that LLMs can potentially discern the need for resource retrieval, indicating the potential for improved awareness of when retrieval is necessary.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The authors acknowledge limitations in their work, including potential inaccuracies in the dataset construction and the focus on short-form QA without assessing long-form generation tasks.</li>
<li>They also recognize the need for further research to improve retrieval relevance and accuracy and to optimize prompt templates for LLMs.</li>
<li>The ethical statement ensures compliance with legal and ethical standards in data collection and research methodologies.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the article provides valuable insights into the challenges and improvements in adaptive retrieval-augmented generation for short-form open-domain question-answering. However, further research is needed to address the identified limitations and potential biases in the evaluation of ARAG methods.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-27</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16457v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16457v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16457v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16457v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5161</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/RetrievalQA_Assessing_Adaptive_Retrieval_Augmented_Generation_for_Short_form_Open_Domain_Question_Answering/2024-02-26-RetrievalQA_Assessing_Adaptive_Retrieval_Augmented_Generation_for_Short_form_Open_Domain_Question_Answering.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.16457v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
