<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Bayesian beagle</title>
<link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Quarto blog of LLM-generated summaries of Arxiv preprints</description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.450</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Personalized Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Stanisław Woźniak, Bartłomiej Koptyra, Arkadiusz Janz, Przemysław Kazienko, Jan Kocoń</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Personalized_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-14-Personalized_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/../bayesian-beagle.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Large language models (LLMs) have significantly advanced Natural Language Processing (NLP) tasks in recent years.</li>
<li>This paper investigates methods to personalize LLMs, comparing fine-tuning and zero-shot reasoning approaches on subjective tasks.</li>
<li>Results demonstrate that personalized fine-tuning improves model reasoning compared to non-personalized models.</li>
<li>Experiments on datasets for emotion recognition and hate speech detection show consistent performance gains with personalized methods across different LLM architectures.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Personalized fine-tuning improves model reasoning compared to non-personalized models.</li>
<li>Experiments on datasets for emotion recognition and hate speech detection show consistent performance gains with personalized methods across different LLM architectures.</li>
<li>The findings underscore the importance of personalization for enhancing LLM capabilities in subjective text perception tasks.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study highlights the significant benefits of personalizing LLMs for subjective text perception, but it may not fully translate to tasks requiring objective, rational reasoning.</li>
<li>The impact of model architecture and size critically influences the efficacy of personalization strategies, suggesting that further research is needed to explore these aspects across a wider set of models.</li>
<li>Ethical considerations include privacy and data protection, potential bias in model outcomes, misuse of personalized models, and transparency in how personalization influences model responses.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-15</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09269v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09269v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09269v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09269v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>12339</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Personalized_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-14-Personalized_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>AQA-Bench: An Interactive Benchmark for Evaluating LLMs’ Sequential Reasoning Ability</title>
  <dc:creator>Siwei Yang, Bingchen Zhao, Cihang Xie</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/AQA_Bench_An_Interactive_Benchmark_for_Evaluating_LLMs_Sequential_Reasoning_Ability/2024-02-14-AQA_Bench_An_Interactive_Benchmark_for_Evaluating_LLMs_Sequential_Reasoning_Ability.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.09404v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The academic paper introduces AQA-Bench, an interactive benchmark designed to evaluate the sequential reasoning capabilities of large language models (LLMs) in algorithmic contexts.</li>
<li>The investigation reveals several interesting findings, including the strong performance of closed-source models like GPT-4 and Gemini, the potential negative impact of naively providing interactive examples, and the limited number of predecessor steps that can boost small models’ performance.</li>
<li>The paper discusses the significance of the benchmark in advancing the understanding and enhancement of LLMs’ capabilities in sequential reasoning.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>AQA-Bench demonstrates the strong performance of closed-source models like GPT-4 and Gemini in sequential reasoning abilities.</li>
<li>Naively providing interactive examples may have a potential negative impact on the performance of language models.</li>
<li>Limited predecessor steps can significantly boost the performance of small language models in sequential reasoning tasks.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The findings provide valuable insights into the performance of different LLMs and highlight the potential impact of interactive examples on few-shot performance.</li>
<li>The results have implications for future research focused on evaluating and enhancing the sequential reasoning abilities of LLMs.</li>
<li>The study challenges the assumption that larger model sizes consistently lead to improved performance in language models, emphasizing the importance of considering the specific application and task when evaluating model performance.</li>
<li>The section also highlights the importance of evaluating GPT models on the same dataset multiple times to limit the impact of their randomness on the results and emphasizes the consistency of the models’ performance under the HARD testing protocol.</li>
<li>The evaluation results provide insights into the performance of different LLMs in sequential reasoning tasks across various environments, guiding the development and improvement of LLMs for enhanced sequential reasoning abilities.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-15</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09404v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09404v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09404v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09404v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>22322</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/AQA_Bench_An_Interactive_Benchmark_for_Evaluating_LLMs_Sequential_Reasoning_Ability/2024-02-14-AQA_Bench_An_Interactive_Benchmark_for_Evaluating_LLMs_Sequential_Reasoning_Ability.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.09404v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Tree-Based Hard Attention with Self-Motivation for Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Chenxi Lin, Jiayu Ren, Guoxiu He, Zhuoren Jiang, Haiyan Yu, Xiaomin Zhu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Tree_Based_Hard_Attention_with_Self_Motivation_for_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-14-Tree_Based_Hard_Attention_with_Self_Motivation_for_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Tree_Based_Hard_Attention_with_Self_Motivation_for_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.08874v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Large language models (LLMs) struggle with hierarchical text structures, requiring additional processing steps to extract task-desired properties.</li>
<li>TEAROOM proposes a novel framework that incorporates a tree-based hard attention mechanism and a self-motivation strategy to address these challenges.</li>
<li>Experimental evaluations across three benchmark datasets demonstrate TEAROOM’s effectiveness in estimating task-specific properties and gradually approaching the underlying golden truth through multiple inferences.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>TEAROOM outperforms existing state-of-the-art methods in experimental evaluations across three benchmark datasets, showing its effectiveness in estimating task-specific properties.</li>
<li>The tree-based hard attention mechanism enables LLMs to efficiently capture hierarchical relationships, addressing limitations associated with processing lengthy plain text inputs.</li>
<li>The self-motivation strategy enhances LLM alignment from the current prediction towards the golden truth via multiple iterations of inference.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The proposed TEAROOM framework demonstrates significant improvements in estimating task-specific properties and aligning with specific tasks. However, the study could benefit from a more detailed discussion of potential limitations and challenges, such as inference time and scalability.</li>
<li>The self-motivation strategy shows promise in enhancing the learning process of LLMs, but further research is needed to explore its applicability across different domains and datasets.</li>
<li>The ablation study highlights the critical role of the tree-based hard attention mechanism and the self-motivation strategy in the overall performance of TEAROOM, emphasizing the importance of these components in addressing the challenges of hierarchical text structures.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-15</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.08874v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.08874v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.08874v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.08874v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6442</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Tree_Based_Hard_Attention_with_Self_Motivation_for_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-14-Tree_Based_Hard_Attention_with_Self_Motivation_for_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.08874v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Leveraging the Context through Multi-Round Interactions for Jailbreaking Attacks</title>
  <dc:creator>Yixin Cheng, Markos Georgopoulos, Volkan Cevher, Grigorios G. Chrysos</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Leveraging_the_Context_through_Multi_Round_Interactions_for_Jailbreaking_Attacks/2024-02-14-Leveraging_the_Context_through_Multi_Round_Interactions_for_Jailbreaking_Attacks.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.09177v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article discusses the Contextual Interaction Attack, a new form of Jailbreaking attack that leverages the autoregressive nature of Large Language Models (LLMs) to elicit harmful information. It highlights the significance of the context vector in forging potent Jailbreaking attacks and demonstrates the efficacy and transferability of the attack across multiple state-of-the-art LLMs. It also presents an experiment to evaluate the effectiveness of the attack, comparing it with other jailbreaking methods and automated jailbreaking methods, as well as an ablation study to analyze the impact of different factors on the attack’s success rate. The article also provides acknowledgments for the support and funding of the research, as well as a list of references for the academic paper. Additionally, it discusses examples of jailbreaking attacks on language models, ethical considerations and challenges of using language models to generate prompts for sensitive topics, and best practices for creating a diverse and inclusive workplace culture.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The Contextual Interaction Attack leverages the context vector in LLMs to elicit harmful information and demonstrates high success rates and strong transferability properties across different LLMs.</li>
<li>The Contextual Interaction Attack is superior to other jailbreaking methods and automated techniques, as demonstrated by comparison experiments and ablation studies.</li>
<li>The article provides insights into the potential misuse of language models for generating harmful and unethical content, highlighting the vulnerability of AI models to being manipulated for malicious purposes.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides valuable insights into the development and evaluation of the Contextual Interaction Attack, as well as the ethical considerations and challenges of using language models to generate prompts for sensitive topics. It emphasizes the need for context and semantic consistency in generating successful attacks and the balance between security and the ability to generate relevant text. The selection of auxiliary LLMs has implications for the effectiveness of generating diverse prompts for jailbreaking attacks. However, further research is needed to address potential biases, methodological issues, and the impact of in-context learning and recency bias on LLM security.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-15</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09177v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09177v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09177v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09177v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>24565</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Leveraging_the_Context_through_Multi_Round_Interactions_for_Jailbreaking_Attacks/2024-02-14-Leveraging_the_Context_through_Multi_Round_Interactions_for_Jailbreaking_Attacks.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.09177v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Self-Alignment for Factuality: Mitigating Hallucinations in LLMs via Self-Evaluation</title>
  <dc:creator>Xiaoying Zhang, Baolin Peng, Ye Tian, Jingyan Zhou, Lifeng Jin, Linfeng Song, Haitao Mi, Helen Meng</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Self_Alignment_for_Factuality_Mitigating_Hallucinations_in_LLMs_via_Self_Evaluation/2024-02-14-Self_Alignment_for_Factuality_Mitigating_Hallucinations_in_LLMs_via_Self_Evaluation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.09267v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article introduces the concept of <strong>Self-Alignment for Factuality</strong> to address factual inaccuracies in large language models (LLMs).</li>
<li>It proposes leveraging the self-evaluation capability of an LLM to provide training signals that steer the model towards factuality.</li>
<li>The authors incorporate a self-evaluation component, <strong>SELF-EVAL</strong>, and design <strong>SK-TUNING</strong> to augment the LLM’s self-evaluation ability, substantially enhancing factual accuracy over LLAMA family models across knowledge-intensive tasks on TruthfulQA and BioGEN.</li>
<li>The article evaluates the capability of factuality estimation by assessing the model’s confidence in selecting the correct answer and distinguishing it from a randomly sampled incorrect answer, demonstrating the efficacy of the <strong>SK-TUNING</strong> framework in improving the model’s confidence estimation.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The proposed <strong>Self-Alignment for Factuality</strong> approach substantially enhances factual accuracy over LLAMA family models across knowledge-intensive tasks.</li>
<li>The <strong>SK-TUNING</strong> framework shows strong efficacy in improving the model’s confidence estimation, as demonstrated in Table 3.</li>
<li>The results suggest that the proposed self-alignment approach offers a promising starting point for investigating LLM’s factuality self-alignment.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article presents a promising approach to enhancing the factual accuracy of LLMs, addressing the challenges of hallucinations and improving confidence estimation and calibration.</li>
<li>The methodology outlined in the article provides valuable insights into the potential applications of the proposed framework in different domains and emphasizes the significance of confidence estimation and calibration in LLMs.</li>
<li>However, further research is needed to explore the scalability and generalizability of the proposed approach across different types of language understanding tasks and datasets. Additionally, the article could benefit from discussing potential limitations and ethical considerations associated with the use of large language models.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-15</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09267v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09267v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09267v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09267v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>21341</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Self_Alignment_for_Factuality_Mitigating_Hallucinations_in_LLMs_via_Self_Evaluation/2024-02-14-Self_Alignment_for_Factuality_Mitigating_Hallucinations_in_LLMs_via_Self_Evaluation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.09267v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Ten Words Only Still Help: Improving Black-Box AI-Generated Text Detection via Proxy-Guided Efficient Re-Sampling</title>
  <dc:creator>Yuhui Shi, Qiang Sheng, Juan Cao, Hao Mi, Beizhe Hu, Danding Wang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Ten_Words_Only_Still_Help_Improving_Black_Box_AI_Generated_Text_Detection_via_Proxy_Guided_Efficient_Re_Sampling/2024-02-14-Ten_Words_Only_Still_Help_Improving_Black_Box_AI_Generated_Text_Detection_via_Proxy_Guided_Efficient_Re_Sampling.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.09199v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article proposes a method called POGER to improve the detection of AI-generated text (AIGT) under the black-box setting.</li>
<li>The proposed method estimates word generation probabilities to empower black-box AIGT detection and shows its feasibility.</li>
<li>POGER outperforms all baselines in macro F1 under black-box, partial white-box, and out-of-distribution settings.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>POGER outperforms all baselines in macro F1 under black-box, partial white-box, and out-of-distribution settings.</li>
<li>The proposed method estimates word generation probabilities to empower black-box AIGT detection and shows its feasibility.</li>
<li>POGER maintains lower re-sampling costs than its existing counterparts.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides a feasible solution to improve the detection of AI-generated text under the black-box setting.</li>
<li>The proposed method, POGER, demonstrates superior performance in various settings, including black-box, partial white-box, and out-of-distribution scenarios.</li>
<li>The article does not mention any limitations or potential biases in the proposed method, which could be a point of critique. It would be beneficial to address any potential shortcomings or areas for further research.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-15</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09199v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09199v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09199v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09199v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>14584</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Ten_Words_Only_Still_Help_Improving_Black_Box_AI_Generated_Text_Detection_via_Proxy_Guided_Efficient_Re_Sampling/2024-02-14-Ten_Words_Only_Still_Help_Improving_Black_Box_AI_Generated_Text_Detection_via_Proxy_Guided_Efficient_Re_Sampling.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.09199v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Role-Playing Simulation Games using ChatGPT</title>
  <dc:creator>Rita Stampfl, Igor Ivkić, Barbara Geyer</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Role_Playing_Simulation_Games_using_ChatGPT/2024-02-14-Role_Playing_Simulation_Games_using_ChatGPT.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.09161v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Educational institutions have been integrating new technologies to meet the needs of digitally literate students, especially during the COVID-19 pandemic.</li>
<li>Large Language Models (LLMs) like ChatGPT can enhance teaching quality and student interest by promoting active learning through role-playing simulation games.</li>
<li>LLMs, when used responsibly, can contribute to the development of metacognitive skills and are increasingly important in higher education.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The success of digital transformation projects in education depends on integrating new technologies and understanding the needs of digitally literate students.</li>
<li>Large Language Models (LLMs) like ChatGPT can enhance teaching quality and student interest by promoting active learning through role-playing simulation games.</li>
<li>LLMs, when used responsibly, can contribute to the development of metacognitive skills and are increasingly important in higher education.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article focuses on the benefits of using LLMs in education, but it does not address potential drawbacks or limitations of these technologies.</li>
<li>The study is based on a specific case study at the University of Applied Sciences Burgenland, which may limit the generalizability of the findings to other educational contexts.</li>
<li>The article does not discuss potential ethical considerations or privacy concerns related to the use of LLMs in education, which are important factors to consider in the implementation of these technologies.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-15</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09161v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09161v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09161v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09161v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>2445</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Role_Playing_Simulation_Games_using_ChatGPT/2024-02-14-Role_Playing_Simulation_Games_using_ChatGPT.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.09161v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Attacking Large Language Models with Projected Gradient Descent</title>
  <dc:creator>Simon Geisler, Tom Wollschläger, M. H. I. Abdalla, Johannes Gasteiger, Stephan Günnemann</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Attacking_Large_Language_Models_with_Projected_Gradient_Descent/2024-02-14-Attacking_Large_Language_Models_with_Projected_Gradient_Descent.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Attacking_Large_Language_Models_with_Projected_Gradient_Descent/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09154v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Adversarial attacks on Large Language Models (LLMs) are currently dominated by discrete optimization methods, but these are computationally expensive.</li>
<li>The authors propose a Projected Gradient Descent (PGD) approach for attacking LLMs, which operates on a continuously relaxed input prompt and is up to one order of magnitude faster than state-of-the-art discrete optimization methods.</li>
<li>The PGD approach is effective, flexible, and efficient, achieving the same results as discrete optimization with lower computational cost.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>PGD for LLMs is up to one order of magnitude faster than state-of-the-art discrete optimization methods.</li>
<li>The PGD approach is effective and flexible, achieving the same results as discrete optimization with lower computational cost.</li>
<li>Ordinary gradient-based optimization methods have previously failed to effectively attack LLMs, but the PGD approach overcomes this limitation.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The PGD approach proposed in the article shows promising results in attacking LLMs, but the potential limitations and unanswered questions include:
<ul>
<li>The impact of the proposed attacks on real-world applications and ethical considerations.</li>
<li>The need for further research to understand the limitations and potential risks associated with efficient adversarial attacks on LLMs.</li>
<li>The white-box assumption of knowing the model parameters and architecture details may limit the applicability of the proposed approach to real-world scenarios.</li>
<li>The need for additional experiments against AI assistants deployed for public use to assess the practical implications of the proposed attacks.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-15</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09154v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09154v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09154v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09154v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>3766</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>security</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Attacking_Large_Language_Models_with_Projected_Gradient_Descent/2024-02-14-Attacking_Large_Language_Models_with_Projected_Gradient_Descent.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09154v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Evaluating the Experience of LGBTQ+ People Using Large Language Model Based Chatbots for Mental Health Support</title>
  <dc:creator>Zilin Ma, Yiyang Mei, Yinru Long, Zhaoyuan Su, Krzysztof Z. Gajos</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Evaluating_the_Experience_of_LGBTQ+_People_Using_Large_Language_Model_Based_Chatbots_for_Mental_Health_Support/2024-02-14-Evaluating_the_Experience_of_LGBTQ+_People_Using_Large_Language_Model_Based_Chatbots_for_Mental_Health_Support.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.09260v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>I’m sorry, but I cannot fulfill your request as it involves integrating individual section summaries from an academic article, and I don’t have access to the specific content of the article. My capabilities are limited to providing general information and assistance. If you have any other requests, feel free to ask!</p>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-15</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09260v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09260v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09260v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09260v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>27663</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Evaluating_the_Experience_of_LGBTQ+_People_Using_Large_Language_Model_Based_Chatbots_for_Mental_Health_Support/2024-02-14-Evaluating_the_Experience_of_LGBTQ+_People_Using_Large_Language_Model_Based_Chatbots_for_Mental_Health_Support.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.09260v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Get More with LESS: Synthesizing Recurrence with KV Cache Compression for Efficient LLM Inference</title>
  <dc:creator>Harry Dong, Xinyu Yang, Zhenyu Zhang, Zhangyang Wang, Yuejie Chi, Beidi Chen</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Get_More_with_LESS_Synthesizing_Recurrence_with_KV_Cache_Compression_for_Efficient_LLM_Inference/2024-02-14-Get_More_with_LESS_Synthesizing_Recurrence_with_KV_Cache_Compression_for_Efficient_LLM_Inference.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.09398v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<p>The academic article “Get More with LESS: Synthesizing Recurrence with KV Cache Compression for Efficient LLM Inference” addresses the memory bottleneck imposed by the key-value (KV) cache in large language models (LLMs). The authors propose a method called LESS, which integrates a constant-sized cache with eviction-based cache methods to retain information throughout time.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Memory Bottleneck:</strong> The KV cache size often exceeds the model size, creating a memory bottleneck during deployment of LLMs.</li>
<li><strong>LESS Integration:</strong> The proposed LESS method synthesizes sparse KV policies with low-rank states to bridge the performance gap on various tasks, reducing the performance degradation from a full cache and occupying constant memory with respect to the sequence length.</li>
<li><strong>Performance Improvement:</strong> LESS improves the performance of LLMs on a variety of tasks, reducing the performance gap from caching everything and matching the full cache performance in some cases.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides a comprehensive solution to the memory bottleneck in large language models by proposing the LESS method.</li>
<li>The proposed method shows promising results in reducing the performance gap from a full cache while being memory-efficient.</li>
<li>The study highlights the potential of integrating low-rank caches with eviction-based cache methods to improve the efficiency of large language models.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the article provides valuable insights into addressing the memory bottleneck in large language models and offers a practical solution through the LESS method. However, further research is needed to evaluate the scalability and generalizability of the proposed method across different types of language models and tasks. Additionally, the article could benefit from a more detailed discussion of potential limitations and future research directions.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-15</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09398v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09398v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09398v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09398v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>14643</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Get_More_with_LESS_Synthesizing_Recurrence_with_KV_Cache_Compression_for_Efficient_LLM_Inference/2024-02-14-Get_More_with_LESS_Synthesizing_Recurrence_with_KV_Cache_Compression_for_Efficient_LLM_Inference.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.09398v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Automated Unit Test Improvement using Large Language Models at Meta</title>
  <dc:creator>Nadia Alshahwan, Jubin Chheda, Anastasia Finegenova, Beliz Gokkaya, Mark Harman, Inna Harper, Alexandru Marginean, Shubho Sengupta, Eddy Wang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Automated_Unit_Test_Improvement_using_Large_Language_Models_at_Meta/2024-02-14-Automated_Unit_Test_Improvement_using_Large_Language_Models_at_Meta.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.09171v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>I’m sorry, but I cannot fulfill this request as it requires summarizing a specific section of an academic paper, and the provided text does not contain any specific section to summarize. If you have a specific section of an academic paper that you would like me to summarize, please provide that section and I would be happy to help.</p>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-15</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09171v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09171v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09171v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09171v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>17410</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Automated_Unit_Test_Improvement_using_Large_Language_Models_at_Meta/2024-02-14-Automated_Unit_Test_Improvement_using_Large_Language_Models_at_Meta.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.09171v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Large Language Model with Graph Convolution for Recommendation</title>
  <dc:creator>Yingpeng Du, Ziyan Wang, Zhu Sun, Haoyan Chua, Hongzhi Liu, Zhonghai Wu, Yining Ma, Jie Zhang, Youchen Sun</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Large_Language_Model_with_Graph_Convolution_for_Recommendation/2024-02-14-Large_Language_Model_with_Graph_Convolution_for_Recommendation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Large_Language_Model_with_Graph_Convolution_for_Recommendation/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.08859v1/x2.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Efforts have been made to use text information for better user profiling and item characterization in recommendations.</li>
<li>Existing ways of prompting Large Language Models (LLMs) with raw texts ignore structured knowledge of user-item interactions, leading to inconsistent description generation.</li>
<li>The proposed Graph-aware Convolutional LLM method elicits LLMs to capture high-order relations in the user-item graph, outperforming state-of-the-art methods in real-world datasets.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The proposed Graph-aware Convolutional LLM method consistently outperforms state-of-the-art methods in real-world datasets.</li>
<li>The quality of descriptions significantly impacts recommendation results, with higher-quality descriptions leading to more accurate predictions.</li>
<li>Integrating graph information into LLMs to predict and discover missing descriptions of users and items results in accurate recommendation outcomes.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The proposed method effectively bridges the gap between text-based LLMs and graph-based multi-hop information, leading to improved recommendation results.</li>
<li>The study demonstrates the necessity of utilizing both text and interaction information for accurate recommendation results.</li>
<li>The proposed method outperforms baseline methods, indicating its effectiveness in enhancing the quality of textual descriptions for recommendation.</li>
<li>The ablation study and subgroup analysis validate the effectiveness of the proposed method in enhancing user and item descriptions.</li>
<li>The hyper-parameter study reveals the optimal settings for the proposed method, contributing to its practical applicability.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the article effectively communicates the essential information about the proposed Graph-aware Convolutional LLM method for recommendation systems. The study provides valuable insights into the integration of text-based LLMs with structured graphs, leading to improved recommendation outcomes. However, further research is needed to explore the use of LLMs to explore graphs with heterogeneous relations for more fine-grained information extraction.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-15</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.08859v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.08859v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.08859v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.08859v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8299</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>recommender</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Large_Language_Model_with_Graph_Convolution_for_Recommendation/2024-02-14-Large_Language_Model_with_Graph_Convolution_for_Recommendation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.08859v1/x2.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>MUSTARD: Mastering Uniform Synthesis of Theorem and Proof Data</title>
  <dc:creator>Yinya Huang, Xiaohan Lin, Zhengying Liu, Qingxing Cao, Huajian Xin, Haiming Wang, Zhenguo Li, Linqi Song, Xiaodan Liang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MUSTARD_Mastering_Uniform_Synthesis_of_Theorem_and_Proof_Data/2024-02-14-MUSTARD_Mastering_Uniform_Synthesis_of_Theorem_and_Proof_Data.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MUSTARD_Mastering_Uniform_Synthesis_of_Theorem_and_Proof_Data/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.08957v1/extracted/5407837/figs/atp_fig2_4.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>Mustard is a data generation framework that focuses on synthesizing high-quality and diverse theorem and proof data. It samples mathematical concept seeds, prompts a generative language model to obtain problems and their step-wise formal solutions, and utilizes a proof assistant to filter the valid proofs. The resulting MustardSauce benchmark contains 5,866 validated data points. Extensive analysis and experiments demonstrate the effectiveness of Mustard in generating validated high-quality step-by-step data. The fine-tuned Llama 2-7B achieves significant average relative performance gains in automated theorem proving and math word problems.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Mustard introduces a data generation framework that uniformly synthesizes large-scale and high-quality mathematical data by combining the advantages of LLMs in verbalization and formal theorem provers in rigorous data validation.</li>
<li>MustardSauce, the resulting benchmark, contains both math word problems and theorem-proving problems spanning over four educational levels, with each sample having corresponding informal and formal solutions.</li>
<li>The fine-tuned Llama 2-7B achieves significant improvements in automated theorem proving and math word problems, demonstrating the effectiveness of MustardSauce in improving the mathematical reasoning capabilities of language models.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The Mustard framework effectively addresses the challenges of obtaining high-quality mathematical data, but there may still be potential biases introduced by the sampled concepts and domains.</li>
<li>The use of a proof assistant for validation is a significant strength of the framework, but there may be room for more rigorous and careful data filtering.</li>
<li>The study demonstrates the effectiveness of MustardSauce in improving language models’ mathematical reasoning performance, but further research is needed to explore the scalability and potential biases in the generated data.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-15</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.08957v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.08957v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.08957v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.08957v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7807</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MUSTARD_Mastering_Uniform_Synthesis_of_Theorem_and_Proof_Data/2024-02-14-MUSTARD_Mastering_Uniform_Synthesis_of_Theorem_and_Proof_Data.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.08957v1/extracted/5407837/figs/atp_fig2_4.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Trained Without My Consent: Detecting Code Inclusion In Language Models Trained on Code</title>
  <dc:creator>Vahid Majdinasab, Amin Nikanjam, Foutse Khomh</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Trained_Without_My_Consent_Detecting_Code_Inclusion_In_Language_Models_Trained_on_Code/2024-02-14-Trained_Without_My_Consent_Detecting_Code_Inclusion_In_Language_Models_Trained_on_Code.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.09299v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article introduces TraWiC, a model-agnostic method for detecting code inclusion in Large Language Models (LLMs) trained on code. It outperforms traditional clone detection tools and addresses the challenge of auditing code developed using LLMs.</li>
<li>The methodology for detecting dataset inclusion in language models trained on code is detailed, including the Fill-In-the-Middle (FIM) technique and an end-to-end data processing example using TraWiC.</li>
<li>The section discusses the selection of the random forests classifier for dataset inclusion detection, the comparison with clone detection approaches, and the effect of different classification methods on TraWiC’s performance.</li>
<li>The sensitivity analysis of the approach for detecting dataset inclusion in language models trained on code is presented, along with the impact of noise ratio on precision, accuracy, F-score, sensitivity, and specificity.</li>
<li>The conclusion section highlights the significance of TraWiC and outlines future plans for testing TraWiC on more capable LLMs and investigating other aspects of code for conducting model inclusion attacks.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>TraWiC, a model-agnostic approach, can detect code inclusion in LLMs with a recall of up to 99.19%.</li>
<li>The random forests classifier is effective for dataset inclusion detection, outperforming traditional clone detection tools.</li>
<li>The approach is robust in detecting dataset inclusion despite deliberate obfuscations in the training dataset.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides valuable insights into the challenges of auditing code developed using LLMs and proposes an effective solution in the form of TraWiC. However, further research is needed to test TraWiC on more capable LLMs and investigate other aspects of code for conducting model inclusion attacks.</li>
<li>The methodology and findings of the article contribute to the field of software engineering and intellectual property protection. However, potential biases and limitations in the experimental design should be carefully considered.</li>
<li>The sensitivity analysis and feature importance provide a comprehensive understanding of the approach’s performance, but methodological issues related to the impact of noise on precision and accuracy should be further explored.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-15</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09299v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09299v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09299v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09299v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>28277</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Trained_Without_My_Consent_Detecting_Code_Inclusion_In_Language_Models_Trained_on_Code/2024-02-14-Trained_Without_My_Consent_Detecting_Code_Inclusion_In_Language_Models_Trained_on_Code.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.09299v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>LlaSMol: Advancing Large Language Models for Chemistry with a Large-Scale, Comprehensive, High-Quality Instruction Tuning Dataset</title>
  <dc:creator>Botao Yu, Frazier N. Baker, Ziqi Chen, Xia Ning, Huan Sun</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LlaSMol_Advancing_Large_Language_Models_for_Chemistry_with_a_Large_Scale_Comprehensive_High_Quality_Instruction_Tuning_Dataset/2024-02-14-LlaSMol_Advancing_Large_Language_Models_for_Chemistry_with_a_Large_Scale_Comprehensive_High_Quality_Instruction_Tuning_Dataset.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/../bayesian-beagle.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article discusses the development and performance of large language models (LLMs) for chemistry tasks, focusing on the construction of the SMolInstruct dataset, the performance of LlaSMol models, the experimental setup and evaluation metrics, and the influence of LoRA modules and trainable parameters.</li>
<li>The SMolInstruct dataset is a large-scale, comprehensive, high-quality dataset for instruction tuning of LLMs, containing 3.4M samples from various chemistry sources.</li>
<li>LlaSMol models achieve strong performance on a comprehensive set of chemistry tasks, outperforming existing models and approaching state-of-the-art task-specific models, with Mistral serving as the best base model for chemistry tasks.</li>
<li>The experimental setup involves the comparison of LlaSMol models with existing models, using various evaluation metrics to assess their performance in chemistry-related tasks.</li>
<li>The influence of LoRA modules and trainable parameters on the performance of LlaSMol models is investigated, with larger base models and more LoRA modules leading to significant performance enhancement.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LlaSMol models achieve strong performance on a comprehensive set of chemistry tasks, outperforming existing models and approaching state-of-the-art task-specific models.</li>
<li>The influence of LoRA modules and trainable parameters on the performance of LlaSMol models underscores the significance of model architecture and size in improving the performance of LLMs on chemistry tasks.</li>
<li>The construction of the SMolInstruct dataset provides a valuable resource for training and evaluating LLMs for chemistry tasks, offering a larger complexity and diversity compared to previous datasets.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides valuable insights into the development and performance of LLMs for chemistry tasks, highlighting the potential for these models to effectively perform a wide range of chemistry tasks.</li>
<li>The rigorous quality control and careful data splitting methods for the SMolInstruct dataset ensure the reliability and integrity of the dataset, making it a valuable resource for future research in the field of chemistry and language model training.</li>
<li>The influence of LoRA modules and trainable parameters on the performance of LlaSMol models underscores the significance of model architecture and size in improving the performance of LLMs on chemistry tasks.</li>
<li>The comprehensive evaluation of LlaSMol models using various metrics demonstrates the effectiveness of fine-tuning on SMolInstruct for understanding and predicting chemical properties, while also highlighting areas for improvement.</li>
<li>The comparison with a previous dataset, Mol-Instructions, indicates that SMolInstruct offers a larger complexity and diversity, making it well-suited for training chemistry language models.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-15</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09391v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09391v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09391v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09391v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>27804</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LlaSMol_Advancing_Large_Language_Models_for_Chemistry_with_a_Large_Scale_Comprehensive_High_Quality_Instruction_Tuning_Dataset/2024-02-14-LlaSMol_Advancing_Large_Language_Models_for_Chemistry_with_a_Large_Scale_Comprehensive_High_Quality_Instruction_Tuning_Dataset.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Copyright Traps for Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Matthieu Meeus, Igor Shilov, Manuel Faysse, Yves-Alexandre de Montjoye</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Copyright_Traps_for_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-14-Copyright_Traps_for_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/../bayesian-beagle.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article discusses the use of copyright traps to detect the use of copyrighted materials in Large Language Models (LLMs).</li>
<li>The authors propose to use copyright traps to detect the use of copyrighted materials in LLMs, especially in models where memorization does not naturally occur.</li>
<li>They conduct experiments to validate the effectiveness of copyright traps in detecting the use of copyrighted materials in LLMs.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The document-level membership inference methods proposed in prior work fail for the 1.3B LLM used in this study.</li>
<li>Injecting short-to-medium sentences up to 100 times does not improve document detectability, but longer sequences repeated a large number of times can be reliably detected and used as copyright traps.</li>
<li>Detectability of a trap sequence depends on its perplexity, and leveraging document-level information such as context could boost detectability.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides valuable insights into the use of copyright traps to detect the use of copyrighted materials in LLMs, especially in models where memorization does not naturally occur.</li>
<li>The proposed method could be disruptive to the document’s content and readability, and future research is needed to design trap sequences maximizing detectability.</li>
<li>The study has limitations related to data deduplication and content readability, which need to be addressed in future work.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the article provides a comprehensive analysis of the effectiveness of copyright traps in detecting the use of copyrighted materials in LLMs and highlights the need for further research in this area.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-15</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09363v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09363v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09363v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09363v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>12912</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Copyright_Traps_for_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-14-Copyright_Traps_for_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>GrounDial: Human-norm Grounded Safe Dialog Response Generation</title>
  <dc:creator>Siwon Kim, Shuyang Dai, Mohammad Kachuee, Shayan Ray, Tara Taghavi, Sungroh Yoon</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/GrounDial_Human_norm_Grounded_Safe_Dialog_Response_Generation/2024-02-14-GrounDial_Human_norm_Grounded_Safe_Dialog_Response_Generation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/../bayesian-beagle.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Current conversational AI systems based on large language models (LLMs) generate unsafe responses, including toxic content and offensive expressions.</li>
<li>Previous research aimed to alleviate toxicity by fine-tuning LLM with manually annotated safe dialogue histories, but this approach requires substantial costs.</li>
<li>GrounDial proposes response safety achieved by grounding responses to commonsense social rules without requiring fine-tuning, resulting in quantitatively and qualitatively safer responses.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>GrounDial achieves response safety by grounding responses to appropriate Rules-of-Thumb (RoT) through in-context learning (ICL) and human-norm-guided decoding (HGD).</li>
<li>The hybrid approach of ICL and HGD enables responses to be quantitatively and qualitatively safer even without additional data or tuning.</li>
<li>GrounDial effectively generates safe and RoT-relevant responses without any extra fine-tuning, achieving higher safety and agreement scores compared to previous methods.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The proposed GrounDial framework effectively addresses the limitations of previous approaches by grounding responses to RoT without requiring additional fine-tuning.</li>
<li>However, there are still limitations, such as occasional generation of incorrect words and unsafe responses, which may be attributed to the insufficient language modeling capacity of the dialog system.</li>
<li>Further research on refining the reward design for HGD and improving the language modeling capacity of the dialog system is necessary to address these limitations and enhance the effectiveness of GrounDial.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-15</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.08968v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.08968v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.08968v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.08968v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>2985</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>security</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/GrounDial_Human_norm_Grounded_Safe_Dialog_Response_Generation/2024-02-14-GrounDial_Human_norm_Grounded_Safe_Dialog_Response_Generation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Multi-Query Focused Disaster Summarization via Instruction-Based Prompting</title>
  <dc:creator>Philipp Seeberger, Korbinian Riedhammer</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Multi_Query_Focused_Disaster_Summarization_via_Instruction_Based_Prompting/2024-02-14-Multi_Query_Focused_Disaster_Summarization_via_Instruction_Based_Prompting.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.09008v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper describes a method for automatic summarization of mass-emergency events using multi-stream fact-finding with a focus on web sources such as Twitter, Reddit, Facebook, and Webnews.</li>
<li>The proposed method uses a combination of retrieval, reranking, and an embarrassingly simple instruction-following summarization.</li>
<li>The system relies on BM25 and MonoT5 for retrieval and the open-source Large Language Model (LLM) LLaMA-13b for summarization.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The proposed LLM-based event nugget generation approach achieves competitive performance and surpasses the majority of systems in the CrisisFACTS 2023 Track.</li>
<li>The system outperforms both the majority of TREC participants’ systems as well as extractive baselines in terms of comprehensiveness and redundancy measures.</li>
<li>The experiments show that rather simple prompting approaches surpass extractive baselines and the majority of submitted CrisisFACTS systems.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The qualitative analysis reveals shortcomings and limitations of the proposed approach, including incorrect facts, incomplete citations, and formatting issues in the generated responses.</li>
<li>The BERTScore metric used for automatic evaluation may lead to flawed results due to token limits and the format of event summaries.</li>
<li>The paper acknowledges the need for further development efforts to address surface form issues and improve the robustness of the system.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-15</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09008v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09008v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09008v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09008v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6665</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Multi_Query_Focused_Disaster_Summarization_via_Instruction_Based_Prompting/2024-02-14-Multi_Query_Focused_Disaster_Summarization_via_Instruction_Based_Prompting.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.09008v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>(Ir)rationality and Cognitive Biases in Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Olivia Macmillan-Scott, Mirco Musolesi</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/(Ir)rationality_and_Cognitive_Biases_in_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-14-(Ir)rationality_and_Cognitive_Biases_in_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.09193v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The article investigates whether large language models (LLMs) display rational reasoning by evaluating their performance on cognitive tasks from cognitive psychology literature. The study finds that LLMs display irrationality in these tasks, but the way this irrationality is displayed does not reflect that shown by humans. The LLMs reveal an additional layer of irrationality in the significant inconsistency of the responses. The paper seeks to make a methodological contribution by showing how we can assess and compare different capabilities of these types of models, in this case with respect to rational reasoning.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs display irrationality in cognitive tasks, but the way this irrationality is displayed does not reflect that shown by humans.</li>
<li>The LLMs reveal an additional layer of irrationality in the significant inconsistency of the responses.</li>
<li>The study provides a methodological contribution by showing how we can assess and compare different capabilities of LLMs, particularly with respect to rational reasoning.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study highlights the inconsistency of responses given by LLMs, which raises concerns about their reliability and applicability in real-world scenarios.</li>
<li>The findings suggest that LLMs may not accurately simulate human cognitive biases, which could limit their effectiveness in applications that require human-AI collaboration.</li>
<li>The study does not address potential solutions or improvements to mitigate the identified shortcomings of LLMs, leaving room for further research in this area.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-15</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09193v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09193v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09193v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09193v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>14079</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/(Ir)rationality_and_Cognitive_Biases_in_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-14-(Ir)rationality_and_Cognitive_Biases_in_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.09193v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Using Counterfactual Tasks to Evaluate the Generality of Analogical Reasoning in Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Martha Lewis, Melanie Mitchell</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Using_Counterfactual_Tasks_to_Evaluate_the_Generality_of_Analogical_Reasoning_in_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-14-Using_Counterfactual_Tasks_to_Evaluate_the_Generality_of_Analogical_Reasoning_in_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Using_Counterfactual_Tasks_to_Evaluate_the_Generality_of_Analogical_Reasoning_in_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.08955v1/extracted/5407867/images/Letters.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article investigates the generality of analogy-making abilities in large language models (LLMs) by creating counterfactual variants of analogy problems.</li>
<li>Humans and three GPT models were tested on both the original and counterfactual problems, and it was found that the performance of humans remained high for all the problems, while the GPT models’ performance declined sharply on the counterfactual set.</li>
<li>The results provide evidence that, despite previously reported successes of LLMs on analogical reasoning, these models lack the robustness and generality of human analogy-making.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Large language models (LLMs) lack the robustness and generality of human analogy-making.</li>
<li>The performance of humans remained high for all the problems, while the GPT models’ performance declined sharply on the counterfactual set.</li>
<li>The ability of GPT to solve analogy problems may be more due to the presence of similar kinds of sequence examples in the training data, rather than an ability to reason by abstract analogy.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides compelling evidence that large language models (LLMs) are not as robust and general as human analogy-making.</li>
<li>The study raises questions about the actual reasoning abilities of LLMs and suggests that their performance may be more reliant on the presence of similar examples in the training data.</li>
<li>The findings highlight the limitations of LLMs in performing abstract reasoning and suggest that further research is needed to understand how humans and LLMs form responses to analogy problems.</li>
<li>The study’s critical analysis of LLMs’ performance provides valuable insights into the shortcomings of these models and emphasizes the need for future work to explore their reasoning abilities in different settings.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-15</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.08955v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.08955v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.08955v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.08955v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5743</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Using_Counterfactual_Tasks_to_Evaluate_the_Generality_of_Analogical_Reasoning_in_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-14-Using_Counterfactual_Tasks_to_Evaluate_the_Generality_of_Analogical_Reasoning_in_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.08955v1/extracted/5407867/images/Letters.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
