<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Bayesian beagle</title>
<link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Quarto blog of LLM-generated summaries of Arxiv preprints</description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.450</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>AUTOACT: Automatic Agent Learning from Scratch via Self-Planning</title>
  <dc:creator>Shuofei Qiao, Ningyu Zhang, Runnan Fang, Yujie Luo, Wangchunshu Zhou, Yuchen Eleanor Jiang, Chengfei Lv, Huajun Chen</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/AUTOACT_Automatic_Agent_Learning_from_Scratch_via_Self_Planning/2024-01-10-AUTOACT_Automatic_Agent_Learning_from_Scratch_via_Self_Planning.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/AUTOACT_Automatic_Agent_Learning_from_Scratch_via_Self_Planning/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05268v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-autoact-automatic-agent-learning-from-scratch-via-self-planning" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-of-autoact-automatic-agent-learning-from-scratch-via-self-planning">Summary of “AutoAct: Automatic Agent Learning from Scratch via Self-Planning”</h2>
<section id="key-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="key-findings">Key Findings</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>AutoAct</strong> is an automatic agent learning framework that does not rely on large-scale annotated data and synthetic trajectories from closed-source models. It leverages a <em>division-of-labor strategy</em> to differentiate the Meta-Agent based on target task information and synthesized trajectories, producing a sub-agent group to complete the task.</li>
<li>Experimentation with various large language models (LLMs) demonstrates that AutoAct yields better or parallel performance compared to various strong baselines, including achieving performance comparable to GPT-3.5-Turbo agent using the Llama-2-13b model.</li>
<li>The study suggests that a <em>proper division-of-labor strategy</em> and the quality of trajectories generated by AutoAct significantly outperforms that of other methods from multiple aspects.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="autoact-framework-summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="autoact-framework-summary">AutoAct Framework (Summary)</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Overview</strong>: AutoAct framework initiates with self-instruct to extend the task database from scratch and self-planning is applied to conduct automatic agent learning, including automatic tool selection, trajectories synthesis, self-differentiation and group planning.</li>
<li><strong>Critical Components of AutoAct</strong>: It includes the Meta-Agent, target task information, and a tool library.</li>
<li><strong>Starting from Scratch via Self-Instruct</strong>: Self-instruct is used to augment the task data based on the examples at hand.</li>
<li><strong>Automatic Agent Learning via Self-Planning</strong>: It includes automatic tool selection, trajectories synthesis, self-differentiation, and group planning.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="experimental-setup" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="experimental-setup">Experimental Setup</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Tasks</strong>: Evaluation was conducted on HotpotQA and ScienceQA question-answering tasks.</li>
<li><strong>Baselines</strong>: Open-source Llama-2 models were chosen as the backbones. Comparison was made with CoT, ReAct, Reflexion, Chameleon, FireAct, BOLAA, and GPT-3.5-Turbo.</li>
<li><strong>Training Setups</strong>: Models were fine-tuned with LoRA and FastChat using DeepSpeed. Different learning rates, sequence lengths, and optimizer types were used for different model scales.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<p>The paper’s strength lies in proposing a novel automatic agent learning framework. However, the paper lacks a thorough comparison with existing related works, and the evaluation is limited to question-answering tasks only. Additionally, the results heavily focus on performance, without much insight into the interpretability or robustness of the AutoAct framework, leaving potential areas for further investigation.</p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-11</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05268v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05268v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05268v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05268v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>9023</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/AUTOACT_Automatic_Agent_Learning_from_Scratch_via_Self_Planning/2024-01-10-AUTOACT_Automatic_Agent_Learning_from_Scratch_via_Self_Planning.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05268v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Divide and Conquer for Large Language Models Reasoning</title>
  <dc:creator>Zijie Meng, Yan Zhang, Zhaopeng Feng, Yang Feng, Gaoang Wang, Joey Tianyi Zhou, Jian Wu, Zuozhu Liu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Divide_and_Conquer_for_Large_Language_Models_Reasoning/2024-01-10-Divide_and_Conquer_for_Large_Language_Models_Reasoning.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Divide_and_Conquer_for_Large_Language_Models_Reasoning/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05190v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary</h3>
<section id="introduction" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h4>
<p>Large language models (LLMs) such as GPT-3 and CoT methods have demonstrated impressive performance in reasoning benchmarks, particularly in multi-choice questions (MCQs). However, existing methods process data uniformly without considering problem-solving difficulty. The authors propose applying <strong>Divide and Conquer</strong> to LLM reasoning to address this issue. They divide questions into subsets based on <strong>statistical confidence scores</strong>, then fix resolved sets and develop methods for nuanced problems.</p>
</section>
<section id="methodology" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="methodology">Methodology</h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Zero-Shot-CoT</strong>: Extends problem-solving representation from triplet to quadruple for multi-step reasoning.</li>
<li><strong>Self-consistency</strong>: Samples multiple reasoning paths and uses majority voting to select the most consistent answer.</li>
<li><strong>Divide</strong>: Divides the dataset into high, medium, and low confidence subsets based on the statistical confidence score.</li>
<li><strong>Conquer</strong>: Prior Knowledge based Reasoning (PKR) and Filter Choices based Reasoning (FCR) used for nuanced problems.</li>
<li><strong>Combination (COM1 and COM2)</strong>: Integration variants using different merging strategies.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="experiments" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="experiments">Experiments</h4>
<p>The study evaluates the strategy across nine datasets, achieving significant improvements in reasoning abilities. Empirical analysis demonstrates a positive correlation of the confidence score with accuracy, longer rationales offering more helpful knowledge, and irrelevant choices distracting the model.</p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Divide and Conquer</strong> significantly improves reasoning abilities across various datasets.</li>
<li>Higher <strong>statistical confidence scores</strong> are positively correlated with accuracy.</li>
<li>Longer rationales and removing irrelevant choices improves the model’s reasoning reliability and effectiveness.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<p>The paper provides valuable insights into improving reasoning abilities in large language models. However, the study primarily focuses on MCQs, and the method’s generalization to other types of questions or tasks remains unexplored. Additionally, the proposed strategies may not be applicable to all LLMs, and further evaluation across a broader range of models is needed. Finally, the paper could benefit from a more detailed discussion of potential limitations and challenges in practical implementation.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-11</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05190v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05190v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05190v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05190v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>11517</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Divide_and_Conquer_for_Large_Language_Models_Reasoning/2024-01-10-Divide_and_Conquer_for_Large_Language_Models_Reasoning.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05190v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Knowledge Sharing in Manufacturing using Large Language Models: User Evaluation and Model Benchmarking</title>
  <dc:creator>Samuel Kernan Freire, Chaofan Wang, Mina Foosherian, Stefan Wellsandt, Santiago Ruiz-Arenas, Evangelos Niforatos</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Knowledge_Sharing_in_Manufacturing_using_Large_Language_Models_User_Evaluation_and_Model_Benchmarking/2024-01-10-Knowledge_Sharing_in_Manufacturing_using_Large_Language_Models_User_Evaluation_and_Model_Benchmarking.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Knowledge_Sharing_in_Manufacturing_using_Large_Language_Models_User_Evaluation_and_Model_Benchmarking/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><p><strong>Large Language Models (LLMs)</strong>, particularly GPT-4, demonstrated superior performance in knowledge-intensive tasks such as information retrieval and decision-making support in a manufacturing setting, suggesting their potential for use in knowledge management in factories.</p></li>
<li><p>The study found that while LLM-based systems offer benefits such as quicker information retrieval and efficient issue resolution, users still expressed a preference for learning from a <strong>human expert</strong> when available.</p></li>
<li><p>Benchmarking multiple LLMs indicated that open-source models like <strong>StableBeluga2</strong>, which guarantee better data security, privacy, and customization, perform closely behind proprietary models like GPT-4, making them attractive options for manufacturing knowledge management.</p></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="system-summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="system-summary">System Summary</h3>
<ul>
<li><p><strong>Introduction</strong>: The paper introduces an LLM-based system designed to assist factory operators in knowledge retrieval and sharing, with a focus on using technology to support knowledge-intensive tasks in Industry 5.0.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Large-Language Model-Powered Tools for Knowledge-Intensive Scenarios</strong>: The section explores the advantages and challenges of using LLMs in manufacturing settings, highlighting examples of LLM-powered tools in similar environments.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Evaluating Large-Language Models</strong>: The section discusses the types of LLM evaluation, criteria, and datasets, with a focus on extrinsic evaluation for real-world tasks.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>System</strong>: Details the fully functional LLM-powered system built for knowledge retrieval and sharing in manufacturing, including its dependencies, knowledge base construction, and query construction.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Model Benchmarking</strong>: Describes the benchmarking experiment conducted to evaluate various LLMs, comparing commercial and open-source options and assessing their performance in answering questions based on factory documentation.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>User Study at the Factory</strong>: Presents the findings of a user study conducted with factory managers, highlighting their perceptions of the system’s usability, content, features, risks and benefits, and employee acceptance and training.</p></li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<p>The paper offers valuable insights into the potential use of LLMs for knowledge management in manufacturing but has several potential limitations:</p>
<ul>
<li><p>The user study involved a limited participant pool of factory managers, potentially overlooking perspectives of other stakeholders such as factory operators.</p></li>
<li><p>Benchmarking only 20 questions and assessing responses using a single coder may limit the generalizability and introduce potential bias in the findings.</p></li>
<li><p>The study design did not include comprehensive real-world evaluations or consider the varied challenges in natural working environments.</p></li>
</ul>
<p>Going forward, future research should address these limitations by involving a broader participant pool, more comprehensive benchmarking, and real-world evaluations to improve the generalizability and practical applicability of the findings. Furthermore, efforts to automate benchmarking and consider the evolving landscape of LLM technology should be prioritized.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-11</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05200v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05200v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05200v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05200v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7959</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Knowledge_Sharing_in_Manufacturing_using_Large_Language_Models_User_Evaluation_and_Model_Benchmarking/2024-01-10-Knowledge_Sharing_in_Manufacturing_using_Large_Language_Models_User_Evaluation_and_Model_Benchmarking.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Multi-User Chat Assistant (MUCA): a Framework Using LLMs to Facilitate Group Conversations</title>
  <dc:creator>Manqing Mao, Paishun Ting, Yijian Xiang, Mingyang Xu, Julia Chen, Jianzhe Lin</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Multi_User_Chat_Assistant_(MUCA)_a_Framework_Using_LLMs_to_Facilitate_Group_Conversations/2024-01-10-Multi_User_Chat_Assistant_(MUCA)_a_Framework_Using_LLMs_to_Facilitate_Group_Conversations.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Multi_User_Chat_Assistant_(MUCA)_a_Framework_Using_LLMs_to_Facilitate_Group_Conversations/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04883v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><p><strong>MUCA Framework Design</strong>: The paper proposes a Multi-User Chat Assistant (MUCA) framework designed to facilitate <strong>multi-user conversations</strong> by incorporating the 3W (What, When, Who) design dimensions. MUCA consists of three modules: Sub-topic Generator, Dialog Analyzer, and Utterance Strategies Arbitrator, collectively enhancing the multi-user chat experience.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>User Simulator (MUS)</strong>: The paper introduces an LLM-based Multi-User Simulator (MUS) to mimic <strong>real user behavior</strong>, facilitating quicker optimization of the MUCA framework.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Effectiveness Demonstration</strong>: Both <strong>case studies</strong> and <strong>user studies</strong> demonstrate that MUCA significantly improves goal-oriented communication tasks and garners strong preference over the baseline chatbot in enhancing chatting efficiency.</p></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="related-work" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="related-work">Related Work</h3>
<p>The paper reviews prior research on chatbots, integration of reinforcement learning techniques, and advancements in large language models (LLMs) for conversational models.</p>
</section>
<section id="muca-framework" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="muca-framework">MUCA Framework</h3>
<p>The paper outlines the design dimensions and challenges faced by multi-user chatbots, tied to the 3W design dimensions. It further describes the architecture of the MUCA framework, detailing the Sub-topic Generator, Dialog Analyzer, and Utterance Strategies Arbitrator modules.</p>
</section>
<section id="user-simulation" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="user-simulation">User Simulation</h3>
<p>The paper introduces the LLM-based Multi-User Simulator (MUS) framework, comprising two primary modules: User Behavior Resembling and User Utterance Generation, demonstrating how it mimics real user behavior.</p>
</section>
<section id="evaluation" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="evaluation">Evaluation</h3>
<p>The paper presents both case studies and user studies to examine the effectiveness of MUCA in facilitating group conversations, drawing focus on goal-oriented communication tasks.</p>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper heavily focuses on the technical aspects of the MUCA framework and its implementation, potentially overshadowing the discussion on broader implications or social impact.</li>
<li>The case studies and user studies could benefit from more quantitative metrics to complement the qualitative findings and provide a more robust evaluation of MUCA’s effectiveness.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-11</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04883v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04883v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04883v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04883v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>20453</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Multi_User_Chat_Assistant_(MUCA)_a_Framework_Using_LLMs_to_Facilitate_Group_Conversations/2024-01-10-Multi_User_Chat_Assistant_(MUCA)_a_Framework_Using_LLMs_to_Facilitate_Group_Conversations.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04883v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Are Language Models More Like Libraries or Like Librarians? Bibliotechnism, the Novel Reference Problem, and the Attitudes of LLMs</title>
  <dc:creator>Harvey Lederman, Kyle Mahowald</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Are_Language_Models_More_Like_Libraries_or_Like_Librarians_Bibliotechnism_the_Novel_Reference_Problem_and_the_Attitudes_of_LLMs/2024-01-10-Are_Language_Models_More_Like_Libraries_or_Like_Librarians_Bibliotechnism_the_Novel_Reference_Problem_and_the_Attitudes_of_LLMs.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Are_Language_Models_More_Like_Libraries_or_Like_Librarians_Bibliotechnism_the_Novel_Reference_Problem_and_the_Attitudes_of_LLMs/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="major-takeaways" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-takeaways">Major Takeaways</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><p><strong>Bibliotechnism</strong>: The paper explores the concept of bibliotechnism and its implications for LLMs. Bibliotechnism argues that LLMs are cultural technologies like libraries or photocopiers, which transmit information but cannot create new content. The paper defends this concept and addresses challenges related to LLMs generating entirely novel text.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Derivative Reference and Meaning</strong>: The paper argues that LLMs’ outputs are derivatively meaningful, meaning that their meaningfulness depends on the content of original human text. It presents a toy model using n-grams to demonstrate how LLMs can produce novel sentences that are nevertheless derivatively meaningful.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Novel Reference Problem</strong>: The paper introduces the Novel Reference Problem, which arises from examples where LLMs generate “novel reference,” using novel names to refer to novel entities. It proposes that LLMs might have a limited form of agency, as evidenced by their ability to generate novel reference.</p></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="sections-summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="sections-summary">Sections Summary</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Introduction</strong>
<ul>
<li>Raises the question of whether LLMs have beliefs, desires, and intentions, and explores the hypothesis that LLMs are cultural technologies akin to libraries or printing presses.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>From Cultural Technology to Derivative Reference and Meaning</strong>
<ul>
<li>Explores the concept of derivative reference and meaning, arguing that LLMs produce inscriptions that are only derivatively meaningful based on the content of original human text.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>LLMs do Produce Derivatively Meaningful Complex Expressions</strong>
<ul>
<li>Discusses how LLMs can produce novel text that is nevertheless derivatively meaningful, suggesting that modern LLMs are causally sensitive to the intelligibility of their PrimaryData.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>The Novel Reference Problem: LLMs Do Not Produce Only Derivatively Meaningful Expressions</strong>
<ul>
<li>Illustrates the problem of novel reference with examples where LLMs generate tokens of names they have never seen before, referring to previously referred-to objects without an association in the PrimaryData.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Responses to the Novel Reference Problem</strong>
<ul>
<li>Considers different responses to the Novel Reference Problem, including human feedback in RLHF, creators’ intentions, intentions in generating the prompt, and reader’s intentions.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Conclusion</strong>
<ul>
<li>Discusses the implications for LLMs having beliefs, desires, and intentions, and argues that the novel reference problem provides evidence that LLMs do have representational states and a limited form of agency.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<p>The paper provides a comprehensive exploration of the concept of bibliotechnism and its implications for LLMs. It presents a strong argument about derivative meaning and addresses the novel reference problem. However, the paper could benefit from more empirical evidence supporting its arguments, especially regarding the behavior and decision-making processes of LLMs. Additionally, it may need to consider the potential limitations and assumptions of its philosophical and theoretical framework.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-11</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04854v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04854v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04854v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04854v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>10471</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Are_Language_Models_More_Like_Libraries_or_Like_Librarians_Bibliotechnism_the_Novel_Reference_Problem_and_the_Attitudes_of_LLMs/2024-01-10-Are_Language_Models_More_Like_Libraries_or_Like_Librarians_Bibliotechnism_the_Novel_Reference_Problem_and_the_Attitudes_of_LLMs.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Aligning Translation-Specific Understanding to General Understanding in Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Yichong Huang, Xiaocheng Feng, Baohang Li, Chengpeng Fu, Wenshuai Huo, Ting Liu, Bing Qin</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Aligning_Translation_Specific_Understanding_to_General_Understanding_in_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-10-Aligning_Translation_Specific_Understanding_to_General_Understanding_in_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Aligning_Translation_Specific_Understanding_to_General_Understanding_in_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05072v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary</h3>
<p><strong>Title:</strong> Aligning Translation-Specific Understanding to General Understanding in Large Language Models</p>
<p><strong>Authors:</strong> Not specified</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h4>
<ol type="1">
<li>Large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated remarkable language understanding and generation, but they have not shown significant advances in machine translation compared to other natural language processing fields.</li>
<li>Misalignment between general understanding and translation-specific understanding inside LLMs is one potential cause of limited translation performance.</li>
<li>The proposed translation process xIoD, which incorporates cross-lingual interpretation of difficult words and interpretation quality control, shows effectiveness in improving machine translation performance.</li>
</ol>
</section>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h3>
<ul>
<li>Large language models (LLMs) have shown remarkable language understanding and generation.</li>
<li>However, LLMs have not achieved significant advances in machine translation compared to other natural language processing fields.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="approach-xiod" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="approach-xiod">Approach: xIoD</h3>
<ul>
<li>Proposed translation process xIoD aligns translation-specific understanding to general understanding inside LLMs.</li>
<li>xIoD consists of three components: difficult word detection, cross-lingual interpretation, and interpretation quality control.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="testbed-challenge-mt-dataset" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="testbed-challenge-mt-dataset">Testbed: Challenge-MT dataset</h3>
<ul>
<li>A benchmark Challenge-MT is proposed, consisting of difficult translation samples, to assess machine translation performance.</li>
<li>SOTA MT systems show extremely poor performance on the Challenge-MT benchmark.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="experiments" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="experiments">Experiments</h3>
<ul>
<li>xIoD achieves significant improvements and state-of-the-art performance in machine translation.</li>
<li>Comparative methods show varying levels of performance in machine translation.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="analysis" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis">Analysis</h3>
<ul>
<li>Ablation study and in-depth analysis of difficult word detection and interpretation generation demonstrate the effectiveness of the xIoD approach.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<p>The paper provides valuable insights into improving machine translation performance by addressing the misalignment between general and translation-specific understanding in large language models. However, the lack of specific authorship and the absence of comparison with existing similar approaches may limit the paper’s comprehensiveness. Additionally, further details on potential limitations and future research directions could enhance the paper’s impact.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-11</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05072v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05072v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05072v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05072v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7284</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Aligning_Translation_Specific_Understanding_to_General_Understanding_in_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-10-Aligning_Translation_Specific_Understanding_to_General_Understanding_in_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05072v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Pre-trained Large Language Models for Financial Sentiment Analysis</title>
  <dc:creator>Wei Luo, Dihong Gong</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Pre_trained_Large_Language_Models_for_Financial_Sentiment_Analysis/2024-01-10-Pre_trained_Large_Language_Models_for_Financial_Sentiment_Analysis.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Pre_trained_Large_Language_Models_for_Financial_Sentiment_Analysis/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><p>Large language models (LLMs), such as the Llama2-7B, demonstrate significant potential for <strong>financial sentiment analysis</strong>. These models exhibit exceptional proficiency in decoding financial texts and understanding subtle sentiment expressions, leading to improved sentiment classification accuracy in financial news titles.</p></li>
<li><p>The supervised fine-tuning (SFT) technique further leverages LLMs to improve classification accuracy, achieving a new <strong>state-of-the-art performance</strong> in financial sentiment analysis.</p></li>
<li><p>The study provides novel insights into the efficient utilization of LLMs, demonstrating the potential of LLMs for fine-tuning to adapt to domain-specific tasks with <strong>minimal training samples</strong>.</p></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h3>
<ul>
<li><p><strong>Financial sentiment analysis</strong> is crucial for various applications in the financial domain, such as market sentiment gauging, customer feedback analysis, and investment decisions.</p></li>
<li><p>Existing sentiment analysis models lack suitability for financial text due to specialized language patterns and the need for extensive labeled datasets.</p></li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="related-work" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="related-work">Related Work</h3>
<ul>
<li><p>Previous studies have focused on applying machine learning and deep learning techniques to sentiment analysis within the financial domain, with LSTM, CNN, and doc2vec approaches being explored.</p></li>
<li><p>Recent advancements in deep learning have seen the utilization of large language models (LLMs) like BERT, which have revolutionized sentiment analysis in the financial domain.</p></li>
<li><p>The paper’s approach diverges from BERT and focuses on exploring the application of the GPT model, specifically the LLaMA model, for financial sentiment analysis.</p></li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="method" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="method">Method</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper introduces algorithms for utilizing the pretrained LLaMA-7B model for financial sentiment analysis, including LLM Few-shot Prediction, Supervised Fine-Tuning, and Sentiment Analysis with Classification Head.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="experiments" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="experiments">Experiments</h3>
<ul>
<li><p>Experimental evaluation using the Financial PhraseBank dataset demonstrates the effectiveness of the proposed approach, achieving improved accuracy and outperforming the state-of-the-art methods.</p></li>
<li><p>An ablation study compares different components of the proposed method, confirming the effectiveness of supervised fine-tuning in improving classification accuracy.</p></li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="conclusion" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="conclusion">Conclusion</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study concludes with the exploration of the potentials of using LLMs for financial sentiment analysis and highlights the significant impact of supervised fine-tuning in achieving state-of-the-art performance.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<ul>
<li><p>The paper could benefit from a more in-depth comparison with other LLMs, such as GPT-3, to provide a comprehensive understanding of the strengths and limitations of the approach.</p></li>
<li><p>The reliance on a single dataset, the Financial PhraseBank, raises questions about the generalizability of the findings to other financial text sources. More diverse datasets could enhance the robustness of the proposed approach.</p></li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-11</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05215v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05215v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05215v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05215v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5021</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Pre_trained_Large_Language_Models_for_Financial_Sentiment_Analysis/2024-01-10-Pre_trained_Large_Language_Models_for_Financial_Sentiment_Analysis.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>I am a Strange Dataset: Metalinguistic Tests for Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Tristan Thrush, Jared Moore, Miguel Monares, Christopher Potts, Douwe Kiela</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/I_am_a_Strange_Dataset_Metalinguistic_Tests_for_Language_Models/2024-01-10-I_am_a_Strange_Dataset_Metalinguistic_Tests_for_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/I_am_a_Strange_Dataset_Metalinguistic_Tests_for_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05300v1/extracted/5340562/robotexplode.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-i-am-a-strange-dataset-metalinguistic-tests-for-language-models" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-of-i-am-a-strange-dataset-metalinguistic-tests-for-language-models">Summary of “I am a Strange Dataset: Metalinguistic Tests for Language Models”</h3>
<section id="major-findings" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h4>
<ol type="1">
<li><p>“I am a Strange Dataset” presents a new dataset to evaluate language models’ capabilities in handling metalinguistic self-reference. The dataset comprises of two subtasks: generation and verification, with additional metalinguistic non-self-reference examples for control testing.</p></li>
<li><p>The dataset was hand-crafted by experts and validated by non-expert annotators. Testing several open-source and closed-source language models, the study found that all models performed close to chance across both subtasks and even on the non-self-referential metalinguistic control data. GPT 4 was the only model that consistently performed significantly better than chance, though it still only scored in the 60% range, while untrained human annotators scored in the 89–93% range.</p></li>
<li><p>The findings suggest that current language models struggle with understanding and generating self-referential and metalinguistic language, with limited evidence of improvement with model scale. This poses a serious challenge for even the best present-day models.</p></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="i.-introduction" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="i.-introduction">I. Introduction</h4>
<ul>
<li>Self-reference, especially metalinguistic self-reference, plays a crucial role in various domains and is considered a key aspect of higher intelligence or consciousness in philosophy. Humans generally have no trouble with metalinguistic language, which involves reasoning about metalinguistic properties and resolving self-reference.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="ii.-related-work" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="ii.-related-work">II. Related Work</h4>
<ul>
<li>The paper presents “I am a Strange Dataset” as the first AI challenge dataset targeting metalinguistics. It also discusses previous work on self-reference with language models, focusing on models’ ability to improve on themselves or their outputs.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="iii.-i-am-a-strange-dataset" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="iii.-i-am-a-strange-dataset">III. I am a Strange Dataset</h4>
<ul>
<li>The dataset is constructed to test whether language models can produce and understand self-referential and metalinguistic statements. It includes self-referential statements and non-self-referential metalinguistic problem categories. The dataset is comprised of 208 examples, and an additional 10 “Impossible Dataset” examples that experts struggled to understand.</li>
</ul>
<section id="a.-tags" class="level5">
<h5 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="a.-tags">A. Tags</h5>
<ul>
<li>The dataset includes 10 tags to categorize examples, capturing different aspects of the mental facilities required to solve the problems.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="b.-metrics" class="level5">
<h5 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="b.-metrics">B. Metrics</h5>
<ul>
<li>The study focuses on testing whether models can generate and understand self-referential and metalinguistic statements, presenting several metrics for generation and validation.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="c.-non-self-referential-control" class="level5">
<h5 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="c.-non-self-referential-control">C. Non-Self-Referential Control</h5>
<ul>
<li>The study compares the performance of models on non-self-referent examples to the original self-referential examples.</li>
</ul>
</section>
</section>
<section id="iv.-human-experiment-details" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="iv.-human-experiment-details">IV. Human Experiment Details</h4>
<ul>
<li>A human baseline is established from annotations by Mechanical Turk workers, demonstrating that humans perform significantly better than language models on the task.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="v.-results" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="v.-results">V. Results</h4>
<ul>
<li>Language models perform close to the level of chance on the “I am a Strange Dataset.” GPT 4 is the only model to achieve scores significantly above random, but still below human performance. Models also struggle with non-self-referential metalinguistic aspects, and there is limited evidence that GPT 4 struggles more with self-referential metalinguistic problems than non-self-referential problems. Model performance improves with scale.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="vi.-conclusion" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="vi.-conclusion">VI. Conclusion</h4>
<ul>
<li>The dataset presents a serious challenge for language models, indicating that self-referential language is particularly difficult for them. The findings suggest that scale beyond 70B parameters may be needed for comparable performance from models.</li>
</ul>
</section>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study does not delve into potential solutions or improvements for language models to better handle metalinguistic self-reference. There may also be limitations in the study’s evaluation methodology and dataset design that could be explored further. Additionally, the impact of different tokenizers and limitations imposed by training data were only briefly discussed and could be areas for deeper investigation.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-11</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05300v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05300v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05300v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05300v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>9407</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/I_am_a_Strange_Dataset_Metalinguistic_Tests_for_Language_Models/2024-01-10-I_am_a_Strange_Dataset_Metalinguistic_Tests_for_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05300v1/extracted/5340562/robotexplode.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>CASA: Causality-driven Argument Sufficiency Assessment</title>
  <dc:creator>Xiao Liu, Yansong Feng, Kai-Wei Chang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/CASA_Causality_driven_Argument_Sufficiency_Assessment/2024-01-10-CASA_Causality_driven_Argument_Sufficiency_Assessment.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/CASA_Causality_driven_Argument_Sufficiency_Assessment/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05249v1/x3.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-casa-causality-driven-argument-sufficiency-assessment" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-of-casa-causality-driven-argument-sufficiency-assessment">Summary of “Casa: Causality-driven Argument Sufficiency Assessment”</h2>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><p><strong>Argument Sufficiency Assessment Challenge</strong>: The paper addresses the challenge of determining whether the premises of a given argument adequately support its conclusion. Existing works relying on human annotations for training classifiers face inconsistencies due to vague and subjective criteria among annotators. This inconsistency poses a challenge in learning accurate models.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Casa Framework</strong>: The authors propose Casa, a zero-shot Causality-driven Argument Sufficiency Assessment framework, leveraging the probability of sufficiency (PS) from the causal literature. The framework utilizes large language models (LLMs) to sample contexts inconsistent with the premises and conclusion and revises them by injecting the premise event, estimating the probability of the conclusion.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Experimental Results</strong>: Casa accurately identifies insufficient arguments in logical fallacy detection datasets, exhibiting an average of 10% improvement over baseline methods. Furthermore, the framework demonstrates practical application in writing assistance, enhancing the sufficiency of student-written arguments.</p></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="framework-details" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="framework-details">Framework Details</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Introduction</strong>: Argumentation and the importance of assessing argument sufficiency.</li>
<li><strong>Casa Framework</strong>: Explanation of the Casa framework, including notations, assumptions, and the overall architecture.</li>
<li><strong>Claim Extraction</strong>: The process of segmenting an argument into multiple premises and one conclusion.</li>
<li><strong>Context Sampling</strong>: How large language models generate contexts consistent with the premises and conclusion.</li>
<li><strong>Revision under Intervention</strong>: Process for revising contexts to include the premise event.</li>
<li><strong>Probability Estimation</strong>: Transforming probability estimation into a natural language inference (NLI) form.</li>
<li><strong>Experiments</strong>: Evaluation on logical fallacy detection datasets, including details on experimental setup and results.</li>
<li><strong>Analysis</strong>: Ablation study, hyperparameter study, and case studies demonstrating the reasoning process of Casa.</li>
<li><strong>Application: Writing Assistance</strong>: Application of Casa in providing writing suggestions for essays, including annotation templates and the results of a human evaluation.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<p>The framework proposed in this paper shows promise in addressing the challenge of argument sufficiency assessment. However, there are some potential limitations and challenges that should be considered: - <strong>Model Design Choices</strong>: The authors highlight some challenges and choices made in the design of their model, suggesting a need for more powerful diverse decoding and counterfactual reasoning methods to improve the framework. - <strong>Data Scope</strong>: The evaluation of model performances on argument sufficiency assessment is limited by the subjective annotation criteria, emphasizing the need for more diverse and objective datasets.</p>
<p>Overall, while Casa demonstrates promising results, the authors acknowledge the need for improved model design and more comprehensive evaluation datasets to further validate its effectiveness.</p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-11</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05249v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05249v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05249v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05249v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8565</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/CASA_Causality_driven_Argument_Sufficiency_Assessment/2024-01-10-CASA_Causality_driven_Argument_Sufficiency_Assessment.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05249v1/x3.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>INACIA: Integrating Large Language Models in Brazilian Audit Courts: Opportunities and Challenges</title>
  <dc:creator>Jayr Pereira, Andre Assumpcao, Julio Trecenti, Luiz Airosa, Caio Lente, Jhonatan Cléto, Guilherme Dobins, Rodrigo Nogueira, Luis Mitchell, Roberto Lotufo</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/INACIA_Integrating_Large_Language_Models_in_Brazilian_Audit_Courts_Opportunities_and_Challenges/2024-01-10-INACIA_Integrating_Large_Language_Models_in_Brazilian_Audit_Courts_Opportunities_and_Challenges.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/INACIA_Integrating_Large_Language_Models_in_Brazilian_Audit_Courts_Opportunities_and_Challenges/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05273v1/extracted/5340491/images/bpmn.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="major-takeaways" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-takeaways">Major Takeaways</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>INACIA (Instrução Assistida com Inteligência Artificial)</strong> is a system developed to streamline administrative case processing and decision-making at the Brazilian Federal Court of Accounts (TCU) using Large Language Models (LLMs).</li>
<li>The system has been successful in automating various stages of case analysis, including information extraction, admissibility examination, Periculum in mora and Fumus boni iuris analyses, and recommendations generation.</li>
<li>Evaluation of the system’s performance demonstrates its potential to handle complex legal tasks, showing promise in augmenting efficiency and judicial fairness within legal systems.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h3>
<p>Large Language Models (LLMs) have become integral in various applications, including administrative case processing and decision-making in legal environments. The authors introduced INACIA as a novel application of LLMs in the Brazilian Federal Court of Accounts, demonstrating its potential to extract relevant information, evaluate legal plausibility, and generate judicial recommendations.</p>
</section>
<section id="background-on-brazilian-audit-courts" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="background-on-brazilian-audit-courts">Background on Brazilian Audit Courts</h3>
<ul>
<li>The Brazilian Federal Court of Accounts (TCU) oversees the budget and financial execution of the Federal Government, playing a crucial role in preventing deviations from regulations, offering guidance, and imposing sanctions when necessary.</li>
<li>TCU is an influential institution for auditing practices and is an early adopter of AI technology, aiming to optimize case processing through the integration of AI systems.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="the-inacia-project" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-inacia-project">The INACIA Project</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Overview</strong>: The project streamlines case analysis through the extraction of basic information, assessment of admissibility, analysis of Periculum in mora and Fumus boni iuris, and generation of recommendations.</li>
<li><strong>Experiments</strong>: The evaluation methodology utilized a validation dataset to assess the system’s performance, showing a moderate level of accuracy in capturing essential elements from cases.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="results" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="results">Results</h3>
<ul>
<li>The evaluation of the recommendations generated by the INACIA pipeline demonstrated moderate accuracy in capturing necessary elements, albeit with room for improvement in both precision and recall.</li>
<li>The results indicated a variation in the quality of the generated recommendations, emphasizing the need to enhance the system’s performance for consistency and completeness.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<p>The paper effectively introduces the INACIA system and presents the results of its evaluation. However, it would benefit from providing more detailed insights into potential limitations or challenges faced during the development and implementation of INACIA. Additionally, further analysis of the system’s performance and its potential impact on legal proceedings could enhance the paper’s depth and practical implications.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-11</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05273v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05273v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05273v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05273v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>10600</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/INACIA_Integrating_Large_Language_Models_in_Brazilian_Audit_Courts_Opportunities_and_Challenges/2024-01-10-INACIA_Integrating_Large_Language_Models_in_Brazilian_Audit_Courts_Opportunities_and_Challenges.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05273v1/extracted/5340491/images/bpmn.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Can ChatGPT Rival Neural Machine Translation? A Comparative Study</title>
  <dc:creator>Zhaokun Jiang, Ziyin Zhang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Can_ChatGPT_Rival_Neural_Machine_Translation_A_Comparative_Study/2024-01-10-Can_ChatGPT_Rival_Neural_Machine_Translation_A_Comparative_Study.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Can_ChatGPT_Rival_Neural_Machine_Translation_A_Comparative_Study/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05176v1/extracted/5340164/figures/error-penalty.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="major-takeaways" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-takeaways">Major Takeaways:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><p><strong>ChatGPT</strong> exhibits strong capabilities in translating Chinese diplomatic texts into English, particularly excelling under human evaluation and semantic-aware automatic evaluation.</p></li>
<li><p>Providing <strong>example or contextual information</strong> to ChatGPT notably improves its translation quality, highlighting the significance of tailored prompts.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Automated metrics</strong> fail to fully distinguish high-quality and lower-quality translations.</p></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h3>
<ul>
<li>Neural machine translation (NMT) has been extensively studied and has shown satisfying quality in various text types.</li>
<li>Large language models (LLMs) like <strong>ChatGPT</strong> are revolutionizing translation technology, with recent studies showing their potential to surpass mainstream NMT engines.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="related-work" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="related-work">Related Work</h3>
<ul>
<li>Prompt engineering has been explored to improve LLM translation performance, while previous research has emphasized both automated metrics and human evaluation in translation quality assessment (TQA).</li>
<li>Comparative studies of LLM translations and NMT have shown LLMs’ strong capacity in translating high-resource languages and specific text types, but competence in translating middle and low-resource languages is not fully known.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="methodology" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="methodology">Methodology</h3>
<ul>
<li>A <strong>corpus</strong> of Chinese diplomatic texts translated into English was used, with ChatGPT and NMT systems (Microsoft Translate, Google Translate, and DeepL) evaluated using four automated metrics and human evaluation based on error-typology and analytic rubrics score.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="results-and-analysis" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="results-and-analysis">Results and Analysis</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Automated metrics</strong> demonstrated ChatGPT’s strong semantic understanding and capability despite deviations from reference translations, while <strong>human evaluation</strong> indicated its variability under different prompting conditions and its superiority over NMT systems. -<strong>Correlation</strong> between automated metrics and human evaluation was weak and non-significant, suggesting the divergence in translation quality assessment methods.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="conclusion" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="conclusion">Conclusion</h3>
<ul>
<li>Limitations of traditional metrics for translation quality assessment were highlighted, emphasizing the need for more nuanced evaluation metrics that consider cultural aspects and contextual appropriateness.</li>
<li>Tailoring prompts to guide the generation process and enhance the translation quality of LLMs like ChatGPT was deemed crucial based on the study’s findings.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<p>The paper provides valuable insights into the translation capabilities of ChatGPT and NMT systems but has limitations such as reliance on publicly available datasets and small sample sizes for human evaluation, which may not fully capture the diversity of translation challenges. Additionally, the study offers prompts to ChatGPT without exploring the potential biases introduced, and the paper could benefit from a more detailed discussion on how to overcome the limitations of automated metrics for translation quality assessment.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-11</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05176v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05176v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05176v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05176v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8993</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Can_ChatGPT_Rival_Neural_Machine_Translation_A_Comparative_Study/2024-01-10-Can_ChatGPT_Rival_Neural_Machine_Translation_A_Comparative_Study.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05176v1/extracted/5340164/figures/error-penalty.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Can AI Write Classical Chinese Poetry like Humans? An Empirical Study Inspired by Turing Test</title>
  <dc:creator>Zekun Deng, Hao Yang, Jun Wang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Can_AI_Write_Classical_Chinese_Poetry_like_Humans_An_Empirical_Study_Inspired_by_Turing_Test/2024-01-10-Can_AI_Write_Classical_Chinese_Poetry_like_Humans_An_Empirical_Study_Inspired_by_Turing_Test.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Can_AI_Write_Classical_Chinese_Poetry_like_Humans_An_Empirical_Study_Inspired_by_Turing_Test/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04952v1/extracted/5339257/fig/yan_ratio.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="major-takeaways" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-takeaways">Major Takeaways</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The study explores whether AI can compose poetry as effectively as humans, particularly focusing on classical Chinese poetry, challenging the notion that machines cannot replicate human creativity and sentiment.</li>
<li>The authors introduce a new evaluation framework inspired by the Turing test, called ProFTAP, to assess AI-generated poetry’s quality compared to human-authored poetry. The framework emphasizes <strong>distinguishability</strong> to measure AI’s poetry writing ability.</li>
<li>The study finds that current large language models (LLMs) exhibit the capability to write classical Chinese poems almost indistinguishable from those created by humans, and certain open-source LLMs even outperform leading proprietary models like GPT-4.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper addresses the ongoing debate about the potential of artificial intelligence surpassing human capabilities.</li>
<li>It emphasizes the significance of poetry as a form of human art and creativity, encapsulating intricate emotions and ideas in a condensed and evocative manner.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="evaluation-framework-for-ai-generated-poetry" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="evaluation-framework-for-ai-generated-poetry">Evaluation Framework for AI-generated Poetry</h3>
<ul>
<li>The authors propose the <strong>Probabilistic Feigenbaum Test for AI-generated Poetry (ProFTAP)</strong>, inspired by the Turing test, where AI’s ability to compose poems is measured based on its <strong>distinguishability</strong> from human-authored poems.</li>
<li>ProFTAP’s procedures include obtaining titles as conditions, preparing AI models, generating poems, post-processing to prevent plagiarism, human judgment, and deriving metrics.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="experimental-results" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="experimental-results">Experimental Results</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study applies ProFTAP to major current LLMs for classical Chinese poetry writing, including open-source and proprietary models.</li>
<li>It finds that finetuned open-source LLMs can write classical Chinese poems nearly indistinguishable from those authored by ancient Chinese poets, highlighting their potential in poetry generation.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="discussion" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="discussion">Discussion</h3>
<ul>
<li>The impact of explicit features such as line length and character repetition on the evaluation of AI-generated poems is explored.</li>
<li>The research highlights the possibility of improving LLMs’ poetry generation capabilities through advanced prompting techniques.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="conclusion" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="conclusion">Conclusion</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper concludes by emphasizing the novelty and potential of the ProFTAP framework for evaluating AI-generated poetry and highlights the scope for future research in this area.</li>
<li>It underscores the need for further advancements in AI poetry generation and evaluation.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<p>The paper could benefit from a more comprehensive discussion on the limitations of the ProFTAP framework, potential biases in human judgment, and the ethical implications of AI mimicking human creativity and sentiment. Additionally, considering the subjective nature of poetry, there might be diverse interpretations and preferences not fully captured by the framework.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-11</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04952v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04952v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04952v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04952v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6278</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Can_AI_Write_Classical_Chinese_Poetry_like_Humans_An_Empirical_Study_Inspired_by_Turing_Test/2024-01-10-Can_AI_Write_Classical_Chinese_Poetry_like_Humans_An_Empirical_Study_Inspired_by_Turing_Test.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04952v1/extracted/5339257/fig/yan_ratio.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Bootstrapping LLM-based Task-Oriented Dialogue Agents via Self-Talk</title>
  <dc:creator>Dennis Ulmer, Elman Mansimov, Kaixiang Lin, Justin Sun, Xibin Gao, Yi Zhang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Bootstrapping_LLM_based_Task_Oriented_Dialogue_Agents_via_Self_Talk/2024-01-10-Bootstrapping_LLM_based_Task_Oriented_Dialogue_Agents_via_Self_Talk.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Bootstrapping_LLM_based_Task_Oriented_Dialogue_Agents_via_Self_Talk/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05033v1/extracted/5339646/img/schema.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>rom the structured prompting (see Figure 15), might come from the last client response not being close enough to the sample answers defined in the workflow, thus leading the structured prompting from Section 3.1 to choose the “None of the above” option. As the agent model is being given the option to freely generate, the model might decide to simply copy the start of the conversation.</p>
<p>In general, our observations show that while the structured prompting and automated evaluation metrics are useful tools for guiding the dialogues and selecting useful training samples, they are not foolproof and the quality of the generated dialogues can vary depending on the specific circumstances of each conversation. As a result, caution is warranted when interpreting the results of the automated evaluations and when using the generated dialogues for finetuning.</p>
<p>Overall, these sample conversations illustrate the dynamics and challenges of using self-talk to bootstrap training data for task-oriented dialogue agents and highlight the complexity of generating high-quality, task-oriented dialogues with language models.</p>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-11</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05033v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05033v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05033v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05033v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>13790</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Bootstrapping_LLM_based_Task_Oriented_Dialogue_Agents_via_Self_Talk/2024-01-10-Bootstrapping_LLM_based_Task_Oriented_Dialogue_Agents_via_Self_Talk.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05033v1/extracted/5339646/img/schema.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Attendre: Wait To Attend By Retrieval With Evicted Queries in Memory-Based Transformers for Long Context Processing</title>
  <dc:creator>Zi Yang, Nan Hua</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Attendre_Wait_To_Attend_By_Retrieval_With_Evicted_Queries_in_Memory_Based_Transformers_for_Long_Context_Processing/2024-01-10-Attendre_Wait_To_Attend_By_Retrieval_With_Evicted_Queries_in_Memory_Based_Transformers_for_Long_Context_Processing.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Attendre_Wait_To_Attend_By_Retrieval_With_Evicted_Queries_in_Memory_Based_Transformers_for_Long_Context_Processing/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04881v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="major-takeaways" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-takeaways">Major Takeaways</h2>
<ul>
<li>The paper introduces the Attendre layer, a wait-to-attend mechanism by retrieving the key-value memory with evicted queries in the query memory to support bidirectional attention in memory-based transformers for long context processing.</li>
<li>The proposed method using eviction policies, such as LRA and LFA, significantly reduces memory size and adapts to various architectures while also supporting bidirectional attention.</li>
<li>The experiments show that the proposed method outperforms baseline methods in the context length extension setup using the TriviaQA reading comprehension task.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>The paper discusses the limitations faced by transformer-based language models (LLMs) when processing arbitrary long input sequences and introduces the Attendre layer to address these issues. It also mentions previous approaches, such as using recurrent states or continuous memory, but highlights the need for more efficient and adaptable methods for long context processing.</p>
</section>
<section id="memory-eviction-policies" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="memory-eviction-policies">Memory &amp; Eviction Policies</h2>
<ul>
<li>The paper introduces two common use cases for memory modules: memorizing a single or group of data and providing searchable keys to accompany values at insertion time for retrieval at a future step.</li>
<li>It discusses different eviction policies, such as FIFO, LRU, and LFU, to manage the memory at insertion time, and proposes the use of LRA and LFA policies to reduce memory size.</li>
<li>The complexities of different memory modules and eviction policies are analyzed, with a focus on minimizing memory size.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="attendre-layer" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="attendre-layer">Attendre Layer</h2>
<ul>
<li>The Attendre layer is introduced, comprising two memory modules: a data-only Q memory to delay queries and a key-value memory for K/Vs.</li>
<li>The process of inserting, evicting, and retrieving K/Vs and queries in the Attendre layer is explained, highlighting how it enables bidirectional attention over “future” K/Vs from the query’s perspective.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="related-work" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="related-work">Related Work</h2>
<ul>
<li>The paper provides a comprehensive review of related work in long context modeling, memory entry types, memory update methods, and other uses of memory in language models.</li>
<li>Various methods and techniques used in memory-based transformers for long context processing are compared and contrasted to highlight their strengths and limitations.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="experiment-context-length-extension-on-triviaqa" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="experiment-context-length-extension-on-triviaqa">Experiment: Context Length Extension on TriviaQA</h2>
<ul>
<li>The paper presents experimental results on the TriviaQA reading comprehension task using two pretrained language models and demonstrates the effectiveness of the proposed memory-based transformers with eviction policies and the Attendre layer in improving performance.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="conclusion" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<ul>
<li>The paper concludes with a summary of the proposed methods and their performance, highlighting the potential for further research and improvements in the area of long context processing with memory-based transformers.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h2>
<ul>
<li>The paper provides a comprehensive overview of the proposed methods and their experimental validation. However, it could benefit from a more detailed analysis of potential limitations or drawbacks of the proposed approach, as well as a discussion of future research directions and potential challenges in real-world applications. Additionally, the technical complexity of the paper may pose a barrier to understanding for readers with limited background in transformer-based language models and memory-based architectures.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-11</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04881v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04881v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04881v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04881v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>10868</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Attendre_Wait_To_Attend_By_Retrieval_With_Evicted_Queries_in_Memory_Based_Transformers_for_Long_Context_Processing/2024-01-10-Attendre_Wait_To_Attend_By_Retrieval_With_Evicted_Queries_in_Memory_Based_Transformers_for_Long_Context_Processing.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04881v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Leveraging Print Debugging to Improve Code Generation in Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Xueyu Hu, Kun Kuang, Jiankai Sun, Hongxia Yang, Fei Wu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Leveraging_Print_Debugging_to_Improve_Code_Generation_in_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-10-Leveraging_Print_Debugging_to_Improve_Code_Generation_in_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Leveraging_Print_Debugging_to_Improve_Code_Generation_in_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05319v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="key-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="key-findings">Key Findings</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Large language models (LLMs) have shown significant progress in code generation tasks but struggle with complex programming problems involving intricate data structures and algorithms.</strong></li>
<li><strong>The proposed in-context learning approach leverages “print debugging” to guide LLMs in debugging by inserting print statements and analyzing logs, leading to a substantial improvement in performance, outperforming rubber duck debugging in easy and medium-level Leetcode problems.</strong></li>
<li><strong>While the print debugging approach was effective in addressing bugs in easy and medium-level problems, it did not yield improvements in hard-level problems, indicating the need for further research to address challenges requiring sophisticated algorithms.</strong></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">1. Introduction</h3>
<ul>
<li>Large language models (LLMs) have shown promise in code generation tasks but struggle with complex programming problems involving intricate data structures and algorithms.</li>
<li>Existing methods such as Reflexion and Self-debug have limitations in providing real-time variable values and effectively leveraging test cases for debugging.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="related-work" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="related-work">2. Related Work</h3>
<ul>
<li>Researchers have explored chain-of-thought prompting and prompting with feedback to enhance model capabilities in reasoning and iterative refinement tasks.</li>
<li>Prompting techniques, including auto-cot, least-to-more, and tree-of-thought, have been proposed to enhance model capabilities.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="our-methods" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="our-methods">3. Our Methods</h3>
<ul>
<li>The proposed approach guides LLMs to employ “print debugging” by adding print statements, executing the code, and analyzing mentioned logs and test cases using one-shot prompting.</li>
<li>The method involves three main steps: adding print statements, execution, and analyzing &amp; fixing, and results in continuous improvement in performance with iterative debugging rounds.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="experiments" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="experiments">4. Experiments</h3>
<ul>
<li>Experimentation with GPT-4 on Leetcode problems demonstrated the effectiveness of the print debugging approach, outperforming other debugging methods in easy and medium-level problems but showing limitations in hard-level challenges.</li>
<li>Ablation studies emphasized the significant impact of both test case explanations and logs in effectively debugging the code.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="analysis" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis">5. Analysis</h3>
<ul>
<li>Analysis of the performance of different debugging methods as the procedure progresses highlighted the continuous increase in performance of print debugging over multiple rounds, compared to other methods.</li>
<li>The distribution of added print statements in the code and the number of lines in the generated logs were examined, showcasing the effectiveness of the print debugging method.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<p>While the proposed print debugging approach showed effectiveness in improving LLMs’ code generation performance, there are some potential concerns: - Limited application to hard-level problems: The method showed limited effectiveness in addressing hard-level problems, emphasizing the need for further research to address challenges requiring advanced algorithms. - Overwhelming log length: In some cases, the logs generated from print statements exceeded a predefined limit, indicating a potential challenge in effectively handling excessive log lengths. - Dependency on iterative rounds: The continuous improvement in performance with iterative debugging rounds may indicate a potential dependency on multiple rounds for effective bug identification and resolution, raising questions about the efficiency of the method in single-round scenarios.</p>
<p>Overall, the proposed print debugging approach provides a valuable contribution to improving LLMs’ code generation performance, but further research is warranted to address its limitations and potential challenges.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-11</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05319v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05319v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05319v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05319v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6337</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Leveraging_Print_Debugging_to_Improve_Code_Generation_in_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-10-Leveraging_Print_Debugging_to_Improve_Code_Generation_in_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05319v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Prompting Large Language Models for Recommender Systems: A Comprehensive Framework and Empirical Analysis</title>
  <dc:creator>Lanling Xu, Junjie Zhang, Bingqian Li, Jinpeng Wang, Mingchen Cai, Wayne Xin Zhao, Ji-Rong Wen</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Prompting_Large_Language_Models_for_Recommender_Systems_A_Comprehensive_Framework_and_Empirical_Analysis/2024-01-10-Prompting_Large_Language_Models_for_Recommender_Systems_A_Comprehensive_Framework_and_Empirical_Analysis.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Prompting_Large_Language_Models_for_Recommender_Systems_A_Comprehensive_Framework_and_Empirical_Analysis/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04997v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-prompting-large-language-models-for-recommender-systems-a-comprehensive-framework-and-empirical-analysis" class="level1">
<h1>Summary of “Prompting Large Language Models for Recommender Systems: A Comprehensive Framework and Empirical Analysis”</h1>
<section id="key-findings" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="key-findings">Key Findings</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Large Language Models (LLMs)</strong>, like ChatGPT, have demonstrated promising abilities in general reasoning tasks, indicating their potential in revolutionizing recommender systems.</li>
<li>LLMs can be employed in three ways for recommendations: as the recommender to make decisions, to enhance traditional recommendation models, and as the recommendation simulator to execute external generative agents in the recommendation process.</li>
<li>The study introduces a comprehensive framework, <em>ProLLM4Rec</em>, that focuses on two key aspects, <em>LLMs</em> and <em>prompt engineering</em>, and conducts experiments to evaluate the impact on recommendation performance.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<ul>
<li>Recommender systems struggle with information overload and the lack of understanding user preferences.</li>
<li>LLMs present an opportunity to compensate for the shortcomings of traditional recommendation models by leveraging their general knowledge and language modeling abilities.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="related-work" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="related-work">Related Work</h2>
<ul>
<li>The paper distinguishes between three paradigms of utilizing LLMs for recommendations: LLM as a recommendation model, LLM improves recommendation models, and LLM as a recommendation simulator.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="general-framework-and-overall-settings" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="general-framework-and-overall-settings">General Framework and Overall Settings</h2>
<ul>
<li>The study introduces the <em>ProLLM4Rec</em> framework that focuses on the capabilities of LLMs and <em>prompt engineering</em> for recommendation tasks.</li>
<li>The framework comprises LLMs, task description, user interest modeling, candidate items construction, and prompting strategies.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="impact-of-large-language-models-as-recommender-systems" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="impact-of-large-language-models-as-recommender-systems">Impact of Large Language Models as Recommender Systems</h2>
<ul>
<li>The study discusses the impact of LLMs in recommendation tasks, considering factors like public availability, tuning strategies, model architecture, parameter scale, and context length.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h2>
<ul>
<li>The paper lacks specific results and empirical findings from the experiments conducted. It would be beneficial to have more detailed insights into the impact of LLMs and prompting strategies on recommendation performances.</li>
<li>The study primarily revolves around the proposed framework without delving into external validation or comparison with existing methodologies. A comparative analysis with traditional recommendation models could provide a better context for the findings.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-11</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04997v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04997v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04997v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04997v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>34860</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>recommender</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Prompting_Large_Language_Models_for_Recommender_Systems_A_Comprehensive_Framework_and_Empirical_Analysis/2024-01-10-Prompting_Large_Language_Models_for_Recommender_Systems_A_Comprehensive_Framework_and_Empirical_Analysis.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04997v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>ANGO: A Next-Level Evaluation Benchmark For Generation-Oriented Language Models In Chinese Domain</title>
  <dc:creator>Bingchao Wang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ANGO_A_Next_Level_Evaluation_Benchmark_For_Generation_Oriented_Language_Models_In_Chinese_Domain/2024-01-10-ANGO_A_Next_Level_Evaluation_Benchmark_For_Generation_Oriented_Language_Models_In_Chinese_Domain.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ANGO_A_Next_Level_Evaluation_Benchmark_For_Generation_Oriented_Language_Models_In_Chinese_Domain/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04898v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="major-takeaways" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-takeaways">Major Takeaways</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>ANGO</strong> introduces a novel Chinese benchmark for evaluating large language models (LLMs) in the domain of natural language processing (NLP), aiming to address issues with existing evaluation datasets and provide more precise guidance for model training.</li>
<li>It proposes a <strong>Keypoint categorization standard</strong> for multi-choice questions, allowing questions to correspond to multiple keypoints, enhancing interpretability of evaluation results.</li>
<li>ANGO’s innovative features pose a stronger challenge to models and reveal more details in evaluation results compared to existing benchmarks, providing a more comprehensive and accurate multi-level, multi-perspective performance results for participating models.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h3>
<p>The paper highlights the recent advancements in NLP, particularly the development of LLMs and the Transformer architecture. It discusses the evolution of benchmarks used to evaluate LLMs, from focusing on Natural Language Understanding (NLU) tasks to more specialized benchmarks with multiple-choice question formats.</p>
</section>
<section id="challenges" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="challenges">Challenges</h3>
<p>Existing multi-choice question benchmarks suffer from issues such as single-subject categorization, immeasurable difficulty, and challenging updates due to potential sampling biases. Traditional benchmarks struggle to provide reliable measurements for modeling abilities across diverse disciplines.</p>
</section>
<section id="contributions" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="contributions">Contributions</h3>
<p>ANGO introduces a novel Chinese benchmark for evaluation, adopting Keypoint categorization, a quantifiable difficulty standard, and specific strategies for sampling, aiming to minimize data leakage impact and provide comprehensive and accurate evaluation results for participating models.</p>
</section>
<section id="data" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="data">Data</h3>
<p>The paper exclusively sources data from the Administrative Proficiency Test (AAT) used in the Chinese civil service examination. Data preprocessing involves removing duplicates, eliminating records containing pictures, and extracting unique formulas using OCR models.</p>
</section>
<section id="sample-strategy" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="sample-strategy">Sample Strategy</h3>
<p>The paper presents a few-shot history sampling strategy and test set sampling method to ensure minimal information loss and achieve a balanced distribution of records for evaluation.</p>
</section>
<section id="evaluation" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="evaluation">Evaluation</h3>
<p>ANGO employs accuracy as the ultimate metric for assessing model performance and introduces new evaluation metrics, such as Human Hit and Human Value, to capture human-like behavior and thinking patterns in model outputs.</p>
</section>
<section id="experiment" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="experiment">Experiment</h3>
<p>The paper details the objectives, models used for evaluation, and results, showcasing performance at different keypoint, difficulty, and question levels.</p>
</section>
<section id="related-work" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="related-work">Related Work</h3>
<p>Comparisons are made to existing benchmarks in both English and Chinese language domains, highlighting the distinct features of ANGO.</p>
</section>
<section id="conclusion" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="conclusion">Conclusion</h3>
<p>ANGO is positioned as a valuable resource for fostering innovation and progress in NLP, with the potential to provide profound understanding of model capabilities and guidance for model design and improvement. The unique features of ANGO enable developers to better evaluate and enhance their own models.</p>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<p>The paper does not thoroughly address potential limitations or biases in the development and implementation of ANGO. It would be beneficial to provide a more detailed discussion on the generalizability and potential biases within the benchmark. Additionally, insights on the scalability and applicability of ANGO to different LLMs could further strengthen the paper.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-11</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04898v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04898v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04898v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04898v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6974</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ANGO_A_Next_Level_Evaluation_Benchmark_For_Generation_Oriented_Language_Models_In_Chinese_Domain/2024-01-10-ANGO_A_Next_Level_Evaluation_Benchmark_For_Generation_Oriented_Language_Models_In_Chinese_Domain.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04898v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Theory of Mind abilities of Large Language Models in Human-Robot Interaction : An Illusion?</title>
  <dc:creator>Mudit Verma, Siddhant Bhambri, Subbarao Kambhampati</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Theory_of_Mind_abilities_of_Large_Language_Models_in_Human_Robot_Interaction__An_Illusion/2024-01-10-Theory_of_Mind_abilities_of_Large_Language_Models_in_Human_Robot_Interaction__An_Illusion.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Theory_of_Mind_abilities_of_Large_Language_Models_in_Human_Robot_Interaction__An_Illusion/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05302v1/extracted/5340607/images/hri_main.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="theory-of-mind-abilities-of-large-language-models-in-human-robot-interaction-an-illusion" class="level1">
<h1>Theory of Mind abilities of Large Language Models in Human-Robot Interaction: An Illusion?</h1>
<section id="major-takeaways" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-takeaways">Major Takeaways</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li>This paper investigates the <strong>Theory of Mind (ToM)</strong> abilities of <strong>Large Language Models (LLMs)</strong> in the context of Human-Robot Interaction (HRI) using the Perceived Behavior Recognition task.</li>
<li>The study reveals the potential usability of LLMs as human proxies in HRI settings; however, it also highlights that LLMs lack the invariance to trivial or irrelevant perturbations required to possess ToM abilities.</li>
<li>While LLMs demonstrate strong performance on vanilla prompts, perturbation tests such as Inconsistent Belief and Uninformative Context break the illusion of their ToM abilities.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<ul>
<li>ToM involves attributing mental states to oneself and others, and understanding that these mental states may differ from one’s own.</li>
<li>ToM is crucial for effective communication and collaboration in human-agent interaction.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="related-work" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="related-work">Related Work</h2>
<ul>
<li>Large Language Models, such as GPT family and others, have gained popularity for their exceptional natural language processing abilities.</li>
<li>ToM has been a challenging goal for AI agents, and previous works have explored the emergent ToM abilities of LLMs.</li>
<li>Previous studies have investigated the variations among behavior types crucial for HRI, but this work focuses on LLM’s failures in ToM abilities.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="preliminaries" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="preliminaries">Preliminaries</h2>
<ul>
<li>Behavior synthesis in HRI requires the agent to possess ToM and reasoning abilities.</li>
<li>The four behavior types considered in this study are explicability, legibility, predictability, and obfuscation.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="methodology" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="methodology">Methodology</h2>
<ul>
<li>The study addresses three key research questions related to ToM reasoning in HRI scenarios.</li>
<li>A user subject study is conducted to compare the performance of lay users and LLMs in ToM reasoning tasks.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="evaluation-domains" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="evaluation-domains">Evaluation Domains</h2>
<ul>
<li>Five domains, including Fetch Robot, Passage Gridworld, Environment Design, Urban Search and Rescue, and Package Delivery, were used for the evaluation of ToM reasoning in HRI scenarios.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="results" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="results">Results</h2>
<ul>
<li>Lay users performed well on ToM reasoning tasks in HRI scenarios, and their responses aligned with LLMs’ performance.</li>
<li>However, perturbation tests revealed that LLMs lack robustness in their ToM reasoning abilities, breaking the illusion of their ToM capabilities.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="case-study" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="case-study">Case Study</h2>
<ul>
<li>A case study with the Fetch robot demonstrated that human users were consistent in answering ToM queries, even when perturbations were introduced.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="conclusion-future-work" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="conclusion-future-work">Conclusion &amp; Future Work</h2>
<ul>
<li>The study contributes to the understanding of LLMs’ ToM abilities in HRI settings and calls for further investigation into the robustness of LLM responses.</li>
<li>Future work could explore additional failure modes of LLMs in ToM tasks and study the impact of using LLMs in HRI settings.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h2>
<ul>
<li>While the study provides valuable insights into the limitations of LLMs in ToM reasoning, it would benefit from further exploration of potential solutions or alternative approaches to address the identified challenges.</li>
<li>The study could also benefit from a more extensive discussion on the implications of the findings for the broader field of HRI and AI.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-11</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05302v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05302v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05302v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05302v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>10659</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Theory_of_Mind_abilities_of_Large_Language_Models_in_Human_Robot_Interaction__An_Illusion/2024-01-10-Theory_of_Mind_abilities_of_Large_Language_Models_in_Human_Robot_Interaction__An_Illusion.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05302v1/extracted/5340607/images/hri_main.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>MISS: A Generative Pretraining and Finetuning Approach for Med-VQA</title>
  <dc:creator>Jiawei Chen, Dingkang Yang, Yue Jiang, Yuxuan Lei, Lihua Zhang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MISS_A_Generative_Pretraining_and_Finetuning_Approach_for_Med_VQA/2024-01-10-MISS_A_Generative_Pretraining_and_Finetuning_Approach_for_Med_VQA.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MISS_A_Generative_Pretraining_and_Finetuning_Approach_for_Med_VQA/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05163v1/extracted/5339622/image/model_arc_5.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="major-takeaways" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-takeaways">Major Takeaways</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><p><strong>MISS</strong> is proposed as a pretraining and finetuning framework for medical Visual Question Answering (Med-VQA). It treats Med-VQA as a generative task, unlike previous methods that treat it as an answer classification task, leading to improved performance in practical application scenarios.</p></li>
<li><p>The framework includes a <strong>Joint Text-Multimodal encoder</strong> and a method called <strong>Transfer and Caption (TransCap)</strong> that extends the feature space of single-modal image datasets using large language models (LLMs).</p></li>
<li><p>Experiments show that the method achieves excellent results with fewer multimodal datasets, indicating the advantages of generative VQA models.</p></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h3>
<p>Medical Visual Question Answering (Med-VQA) is a challenging task that requires deeper and more accurate understanding of medical images compared to VQA of natural images. Due to privacy concerns and expensive annotation processes, large-scale datasets for training are scarce, making Med-VQA a highly challenging task.</p>
</section>
<section id="related-work" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="related-work">Related Work</h3>
<p>Early works used RNNs and CNNs to extract textual and visual features for Med-VQA tasks. The emergence of transformers has enabled the migration of large-scale pretraining from the textual domain to the multimodal domain. Previous works have treated VQA as a classification or rank task, limiting their effectiveness in practical application scenarios. The paper proposes a new pretraining and fine-tuning paradigm, treating VQA as a generative task.</p>
</section>
<section id="method" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="method">Method</h3>
<p>The proposed framework includes a Joint Text-Multimodal encoder and a method called Transfer and Caption (TransCap) for constructing multimodal medical data based on unimodal image datasets. The framework adopts the pretraining and finetuning paradigm, utilizing tasks like Image-Text Contrastive Learning (ITC), Image-Text Matching (ITM), and Mask Language Modeling (MLM) for multi-modal pretraining. The paper details the model architecture, pretraining process, TransCap method, and VQA finetuning.</p>
</section>
<section id="experiment" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="experiment">Experiment</h3>
<p>The paper compares the proposed framework with existing approaches on VQA-RAD and Slake datasets, demonstrating improved performance in both open-ended and closed-ended questions. Ablation studies show the impact of different components of the framework, indicating the effectiveness of the Joint Text-Multimodal encoder and the positive effect of TransCap on VQA performance.</p>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<p>The proposed framework demonstrates promising results, especially in terms of treating Med-VQA as a generative task and the novel TransCap method for constructing multimodal medical data. However, the paper lacks a discussion on potential limitations or challenges in implementing the proposed framework in real-world scenarios. The generalization of the framework to diverse medical imaging modalities or its scalability with larger datasets could also be areas for further exploration.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-11</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05163v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05163v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05163v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05163v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7911</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MISS_A_Generative_Pretraining_and_Finetuning_Approach_for_Med_VQA/2024-01-10-MISS_A_Generative_Pretraining_and_Finetuning_Approach_for_Med_VQA.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05163v1/extracted/5339622/image/model_arc_5.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Impact of Reasoning Step Length on Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Mingyu Jin, Qinkai Yu, Dong shu, Haiyan Zhao, Wenyue Hua, Yanda Meng, Yongfeng Zhang, Mengnan Du</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/The_Impact_of_Reasoning_Step_Length_on_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-10-The_Impact_of_Reasoning_Step_Length_on_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/The_Impact_of_Reasoning_Step_Length_on_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04925v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><p><strong>Lengthening reasoning steps enhances LLMs’ abilities</strong>: Increasing the length of reasoning steps in prompts significantly enhances LLMs’ reasoning abilities across multiple datasets, even without adding new information into the prompt.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Incorrect rationales can yield favorable outcomes</strong>: Surprisingly, incorrect rationales can yield favorable outcomes if they maintain the requisite length of inference, especially in tasks such as mathematical problems.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Task-dependent advantages of reasoning steps</strong>: The advantages of increasing reasoning steps are task-dependent: simpler tasks require fewer steps, whereas complex tasks gain significantly from longer inference sequences.</p></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analyzing-methods" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analyzing-methods">Analyzing Methods</h3>
<ul>
<li><p><strong>Preliminary</strong>: Zero-Shot-CoT and Few-Shot-CoT are explored, with experiments on expanding and compressing rationale reasoning steps within CoT demonstrations.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Analyzing Zero-shot CoT</strong>: Modifying the initial prompt to guide LLMs to engage in more extensive thinking significantly enhances performance in zero-shot settings.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Analyzing Few-shot CoT</strong>: Strategies for expanding reasoning steps, such as interpreting the word, reading the question again, repeating state, self-verification, and making equation, all showed corresponding patterns in the model’s responses.</p></li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="experimental-results" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="experimental-results">Experimental Results</h3>
<ul>
<li><p><strong>Relationship Between Steps and Accuracy</strong>: A linear relationship between reasoning step quantity and accuracy was observed, indicating the direct correlation between step count and accuracy.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Effect of Prompt with Wrong Answer</strong>: Changing a step in the prompt to an incorrect answer minimally affected the chain of thought in reasoning processes, indicating that the large language model learns more about the chain of thought patterns in the prompt.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Compressing Reasoning Steps</strong>: Compressing reasoning steps in few-shot demonstrations led to a notable decline in LLM performance, highlighting the importance of increasing reasoning steps for CoT performance.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Performance on Different Size Models</strong>: The model with the best initial performance exhibited the highest tolerance to strategy, while the worst-performing model showed the highest boosting effect.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Influence of Questions in CoT Examples</strong>: Deliberate alterations to sample questions minimally impacted performance, suggesting that the length of the reasoning steps predominantly influences the reasoning capabilities of large-scale models.</p></li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique-and-future-work" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique-and-future-work">Critique and Future Work</h3>
<p>The paper effectively demonstrates the impact of reasoning step length on large language models. However, the experiments are primarily limited to a specific set of models and datasets, and the generalizability of the findings to other models and tasks remains unclear. Additionally, the paper lacks a detailed discussion of potential biases and limitations in the experimental design, which could impact the robustness of the conclusions. Future work should focus on generalizing the findings to a broader set of models and tasks and addressing potential biases in the experimental design.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-11</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04925v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04925v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04925v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04925v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6456</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/The_Impact_of_Reasoning_Step_Length_on_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-10-The_Impact_of_Reasoning_Step_Length_on_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04925v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
