<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Bayesian beagle</title>
<link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Quarto blog of LLM-generated summaries of Arxiv preprints</description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.450</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Do Multilingual Large Language Models Mitigate Stereotype Bias?</title>
  <dc:creator>Shangrui Nie, Michael Fromm, Charles Welch, Rebekka Görge, Akbar Karimi, Joan Plepi, Nazia Afsan Mowmita, Nicolas Flores-Herr, Mehdi Ali, Lucie Flek</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Do_Multilingual_Large_Language_Models_Mitigate_Stereotype_Bias/2024-07-08-Do_Multilingual_Large_Language_Models_Mitigate_Stereotype_Bias.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2407.05740v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>Summary: This paper investigates the impact of multilingual training on bias mitigation in large language models (LLMs). The authors train six LLMs of identical size (2.6B parameters) and architecture, including five monolingual models (English, German, French, Italian, and Spanish) and one multilingual model. The models are evaluated on standard bias benchmarks, which are automatically translated and verified for both translation quality and bias preservation. The results show that multilingual training effectively mitigates bias, and multilingual models achieve not only lower bias but also superior prediction accuracy compared to monolingual models with the same amount of training data, model architecture, and size.</p>
<p>Major Findings: 1. Multilingual training effectively mitigates bias in LLMs. 2. Multilingual models achieve lower bias than monolingual models with the same amount of training data, model architecture, and size. 3. Multilingual models outperform monolingual models in prediction accuracy.</p>
<p>Analysis and Critique: The paper presents a well-structured and coherent summary of the research, providing a clear overview of the methodology and findings. The use of a controlled setting and the evaluation of both bias and prediction accuracy are strengths of the study. However, the paper does not discuss potential limitations or shortcomings of the research, such as the generalizability of the findings to other languages or the impact of different translation methods on the results. Additionally, the paper does not address the potential for biases to be introduced during the translation process, which could affect the validity of the results. Further research is needed to explore these issues and to validate the findings in other contexts.</p>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-09</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.05740v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.05740v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.05740v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.05740v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>21234</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Do_Multilingual_Large_Language_Models_Mitigate_Stereotype_Bias/2024-07-08-Do_Multilingual_Large_Language_Models_Mitigate_Stereotype_Bias.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2407.05740v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>From Loops to Oops: Fallback Behaviors of Language Models Under Uncertainty</title>
  <dc:creator>Maor Ivgi, Ori Yoran, Jonathan Berant, Mor Geva</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/From_Loops_to_Oops_Fallback_Behaviors_of_Language_Models_Under_Uncertainty/2024-07-08-From_Loops_to_Oops_Fallback_Behaviors_of_Language_Models_Under_Uncertainty.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/From_Loops_to_Oops_Fallback_Behaviors_of_Language_Models_Under_Uncertainty/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.06071v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary:</strong></p>
<p>The paper “From Loops to Oops: Fallback Behaviors of Language Models Under Uncertainty” investigates the undesirable behaviors of large language models (LLMs), such as hallucinations and sequence repetitions, and proposes to view these behaviors as fallbacks that models exhibit under uncertainty. The authors categorize fallback behaviors into sequence repetitions, degenerate text, and hallucinations, and extensively analyze them in models from the same family that differ by the amount of pretraining tokens, parameter count, or the inclusion of instruction-following training. The experiments reveal a clear and consistent ordering of fallback behaviors, with more advanced LLMs exhibiting more complex fallback behaviors. The same ordering is observed throughout a single generation, even for the best-performing models, as uncertainty increases. The paper also demonstrates that common decoding techniques, such as random sampling, might alleviate some unwanted behaviors like sequence repetitions but increase harder-to-detect hallucinations.</p>
<p><strong>Major Findings:</strong></p>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs exhibit a clear and consistent ordering of fallback behaviors, with more advanced models (trained on more tokens, having more parameters, or instruction-tuned) shifting from sequence repetitions to degenerate text and then to hallucinations.</li>
<li>The same ordering of fallback behaviors is observed throughout a single generation, even for the best-performing models, as uncertainty increases.</li>
<li>Common decoding techniques, such as random sampling, might alleviate some unwanted behaviors like sequence repetitions but increase harder-to-detect hallucinations.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></p>
<p>The paper provides a comprehensive analysis of the fallback behaviors of LLMs under uncertainty, offering valuable insights into the relationship between model complexity, training, and the emergence of different fallback behaviors. The authors’ categorization of fallback behaviors and their extensive experiments contribute to a better understanding of the limitations and challenges of LLMs. However, the paper does not discuss potential solutions to mitigate the identified issues or explore the implications of these findings for the development and deployment of LLMs in real-world applications. Additionally, the paper does not address the potential impact of different decoding strategies on the performance and reliability of LLMs. Further research is needed to investigate these aspects and develop more robust and reliable LLMs.</p>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-09</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.06071v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.06071v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.06071v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.06071v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>17045</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/From_Loops_to_Oops_Fallback_Behaviors_of_Language_Models_Under_Uncertainty/2024-07-08-From_Loops_to_Oops_Fallback_Behaviors_of_Language_Models_Under_Uncertainty.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.06071v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>T2VSafetyBench: Evaluating the Safety of Text-to-Video Generative Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Yibo Miao, Yifan Zhu, Yinpeng Dong, Lijia Yu, Jun Zhu, Xiao-Shan Gao</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/T2VSafetyBench_Evaluating_the_Safety_of_Text_to_Video_Generative_Models/2024-07-08-T2VSafetyBench_Evaluating_the_Safety_of_Text_to_Video_Generative_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/T2VSafetyBench_Evaluating_the_Safety_of_Text_to_Video_Generative_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.05965v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper introduces T2VSafetyBench, a new benchmark for evaluating the safety of text-to-video (T2V) models. The benchmark is designed to address the lack of comprehensive quantitative understanding of T2V safety, which poses a challenge to their reliability and practical deployment. T2VSafetyBench defines 12 critical aspects of video generation safety and constructs a malicious prompt dataset using LLMs and jailbreaking prompt attacks. The evaluation results reveal several important findings, including:</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>No single model excels in all aspects, with different models showing various strengths.</li>
<li>The correlation between GPT-4 assessments and manual reviews is generally high.</li>
<li>There is a trade-off between the usability and safety of text-to-video generative models.</li>
</ol>
<p>The paper highlights the urgency of prioritizing video safety as the field of video generation rapidly advances.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Different models have distinct strengths in managing various safety aspects. For example, Stable Video Diffusion performs exceptionally well in mitigating sexual content, while Gen2 excels in handling gore and disturbing content. Pika shows remarkable defensive capability in political sensitivity and copyright-related areas.</li>
<li>The correlation between GPT-4’s assessments and manual reviews is generally high, with a correlation coefficient exceeding 0.8 in most dimensions. This finding supports the rationality of leveraging GPT-4 for large-scale evaluations in this context.</li>
<li>There is a trade-off between the accessibility and safety of text-to-video generative models. Models with worse comprehension and generation capability may fail to meet minimal standards for understanding abstract and complex aspects of safety risks, such as borderline pornography, discrimination, and temporal risk, paradoxically enhancing safety. However, this also implies that as video generation evolves and model capability strengthens, the safety risks across various dimensions are likely to surge.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper provides a comprehensive benchmark for evaluating the safety of T2V models, which is a significant contribution to the field. However, the benchmark focuses on 12 critical aspects, and there may be other safety aspects that have not been considered.</li>
<li>The paper rel</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-09</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.05965v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.05965v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.05965v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.05965v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8108</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/T2VSafetyBench_Evaluating_the_Safety_of_Text_to_Video_Generative_Models/2024-07-08-T2VSafetyBench_Evaluating_the_Safety_of_Text_to_Video_Generative_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.05965v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Towards Optimizing and Evaluating a Retrieval Augmented QA Chatbot using LLMs with Human in the Loop</title>
  <dc:creator>Anum Afzal, Alexander Kowsik, Rajna Fani, Florian Matthes</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Towards_Optimizing_and_Evaluating_a_Retrieval_Augmented_QA_Chatbot_using_LLMs_with_Human_in_the_Loop/2024-07-08-Towards_Optimizing_and_Evaluating_a_Retrieval_Augmented_QA_Chatbot_using_LLMs_with_Human_in_the_Loop.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Towards_Optimizing_and_Evaluating_a_Retrieval_Augmented_QA_Chatbot_using_LLMs_with_Human_in_the_Loop/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.05925v1/extracted/5667060/images/n-tokens-articles.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper presents a study on the development of an HR support chatbot using Large Language Models (LLMs) with a human-in-the-loop approach. The chatbot was developed in collaboration with SAP SE to address employee inquiries efficiently and effectively. The study focuses on enhancing the chatbot’s response quality and exploring alternative retrieval methods. The experiments and evaluation conclude that GPT-4 outperforms other models and can overcome inconsistencies in data through internal reasoning capabilities. Additionally, reference-free evaluation metrics such as G-Eval and Prometheus demonstrate reliability closely aligned with human evaluation.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) approach was used to develop the HR chatbot, allowing the model to produce more grounded answers and reducing hallucinations.</li>
<li>The study optimized different modules of the standard RAG pipeline, such as the retriever and model prompts, while constantly incorporating feedback from domain experts.</li>
<li>The experiments benchmarked OpenAI’s models and used the open-source LongT5 and BERT as baselines. The findings related to the retriever and the reliability of automatic evaluation metrics can benefit both the industry and the research community.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper does not provide a detailed description of the methodology used for prompt optimization and evaluation, which could be essential for reproducibility and further research.</li>
<li>The study does not discuss the limitations of using LLMs for HR support, such as potential biases in the generated responses or the need for continuous updates to keep up with changing HR policies.</li>
<li>The paper does not address the potential privacy concerns related to using LLMs for HR support, as these models may require access to sensitive employee data.</li>
<li>The study does not explore the potential of using other LLMs or hybrid models that combine the strengths of different models to improve the chatbot’s performance further.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the scalability and generalizability of the proposed approach to other domains or industries, which could be an essential aspect of its practical applicability.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-09</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.05925v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.05925v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.05925v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.05925v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6545</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Towards_Optimizing_and_Evaluating_a_Retrieval_Augmented_QA_Chatbot_using_LLMs_with_Human_in_the_Loop/2024-07-08-Towards_Optimizing_and_Evaluating_a_Retrieval_Augmented_QA_Chatbot_using_LLMs_with_Human_in_the_Loop.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.05925v1/extracted/5667060/images/n-tokens-articles.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Using Grammar Masking to Ensure Syntactic Validity in LLM-based Modeling Tasks</title>
  <dc:creator>Lukas Netz, Jan Reimar, Bernhard Rumpe</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Using_Grammar_Masking_to_Ensure_Syntactic_Validity_in_LLM_based_Modeling_Tasks/2024-07-08-Using_Grammar_Masking_to_Ensure_Syntactic_Validity_in_LLM_based_Modeling_Tasks.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.06146v1/extracted/5717365/img/FSL.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper presents a method called grammar masking, which is used to guide large language models (LLMs) toward producing syntactically correct models for a given context-free grammar. The authors evaluate this method by comparing it to previous successful modeling tasks for LLMs using only few-shot learning. The study focuses on the syntactic correctness of the models produced by the LLM and evaluates two approaches: one that only uses FSL and one that combines FSL with grammar masking. The results indicate that the constrained generation method significantly increases the percentage of syntactically correct outputs, but this improvement comes at the cost of increased generation time.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The constrained generation method significantly increases the percentage of syntactically correct outputs from 46.52% to 92.63% (Llama 3).</li>
<li>This improvement comes at the cost of increased generation time, with constrained generation taking an average of 74.09 seconds compared to 5.71 seconds for unconstrained generation.</li>
<li>Similar results are observed for other LLMs, with constrained generation producing a higher percentage of syntactically correct outputs than unconstrained generation.</li>
<li>The study also shows that the constrained generation method is more effective for the Class Diagram DSL CD4A than for the Structured English DSL SEN.</li>
<li>The results do not show the best possible modeling capabilities of the individual models, as the few-shot learning prompting was not optimized intensively.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The study does not address the semantic accuracy of the generated models, which is an important aspect of model-driven software engineering.</li>
<li>The study does not consider the impact of the increased generation time on the overall performance of the modeling process.</li>
<li>The study does not discuss the potential limitations of the grammar masking method, such as the need for a well-defined grammar and the potential for overfitting to the training data.</li>
<li>The study does not compare the performance of the grammar masking method to other methods for guiding LLMs, such as fine-tuning or prompt engineering.</li>
<li>The study does not discuss the potential applications of the grammar masking method beyond model-driven software</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-09</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.06146v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.06146v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.06146v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.06146v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6526</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Using_Grammar_Masking_to_Ensure_Syntactic_Validity_in_LLM_based_Modeling_Tasks/2024-07-08-Using_Grammar_Masking_to_Ensure_Syntactic_Validity_in_LLM_based_Modeling_Tasks.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.06146v1/extracted/5717365/img/FSL.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Retrieved In-Context Principles from Previous Mistakes</title>
  <dc:creator>Hao Sun, Yong Jiang, Bo Wang, Yingyan Hou, Yan Zhang, Pengjun Xie, Fei Huang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Retrieved_In_Context_Principles_from_Previous_Mistakes/2024-07-08-Retrieved_In_Context_Principles_from_Previous_Mistakes.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Retrieved_In_Context_Principles_from_Previous_Mistakes/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.05682v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper introduces a novel approach called Retrieved In-Context Principles (RICP), a teacher-student framework designed to improve the performance of large language models (LLMs) by learning from mistakes. RICP generates principles based on the student’s observed mistakes, which the student then applies to prevent the recurrence of similar mistakes. The method involves three stages: Insight Generation, Principle Formulation, and Principle Utilization. RICP significantly enhances the customization and error coverage of principles by providing both question-level and task-level principles. Extensive experiments on seven benchmarks across three reasoning tasks with various LLMs demonstrate that RICP consistently enhances model performance.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>RICP is a novel teacher-student framework that utilizes teacher-generated principles to prevent the student from making similar mistakes.</li>
<li>RICP significantly enhances the customization and error coverage of principles by providing both question-level and task-level principles.</li>
<li>Extensive experiments on seven benchmarks across three reasoning tasks with various LLMs demonstrate that RICP consistently enhances model performance.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential limitations of the RICP approach, such as the requirement for a significantly more advanced teacher model than the student model and the overhead associated with the principle generation process.</li>
<li>The paper does not provide a detailed comparison of RICP with other existing methods that utilize mistakes to improve the performance of LLMs.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential ethical implications of the proposed method, such as the potential for the method to be used to generate misleading or harmful content.</li>
<li>The paper does not provide a detailed analysis of the computational complexity of the RICP approach, which is an important factor to consider when evaluating the practicality of the method.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential impact of the RICP approach on the interpretability of the LLMs, which is an important consideration in the development of AI systems.</li>
<li>The paper does not provide a detailed analysis of the potential biases that may be introduced by the RICP approach, which is an important consideration in the development of AI systems.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-09</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.05682v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.05682v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.05682v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.05682v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5199</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Retrieved_In_Context_Principles_from_Previous_Mistakes/2024-07-08-Retrieved_In_Context_Principles_from_Previous_Mistakes.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.05682v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>LLM-Based Open-Domain Integrated Task and Knowledge Assistants with Programmable Policies</title>
  <dc:creator>Harshit Joshi, Shicheng Liu, James Chen, Robert Weigle, Monica S. Lam</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLM_Based_Open_Domain_Integrated_Task_and_Knowledge_Assistants_with_Programmable_Policies/2024-07-08-LLM_Based_Open_Domain_Integrated_Task_and_Knowledge_Assistants_with_Programmable_Policies.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLM_Based_Open_Domain_Integrated_Task_and_Knowledge_Assistants_with_Programmable_Policies/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.05674v1/x2.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary:</strong></p>
<p>The paper presents KITA, a programmable framework for creating task-oriented conversational agents that can handle complex user interactions. Unlike traditional dialogue trees, KITA provides reliable grounded responses and controllable agent policies through its expressive specification, KITA Worksheet. The authors conducted a real-user study involving 62 participants, demonstrating that KITA outperforms the GPT-4 with function calling baseline by 26.1, 22.5, and 52.4 points on execution accuracy, dialogue act accuracy, and goal completion rate, respectively.</p>
<p><strong>Major Findings:</strong></p>
<ol type="1">
<li>KITA provides reliable grounded responses and controllable agent policies through its expressive specification, KITA Worksheet.</li>
<li>KITA outperforms the GPT-4 with function calling baseline in a real-user study involving 62 participants.</li>
<li>KITA supports full compositionality of tasks and knowledge queries.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></p>
<p>The paper presents a novel approach to creating task-oriented conversational agents that can handle complex user interactions. The use of KITA Worksheet as an expressive specification for agent policies is a significant contribution, as it allows for more control and flexibility in designing conversational agents. The real-user study demonstrates the effectiveness of KITA in handling complex user interactions and outperforming existing methods.</p>
<p>However, the paper does not provide a detailed comparison with other programmable frameworks for creating task-oriented conversational agents. Additionally, the authors do not discuss the limitations of KITA or potential biases that may arise from using the framework. The paper also does not provide a clear explanation of how KITA handles ambiguity in user inputs or how it adapts to changes in user behavior over time.</p>
<p>Overall, the paper presents a promising approach to creating task-oriented conversational agents that can handle complex user interactions. However, further research is needed to compare KITA with other programmable frameworks and to address potential limitations and biases in the framework.</p>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-09</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.05674v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.05674v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.05674v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.05674v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>23690</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLM_Based_Open_Domain_Integrated_Task_and_Knowledge_Assistants_with_Programmable_Policies/2024-07-08-LLM_Based_Open_Domain_Integrated_Task_and_Knowledge_Assistants_with_Programmable_Policies.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.05674v1/x2.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Generative Debunking of Climate Misinformation</title>
  <dc:creator>Francisco Zanartu, Yulia Otmakhova, John Cook, Lea Frermann</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Generative_Debunking_of_Climate_Misinformation/2024-07-08-Generative_Debunking_of_Climate_Misinformation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Generative_Debunking_of_Climate_Misinformation/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.05599v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level1">
<h1>Summary:</h1>
<p>The study presents an approach called generative debunking, which combines generative AI with past research on climate contrarian claim classification and fallacy detection. The goal is to automatically detect and correct climate misinformation at scale. The authors build upon the CARDS classifier and the FLICC model to develop a system that produces structured and psychologically grounded “truth sandwich” debunkings. The system is tested with three unique combinations of prompting strategies and large language models (LLMs) of different sizes. The results reveal promising performance of GPT-4 and Mixtral when combined with structured prompts. However, the study also identifies specific challenges, such as a lack of factuality and relevancy, even with the latest LLMs.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level1">
<h1>Major Findings:</h1>
<ol type="1">
<li>The generative debunking approach adopts elements of the 4D framework, which involves detecting, deconstructing, debunking, and deploying corrective interventions.</li>
<li>The study combines open (Mixtral, Palm2) and proprietary (GPT-4) LLMs with prompting strategies of varying complexity to produce structured and psychologically grounded “truth sandwich” debunkings.</li>
<li>Experiments reveal promising performance of GPT-4 and Mixtral when combined with structured prompts.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level1">
<h1>Analysis and Critique:</h1>
<ol type="1">
<li>The study identifies specific challenges of debunking generation and human evaluation, such as a lack of factuality and relevancy, even with the latest LLMs.</li>
<li>The authors acknowledge that their system is not currently fit for broader deployment and that a more thorough evaluation is needed in future work.</li>
<li>The study does not systematically study the impact of individual prompt design decisions, nor does it exhaustively combine all prompts with all LLMs.</li>
<li>The authors did not evaluate their current models’ abilities to distinguish input myths from fact, which is outside the scope of this study.</li>
<li>The study was supported by the Melbourne Center of AI and Digital Ethics and the Australian Research Council Discovery Early Career Research Award.</li>
</ol>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-09</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.05599v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.05599v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.05599v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.05599v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6823</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Generative_Debunking_of_Climate_Misinformation/2024-07-08-Generative_Debunking_of_Climate_Misinformation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.05599v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Merge, Ensemble, and Cooperate! A Survey on Collaborative Strategies in the Era of Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Jinliang Lu, Ziliang Pang, Min Xiao, Yaochen Zhu, Rui Xia, Jiajun Zhang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Merge_Ensemble_and_Cooperate!_A_Survey_on_Collaborative_Strategies_in_the_Era_of_Large_Language_Models/2024-07-08-Merge_Ensemble_and_Cooperate!_A_Survey_on_Collaborative_Strategies_in_the_Era_of_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Merge_Ensemble_and_Cooperate!_A_Survey_on_Collaborative_Strategies_in_the_Era_of_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.06089v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level1">
<h1>Summary</h1>
<p>The paper “Merge, Ensemble, and Cooperate! A Survey on Collaborative Strategies in the Era of Large Language Models” provides a comprehensive overview of the emerging research area of collaboration strategies for Large Language Models (LLMs). The authors categorize these strategies into three primary approaches: Merging, Ensemble, and Cooperation.</p>
<p>Merging involves integrating multiple LLMs in the parameter space, while Ensemble combines the outputs of various LLMs. Cooperation leverages different LLMs to allow full play to their diverse capabilities for specific tasks. The paper discusses the potential applications of these methods and outlines future research directions.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li><p><strong>Merging</strong>: This approach integrates the parameters of multiple LLMs into a single, unified model, requiring that the parameters are compatible within a linear space. Merging methods are tailored to be more suitable for LLMs, effectively leveraging the collaborative advantages of diverse LLMs.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Ensemble</strong>: Ensemble methods focus on combining the outputs generated by various LLMs to produce coherent results, with less emphasis on the parameters of the individual models. These methods are derived from traditional fusion techniques commonly explored in machine learning.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Cooperation</strong>: Cooperation extends beyond merging and ensemble, focusing on cooperative methods that harness the diverse strengths of LLMs to achieve specific objectives. These techniques expand the methodologies for model collaboration, holding significant research importance for LLMs.</p></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique</h2>
<p>The paper provides a well-structured and coherent summary of the emerging research area of collaboration strategies for LLMs. The authors’ categorization of these strategies into Merging, Ensemble, and Cooperation offers a clear understanding of their respective frameworks and applications.</p>
<p>However, the paper does not discuss the potential limitations, unanswered questions, or biases that may be apparent while reviewing the text. Additionally, the paper does not address any methodological issues, conflicting evidence, or areas that require further research or clarification.</p>
<p>In conclusion, the paper serves as a valuable resource for understanding the strategies and methodologies for collaborative efforts among LLMs. However, it would benefit from a more critical analysis of the discussed topics, addressing potential limitations and areas for further research.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-09</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.06089v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.06089v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.06089v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.06089v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>14228</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Merge_Ensemble_and_Cooperate!_A_Survey_on_Collaborative_Strategies_in_the_Era_of_Large_Language_Models/2024-07-08-Merge_Ensemble_and_Cooperate!_A_Survey_on_Collaborative_Strategies_in_the_Era_of_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.06089v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>What’s Wrong with Your Code Generated by Large Language Models? An Extensive Study</title>
  <dc:creator>Shihan Dou, Haoxiang Jia, Shenxi Wu, Huiyuan Zheng, Weikang Zhou, Muling Wu, Mingxu Chai, Jessica Fan, Caishuang Huang, Yunbo Tao, Yan Liu, Enyu Zhou, Ming Zhang, Yuhao Zhou, Yueming Wu, Rui Zheng, Ming Wen, Rongxiang Weng, Jingang Wang, Xunliang Cai, Tao Gui, Xipeng Qiu, Qi Zhang, Xuanjing Huang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Whats_Wrong_with_Your_Code_Generated_by_Large_Language_Models_An_Extensive_Study/2024-07-08-Whats_Wrong_with_Your_Code_Generated_by_Large_Language_Models_An_Extensive_Study.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Whats_Wrong_with_Your_Code_Generated_by_Large_Language_Models_An_Extensive_Study/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.06153v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>This paper presents a comprehensive empirical study on the effectiveness and limitations of code generation using large language models (LLMs). The study evaluates seven widely-used LLMs across three popular benchmarks and reveals that these models struggle to generate accurate code for more complex problems. The authors manually annotate bug types in the generated code, construct a taxonomy of these bugs, analyze their distributions, and summarize 14 findings that lead to the generation of erroneous code.</p>
<p>To evaluate the effectiveness of LLMs in real-world projects, the authors design a rigorous benchmark construction process to minimize data leakage and create a real-world project benchmark called RWPB. Additionally, the paper proposes a novel method that introduces self-critique, allowing LLMs to iteratively critique their generated codes and fix bugs.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs face challenges in generating successful code for more complex problems and tend to produce code that is shorter yet more complicated compared to canonical solutions.</li>
<li>The study develops a taxonomy of bugs for incorrect codes, including three categories and 12 sub-categories, and analyzes the root cause for common bug types.</li>
<li>The authors propose a novel training-free iterative method that introduces self-critique, enabling LLMs to critique and correct their generated code based on bug types and compiler feedback.</li>
<li>Experimental results demonstrate that the proposed approach can significantly mitigate bugs and increase the passing rate by 29.2% after two iterations, indicating substantial potential for LLMs to handle more complex problems.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The paper provides a thorough evaluation of LLMs in code generation and offers valuable insights into their limitations and potential areas for improvement. However, the study could benefit from a more in-depth analysis of the impact of different training methods and hyperparameters on the performance of LLMs in code generation tasks. Additionally, the authors could explore the potential of using more diverse and complex benchmarks to further evaluate the capabilities of LLMs in handling real-world code generation challenges.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-09</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.06153v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.06153v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.06153v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.06153v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>14163</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Whats_Wrong_with_Your_Code_Generated_by_Large_Language_Models_An_Extensive_Study/2024-07-08-Whats_Wrong_with_Your_Code_Generated_by_Large_Language_Models_An_Extensive_Study.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.06153v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>LLaMAX: Scaling Linguistic Horizons of LLM by Enhancing Translation Capabilities Beyond 100 Languages</title>
  <dc:creator>Yinquan Lu, Wenhao Zhu, Lei Li, Yu Qiao, Fei Yuan</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLaMAX_Scaling_Linguistic_Horizons_of_LLM_by_Enhancing_Translation_Capabilities_Beyond_100_Languages/2024-07-08-LLaMAX_Scaling_Linguistic_Horizons_of_LLM_by_Enhancing_Translation_Capabilities_Beyond_100_Languages.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLaMAX_Scaling_Linguistic_Horizons_of_LLM_by_Enhancing_Translation_Capabilities_Beyond_100_Languages/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.05975v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper presents LLaMAX, a series of open-sourced models that enhance the translation performance of the LLaMA series models across more than 100 languages. The authors conduct a comprehensive analysis of key techniques in multilingual continual pre-training, including vocabulary extension and data augmentation. The LLaMAX2 model, trained over 60 days using 24 A100 GPUs, significantly enhances translation capabilities and achieves comparable performance to the specialized translation model M2M-100-12B on the Flores-101 benchmark. The paper also provides extensive experiments on key technique design, comprehensive translation benchmark evaluation across various models, general task testing, and supervised fine-tuning on task-specific data, demonstrating the superiority of LLaMAX.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The LLaMAX series models enhance the translation performance of the LLaMA series models across more than 100 languages.</li>
<li>The LLaMAX2 model, trained over 60 days using 24 A100 GPUs, significantly enhances translation capabilities and achieves comparable performance to the specialized translation model M2M-100-12B on the Flores-101 benchmark.</li>
<li>The LLaMAX2 model demonstrates an average improvement of more than 10 spBLEU compared to baseline models in low-resource-centric translation.</li>
<li>The LLaMAX2 model shows significant performance enhancements even for languages not included in the training set when evaluated on Flores-200.</li>
<li>Enhancing translation capabilities also establishes a robust multilingual base model foundation, with an average improvement of 5 points over LLaMA2 on X-CSQA, XNLI, and MGSM tasks.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The paper presents a significant contribution to the field of multilingual translation by introducing the LLaMAX series models, which enhance the translation performance of the LLaMA series models across more than 100 languages. The authors provide a comprehensive analysis of key techniques in multilingual continual pre-training, including vocabulary extension and data augmentation. The LLaMAX2 model, trained over 60 days using 24 A</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-09</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.05975v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.05975v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.05975v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.05975v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>10244</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLaMAX_Scaling_Linguistic_Horizons_of_LLM_by_Enhancing_Translation_Capabilities_Beyond_100_Languages/2024-07-08-LLaMAX_Scaling_Linguistic_Horizons_of_LLM_by_Enhancing_Translation_Capabilities_Beyond_100_Languages.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.05975v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Distilling System 2 into System 1</title>
  <dc:creator>Ping Yu, Jing Xu, Jason Weston, Ilia Kulikov</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Distilling_System_2_into_System_1/2024-07-08-Distilling_System_2_into_System_1.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Distilling_System_2_into_System_1/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.06023v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>This paper explores the concept of “System 2 distillation” in large language models (LLMs), which involves transferring higher quality outputs from System 2 techniques (methods that generate intermediate tokens for reasoning) back into LLM generations without intermediate reasoning token sequences. The authors propose a self-supervised method to “compile” (distill) System 2 techniques into System 1, resulting in improved results compared to the original System 1 performance and with less inference cost than System 2. The authors posit that System 2 distillation will be an important feature of future continually learning AI systems, enabling them to focus System 2 capabilities on reasoning tasks that they cannot yet do well.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The authors propose a self-supervised method to distill System 2 techniques into System 1, resulting in improved results compared to the original System 1 performance and with less inference cost than System 2.</li>
<li>The authors show that several System 2 techniques can be successfully distilled, including Chain-of-Thought, Rephrase and Respond, System 2 Attention, and Branch-Solve-Merge.</li>
<li>The authors posit that System 2 distillation will be an important feature of future continually learning AI systems, enabling them to focus System 2 capabilities on reasoning tasks that they cannot yet do well.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The authors do not provide a comprehensive evaluation of the proposed method, and it is unclear how well it performs compared to other distillation methods.</li>
<li>The authors do not discuss the limitations of their proposed method, such as the potential for overfitting or the need for large amounts of data.</li>
<li>The authors do not provide a clear definition of what constitutes a “higher quality” output, and it is unclear how this is measured.</li>
<li>The authors do not discuss the potential ethical implications of using System 2 distillation, such as the potential for bias or the need for transparency.</li>
<li>The authors do not discuss the potential impact of System 2 distillation on the development of AI systems, such as the potential for increased automation or the need for new forms of human-AI collaboration.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-09</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.06023v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.06023v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.06023v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.06023v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8154</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Distilling_System_2_into_System_1/2024-07-08-Distilling_System_2_into_System_1.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.06023v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>ANOLE: An Open, Autoregressive, Native Large Multimodal Models for Interleaved Image-Text Generation</title>
  <dc:creator>Ethan Chern, Jiadi Su, Yan Ma, Pengfei Liu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ANOLE_An_Open_Autoregressive_Native_Large_Multimodal_Models_for_Interleaved_Image_Text_Generation/2024-07-08-ANOLE_An_Open_Autoregressive_Native_Large_Multimodal_Models_for_Interleaved_Image_Text_Generation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ANOLE_An_Open_Autoregressive_Native_Large_Multimodal_Models_for_Interleaved_Image_Text_Generation/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.06135v1/x2.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>Anole is an open, autoregressive, native large multimodal model for interleaved image-text generation. It is built on top of Chameleon, a model developed by Meta AI, and adopts an innovative fine-tuning strategy that is both data-efficient and parameter-efficient. Anole demonstrates high-quality, coherent multimodal generation capabilities and has been open-sourced along with its training framework and instruction tuning data.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Full Open-Source Implementation</strong>: Anole has facilitated the vision and multimodal generation capabilities from Chameleon through an innovative fine-tuning approach, unlocking the model’s most crucial technological aspects. This comprehensive open-source release allows researchers and developers to fully utilize and build upon it.</li>
<li><strong>Data and Parameter Efficient Fine-Tuning</strong>: Anole’s method fine-tunes fewer than 40M parameters, requiring only about 6,000 samples to effectively facilitate vision and multimodal generation capabilities. This demonstrates a highly efficient approach to facilitate complex functionality in LMMs.</li>
<li><strong>Training, Multimodal Inference, and Qualitative Evaluation</strong>: Anole provides a training and multimodal inference framework for unified tokenizer-based multimodal models. This infrastructure significantly lowers the barrier to entry for developing and experimenting with autoregressive LMMs, making it accessible to a wider range of researchers.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Anole’s open-source nature and its ability to generate high-quality, coherent interleaved image-text sequences are significant contributions to the field of multimodal AI.</li>
<li>The innovative fine-tuning strategy used by Anole is both data-efficient and parameter-efficient, making it a highly efficient approach for facilitating complex functionality in LMMs.</li>
<li>However, Anole’s image generation capabilities have not been aligned to ensure safety and harmlessness. This is a critical issue that needs to be addressed to ensure the ethical use of generated images.</li>
<li>The model is still under development and has many limitations that need to be addressed, including enhancing its precise instruction-following capability, extending its context length, and improving its multimod</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-09</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.06135v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.06135v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.06135v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.06135v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>3311</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ANOLE_An_Open_Autoregressive_Native_Large_Multimodal_Models_for_Interleaved_Image_Text_Generation/2024-07-08-ANOLE_An_Open_Autoregressive_Native_Large_Multimodal_Models_for_Interleaved_Image_Text_Generation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.06135v1/x2.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Generation and De-Identification of Indian Clinical Discharge Summaries using LLMs</title>
  <dc:creator>Sanjeet Singh, Shreya Gupta, Niralee Gupta, Naimish Sharma, Lokesh Srivastava, Vibhu Agarwal, Ashutosh Modi</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Generation_and_De_Identification_of_Indian_Clinical_Discharge_Summaries_using_LLMs/2024-07-08-Generation_and_De_Identification_of_Indian_Clinical_Discharge_Summaries_using_LLMs.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Generation_and_De_Identification_of_Indian_Clinical_Discharge_Summaries_using_LLMs/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.05887v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper discusses the importance of data de-identification in healthcare, particularly in India, where rapid digitization is taking place. The authors highlight the risks of revealing patient identity even from anonymized data and the need for a robust data de-identification pipeline. They evaluate the performance of existing de-identification methods, including NLP-based methods, on a dataset of 99 de-identified discharge summaries from an Indian hospital. The results show poor cross-institutional performance of these methods. To overcome the data scarcity, the authors explore generating synthetic clinical reports using LLMs and evaluate their use in creating high-performing de-identification systems with good generalization capabilities.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Existing de-identification methods, including NLP-based methods, perform poorly when evaluated on data from a different institution compared to the one that contributed the training data.</li>
<li>The study introduces a new dataset (Indian Clinical Discharge Summaries) obtained from an Indian hospital and evaluates the performance of the PI-RoBERTa model on this dataset for the task of de-identification. The results show poor cross-institutional performance.</li>
<li>To overcome data scarcity, the authors explore generating synthetic clinical reports using LLMs and evaluate their use in creating high-performing de-identification systems with good generalization capabilities.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The paper provides a valuable contribution to the field of data de-identification in healthcare, particularly in the context of India. The authors highlight the importance of a robust data de-identification pipeline and the risks associated with revealing patient identity even from anonymized data. The evaluation of existing de-identification methods on a dataset of 99 de-identified discharge summaries from an Indian hospital is a significant contribution to the field. However, the study is limited by the small size of the dataset, which may not be representative of the broader population. The use of LLMs to generate synthetic clinical reports is a promising approach to overcome data scarcity, but the authors do not provide a detailed evaluation of the quality of the generated reports. Additionally, the study does not discuss the potential ethical implications of using LLMs to generate synthetic clinical reports. Overall, the paper provides a valuable contribution to the field of data de-identification in healthcare</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-09</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.05887v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.05887v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.05887v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.05887v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>9455</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Generation_and_De_Identification_of_Indian_Clinical_Discharge_Summaries_using_LLMs/2024-07-08-Generation_and_De_Identification_of_Indian_Clinical_Discharge_Summaries_using_LLMs.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.05887v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>HyCIR: Boosting Zero-Shot Composed Image Retrieval with Synthetic Labels</title>
  <dc:creator>Yingying Jiang, Hanchao Jia, Xiaobing Wang, Peng Hao</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/HyCIR_Boosting_Zero_Shot_Composed_Image_Retrieval_with_Synthetic_Labels/2024-07-08-HyCIR_Boosting_Zero_Shot_Composed_Image_Retrieval_with_Synthetic_Labels.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2407.05795v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper proposes a novel approach called Hybrid CIR (HyCIR) to improve the performance of Zero-Shot Composed Image Retrieval (ZS-CIR) by using synthetic labels. The authors introduce a new label synthesis pipeline, SynCir, which generates synthetic labels for CIR using unlabeled images. SynCir consists of three steps: image pair extraction, label generation, and data filter. The proposed hybrid training strategy combines contrastive learning for ZS-CIR with large-scale unlabeled images and contrastive learning with synthetic CIR triplets. The experiments conducted on common CIR benchmarks, CIRR and CIRCO, demonstrate that the proposed solution achieves state-of-the-art zero-shot performance.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The proposed Hybrid CIR (HyCIR) approach uses synthetic labels to boost the performance of ZS-CIR with a hybrid training strategy.</li>
<li>A new pipeline, SynCir, is proposed to generate labels for CIR, which consists of image pair extraction, label generation, and data filter. SynCir can generate diverse labels from unlabeled images, making it easy to scale up to more data.</li>
<li>The hybrid training strategy introduced in this work combines contrastive learning for ZS-CIR with large-scale unlabeled images and contrastive learning with synthetic CIR triplets.</li>
<li>The proposed solution achieves state-of-the-art zero-shot performance on CIRR test set (R@5: 69.03%) and CIRCO test set (mAP@5: 18.91%).</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The paper presents a promising approach to improve the performance of ZS-CIR by using synthetic labels. The proposed HyCIR approach and the SynCir pipeline are well-designed and demonstrate significant improvements in the performance of ZS-CIR. However, there are a few potential limitations and areas for improvement:</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>The quality of the synthetic labels generated by SynCir may impact the performance of ZS-CIR. The authors acknowledge this limitation and suggest using stronger models and enhanced data filter in the data synthesis pipeline to improve the quality of synthetic labels.</li>
<li>The proposed approach has only been evaluated on</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-09</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.05795v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.05795v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.05795v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.05795v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>10950</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/HyCIR_Boosting_Zero_Shot_Composed_Image_Retrieval_with_Synthetic_Labels/2024-07-08-HyCIR_Boosting_Zero_Shot_Composed_Image_Retrieval_with_Synthetic_Labels.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2407.05795v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Enhancing Language Model Rationality with Bi-Directional Deliberation Reasoning</title>
  <dc:creator>Yadong Zhang, Shaoguang Mao, Wenshan Wu, Yan Xia, Tao Ge, Man Lan, Furu Wei</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Enhancing_Language_Model_Rationality_with_Bi_Directional_Deliberation_Reasoning/2024-07-08-Enhancing_Language_Model_Rationality_with_Bi_Directional_Deliberation_Reasoning.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Enhancing_Language_Model_Rationality_with_Bi_Directional_Deliberation_Reasoning/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.06112v1/extracted/5711539/figure/bi-directional_reasoning.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper introduces BI-Directional DEliberation Reasoning (BIDDER), a novel reasoning approach designed to enhance the decision-making capabilities of large language models (LLMs). Unlike traditional unidirectional reasoning methods, BIDDER incorporates principles of rational decision-making, such as managing uncertainty and predicting expected utility. The approach involves three key processes: inferring hidden states from historical data, using these hidden states to predict future potential states and outcomes, and integrating historical information and long-term outcomes to inform reasoning. BIDDER’s effectiveness was tested in two well-defined scenarios: Poker (Limit Texas Hold’em) and Negotiation. The experiments demonstrated that BIDDER significantly improves the decision-making capabilities of LLMs and LLM agents.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>BIDDER is a novel reasoning approach that enhances the decision-making capabilities of LLMs by incorporating principles of rational decision-making, such as managing uncertainty and predicting expected utility.</li>
<li>BIDDER involves three key processes: inferring hidden states from historical data, using these hidden states to predict future potential states and outcomes, and integrating historical information and long-term outcomes to inform reasoning.</li>
<li>BIDDER’s effectiveness was tested in two well-defined scenarios: Poker (Limit Texas Hold’em) and Negotiation. The experiments demonstrated that BIDDER significantly improves the decision-making capabilities of LLMs and LLM agents.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>While BIDDER shows promise in enhancing the decision-making capabilities of LLMs, there are several potential limitations and areas for further research.</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>The effectiveness of BIDDER may be dependent on the quality and quantity of historical data available. In scenarios with limited historical data, BIDDER’s ability to infer hidden states and predict future outcomes may be compromised.</li>
<li>The integration of historical information and long-term outcomes to inform reasoning may be computationally intensive, potentially limiting the scalability of BIDDER in complex decision-making scenarios.</li>
<li>The experiments conducted in the paper are limited to two well-defined scenarios. Further research is needed to evaluate the effectiveness of BIDDER in a wider range of decision-making scenarios.</li>
<li>The paper does not provide a detailed comparison of B</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-09</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.06112v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.06112v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.06112v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.06112v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5655</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Enhancing_Language_Model_Rationality_with_Bi_Directional_Deliberation_Reasoning/2024-07-08-Enhancing_Language_Model_Rationality_with_Bi_Directional_Deliberation_Reasoning.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.06112v1/extracted/5711539/figure/bi-directional_reasoning.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>iLLM-TSC: Integration reinforcement learning and large language model for traffic signal control policy improvement</title>
  <dc:creator>Aoyu Pang, Maonan Wang, Man-On Pun, Chung Shue Chen, Xi Xiong</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/iLLM_TSC_Integration_reinforcement_learning_and_large_language_model_for_traffic_signal_control_policy_improvement/2024-07-08-iLLM_TSC_Integration_reinforcement_learning_and_large_language_model_for_traffic_signal_control_policy_improvement.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/iLLM_TSC_Integration_reinforcement_learning_and_large_language_model_for_traffic_signal_control_policy_improvement/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.06025v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary:</strong></p>
<p>The paper introduces a novel integration framework, iLLM-TSC, which combines a large language model (LLM) with reinforcement learning (RL) to address the limitations of existing RL-based traffic signal control (TSC) systems. These limitations include imperfect observations caused by degraded communication and the absence of rare real-life events in the reward function, such as unconsidered emergency vehicles. The iLLM-TSC framework allows RL agents to make initial decisions based on observed data, leveraging their ability to learn from specific environments. Subsequently, the LLM model refines these decisions by incorporating additional real-time information not initially used by the RL agents. This integration approach can be seamlessly integrated with existing RL-based TSC systems without requiring modifications. Extensive testing confirms that the iLLM-TSC approach reduces the average waiting time by 17.5% in degraded communication conditions compared to traditional RL methods.</p>
<p><strong>Major Findings:</strong></p>
<ol type="1">
<li>The iLLM-TSC framework integrates RL with LLMs to enhance TSC, employing a dual-step decision-making process where RL agents initially make decisions based on direct observations, and then LLM agents evaluate these decisions considering the broader environmental context.</li>
<li>The iLLM-TSC framework significantly reduces the average waiting time by 17.5% in degraded communication scenarios compared to traditional RL methods, highlighting the enhanced scene comprehension capabilities of LLMs tailored specifically for TSC applications.</li>
<li>The iLLM-TSC framework can be seamlessly integrated with existing RL-based TSC systems without requiring modifications.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></p>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper effectively addresses the limitations of existing RL-based TSC systems by integrating LLMs to handle overlooked elements in the reward function and gaps in state information.</li>
<li>The iLLM-TSC framework demonstrates promising results in reducing average waiting times in degraded communication scenarios, but further research is needed to evaluate its performance in other challenging traffic conditions.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss potential limitations or unanswered questions, such as the computational requirements of the iLLM-TSC framework or its scalability to larger traffic networks.</li>
<li>The paper does not provide</li>
</ol>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-09</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.06025v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.06025v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.06025v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.06025v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8535</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/iLLM_TSC_Integration_reinforcement_learning_and_large_language_model_for_traffic_signal_control_policy_improvement/2024-07-08-iLLM_TSC_Integration_reinforcement_learning_and_large_language_model_for_traffic_signal_control_policy_improvement.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.06025v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Depression Detection and Analysis using Large Language Models on Textual and Audio-Visual Modalities</title>
  <dc:creator>Avinash Anand, Chayan Tank, Sarthak Pol, Vinayak Katoch, Shaina Mehta, Rajiv Ratn Shah</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Depression_Detection_and_Analysis_using_Large_Language_Models_on_Textual_and_Audio_Visual_Modalities/2024-07-08-Depression_Detection_and_Analysis_using_Large_Language_Models_on_Textual_and_Audio_Visual_Modalities.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Depression_Detection_and_Analysis_using_Large_Language_Models_on_Textual_and_Audio_Visual_Modalities/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.06125v1/extracted/5715821/net_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper presents a study on depression detection and analysis using large language models (LLMs) on textual and audio-visual modalities. The authors highlight the significance of depression as a global health issue and the challenges in its diagnosis and treatment. They propose a multi-modal architecture that utilizes behavioral clues for more effective depression detection, marking a significant advancement in mental health diagnostics.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The proposed textual network and audio-visual network, which predict the PHQ-8 scores of patients using their audio, visual, and textual clues, demonstrate better results than the AVEC 2019 challenge baseline results and current SOTA regression analysis architectures.</li>
<li>The proposed solution achieved a Root Mean Square Error (RMSE) score of 3.98 on Textual Modality and an accuracy of 71.43% in the classification task.</li>
<li>The paper also includes a novel audio-visual multi-modal network that predicts PHQ-8 scores with an RMSE of 6.51.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The paper presents an innovative approach to depression detection and analysis using LLMs on textual and audio-visual modalities. The proposed multi-modal architecture shows promising results, outperforming the AVEC 2019 challenge baseline results and current SOTA regression analysis architectures. However, the study has some limitations, such as the potential biases in the dataset and the need for further research to overcome these limitations. Additionally, the paper does not discuss the generalizability of the proposed approach to other mental health disorders or its applicability in real-world clinical settings. Further research is needed to address these issues and validate the proposed approach in diverse populations and clinical contexts.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-09</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.06125v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.06125v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.06125v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.06125v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>9401</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Depression_Detection_and_Analysis_using_Large_Language_Models_on_Textual_and_Audio_Visual_Modalities/2024-07-08-Depression_Detection_and_Analysis_using_Large_Language_Models_on_Textual_and_Audio_Visual_Modalities.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.06125v1/extracted/5715821/net_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Is GPT-4 Alone Sufficient for Automated Essay Scoring?: A Comparative Judgment Approach Based on Rater Cognition</title>
  <dc:creator>Seungju Kim, Meounggun Jo</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Is_GPT_4_Alone_Sufficient_for_Automated_Essay_Scoring_A_Comparative_Judgment_Approach_Based_on_Rater_Cognition/2024-07-08-Is_GPT_4_Alone_Sufficient_for_Automated_Essay_Scoring_A_Comparative_Judgment_Approach_Based_on_Rater_Cognition.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Is_GPT_4_Alone_Sufficient_for_Automated_Essay_Scoring_A_Comparative_Judgment_Approach_Based_on_Rater_Cognition/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.05733v1/x2.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>This study explores a novel approach to utilizing Large Language Models (LLMs) for Automated Essay Scoring (AES) by employing Comparative Judgment (CJ). The proposed method prompts LLMs to choose the better essay between two given essays without any additional training, using only zero-shot prompting. The research aims to address four main questions:</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>When using a rubric-based scoring strategy, will the GPT-4 model be able to better imitate human-rater scores compared to the GPT-3.5 model?</li>
<li>When using a rubric-based scoring strategy, will GPT models be able to better imitate human rater’s scores if an elaborated scoring rubric with descriptors is used?</li>
<li>When using a CJ-based scoring strategy, will the GPT model be able to better imitate human rater scores compared to the rubric-based scoring strategy?</li>
<li>When using a CJ-based scoring strategy and utilizing fine-grained scores, will GPT models be able to better imitate human rater scores?</li>
</ol>
<p>The study uses essay sets 7 and 8 from the ASAP dataset, which include multiple raters’ scores and analytical scoring based on 4 and 6 traits, respectively. The LLM models used for inference are the GPT-3.5 model and the GPT-4 model, both developed by OpenAI.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The GPT-4 model demonstrated substantially better performance compared to GPT-3.5, except for traits 5 and 6 of Essay Set 8, where performance decreased.</li>
<li>When using elaborated rubrics with descriptors, the GPT-3.5 model showed an increase in the average QWK values across traits compared to the Basic-type rubric. However, under the GPT-4 model condition, some traits exhibited either no difference or even a decrease in QWK values.</li>
<li>Under the CJ-based scoring condition, the average QWK values were 0.573 for GPT-3.5 and 0.674 for GPT-4, representing performance improvements of approximately 30.8% and 18.9%, respectively, compared to</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-09</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.05733v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.05733v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.05733v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.05733v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6518</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Is_GPT_4_Alone_Sufficient_for_Automated_Essay_Scoring_A_Comparative_Judgment_Approach_Based_on_Rater_Cognition/2024-07-08-Is_GPT_4_Alone_Sufficient_for_Automated_Essay_Scoring_A_Comparative_Judgment_Approach_Based_on_Rater_Cognition.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.05733v1/x2.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>KG-FPQ: Evaluating Factuality Hallucination in LLMs with Knowledge Graph-based False Premise Questions</title>
  <dc:creator>Yanxu Zhu, Jinlin Xiao, Yuhang Wang, Jitao Sang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/KG_FPQ_Evaluating_Factuality_Hallucination_in_LLMs_with_Knowledge_Graph_based_False_Premise_Questions/2024-07-08-KG_FPQ_Evaluating_Factuality_Hallucination_in_LLMs_with_Knowledge_Graph_based_False_Premise_Questions.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/KG_FPQ_Evaluating_Factuality_Hallucination_in_LLMs_with_Knowledge_Graph_based_False_Premise_Questions/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.05868v1/extracted/5716829/example.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper introduces an automated, scalable pipeline to create False Premise Questions (FPQs) based on knowledge graphs (KGs) to evaluate factuality hallucination in large language models (LLMs). The process involves modifying true triplets from KGs to create false premises and then utilizing GPTs to generate semantically rich FPQs. The proposed method is used to create a comprehensive benchmark, the Knowledge Graph-based False Premise Questions (KG-FPQ), which contains approximately 178k FPQs across three knowledge domains, at six levels of confusability, and in two task formats. The KG-FPQ dataset and code are available at <a href="https://github.com/yanxuzhu/KG-FPQ" class="uri">https://github.com/yanxuzhu/KG-FPQ</a>.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The proposed automated and scalable pipeline combines KGs and GPTs for constructing FPQ datasets, by editing true triplets into false triplets and utilizing GPTs to generate FPQs.</li>
<li>Based on the proposed method, a comprehensive benchmark, KG-FPQ, is created, containing FPQs across three knowledge domains, at six levels of confusability, and in two task formats.</li>
<li>An automated evaluator for generative hallucination evaluation, FPQ-Judge, is fine-tuned, achieving 93% accuracy on a manually annotated test set. Furthermore, an in-depth evaluation of factuality hallucination induced by FPQs is conducted on several representative LLMs, yielding valuable insights.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The paper presents a valuable contribution to the evaluation of factuality hallucination in LLMs by introducing an automated and scalable pipeline for constructing FPQ datasets. The proposed method allows for the creation of a comprehensive benchmark, KG-FPQ, which covers various knowledge domains, confusability levels, and task formats. The evaluation of several representative LLMs on KG-FPQ provides valuable insights into the performance of these models in handling FPQs.</p>
<p>However, the paper does not discuss potential limitations or shortcomings of the proposed method. For instance, the reliance on KGs for generating FPQs might</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-09</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.05868v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.05868v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.05868v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.05868v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7115</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/KG_FPQ_Evaluating_Factuality_Hallucination_in_LLMs_with_Knowledge_Graph_based_False_Premise_Questions/2024-07-08-KG_FPQ_Evaluating_Factuality_Hallucination_in_LLMs_with_Knowledge_Graph_based_False_Premise_Questions.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2407.05868v1/extracted/5716829/example.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
