<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Bayesian beagle</title>
<link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Quarto blog of LLM-generated summaries of Arxiv preprints</description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.450</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Aligning Teacher with Student Preferences for Tailored Training Data Generation</title>
  <dc:creator>Yantao Liu, Zhao Zhang, Zijun Yao, Shulin Cao, Lei Hou, Juanzi Li</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Aligning_Teacher_with_Student_Preferences_for_Tailored_Training_Data_Generation/2024-06-27-Aligning_Teacher_with_Student_Preferences_for_Tailored_Training_Data_Generation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Aligning_Teacher_with_Student_Preferences_for_Tailored_Training_Data_Generation/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19227v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper introduces ARTE, a novel framework for tailored training example generation in Knowledge Distillation. ARTE aligns the teacher language model with the student language model’s preferences to generate tailored training examples, inspired by responsive teaching in pedagogy. The framework consists of three main steps: Knowledge Elicitation, Preference Collection, and Preference Alignment. Extensive experiments on academic benchmarks demonstrate the superiority of ARTE over existing instruction-tuning datasets distilled from powerful LLMs. The paper also investigates the generalization of the aligned teacher model across tasks and students.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>ARTE outperforms existing instruction-tuning datasets by a large margin in extensive experiments on academic reasoning benchmarks.</li>
<li>The fine-tuned student model in ARTE achieves better generalization ability on reasoning tasks, as demonstrated by its performance on various academic reasoning benchmarks.</li>
<li>The aligned teacher model in ARTE can generate tailored training examples for unseen tasks and unseen student models, as shown by its generalization across tasks and students.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper does not discuss the computational cost of ARTE, which could be a potential limitation for its practical application.</li>
<li>The paper does not provide a detailed comparison of ARTE with other alignment methods, such as PPO, which could be a potential area for further research.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential biases or limitations of the preference collection step, which could impact the quality of the tailored training examples generated by ARTE.</li>
<li>The paper does not provide a detailed analysis of the impact of the size of the preference set on the performance of ARTE, which could be a potential area for further research.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential impact of the choice of the teacher and student models on the performance of ARTE, which could be a potential area for further research.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-07</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.19227v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.19227v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19227v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19227v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8697</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Aligning_Teacher_with_Student_Preferences_for_Tailored_Training_Data_Generation/2024-06-27-Aligning_Teacher_with_Student_Preferences_for_Tailored_Training_Data_Generation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19227v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Subtractive Training for Music Stem Insertion using Latent Diffusion Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Ivan Villa-Renteria, Mason L. Wang, Zachary Shah, Zhe Li, Soohyun Kim, Neelesh Ramachandran, Mert Pilanci</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Subtractive_Training_for_Music_Stem_Insertion_using_Latent_Diffusion_Models/2024-06-27-Subtractive_Training_for_Music_Stem_Insertion_using_Latent_Diffusion_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/../bayesian-beagle.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article presents a method for subtractive training for music stem insertion using latent diffusion models.</li>
<li>The authors use a text prompt to generate edit instructions from music captions, focusing on adding a specific instrument (drums) to a background music track.</li>
<li>The study aims to improve the performance of text-to-music generative AI models by providing more accurate and truthful captions for music pieces.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The authors propose a novel approach to subtractive training for music stem insertion using latent diffusion models.</li>
<li>The text prompt used in the study is designed to generate edit instructions for adding a specific instrument (drums) to a background music track.</li>
<li>The study emphasizes the importance of accurate and truthful captions for music pieces to improve the performance of text-to-music generative AI models.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article presents an innovative approach to subtractive training for music stem insertion, which could potentially improve the performance of text-to-music generative AI models.</li>
<li>However, the study focuses solely on adding drums to a background music track, which may limit its applicability to other instruments or music genres.</li>
<li>The authors do not discuss any potential limitations or biases in their method, such as the impact of the chosen action words on the generated captions or the generalizability of the approach to different music datasets.</li>
<li>Further research is needed to evaluate the effectiveness of this method in handling other instruments and music genres, as well as to address any potential limitations or biases in the approach.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-07</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.19328v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.19328v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19328v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19328v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>1133</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Subtractive_Training_for_Music_Stem_Insertion_using_Latent_Diffusion_Models/2024-06-27-Subtractive_Training_for_Music_Stem_Insertion_using_Latent_Diffusion_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Averaging log-likelihoods in direct alignment</title>
  <dc:creator>Nathan Grinsztajn, Yannis Flet-Berliac, Mohammad Gheshlaghi Azar, Florian Strub, Bill Wu, Eugene Choi, Chris Cremer, Arash Ahmadian, Yash Chandak, Olivier Pietquin, Matthieu Geist</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Averaging_log_likelihoods_in_direct_alignment/2024-06-27-Averaging_log_likelihoods_in_direct_alignment.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Averaging_log_likelihoods_in_direct_alignment/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19188v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper introduces a new approach for making direct alignment length-invariant in the context of Large Language Models (LLMs).</li>
<li>The proposed method involves introducing a new averaging operator for policies and composing it with the operator providing the optimal RL solution.</li>
<li>The authors empirically study the effect of such averaging, observing a trade-off between the length of generations and their scores.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The authors propose a principled approach for making direct alignment length-invariant by introducing a new averaging operator for policies and composing it with the operator providing the optimal RL solution.</li>
<li>The proposed method is applied to direct alignment, which translates into replacing log-likelihoods by length-normalized log-likelihoods in the underlying loss function.</li>
<li>The authors empirically study the effect of such averaging and observe a trade-off between the length of generations and their scores.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper presents a novel approach to address the issue of length-invariance in direct alignment methods for LLMs.</li>
<li>The proposed method is mathematically principled and provides a practical algorithm for direct alignment methods.</li>
<li>The authors empirically study the effect of such averaging and observe a trade-off between the length of generations and their scores. However, the paper does not provide a clear explanation for this trade-off or its implications for the performance of LLMs.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential limitations or drawbacks of the proposed method, such as its computational complexity or its impact on the convergence of the optimization process.</li>
<li>The paper does not compare the proposed method to other existing approaches for making direct alignment length-invariant, which could provide a more comprehensive evaluation of its performance.</li>
<li>The paper does not provide a clear motivation for the need for length-invariance in direct alignment methods, which could help to better understand the significance of the proposed approach.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-07</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.19188v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.19188v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19188v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19188v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5452</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Averaging_log_likelihoods_in_direct_alignment/2024-06-27-Averaging_log_likelihoods_in_direct_alignment.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19188v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>LayoutCopilot: An LLM-powered Multi-agent Collaborative Framework for Interactive Analog Layout Design</title>
  <dc:creator>Bingyang Liu, Haoyi Zhang, Xiaohan Gao, Zichen Kong, Xiyuan Tang, Yibo Lin, Runsheng Wang, Ru Huang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LayoutCopilot_An_LLM_powered_Multi_agent_Collaborative_Framework_for_Interactive_Analog_Layout_Design/2024-06-27-LayoutCopilot_An_LLM_powered_Multi_agent_Collaborative_Framework_for_Interactive_Analog_Layout_Design.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/../bayesian-beagle.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article discusses improving the performance of over-the-air (OTA) layouts, focusing on six potential high-level solutions.</li>
<li>The first solution involves enhancing symmetry with the symAdd function, which can improve the layout’s performance by reducing the impact of asymmetrical components.</li>
<li>The second solution is to improve matching with deviceMove and deviceSwap functions, which can help align components and reduce variations in their properties.</li>
<li>The third solution is to reduce parasitics with wireWidth and wireSpacing, which can minimize the impact of unwanted capacitance and resistance in the layout.</li>
<li>The fourth solution is to prevent crosstalk with wireSpacing, which can reduce the interference between adjacent wires.</li>
<li>The fifth solution is to improve routing with netPriority and netTopology, which can optimize the layout’s wiring and reduce signal delays.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Enhancing symmetry</strong> with the symAdd function can improve the performance of OTA layouts by reducing the impact of asymmetrical components.</li>
<li><strong>Improving matching</strong> with deviceMove and deviceSwap functions can help align components and reduce variations in their properties, leading to better performance.</li>
<li><strong>Reducing parasitics</strong> with wireWidth and wireSpacing can minimize the impact of unwanted capacitance and resistance in the layout, improving its overall performance.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides a clear and concise overview of the potential solutions for improving the performance of OTA layouts.</li>
<li>However, the article does not provide any empirical evidence or case studies to support the effectiveness of these solutions.</li>
<li>The article also does not discuss any potential limitations or trade-offs associated with implementing these solutions, such as increased design complexity or manufacturing costs.</li>
<li>Further research is needed to evaluate the effectiveness of these solutions in real-world applications and to identify any potential limitations or trade-offs.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-07</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.18873v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.18873v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.18873v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.18873v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>91</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LayoutCopilot_An_LLM_powered_Multi_agent_Collaborative_Framework_for_Interactive_Analog_Layout_Design/2024-06-27-LayoutCopilot_An_LLM_powered_Multi_agent_Collaborative_Framework_for_Interactive_Analog_Layout_Design.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Disentangling Knowledge-based and Visual Reasoning by Question Decomposition in KB-VQA</title>
  <dc:creator>Elham J. Barezi, Parisa Kordjamshidi</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Disentangling_Knowledge_based_and_Visual_Reasoning_by_Question_Decomposition_in_KB_VQA/2024-06-27-Disentangling_Knowledge_based_and_Visual_Reasoning_by_Question_Decomposition_in_KB_VQA.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Disentangling_Knowledge_based_and_Visual_Reasoning_by_Question_Decomposition_in_KB_VQA/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.18839v1/extracted/5694501/imgs/data4.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The article presents a study on the Knowledge-Based Visual Question Answering (KB-VQA) problem, where models need to ground a question into the visual modality to find the answer. The authors propose a question decomposer to find several simpler questions to guide the captioner and provide a richer textual representation of the given image. The proposed method involves using models such as PromptCap or InstructBlip for visual questions and GPT models for non-visual questions to extract extra knowledge required to answer the question. The results demonstrate the positive impact of using simple questions before retrieving visual or non-visual information, with up to 2% improvement in accuracy on three well-known VQA datasets.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Replacing a complex question with several simpler questions helps to extract more relevant information from the image and provide a stronger comprehension of it.</li>
<li>Decomposing the questions helps to find non-visual parts of the question to retrieve the extra required information.</li>
<li>Using a question decomposer to find several simpler questions to guide the captioner and provide a richer textual representation of the given image improves the final accuracy for the KB-VQA task.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The proposed method addresses some weaknesses of current image-to-text captioners for KB-VQA problems, including question decomposition to extract more visual details required to address the given question. However, the method relies on the implicit knowledge of the LLMs and does not exploit explicit sources of knowledge to find the answer. Additionally, the method does not address the issue of noisy retrieval from external KBs, which can affect the final accuracy. The method also does not evaluate the performance of the proposed method on other VQA datasets or compare it to other state-of-the-art methods.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-07</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.18839v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.18839v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.18839v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.18839v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>4974</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Disentangling_Knowledge_based_and_Visual_Reasoning_by_Question_Decomposition_in_KB_VQA/2024-06-27-Disentangling_Knowledge_based_and_Visual_Reasoning_by_Question_Decomposition_in_KB_VQA.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.18839v1/extracted/5694501/imgs/data4.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Fine-tuned network relies on generic representation to solve unseen cognitive task</title>
  <dc:creator>Dongyan Lin</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Fine_tuned_network_relies_on_generic_representation_to_solve_unseen_cognitive_task/2024-06-27-Fine_tuned_network_relies_on_generic_representation_to_solve_unseen_cognitive_task.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Fine_tuned_network_relies_on_generic_representation_to_solve_unseen_cognitive_task/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.18926v1/extracted/5694287/figures/fig1_task.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study investigates the ability of pretrained GPT-2 to solve a context-dependent decision-making problem based on numerical comparison through fine-tuning.</li>
<li>The task is adapted from neuroscience and cognitive science literature and is entirely novel to GPT models.</li>
<li>The results show that fine-tuned models depend heavily on pretrained representations, particularly in later layers, while models trained from scratch develop different, more task-specific mechanisms.</li>
<li>The findings highlight the advantages and limitations of pretraining for task generalization and underscore the need for further investigation into the mechanisms underpinning task-specific fine-tuning in LLMs.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Fine-tuned models rely more on pretrained representations to solve a novel decision-making task, while models optimized from scratch develop alternative mechanisms.</li>
<li>Fine-tuned models show significant reliance on attention heads in later layers, which are likely crucial for generic language modeling, as these heads were developed during pretraining.</li>
<li>Models trained from scratch develop task-specific solutions, with significant performance drops upon ablating heads in the first layer, suggesting that these heads are vital for extracting task-relevant numerical information.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study provides valuable insights into the mechanisms underlying task-specific fine-tuning in LLMs.</li>
<li>The use of a novel task adapted from neuroscience and cognitive science literature is a strength of the study, as it allows for the exploration of the data with computational neuroscience methods and direct comparisons between representations in biological and artificial neural networks.</li>
<li>However, the study is limited by its focus on a single cognitive task, and further studies with more diverse cognitive tasks are required to understand how pretrained representations support task-specific fine-tuning.</li>
<li>Additionally, the study relies on qualitative observations, and the development of new quantitative metrics is needed to ensure scientific rigor in the results.</li>
<li>The field of mechanistic interpretability in LLMs, which is also largely qualitative at present, requires new quantitative methods to advance.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-07</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.18926v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.18926v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.18926v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.18926v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>4648</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Fine_tuned_network_relies_on_generic_representation_to_solve_unseen_cognitive_task/2024-06-27-Fine_tuned_network_relies_on_generic_representation_to_solve_unseen_cognitive_task.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.18926v1/extracted/5694287/figures/fig1_task.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Fairness and Bias in Multimodal AI: A Survey</title>
  <dc:creator>Tosin Adewumi, Lama Alkhaled, Namrata Gurung, Goya van Boven, Irene Pagliai</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Fairness_and_Bias_in_Multimodal_AI_A_Survey/2024-06-27-Fairness_and_Bias_in_Multimodal_AI_A_Survey.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/../bayesian-beagle.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>This survey paper aims to fill the gap in the literature regarding the study of fairness and bias in Large Multimodal Models (LMMs) compared to Large Language Models (LLMs). The authors provide 50 examples of datasets and models along with the challenges affecting them. They identify a new category of quantifying bias (preuse) in addition to the two well-known ones in the literature: intrinsic and extrinsic. The paper also critically discusses various ways researchers are addressing these challenges.</p>
<p>The authors conducted a filtered search on Google Scholar with two slightly differently-worded phrases: “Fairness and Bias in Large Multimodal Models” and “Fairness and Bias in Large Language Models.” The search was filtered to the period 2014-2024, during which deep learning made significant progress. The results revealed that there are fewer scientific papers on the former.</p>
<p>The paper reviews some LMMs and LLMs and the fairness and bias challenges they have. Tables 2 and 3 summarize some relevant datasets and the models, respectively. All the 25 datasets identified have their challenges, including stereotypes, porn, misogyny, racial, gender, religious, cultural, age, and demographic biases.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper identifies a new category of quantifying bias (preuse) in addition to the two well-known ones in the literature: intrinsic and extrinsic.</li>
<li>The paper provides 50 examples of datasets and models along with the challenges affecting them.</li>
<li>The paper critically discusses various ways researchers are addressing the challenges of fairness and bias.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The paper provides a comprehensive survey of fairness and bias across a wide spectrum of LMMs, LLMs, and multimodal datasets. However, the paper could have provided more details on the methodology used to identify the 50 examples of datasets and models. Additionally, the paper could have provided more in-depth analysis and critique of the various ways researchers are addressing the challenges of fairness and bias.</p>
<p>The paper also acknowledges that it may be almost impossible to automatically filter a dataset or debias a model to be 100% free of unfair, bias,</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-07</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.19097v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.19097v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19097v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19097v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5909</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Fairness_and_Bias_in_Multimodal_AI_A_Survey/2024-06-27-Fairness_and_Bias_in_Multimodal_AI_A_Survey.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Fundamental Problems With Model Editing: How Should Rational Belief Revision Work in LLMs?</title>
  <dc:creator>Peter Hase, Thomas Hofweber, Xiang Zhou, Elias Stengel-Eskin, Mohit Bansal</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Fundamental_Problems_With_Model_Editing_How_Should_Rational_Belief_Revision_Work_in_LLMs/2024-06-27-Fundamental_Problems_With_Model_Editing_How_Should_Rational_Belief_Revision_Work_in_LLMs.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Fundamental_Problems_With_Model_Editing_How_Should_Rational_Belief_Revision_Work_in_LLMs/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19354v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary:</strong></p>
<p>The paper critiques the predominant formulation of the model editing problem and proposes a semi-synthetic setting for evaluating model editing. The authors present 12 open challenges, summarized in three categories: (1) challenges with defining the model editing problem, (2) challenges with developing benchmarks, and (3) challenges with assuming LLMs have editable beliefs. The paper also introduces a semi-synthetic setting for evaluating model editing that precisely formalizes the problem, albeit with a simplified problem and models trained from scratch. The evaluation compares an LLM against a Bayesian model, reflecting that Bayesian epistemology is the gold standard in belief revision. The authors use facts from Wikidata to generate a corpus of noisy sentences, which they then train an autoregressive Transformer on. By fitting a Bayesian model to the same data, they obtain exact Bayesian posteriors that serve as the targets for evaluating language models. The experiments show that edits to language models generalize poorly with respect to other relevant beliefs, yielding inconsistent model beliefs.</p>
<p><strong>Major Findings:</strong></p>
<ol type="1">
<li>The model editing problem stands on shaky theoretical ground, as it has been framed as an instance of the belief revision problem in philosophy. This inheritance of longstanding challenges regarding how to rationally respond to new information about the world poses a significant issue for model editing.</li>
<li>The paper presents 12 open challenges for model editing, organized into three categories: (1) challenges with defining the model editing problem, (2) challenges with developing benchmarks, and (3) challenges with assuming LLMs have editable beliefs.</li>
<li>The authors introduce a semi-synthetic setting for evaluating model editing that precisely formalizes the problem, using a Bayesian model as the gold standard for belief revision.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></p>
<p>The paper provides a comprehensive critique of the model editing problem and proposes a semi-synthetic setting for evaluating model editing. However, the proposed setting simplifies the problem and uses models trained from scratch, which may not fully capture the complexities of real-world LLMs. Additionally, the paper does not address potential solutions to the 12 open challenges it presents, leaving room for further research in this area. The experiments conducted in the paper</p>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-07</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.19354v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.19354v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19354v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19354v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>14906</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Fundamental_Problems_With_Model_Editing_How_Should_Rational_Belief_Revision_Work_in_LLMs/2024-06-27-Fundamental_Problems_With_Model_Editing_How_Should_Rational_Belief_Revision_Work_in_LLMs.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19354v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Seeing Is Believing: Black-Box Membership Inference Attacks Against Retrieval Augmented Generation</title>
  <dc:creator>Yuying Li, Gaoyang Liu, Yang Yang, Chen Wang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Seeing_Is_Believing_Black_Box_Membership_Inference_Attacks_Against_Retrieval_Augmented_Generation/2024-06-27-Seeing_Is_Believing_Black_Box_Membership_Inference_Attacks_Against_Retrieval_Augmented_Generation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Seeing_Is_Believing_Black_Box_Membership_Inference_Attacks_Against_Retrieval_Augmented_Generation/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19234v1/extracted/5696061/fig1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level1">
<h1>Summary:</h1>
<p><strong>Seeing Is Believing: Black-Box Membership Inference Attacks Against Retrieval Augmented Generation</strong></p>
<section id="summary-1" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-1">Summary:</h2>
<ul>
<li>The paper explores the use of Membership Inference Attacks (MIA) to determine whether a sample is part of the knowledge database of a Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) system.</li>
<li>The core hypothesis is that if a sample is a member, it will exhibit significant similarity to the text generated by the RAG system.</li>
<li>The authors compute the cosine similarity and the model’s perplexity to establish a membership score, building robust features.</li>
<li>Two novel attack strategies are introduced: a Threshold-based Attack and a Machine Learning-based Attack, designed to accurately identify membership.</li>
<li>Experimental validation of the methods achieved a ROC AUC of 82%.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>MIA for RAG Systems</strong>: The paper demonstrates the effectiveness of using MIA to determine whether a sample is part of the knowledge database of a RAG system.</li>
<li><strong>Robust Features</strong>: The authors compute the cosine similarity and the model’s perplexity to establish a membership score, building robust features.</li>
<li><strong>Novel Attack Strategies</strong>: Two novel attack strategies are introduced: a Threshold-based Attack and a Machine Learning-based Attack, designed to accurately identify membership.</li>
<li><strong>Experimental Validation</strong>: The experimental validation of the methods achieved a ROC AUC of 82%.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h2>
<ul>
<li>The paper provides a novel approach to assessing the security and privacy of RAG systems’ external databases.</li>
<li>The use of MIA to determine whether a sample is part of the knowledge database of a RAG system is a significant contribution.</li>
<li>The introduction of two novel attack strategies is a valuable addition to the field.</li>
<li>The experimental validation of the methods is a strength of the paper.</li>
<li>However, the paper does not discuss potential countermeasures or defenses against these attacks, which could be a limitation.</li>
<li>Additionally, the paper does not explore the potential impact of these attacks on the performance of RAG systems, which could be an area for future research.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-07</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.19234v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.19234v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19234v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19234v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>3427</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Seeing_Is_Believing_Black_Box_Membership_Inference_Attacks_Against_Retrieval_Augmented_Generation/2024-06-27-Seeing_Is_Believing_Black_Box_Membership_Inference_Attacks_Against_Retrieval_Augmented_Generation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19234v1/extracted/5696061/fig1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Contrastive Policy Gradient: Aligning LLMs on sequence-level scores in a supervised-friendly fashion</title>
  <dc:creator>Yannis Flet-Berliac, Nathan Grinsztajn, Florian Strub, Eugene Choi, Chris Cremer, Arash Ahmadian, Yash Chandak, Mohammad Gheshlaghi Azar, Olivier Pietquin, Matthieu Geist</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Contrastive_Policy_Gradient_Aligning_LLMs_on_sequence_level_scores_in_a_supervised_friendly_fashion/2024-06-27-Contrastive_Policy_Gradient_Aligning_LLMs_on_sequence_level_scores_in_a_supervised_friendly_fashion.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Contrastive_Policy_Gradient_Aligning_LLMs_on_sequence_level_scores_in_a_supervised_friendly_fashion/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19185v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper introduces Contrastive Policy Gradient (CoPG), a new Reinforcement Learning (RL) algorithm designed for finetuning Large Language Models (LLMs). CoPG is a form of policy gradient that contrasts the reward with a specific baseline, allowing for a supervised-friendly objective function that does not rely on fresh generations from the model. This enables learning a policy in a pure offline setting without relying on importance sampling or clipping of log-probability ratios, and without requiring an additional value network.</p>
<p>CoPG has been proven to optimize for the optimal KL-regularized policy and generalizes policy gradient, RLOO, and IPO. The paper demonstrates the convergence properties of CoPG in a controlled bandit experiment and shows that it can optimize a reward function in a fully offline and off-policy manner for LLMs, achieving higher rewards than direct alignment approaches.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>CoPG is a new RL algorithm for finetuning LLMs that uses a supervised-friendly objective function, enabling learning in a pure offline setting without relying on importance sampling or clipping of log-probability ratios.</li>
<li>CoPG has been proven to optimize for the optimal KL-regularized policy and generalizes policy gradient, RLOO, and IPO.</li>
<li>CoPG has been demonstrated to optimize a reward function in a fully offline and off-policy manner for LLMs, achieving higher rewards than direct alignment approaches.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>While CoPG has been proven to optimize for the optimal KL-regularized policy and has been demonstrated to optimize a reward function in a fully offline and off-policy manner for LLMs, achieving higher rewards than direct alignment approaches, it has only been validated in a simple bandit problem and a larger scale LLM experiment. Further validation on more tasks and rewards in the context of LLMs is needed.</p>
<p>CoPG works in a pure offline setting, which is a strength, but it would benefit from using fresh generations too, as well as from possibly heterogeneous sources of data. The proposed approach optimizes for a single reward model, and its extension to multiple rewards remains an interesting open question. Additionally, the approach assumes that the reward model is reliable, which is often</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-07</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.19185v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.19185v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19185v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19185v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8271</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Contrastive_Policy_Gradient_Aligning_LLMs_on_sequence_level_scores_in_a_supervised_friendly_fashion/2024-06-27-Contrastive_Policy_Gradient_Aligning_LLMs_on_sequence_level_scores_in_a_supervised_friendly_fashion.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19185v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Sonnet or Not, Bot? Poetry Evaluation for Large Models and Datasets</title>
  <dc:creator>Melanie Walsh, Anna Preus, Maria Antoniak</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Sonnet_or_Not_Bot_Poetry_Evaluation_for_Large_Models_and_Datasets/2024-06-27-Sonnet_or_Not_Bot_Poetry_Evaluation_for_Large_Models_and_Datasets.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Sonnet_or_Not_Bot_Poetry_Evaluation_for_Large_Models_and_Datasets/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.18906v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The article “Sonnet or Not, Bot?” explores the poetic capabilities of large language models (LLMs) and their ability to recognize and generate poetry. The authors develop a task to evaluate how well LLMs can identify more than 20 poetic forms and formal elements in the English language. They find that LLMs, particularly GPT-4 and GPT-4o, can successfully identify both common and uncommon fixed poetic forms, such as sonnets, sestinas, and pantoums, at surprisingly high accuracy levels when compared to annotations by human experts. However, performance varies widely by poetic form and feature; the models struggle to identify unfixed poetic forms, especially ones based on topic or visual features.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs, particularly GPT-4 and GPT-4o, can successfully identify both common and uncommon fixed poetic forms, such as sonnets, sestinas, and pantoums, at high accuracy levels when compared to annotations by human experts.</li>
<li>Performance varies widely by poetic form and feature; the models struggle to identify unfixed poetic forms, especially ones based on topic or visual features.</li>
<li>While the LLMs have most success with the poetic forms most commonly found in popular pretraining datasets, the authors do not see major differences when they compare model performance on poems from major online poetry institutions, popular pretraining datasets, or print books with little to no digital presence.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article provides a comprehensive evaluation of LLMs’ ability to recognize poetic forms, which is a significant contribution to the field of NLP. However, the study has some limitations. The authors acknowledge that the circulation of poetry is different from other literary texts, which may result in unmeasured differences in pretraining datasets. Additionally, the study focuses on English-language poetry, which may not be representative of poetry in other languages. The authors also note that identifying poetic form is a “difficult” task, even for expert human annotators, which may limit the accuracy of the LLMs’ evaluations. Finally, the study does not address the potential biases in the pretraining datasets, which could impact the models’ performance.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-07</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.18906v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.18906v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.18906v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.18906v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>3809</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Sonnet_or_Not_Bot_Poetry_Evaluation_for_Large_Models_and_Datasets/2024-06-27-Sonnet_or_Not_Bot_Poetry_Evaluation_for_Large_Models_and_Datasets.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.18906v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>PhysioLLM: Supporting Personalized Health Insights with Wearables and Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Cathy Mengying Fang, Valdemar Danry, Nathan Whitmore, Andria Bao, Andrew Hutchison, Cayden Pierce, Pattie Maes</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/PhysioLLM_Supporting_Personalized_Health_Insights_with_Wearables_and_Large_Language_Models/2024-06-27-PhysioLLM_Supporting_Personalized_Health_Insights_with_Wearables_and_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/PhysioLLM_Supporting_Personalized_Health_Insights_with_Wearables_and_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19283v1/extracted/5696245/overview.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level1">
<h1>Summary:</h1>
<p><strong>PhysioLLM: Supporting Personalized Health Insights with Wearables and Large Language Models</strong></p>
<p>PhysioLLM is an interactive system that leverages large language models (LLMs) to provide personalized health understanding and exploration by integrating physiological data from wearables with contextual information. Unlike commercial health apps for wearables, PhysioLLM offers a comprehensive statistical analysis component that discovers correlations and trends in user data, allowing users to ask questions in natural language and receive generated personalized insights, and guides them to develop actionable goals.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Improved Understanding of Health Data</strong>: PhysioLLM outperforms both the Fitbit App alone and a generic LLM chatbot in facilitating a deeper, personalized understanding of health data.</li>
<li><strong>Personalized Insights</strong>: The system provides effective personalized insights using an LLM architecture, which improves one’s understanding of their own health.</li>
<li><strong>Actionable Steps Toward Personal Health Goals</strong>: The interface is perceived as more personalized than chatting with a generic LLM-based chatbot, and it results in users having more motivation to change and their goals being found to be more actionable.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Limited Expert Health Knowledge</strong>: The system uses an off-the-shelf, general-purpose LLM, which has limited expert health knowledge. Integrations of fine-tuned specialized LLMs with the system will further improve the quality of the insights.</li>
<li><strong>Handling Randomness and Unknowns</strong>: The system has limitations in handling the randomness and unknowns in the data and contexts. However, its adaptability ensures beneficial and personalized suggestions.</li>
<li><strong>Potential for Positive Behavior Change</strong>: Anecdotal evidence suggests that the system has the potential to nudge people towards positive behavior change, which merits further study.</li>
<li><strong>Privacy and Ethical Considerations</strong>: The system has embedded counter-action prompts to prevent abusive uses, but further tests on the robustness of the safety prompt are needed. The system should acknowledge its limitations and ensure that no raw data is sent to the LLM, and all data and survey results are de-identified.</li>
<li>**Broader User</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-07</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.19283v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.19283v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19283v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19283v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7356</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/PhysioLLM_Supporting_Personalized_Health_Insights_with_Wearables_and_Large_Language_Models/2024-06-27-PhysioLLM_Supporting_Personalized_Health_Insights_with_Wearables_and_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19283v1/extracted/5696245/overview.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Efficient course recommendations with T5-based ranking and summarization</title>
  <dc:creator>Thijmen Bijl, Niels van Weeren, Suzan Verberne</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Efficient_course_recommendations_with_T5_based_ranking_and_summarization/2024-06-27-Efficient_course_recommendations_with_T5_based_ranking_and_summarization.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Efficient_course_recommendations_with_T5_based_ranking_and_summarization/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19018v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>This paper presents a two-stage retrieval pipeline for a course recommender system that ranks courses for skill-occupation pairs. The in-production recommender system, BrightFit, provides course recommendations from multiple sources, but some course descriptions are long and noisy, while retrieval and ranking in an online system need to be highly efficient. The proposed pipeline uses RankT5 finetuned on MSMARCO as a re-ranker and compares two summarizers for course descriptions: a LongT5 model finetuned for the task and a generative LLM (Vicuna) with in-context learning. The paper also experiments with quantization to reduce the size of the ranking model and increase inference speed. The proposed two-stage ranking with automatic summarization achieves a substantial improvement over the in-production (BM25) ranker on two newly labeled datasets. However, the improved quality of the ranking was not confirmed by an A/B test, which showed a higher clickthrough rate for BM25-ranking than for the proposed two-stage retrieval.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The proposed two-stage retrieval pipeline with automatic summarization achieves a substantial improvement over the in-production (BM25) ranker on two newly labeled datasets.</li>
<li>Quantization of RankT5 results in a 40% speed-up without compromising the quality of the recommendations.</li>
<li>The improved quality of the ranking was confirmed by a questionnaire completed by 29 respondents, but not by an A/B test, which showed a higher clickthrough rate for BM25-ranking than for the proposed two-stage retrieval.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The paper presents a promising approach to course recommendation with a two-stage retrieval pipeline that leverages the power of transformer-based models while keeping the time to generate recommendations reasonable. The use of quantization to reduce the size of the ranking model and increase inference speed is also a valuable contribution. However, the paper does not discuss the potential limitations or biases of the proposed approach, nor does it address the issue of cold start, which is a common problem in recommender systems. Additionally, the fact that the improved quality of the ranking was not confirmed by an A/B test raises questions about the generalizability of the</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-07</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.19018v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.19018v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19018v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19018v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>9587</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>recommender</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Efficient_course_recommendations_with_T5_based_ranking_and_summarization/2024-06-27-Efficient_course_recommendations_with_T5_based_ranking_and_summarization.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19018v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Can we teach language models to gloss endangered languages?</title>
  <dc:creator>Michael Ginn, Mans Hulden, Alexis Palmer</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Can_we_teach_language_models_to_gloss_endangered_languages/2024-06-27-Can_we_teach_language_models_to_gloss_endangered_languages.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Can_we_teach_language_models_to_gloss_endangered_languages/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.18895v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>This paper explores the use of large language models (LLMs) for generating interlinear glossed text (IGT) in endangered languages. The authors investigate the effectiveness of LLMs in producing IGT without any traditional training, focusing on in-context learning. They propose new approaches for selecting examples to provide in-context and observe that targeted selection can significantly improve performance. The study finds that LLM-based methods outperform standard transformer baselines, despite requiring no training. However, they still underperform state-of-the-art supervised systems for the task. The proposed approaches are highly practical for researchers outside the NLP community, requiring minimal effort to use.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs can be effective at generating IGT in endangered languages using in-context learning, without any traditional training.</li>
<li>Targeted selection of examples to provide in-context can significantly improve performance.</li>
<li>LLM-based methods outperform standard transformer baselines, despite requiring no training.</li>
<li>LLM-based methods still underperform state-of-the-art supervised systems for the task.</li>
<li>The proposed approaches are highly practical for researchers outside the NLP community, requiring minimal effort to use.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The paper presents an interesting approach to generating IGT in endangered languages using LLMs. The authors’ findings suggest that LLMs can be effective at this task, even without traditional training. However, the study has some limitations.</p>
<p>First, the authors do not provide a detailed comparison of the performance of LLM-based methods with state-of-the-art supervised systems. While they mention that LLM-based methods underperform these systems, they do not provide a quantitative comparison.</p>
<p>Second, the authors do not discuss the potential biases or limitations of LLMs in generating IGT. For example, LLMs may struggle with languages that have limited data or are not well-represented in their training data.</p>
<p>Third, the authors do not discuss the potential ethical implications of using LLMs for generating IGT. For example, there may be concerns about the accuracy and reliability of the generated IGT, particularly if it is used for research or language documentation purposes.</p>
<p>Overall, the paper presents an interesting approach to generating IGT in</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-07</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.18895v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.18895v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.18895v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.18895v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6433</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Can_we_teach_language_models_to_gloss_endangered_languages/2024-06-27-Can_we_teach_language_models_to_gloss_endangered_languages.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.18895v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>T-FREE: Tokenizer-Free Generative LLMs via Sparse Representations for Memory-Efficient Embeddings</title>
  <dc:creator>Björn Deiseroth, Manuel Brack, Patrick Schramowski, Kristian Kersting, Samuel Weinbach</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/T_FREE_Tokenizer_Free_Generative_LLMs_via_Sparse_Representations_for_Memory_Efficient_Embeddings/2024-06-27-T_FREE_Tokenizer_Free_Generative_LLMs_via_Sparse_Representations_for_Memory_Efficient_Embeddings.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/T_FREE_Tokenizer_Free_Generative_LLMs_via_Sparse_Representations_for_Memory_Efficient_Embeddings/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19223v1/x3.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level1">
<h1>Summary:</h1>
<p>The paper introduces T-Free, a novel approach to tokenization for large language models (LLMs) that directly embeds words through sparse activation patterns over character triplets, eliminating the need for a reference corpus. T-Free exploits morphological similarities and allows for strong compression of embedding layers, achieving competitive downstream performance with a parameter reduction of more than 85% on these layers. Additionally, T-Free shows significant improvements in cross-lingual transfer learning.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level1">
<h1>Major Findings:</h1>
<ol type="1">
<li>T-Free eliminates the need for subword tokens, retaining near-optimal performance across languages.</li>
<li>T-Free explicitly models character overlaps between morphologically similar words without the need to learn an embedding for each variant from scratch.</li>
<li>T-Free reduces the size of the embedding layers by 333% and the average encoding length of text by 444% compared to a unigram baseline.</li>
<li>T-Free remains highly competitive on standard downstream model performance benchmarks.</li>
<li>For transfer learning to an unseen language, the T-Free model quickly improves performance, while the tokenizer baseline shows only minor adaptation.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level1">
<h1>Analysis and Critique:</h1>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper presents a promising approach to tokenization that addresses the limitations of traditional tokenizers, such as computational overhead, ineffective vocabulary use, and unnecessarily large embedding and head layers.</li>
<li>The use of sparse activation patterns over character triplets allows for the exploitation of morphological similarities, leading to strong compression of embedding layers.</li>
<li>The experimental evaluation demonstrates competitive downstream performance with a significant reduction in parameters, highlighting the potential of T-Free for more efficient and effective language modeling.</li>
<li>However, the paper does not provide a detailed comparison with other tokenization methods, such as Byte Pair Encoding (BPE) or Unigram, which could help to better understand the advantages and limitations of T-Free.</li>
<li>Additionally, the paper does not discuss the potential impact of T-Free on the training and inference time of LLMs, which is an important consideration for practical applications.</li>
<li>Further research is needed to evaluate the performance of T-Free on a wider range of languages and tasks, as well as to explore its potential for other applications,</li>
</ol>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-07</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.19223v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.19223v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19223v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19223v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8998</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/T_FREE_Tokenizer_Free_Generative_LLMs_via_Sparse_Representations_for_Memory_Efficient_Embeddings/2024-06-27-T_FREE_Tokenizer_Free_Generative_LLMs_via_Sparse_Representations_for_Memory_Efficient_Embeddings.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19223v1/x3.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Simulating Classroom Education with LLM-Empowered Agents</title>
  <dc:creator>Zheyuan Zhang, Daniel Zhang-Li, Jifan Yu, Linlu Gong, Jinchang Zhou, Zhiyuan Liu, Lei Hou, Juanzi Li</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Simulating_Classroom_Education_with_LLM_Empowered_Agents/2024-06-27-Simulating_Classroom_Education_with_LLM_Empowered_Agents.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Simulating_Classroom_Education_with_LLM_Empowered_Agents/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19226v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper introduces SimClass, a multi-agent classroom simulation framework that utilizes large language models (LLMs) to simulate real-world classroom interactions. The framework recognizes representative class roles and introduces a novel class control mechanism for automatic classroom teaching. The authors conducted user experiments in two real-world courses and demonstrated that LLMs can effectively simulate traditional classroom interaction patterns while enhancing user experience. The study also observed emergent group behaviors among agents in SimClass, where agents collaborate to create enlivening interactions in classrooms to improve user learning process.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>SimClass exhibits behaviors, interaction patterns, and characteristics similar to those of traditional classrooms.</li>
<li>Multiple classroom agents enable users to engage more effectively in class and enhance their sense of presence.</li>
<li>The control mechanism spontaneously elicits the emergent behaviors in the multi-agent classroom system, including collaborative teaching and discussion, emotional company, and discipline control.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The paper presents an innovative approach to simulating classroom education using LLM-empowered agents. The authors successfully demonstrate the potential of LLMs in simulating traditional classroom interaction patterns and enhancing user experience. However, the study has some limitations. Firstly, the experiments were conducted using GPT-4 as the backbone model, which may not generalize to other LLMs. Secondly, the study involved a limited number of agents, which may not capture the full range of behaviors in a real-world classroom. Lastly, the study applied a limited quantity of functions in the system, which could be expanded to further enhance the performance of the system.</p>
<p>Despite these limitations, the paper provides valuable insights into the potential of LLMs in simulating classroom education. The emergent group behaviors observed among agents in SimClass highlight the potential of LLMs in creating enlivening interactions in classrooms. The study also underscores the importance of designing a control mechanism that can spontaneously elicit these behaviors.</p>
<p>In conclusion, the paper presents a promising approach to simulating classroom education using LLM-empowered agents. The study demonstrates the potential of LLMs in simulating traditional classroom interaction patterns and enhancing user experience. However, further research is needed to explore the potential of LLMs in simulating a wider range of classroom behaviors and to</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-07</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.19226v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.19226v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19226v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19226v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6252</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Simulating_Classroom_Education_with_LLM_Empowered_Agents/2024-06-27-Simulating_Classroom_Education_with_LLM_Empowered_Agents.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19226v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Jump Starting Bandits with LLM-Generated Prior Knowledge</title>
  <dc:creator>Parand A. Alamdari, Yanshuai Cao, Kevin H. Wilson</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Jump_Starting_Bandits_with_LLM_Generated_Prior_Knowledge/2024-06-27-Jump_Starting_Bandits_with_LLM_Generated_Prior_Knowledge.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Jump_Starting_Bandits_with_LLM_Generated_Prior_Knowledge/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19317v1/extracted/5696345/figs/pre_train.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper presents a novel approach to jump-start contextual multi-armed bandits using Large Language Models (LLMs) to simulate human preferences and reduce online learning regret. The proposed method, Contextual Bandits with LLM Initialization (CBLI), generates a pre-training dataset of approximate human preferences using LLMs, significantly reducing data-gathering costs and improving performance for the first users in a campaign. The authors empirically demonstrate the effectiveness of CBLI in two settings: a standard contextual bandit and a sleeping bandit setup, achieving 14-17% and 19-20% reduction in early regret, respectively.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs can be used to generate synthetic reward distributions for pre-training contextual bandits, improving their performance and reducing online learning regret.</li>
<li>CBLI achieves a significant reduction in early regret in both standard contextual bandit and sleeping bandit setups.</li>
<li>Even when certain privacy-sensitive attributes are withheld, CBLI still achieves a substantial reduction in early regret.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper does not address potential biases in LLM-generated responses, which could impact the performance of CBLI in real-world applications.</li>
<li>The authors do not discuss the scalability of CBLI to a larger number of arms, which could be a limitation in some applications.</li>
<li>The focus on total, accumulated regret may not be sufficient in contexts where other goals or constraints are present, such as adaptive treatment assignment.</li>
<li>The paper does not explore the potential negative impacts of CBLI on certain subpopulations of interest, which should be considered in future work.</li>
<li>The authors acknowledge that distributional misalignment between LLM-generated rewards and ground truth could lead to worse regret than cold-starting the CB, but do not provide a solution to this potential issue.</li>
</ol>
<p>Overall, the paper presents an innovative approach to jump-start contextual multi-armed bandits using LLMs, demonstrating its effectiveness in reducing early regret. However, further research is needed to address potential biases, scalability, and the impact on specific subpopulations. Additionally, robustness techniques should be incorporated to maximize the usefulness of CBLI in the future.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-07</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.19317v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.19317v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19317v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19317v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8270</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>recommender</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Jump_Starting_Bandits_with_LLM_Generated_Prior_Knowledge/2024-06-27-Jump_Starting_Bandits_with_LLM_Generated_Prior_Knowledge.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.19317v1/extracted/5696345/figs/pre_train.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>LICO: Large Language Models for In-Context Molecular Optimization</title>
  <dc:creator>Tung Nguyen, Aditya Grover</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LICO_Large_Language_Models_for_In_Context_Molecular_Optimization/2024-06-27-LICO_Large_Language_Models_for_In_Context_Molecular_Optimization.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LICO_Large_Language_Models_for_In_Context_Molecular_Optimization/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.18851v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level1">
<h1>Summary:</h1>
<p>The paper introduces LICO, a method that leverages pretrained Large Language Models (LLMs) for black-box optimization. LICO extends existing LLMs to non-language domains by using separate embedding and prediction layers. The model is trained on a diverse set of semi-synthetic functions for few-shot predictions, enabling efficient generalization to various optimization tasks. LICO achieves state-of-the-art performance on the Practical Molecular Optimization (PMO) benchmark, which includes over 20 objective functions. Ablation analyses highlight the importance of incorporating language instruction to guide in-context learning and semi-synthetic training for better generalization.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level1">
<h1>Major Findings:</h1>
<ol type="1">
<li>LICO achieves state-of-the-art performance on the PMO benchmark, outperforming existing methods in molecular optimization.</li>
<li>Incorporating language instruction to guide in-context learning and semi-synthetic training improves the model’s generalization capabilities.</li>
<li>Larger LLMs with stronger pattern-matching capabilities obtained through extensive language pretraining perform better in black-box optimization tasks.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level1">
<h1>Analysis and Critique:</h1>
<p>The paper presents a novel approach to black-box optimization using pretrained LLMs, demonstrating its effectiveness on the PMO benchmark. However, the method assumes the availability of an accessible set of intrinsic functions, which may not be the case for all scientific domains. In such cases, a better synthetic data generation process incorporating domain knowledge is needed to aid generalization.</p>
<p>The paper also highlights the importance of using a pretrained LLM, as a scratch model with the same number of parameters performs much worse. This emphasizes the value of the pattern-matching capabilities that LLMs acquire through extensive language pretraining.</p>
<p>The authors provide a detailed description of the methodology, training details, and optimization hyperparameters, ensuring the reproducibility of their results. However, the paper does not discuss the limitations of the work performed by the authors, which could provide valuable insights for future research.</p>
<p>In conclusion, the paper presents a promising approach to black-box optimization using pretrained LLMs, demonstrating its potential in molecular optimization. However, further research is needed to evaluate its applicability and generality in other domains and explore other</p>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-07</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.18851v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.18851v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.18851v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.18851v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>11485</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LICO_Large_Language_Models_for_In_Context_Molecular_Optimization/2024-06-27-LICO_Large_Language_Models_for_In_Context_Molecular_Optimization.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.18851v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Methodology of Adapting Large English Language Models for Specific Cultural Contexts</title>
  <dc:creator>Wenjing Zhang, Siqi Xiao, Xuejiao Lei, Ning Wang, Huazheng Zhang, Meijuan An, Bikun Yang, Zhaoxiang Liu, Kai Wang, Shiguo Lian</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Methodology_of_Adapting_Large_English_Language_Models_for_Specific_Cultural_Contexts/2024-06-27-Methodology_of_Adapting_Large_English_Language_Models_for_Specific_Cultural_Contexts.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Methodology_of_Adapting_Large_English_Language_Models_for_Specific_Cultural_Contexts/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.18192v2/extracted/5694512/fig1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper proposes a rapid adaptation method for large language models (LLMs) in specific cultural contexts, using instruction-tuning based on specific cultural knowledge and safety values data.</li>
<li>The method is demonstrated using LLaMA3-8B as the English LLM and Chinese as the specific cultural context.</li>
<li>The evaluation results show that the adapted LLM significantly improves its capabilities in domain-specific knowledge and adaptability to safety values while maintaining its original expertise advantages.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The proposed method enables rapid adaptation of LLMs to specific cultural contexts without the need for pre-training.</li>
<li>The adapted LLM significantly enhances its capabilities in domain-specific knowledge and adaptability to safety values.</li>
<li>The adapted LLM maintains its original expertise advantages.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper provides a novel approach to adapting LLMs to specific cultural contexts, which is a significant contribution to the field.</li>
<li>The evaluation results demonstrate the effectiveness of the proposed method. However, the paper does not discuss the potential limitations or biases of the method.</li>
<li>The paper does not provide a comparison with other methods for adapting LLMs to specific cultural contexts, which could have strengthened the argument for the proposed method.</li>
<li>The paper focuses on the Chinese cultural context, and it is unclear how the proposed method would perform in other cultural contexts.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential ethical implications of adapting LLMs to specific cultural contexts, which is an important consideration in the field of AI.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-07</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.18192v2">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.18192v2</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.18192v2">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.18192v2</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>4216</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Methodology_of_Adapting_Large_English_Language_Models_for_Specific_Cultural_Contexts/2024-06-27-Methodology_of_Adapting_Large_English_Language_Models_for_Specific_Cultural_Contexts.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.18192v2/extracted/5694512/fig1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>ELCoRec: Enhance Language Understanding with Co-Propagation of Numerical and Categorical Features for Recommendation</title>
  <dc:creator>Jizheng Chen, Kounianhua Du, Jianghao Lin, Bo Chen, Ruiming Tang, Weinan Zhang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ELCoRec_Enhance_Language_Understanding_with_Co_Propagation_of_Numerical_and_Categorical_Features_for_Recommendation/2024-06-27-ELCoRec_Enhance_Language_Understanding_with_Co_Propagation_of_Numerical_and_Categorical_Features_for_Recommendation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ELCoRec_Enhance_Language_Understanding_with_Co_Propagation_of_Numerical_and_Categorical_Features_for_Recommendation/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.18825v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper introduces ELCoRec, a framework designed to enhance language understanding with co-propagation of numerical and categorical features for recommendation. The framework aims to address the challenges of numerical insensitivity and encoding overhead in large language models (LLMs) for accurate user behavior modeling. ELCoRec introduces a downstream graph attention network (GAT) as a unified expert network for feature encoding, which can better utilize heterogeneous nodes to encode features of different kinds compared to general CTR prediction models. The framework also proposes a Recent interaction Augmented Prompt (RAP) template to capture both the global information related to the target item and the recent information emphasizing the latest trends of user preferences.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>ELCoRec addresses the numerical insensitivity problem by parallelly propagating numerical and categorical features using a GAT expert network, offering an informative user preference encoding that enhances LLM’s understanding towards numerical features.</li>
<li>The encoding overhead is alleviated by injecting the preference encoding into the LLM’s semantic space via soft prompting at the cost of a single token embedding.</li>
<li>The RAP template is proposed to better obtain user’s recent interests and form the textual input of ELCoRec, which connects user history retrieved item sequence and recent item sequence along with the placeholder token for embedding injection.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The paper presents a novel approach to addressing the challenges of numerical insensitivity and encoding overhead in LLMs for recommendation tasks. The proposed ELCoRec framework and RAP template offer a promising solution to these issues by incorporating recent user interactions and leveraging a GAT expert network for feature encoding. However, the paper does not discuss potential limitations, unanswered questions, or conflicting evidence that may arise from the proposed method. Additionally, the paper does not provide a detailed comparison with other existing methods that address similar challenges in LLMs for recommendation tasks. Further research is needed to evaluate the performance of ELCoRec in comparison to other state-of-the-art methods and to identify any potential shortcomings or areas for improvement.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-07-07</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.18825v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.18825v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.18825v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.18825v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>9136</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>recommender</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ELCoRec_Enhance_Language_Understanding_with_Co_Propagation_of_Numerical_and_Categorical_Features_for_Recommendation/2024-06-27-ELCoRec_Enhance_Language_Understanding_with_Co_Propagation_of_Numerical_and_Categorical_Features_for_Recommendation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.18825v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
