<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Bayesian beagle</title>
<link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Quarto blog of LLM-generated summaries of Arxiv preprints</description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.450</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 05:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>KIVI: A Tuning-Free Asymmetric 2bit Quantization for KV Cache</title>
  <dc:creator>Zirui Liu, Jiayi Yuan, Hongye Jin, Shaochen Zhong, Zhaozhuo Xu, Vladimir Braverman, Beidi Chen, Xia Hu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/KIVI_A_Tuning_Free_Asymmetric_2bit_Quantization_for_KV_Cache/2024-02-05-KIVI_A_Tuning_Free_Asymmetric_2bit_Quantization_for_KV_Cache.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/KIVI_A_Tuning_Free_Asymmetric_2bit_Quantization_for_KV_Cache/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Efficiently serving large language models (LLMs) requires batching many requests together to reduce the cost per request. Yet, the key-value (KV) cache, which stores attention keys and values to avoid re-computations, significantly increases memory demands and becomes the new bottleneck in speed and memory usage. This memory demand increases with larger batch sizes and longer context lengths. Additionally, the inference speed is limited by the size of KV cache, as the GPU’s SRAM must load the entire KV cache from the main GPU memory for each token generated, causing the computational core to be idle during this process.</li>
<li>A straightforward and effective solution to reduce KV cache size is quantization, which decreases the total bytes taken by KV cache. However, there is a lack of in-depth studies that explore the element distribution of KV cache to understand the hardness and limitation of KV cache quantization. To fill the gap, the authors conducted a comprehensive study on the element distribution in KV cache of popular LLMs. Their findings indicate that the key cache should be quantized per-channel, i.e., group elements along the channel dimension and quantize them together. In contrast, the value cache should be quantized per-token.</li>
<li>Based on the above insights, the authors proposed KIVI, a plug-and-play extreme low-bit KV cache quantization method. KIVI quantizes key cache per-channel and quantizes value cache per-token. The per-token value cache quantization aligns well with the streaming nature of auto-regressive inference, allowing newly quantized tensors to be directly appended to the existing quantized value cache by token dimension.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Efficiently serving large language models (LLMs) requires batching many requests together to reduce the cost per request.</li>
<li>The key-value (KV) cache, which stores attention keys and values to avoid re-computations, significantly increases memory demands and becomes the new bottleneck in speed and memory usage.</li>
<li>The proposed KIVI algorithm quantizes key cache per-channel and quantizes value cache per-token, enabling extreme low-bit KV cache quantization.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The proposed KIVI algorithm provides a promising solution to the challenges associated with large language models. However, the study could benefit from further validation on a wider range of LLMs and real-world applications to assess its generalizability and practical utility. Additionally, the authors should consider addressing potential trade-offs and limitations associated with the proposed quantization approach.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.02750v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.02750v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.02750v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.02750v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>13762</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/KIVI_A_Tuning_Free_Asymmetric_2bit_Quantization_for_KV_Cache/2024-02-05-KIVI_A_Tuning_Free_Asymmetric_2bit_Quantization_for_KV_Cache.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Chain-of-Feedback: Mitigating the Effects of Inconsistency in Responses</title>
  <dc:creator>Jinwoo Ahn</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Chain_of_Feedback_Mitigating_the_Effects_of_Inconsistency_in_Responses/2024-02-05-Chain_of_Feedback_Mitigating_the_Effects_of_Inconsistency_in_Responses.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Chain_of_Feedback_Mitigating_the_Effects_of_Inconsistency_in_Responses/img/2402.02648v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Large Language Models (LLMs) often provide inconsistent outputs for knowledge-intensive questions, decreasing the reliability and validity of responses.</li>
<li>The Chain-of-Feedback (CoF) system triggers LLMs to deviate more from the actual answer, while Recursive Chain of Feedback (R-CoF) is a novel prompting method being studied to mitigate inconsistencies.</li>
<li>Relying heavily on AI agents like ChatGPT can lead to the public perceiving them as reliable sources of information, despite potential inaccuracies and inconsistencies.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs are prone to generating contradicting sentences and being distracted with irrelevant context, leading to unreliable responses.</li>
<li>Meaningless feedback requesting another attempt from LLMs decreases the quality of the response, highlighting the need for improved prompting methods.</li>
<li>R-CoF aims to break down complex problems into smaller steps, allowing users to verify correctness and adjust incorrect reasoning to reach the correct solution.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article raises awareness of the risks associated with relying on AI agents for information, highlighting the potential for misleading or inaccurate responses.</li>
<li>The preliminary experiments show promising insights into the impact of prompting methods on LLM responses, but further research is needed to validate the effectiveness of R-CoF.</li>
<li>The limitations of the ongoing work, such as time constraints and the need for extensive experiments with larger datasets and different public models, indicate the need for more comprehensive research in this area.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.02648v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.02648v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.02648v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.02648v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>3742</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Chain_of_Feedback_Mitigating_the_Effects_of_Inconsistency_in_Responses/2024-02-05-Chain_of_Feedback_Mitigating_the_Effects_of_Inconsistency_in_Responses.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Chain_of_Feedback_Mitigating_the_Effects_of_Inconsistency_in_Responses/img/2402.02648v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Intent-based Prompt Calibration: Enhancing prompt optimization with synthetic boundary cases</title>
  <dc:creator>Elad Levi, Eli Brosh, Matan Friedmann</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Intent_based_Prompt_Calibration_Enhancing_prompt_optimization_with_synthetic_boundary_cases/2024-02-05-Intent_based_Prompt_Calibration_Enhancing_prompt_optimization_with_synthetic_boundary_cases.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Intent_based_Prompt_Calibration_Enhancing_prompt_optimization_with_synthetic_boundary_cases/img/2402.03099v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Prompt engineering is essential for optimizing the performance of Large Language Models (LLMs) due to their high sensitivity to the given prompt and the ambiguity of textual task instructions.</li>
<li>Recent studies have shown that LLMs can automatically conduct prompt engineering by employing a meta-prompt that incorporates the outcomes of the last trials and proposes an improved prompt.</li>
<li>However, the requirement for a high-quality benchmark to compare different prompts is difficult and expensive to acquire in many real-world use cases.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Automatic Prompt Engineering:</strong> Recent studies have demonstrated the capabilities of LLMs to automatically conduct prompt engineering by employing a meta-prompt that incorporates the outcomes of the last trials and proposes an improved prompt.</li>
<li><strong>Challenges in Benchmarking:</strong> The requirement for a high-quality benchmark to compare different prompts is difficult and expensive to acquire in many real-world use cases.</li>
<li><strong>New Method for Automatic Prompt Engineering:</strong> The article introduces a new method for automatic prompt engineering, using a calibration process that iteratively refines the prompt to the user intent.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides valuable insights into the challenges of prompt engineering and the potential of LLMs to automatically conduct prompt optimization.</li>
<li>However, the reliance on high-quality benchmarks and the difficulty of acquiring them in real-world use cases is a significant limitation.</li>
<li>The new method for automatic prompt engineering using a calibration process is promising, but further research is needed to validate its effectiveness in diverse real-world tasks and datasets.</li>
<li>The article could benefit from a more detailed discussion of the limitations and potential biases of the proposed method, as well as the need for further research and validation in real-world scenarios.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03099v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03099v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03099v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03099v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>11827</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Intent_based_Prompt_Calibration_Enhancing_prompt_optimization_with_synthetic_boundary_cases/2024-02-05-Intent_based_Prompt_Calibration_Enhancing_prompt_optimization_with_synthetic_boundary_cases.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Intent_based_Prompt_Calibration_Enhancing_prompt_optimization_with_synthetic_boundary_cases/img/2402.03099v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>UniMem: Towards a Unified View of Long-Context Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Junjie Fang, Likai Tang, Hongzhe Bi, Yujia Qin, Si Sun, Zhenyu Li, Haolun Li, Yongjian Li, Xin Cong, Yukun Yan, Xiaodong Shi, Sen Song, Yankai Lin, Zhiyuan Liu, Maosong Sun</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/UniMem_Towards_a_Unified_View_of_Long_Context_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-05-UniMem_Towards_a_Unified_View_of_Long_Context_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/UniMem_Towards_a_Unified_View_of_Long_Context_Large_Language_Models/img/2402.03009v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Long-context processing is crucial for large language models (LLMs) but poses computational challenges.</li>
<li>UniMem is introduced as a unified framework for understanding various long-context methods.</li>
<li>UniMix, an innovative approach, integrates the strengths of existing algorithms and achieves superior performance in handling long contexts.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Memory Management:</strong>
<ul>
<li>UniMix outperforms existing methods with “FIFO” overflow handling, but “Clear all” has a negative impact.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Memory Write:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Increasing “Memory Tokens” does not demonstrate a positive effect on performance.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Memory Injection:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Layer (16) exhibits the lowest perplexity, indicating the sensitivity of UniMix to specific layers within the model architecture.</li>
</ul></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study provides a comprehensive analysis of existing long-context methods and introduces a novel approach, UniMix, which outperforms other methods.</li>
<li>The impact of different dimensions, such as memory management, memory write, and memory injection, on performance is thoroughly investigated.</li>
<li>The study provides valuable insights into the design and optimization of long-context language models, contributing to the advancement of the field.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the study offers a well-structured and coherent analysis of long-context language models, highlighting the potential for further research and development in this area.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03009v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03009v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03009v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03009v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>13162</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/UniMem_Towards_a_Unified_View_of_Long_Context_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-05-UniMem_Towards_a_Unified_View_of_Long_Context_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/UniMem_Towards_a_Unified_View_of_Long_Context_Large_Language_Models/img/2402.03009v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Empowering Time Series Analysis with Large Language Models: A Survey</title>
  <dc:creator>Yushan Jiang, Zijie Pan, Xikun Zhang, Sahil Garg, Anderson Schneider, Yuriy Nevmyvaka, Dongjin Song</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Empowering_Time_Series_Analysis_with_Large_Language_Models_A_Survey/2024-02-05-Empowering_Time_Series_Analysis_with_Large_Language_Models_A_Survey.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Empowering_Time_Series_Analysis_with_Large_Language_Models_A_Survey/img/2402.03182v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Large language models (LLMs) have shown remarkable capabilities in various natural language tasks and have been exploited for time series analysis.</li>
<li>The survey provides a systematic overview of existing methods that leverage LLMs for time series analysis, categorizing them into different groups and discussing their applications in various domains.</li>
<li>The survey also highlights future research opportunities to advance time series analysis with LLMs.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Pre-trained LLMs for Time Series Analysis:</strong> Recent advances have shown that pre-trained LLMs can be exploited to capture complex dependencies in time series data and facilitate various applications.</li>
<li><strong>Taxonomy of Time Series LLMs:</strong> The survey categorizes and summarizes existing methods based on the proposed taxonomy of methodology, providing a comprehensive overview of the field.</li>
<li><strong>Applications of Time Series LLMs:</strong> The survey discusses the applications of time series LLMs in general and spatial-temporal time series data, tailored to specific domains.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Tokenization &amp; Prompt Design:</strong> The survey highlights the need for novel tokenization methods and better prompt design to improve model performance.</li>
<li><strong>Interpretability:</strong> The survey emphasizes the importance of developing algorithms to provide interpretations for the LLMs’ output.</li>
<li><strong>Multi-modality:</strong> The survey suggests investigating how to incorporate multi-modality input via LLMs and interpret the output accordingly.</li>
<li><strong>Domain Generalization:</strong> The survey emphasizes the need to tackle the distribution shift or domain shift problem by leveraging appropriate time series augmentation techniques.</li>
<li><strong>Scaling Laws of Time Series LLMs:</strong> The survey highlights the importance of understanding the scaling laws of LLMs and their impact on performance.</li>
<li><strong>Time Series LLMs as Agents:</strong> The survey suggests exploring how LLMs can be used to assist in decision-making processes and provide more personalized predictions and decisions.</li>
<li><strong>Bias and Safety:</strong> The survey emphasizes the need to mitigate potential biases in LLMs and ensure the reliability and safety of their outputs.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the survey provides a comprehensive overview of the field of time series analysis with LLMs and highlights important research directions for future advancements. However, it could benefit from a more detailed discussion of potential biases and safety concerns associated with LLMs. Additionally, further exploration of interpretability and explainability methods for LLMs would enhance the survey’s coverage of critical analysis.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03182v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03182v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03182v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03182v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>14491</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Empowering_Time_Series_Analysis_with_Large_Language_Models_A_Survey/2024-02-05-Empowering_Time_Series_Analysis_with_Large_Language_Models_A_Survey.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Empowering_Time_Series_Analysis_with_Large_Language_Models_A_Survey/img/2402.03182v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Nevermind: Instruction Override and Moderation in Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Edward Kim</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Nevermind_Instruction_Override_and_Moderation_in_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-05-Nevermind_Instruction_Override_and_Moderation_in_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.03303v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Investigates and benchmarks Large Language Models (LLMs) on the task of explicit instruction following in conflicting situations, such as overrides.</li>
<li>Larger models perform the best in following instructions that override internal and contextual instructions, and are obedient, even to a fault.</li>
<li>Maintaining instruction following capabilities when scaling to longer contexts via rope scaling requires a significant buffer from the edge of the perplexity cliff.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Larger models perform the best in following instructions that override internal and contextual instructions, and are obedient, even to a fault.</li>
<li>When scaling to longer contexts via rope scaling, a significant buffer needs to be maintained from the edge of the perplexity cliff in order to maintain instruction following capabilities.</li>
<li>Improving instruction following is fundamentally at odds with the ability of a language model to follow given safety filters or guidelines.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Larger models exhibit superior capability in navigating instructions that require overriding both internal knowledge and contextual cues, demonstrating a high degree of obedience.</li>
<li>The introduction of rope scaling to extend context handling introduces the necessity of a carefully managed buffer to avoid the perplexity cliff, ensuring the models maintain their ability to follow instructions effectively.</li>
<li>However, there is a fundamental tension between enhancing a model’s ability to override instructions and maintaining adherence to safety protocols and guidelines.</li>
<li>Over-alignment of the models destroys model weights and reduces their general capabilities; thus, an alternative framework has been developed that has parallels to neuro-inspired cognitive control.</li>
<li>The research suggests that a path to developing safe and trustworthy AI may lie in mechanisms external to the LLMs themselves, akin to the introduction of a pre-frontal cortex that understands what rules and behaviors are acceptable in various situations.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03303v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03303v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03303v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03303v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>9483</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Nevermind_Instruction_Override_and_Moderation_in_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-05-Nevermind_Instruction_Override_and_Moderation_in_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.03303v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="67" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Matrix: A Bayesian learning model for LLMs</title>
  <dc:creator>Siddhartha Dalal, Vishal Misra</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/The_Matrix_A_Bayesian_learning_model_for_LLMs/2024-02-05-The_Matrix_A_Bayesian_learning_model_for_LLMs.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/The_Matrix_A_Bayesian_learning_model_for_LLMs/img/2402.03175v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>In this paper, the authors introduce a Bayesian learning model to understand the behavior of Large Language Models (LLMs). They explore the optimization metric of LLMs, which is based on predicting the next token, and develop a novel model grounded in this principle. The authors construct an ideal generative text model represented by a multinomial transition probability matrix with a prior, and examine how LLMs approximate this matrix. They discuss the continuity of the mapping between embeddings and multinomial distributions, and present the Dirichlet approximation theorem to approximate any prior. Additionally, they demonstrate how text generation by LLMs aligns with Bayesian learning principles and delve into the implications for in-context learning, specifically explaining why in-context learning emerges in larger models where prompts are considered as samples to be updated. The findings indicate that the behavior of LLMs is consistent with Bayesian Learning, offering new insights into their functioning and potential applications.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The authors introduce a Bayesian learning model to understand the behavior of Large Language Models (LLMs).</li>
<li>They explore the optimization metric of LLMs, which is based on predicting the next token, and develop a novel model grounded in this principle.</li>
<li>The authors demonstrate how text generation by LLMs aligns with Bayesian learning principles and delve into the implications for in-context learning, specifically explaining why in-context learning emerges in larger models where prompts are considered as samples to be updated.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper provides a comprehensive understanding of the behavior of Large Language Models (LLMs) and their alignment with Bayesian learning principles.</li>
<li>The findings offer valuable insights into the functioning of LLMs and their potential applications.</li>
<li>The authors effectively demonstrate the implications for in-context learning, particularly in larger models, and provide a strong theoretical framework for understanding the behavior of LLMs.</li>
<li>However, the paper could benefit from more empirical evidence to support the theoretical framework and findings presented. Additionally, further research is needed to validate the practical applications of the Bayesian learning model for LLMs.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03175v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03175v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03175v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03175v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>9695</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/The_Matrix_A_Bayesian_learning_model_for_LLMs/2024-02-05-The_Matrix_A_Bayesian_learning_model_for_LLMs.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/The_Matrix_A_Bayesian_learning_model_for_LLMs/img/2402.03175v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Homograph Attacks on Maghreb Sentiment Analyzers</title>
  <dc:creator>Fatima Zahra Qachfar, Rakesh M. Verma</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Homograph_Attacks_on_Maghreb_Sentiment_Analyzers/2024-02-05-Homograph_Attacks_on_Maghreb_Sentiment_Analyzers.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Homograph_Attacks_on_Maghreb_Sentiment_Analyzers/img/2402.03171v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Homograph attacks have a significant impact on the Sentiment Analysis (SA) task of different Arabic dialects from the Maghreb North-African countries.</li>
<li>The attacks result in a 65.3% decrease in transformer classification from an F1-score of 0.95 to 0.33 when data is written in “Arabizi”.</li>
<li>The study aims to highlight the weaknesses of large language models (LLMs) and prioritize ethical and responsible Machine Learning.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Homograph attacks result in a 65.3% decrease in transformer classification from an F1-score of 0.95 to 0.33 when data is written in “Arabizi”.</li>
<li>Large language models (LLMs) are susceptible to malicious attacks such as homograph attacks, which pose significant challenges for LLMs that accept raw unfiltered input text.</li>
<li>The impact of character-based attacks on North-African languages is highlighted, emphasizing the importance of ethical and responsible machine learning.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The study focuses on the impact of homograph attacks on sentiment analyzers of North African dialects, but it does not delve into potential solutions or defense mechanisms against these attacks.</li>
<li>The research acknowledges the weaknesses of large language models (LLMs) but does not provide a comprehensive analysis of potential defense mechanisms or strategies to mitigate the impact of homograph attacks.</li>
<li>The study emphasizes the importance of ethical and responsible machine learning, but it does not provide concrete recommendations or guidelines for implementing ethical practices in the development of machine learning models.</li>
<li>The research is limited to highlighting the impact of homograph attacks on sentiment analysis, but it does not explore the broader implications of these attacks on other natural language processing tasks or applications.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03171v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03171v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03171v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03171v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>2178</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Homograph_Attacks_on_Maghreb_Sentiment_Analyzers/2024-02-05-Homograph_Attacks_on_Maghreb_Sentiment_Analyzers.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Homograph_Attacks_on_Maghreb_Sentiment_Analyzers/img/2402.03171v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>LLM Agents in Interaction: Measuring Personality Consistency and Linguistic Alignment in Interacting Populations of Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Ivar Frisch, Mario Giulianelli</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLM_Agents_in_Interaction_Measuring_Personality_Consistency_and_Linguistic_Alignment_in_Interacting_Populations_of_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-05-LLM_Agents_in_Interaction_Measuring_Personality_Consistency_and_Linguistic_Alignment_in_Interacting_Populations_of_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLM_Agents_in_Interaction_Measuring_Personality_Consistency_and_Linguistic_Alignment_in_Interacting_Populations_of_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.02896v1/extracted/5389989/figures/bfi_after_init_boxplot.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article explores the impact of language interaction on the behavior of persona-conditioned large language model (LLM) agents.</li>
<li>The study conditions GPT-3.5 on personality profiles and creates two groups of LLM agents to assess personality consistency and linguistic alignment during a collaborative writing task.</li>
<li>The findings indicate that different profiles exhibit varying degrees of personality consistency and linguistic alignment to their conversational partners.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The study demonstrates that LLM behavior can be shaped to adhere to specific personality profiles.</li>
<li>LLM agents show varying degrees of personality consistency and linguistic alignment in interaction, with differences between agent groups.</li>
<li>The degree of linguistic alignment of LLM agents to their conversational partners is not symmetric across personas.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study provides valuable insights into the impact of dialogue-based interaction on the personality consistency and linguistic behavior of LLM agents.</li>
<li>The findings suggest that LLM agents exhibit varying degrees of personality consistency and linguistic alignment, highlighting the need for robust approaches to persona conditioning.</li>
<li>The study is exploratory and has limitations, such as the use of extreme personas that do not reflect real-life personality categorizations of human subjects.</li>
<li>The potential ethical implications of using AI agents in human-AI interaction are acknowledged, and the study advocates for transparent disclosure of AI usage to foster trust and ensure ethical engagement with technology.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.02896v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.02896v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.02896v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.02896v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5945</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLM_Agents_in_Interaction_Measuring_Personality_Consistency_and_Linguistic_Alignment_in_Interacting_Populations_of_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-05-LLM_Agents_in_Interaction_Measuring_Personality_Consistency_and_Linguistic_Alignment_in_Interacting_Populations_of_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.02896v1/extracted/5389989/figures/bfi_after_init_boxplot.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Large Language Models are Geographically Biased</title>
  <dc:creator>Rohin Manvi, Samar Khanna, Marshall Burke, David Lobell, Stefano Ermon</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Large_Language_Models_are_Geographically_Biased/2024-02-05-Large_Language_Models_are_Geographically_Biased.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Large_Language_Models_are_Geographically_Biased/img/2402.02680v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Large Language Models (LLMs) inherently carry the biases contained in their training corpora, which can lead to the perpetuation of societal harm.</li>
<li>The study proposes to understand what LLMs know about the world through the lens of geography, particularly focusing on geospatial predictions.</li>
<li>The study demonstrates that LLMs are capable of making accurate zero-shot geospatial predictions and exhibit common biases across a range of objective and subjective topics.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs are capable of making very accurate zero-shot geospatial predictions, showing strong monotonic correlation with ground truth.</li>
<li>LLMs exhibit geographic biases across a range of both objective and subjective topics, particularly biased against areas with lower socioeconomic conditions.</li>
<li>All LLMs are likely biased to some degree, with significant variation in the magnitude of bias across existing LLMs.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study provides valuable insights into the biases present in LLMs, particularly in the context of geospatial predictions.</li>
<li>The findings highlight the need for further research and development to mitigate biases in LLMs, especially in sensitive subjective topics.</li>
<li>The study’s focus on geographic bias adds a new dimension to the understanding of biases in LLMs, contributing to the broader conversation on fairness and accuracy in language models.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.02680v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.02680v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.02680v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.02680v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>15193</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Large_Language_Models_are_Geographically_Biased/2024-02-05-Large_Language_Models_are_Geographically_Biased.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Large_Language_Models_are_Geographically_Biased/img/2402.02680v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>C-RAG: Certified Generation Risks for Retrieval-Augmented Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Mintong Kang, Nezihe Merve Gürel, Ning Yu, Dawn Song, Bo Li</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/C_RAG_Certified_Generation_Risks_for_Retrieval_Augmented_Language_Models/2024-02-05-C_RAG_Certified_Generation_Risks_for_Retrieval_Augmented_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/C_RAG_Certified_Generation_Risks_for_Retrieval_Augmented_Language_Models/img/2402.03181v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The academic article introduces the C-RAG framework for certifying generation risks for retrieval-augmented language models (RAG). It proposes a constrained generation protocol for RAG models and provides conformal risk analysis to control generation risks based on test statistics from in-distribution calibration samples. The paper offers two types of generation risk guarantees for RAG models and extends the conformal generation risk analysis to handle test-time distribution shifts for general bounded risk functions. The analysis setup and retrieval quality analysis of the C-RAG certification framework are discussed, along with the support received from various organizations and the references used in the paper. The paper also presents the conformal generation risks for RAG models, a theorem for bounding the risk of a retrieval model on a shifted distribution, and an algorithm for graph-based valid configurations search. It evaluates the probability vector and the single-layer self-attention transformer in the context of a retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) model and discusses the finite-sample error of the calibration set. The section also evaluates the conformal risks of RAG models with variations in the number of retrieved examples and compares the conformal risk bounds for different retrieval models.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The C-RAG framework provides a robust approach to certifying the trustworthiness of RAG models, addressing credibility and reliability concerns associated with large language models.</li>
<li>The extension of the conformal generation risk analysis to handle test-time distribution shifts enhances the applicability of the framework in real-world scenarios.</li>
<li>The evaluation of the conformal risks of RAG models highlights the effectiveness of RAG models in reducing conformal risks and compares the performance of different retrieval models.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper provides a comprehensive overview of the C-RAG framework, laying the groundwork for theoretical analysis and empirical validation.</li>
<li>The acknowledgements and references sections add credibility and reliability to the research, allowing readers to explore the sources used in the paper.</li>
<li>The theoretical results and algorithms presented offer a statistical framework for evaluating the performance and confidence levels of the RAG models, contributing to the broader context of the paper’s focus on improving the generation quality of large language models.</li>
<li>The mathematical formulations and bounds for the statistical guarantee of conformal risk in the context of the RAG model contribute to the understanding of the RAG model’s performance and robustness in practical applications.</li>
<li>The equations provided offer a practical way to calculate and evaluate the conformal risk, essential for assessing the reliability of predictions in various applications. Additionally, the identification of valid configurations with specified risk levels adds practical value to the application of RAG models in real-world scenarios.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03181v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03181v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03181v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03181v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>33709</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/C_RAG_Certified_Generation_Risks_for_Retrieval_Augmented_Language_Models/2024-02-05-C_RAG_Certified_Generation_Risks_for_Retrieval_Augmented_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/C_RAG_Certified_Generation_Risks_for_Retrieval_Augmented_Language_Models/img/2402.03181v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Constrained Decoding for Cross-lingual Label Projection</title>
  <dc:creator>Duong Minh Le, Yang Chen, Alan Ritter, Wei Xu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Constrained_Decoding_for_Cross_lingual_Label_Projection/2024-02-05-Constrained_Decoding_for_Cross_lingual_Label_Projection.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Constrained_Decoding_for_Cross_lingual_Label_Projection/img/2402.03131v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The academic article addresses the challenge of label projection in cross-lingual NLP tasks and introduces a new approach called Constraint Decoding for Cross-lingual Label Projection (CODEC). The proposed method uses constrained decoding to accurately translate and project annotated label spans from a high-resource language to a low-resource language, leading to improved translation quality and accuracy of label projection. Extensive experiments demonstrate that CODEC outperforms existing label projection methods and significantly improves cross-lingual transfer performance.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>CODEC outperforms existing label projection methods and significantly improves cross-lingual transfer performance.</li>
<li>The translation quality is a significant factor in the effectiveness of label projection methods.</li>
<li>The CODEC method demonstrates superior performance in cross-lingual Named Entity Recognition tasks across multiple languages.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The CODEC method offers a promising solution to the challenges of label projection in cross-lingual NLP tasks, with the potential to significantly impact various applications of multilingual language models.</li>
<li>The results of the CODEC method highlight the importance of translation quality and the potential of different translation systems for improved performance in cross-lingual NLP tasks.</li>
<li>The development of MasakhaNER 2.0 represents a significant step in addressing the linguistic diversity of African languages and has the potential to advance NLP research for under-resourced languages.</li>
<li>The technical implementation details of the CODEC system provide transparency and reproducibility, while the impact of the scale of the machine translation model underscores the significance of model selection in cross-lingual NLP tasks.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03131v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03131v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03131v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03131v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>21856</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Constrained_Decoding_for_Cross_lingual_Label_Projection/2024-02-05-Constrained_Decoding_for_Cross_lingual_Label_Projection.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Constrained_Decoding_for_Cross_lingual_Label_Projection/img/2402.03131v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>A Framework for Partially Observed Reward-States in RLHF</title>
  <dc:creator>Chinmaya Kausik, Mirco Mutti, Aldo Pacchiano, Ambuj Tewari</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_Framework_for_Partially_Observed_Reward_States_in_RLHF/2024-02-05-A_Framework_for_Partially_Observed_Reward_States_in_RLHF.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_Framework_for_Partially_Observed_Reward_States_in_RLHF/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article introduces a new framework for reinforcement learning from human feedback (RLHF) called Partially Observable Reinforcement Learning with Recursive Reward-State Dynamics (PORRL). It addresses the limitations of current models by explicitly incorporating “internal states” and intermediate feedback, offering a more comprehensive approach to reinforcement learning from human feedback.</li>
<li>The concept of dueling regret in the context of Partially Observable Markov Decision Processes (PORMDP) is discussed, highlighting the challenges in reducing dueling feedback to cardinal feedback. The section lays the foundation for the introduction of optimistic algorithms and provides a theoretical framework for analyzing regret bounds in the context of dueling feedback.</li>
<li>The relationship between dueling and cardinal feedback models is explored, and a reduction from dueling to optimistic cardinal PORRL is proposed. This section highlights the challenges in reducing dueling feedback to cardinal feedback and proposes a new approach to address this issue.</li>
<li>The article introduces a generic optimistic algorithm for cardinal PORRL using confidence sets, providing a general framework for optimistic reinforcement learning.</li>
<li>Two generic optimistic algorithms for reinforcement learning, Generic Confidence-Set Optimism and Generic Bonus-Based Optimism, are presented, along with detailed proofs and concentration results for the Cardinal POR-UCRL method.</li>
<li>The bounding of probability model deviations in the context of POR-UCRL regret is discussed, providing theoretical bounds and proofs for the regret of POR-UCRL under specific conditions.</li>
<li>Key concepts related to confidence sets, trajectory-dependent bonuses, and probability bonuses are introduced, providing a foundation for understanding the bounds on value error and the sum of bonuses in the POR-UCBVI algorithm.</li>
<li>Reduction algorithms from dueling to confidence-set-based optimism and bonus-based optimism are presented, establishing the conditions under which the dueling regret can be bounded in each case.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The introduction of the PORRL framework addresses the limitations of current models and offers a more comprehensive approach to reinforcement learning from human feedback.</li>
<li>The challenges and proposed solutions for reducing dueling feedback to cardinal feedback provide valuable insights into the theoretical and practical implications of handling feedback models in reinforcement learning.</li>
<li>The development of generic optimistic algorithms and the theoretical bounds for regret in various reinforcement learning scenarios contribute to the advancement of the field.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides a comprehensive and innovative approach to reinforcement learning from human feedback, addressing the limitations of current models and proposing novel solutions.</li>
<li>The theoretical foundations and practical implications of the proposed algorithms and reductions are well-supported, contributing to the development of robust and reliable reinforcement learning methods.</li>
<li>The focus on theoretical bounds and proofs enhances the rigor and reliability of the proposed algorithms, laying a strong foundation for future research and practical applications.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03282v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03282v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03282v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03282v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>37124</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_Framework_for_Partially_Observed_Reward_States_in_RLHF/2024-02-05-A_Framework_for_Partially_Observed_Reward_States_in_RLHF.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>GUARD: Role-playing to Generate Natural-language Jailbreakings to Test Guideline Adherence of Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Haibo Jin, Ruoxi Chen, Andy Zhou, Jinyin Chen, Yang Zhang, Haohan Wang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/GUARD_Role_playing_to_Generate_Natural_language_Jailbreakings_to_Test_Guideline_Adherence_of_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-05-GUARD_Role_playing_to_Generate_Natural_language_Jailbreakings_to_Test_Guideline_Adherence_of_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/GUARD_Role_playing_to_Generate_Natural_language_Jailbreakings_to_Test_Guideline_Adherence_of_Large_Language_Models/img/2402.03299v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper introduces GUARD, a system for testing Large Language Models (LLMs) to ensure they adhere to guidelines. GUARD uses a role-playing approach to generate jailbreak prompts, which are used to test the LLMs’ responses to potentially harmful or unethical queries. The system consists of four roles: Translator, Generator, Evaluator, and Optimizer, each responsible for different aspects of generating and evaluating jailbreak prompts. GUARD leverages existing jailbreak prompts and organizes them into a knowledge graph to make them more accessible and easier to retrieve. The system also automatically follows government-issued guidelines to generate jailbreaks and has been empirically validated on various LLMs, demonstrating its effectiveness in inducing unethical or guideline-violating responses.</p>
<p><strong>Key Terms:</strong> - Large Language Models (LLMs) - Jailbreaks - Role-playing system - Knowledge graph - Translator, Generator, Evaluator, Optimizer</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>GUARD system effectively generates jailbreak prompts to test LLMs’ adherence to guidelines.</li>
<li>Role-playing models and the number of pre-collected jailbreaks impact GUARD’s performance.</li>
<li>Role-playing techniques can be used to test the ethical and legal adherence of LLMs, highlighting the potential for generating harmful and unethical content.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The GUARD system offers an innovative approach to testing LLMs, but potential limitations and biases should be further explored.</li>
<li>The impact of role-playing models and pre-collected jailbreaks on GUARD’s performance requires additional research.</li>
<li>Ethical considerations regarding the development and use of language models in natural language processing are raised, emphasizing the need for responsible and ethical AI development.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03299v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03299v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03299v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03299v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>20870</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/GUARD_Role_playing_to_Generate_Natural_language_Jailbreakings_to_Test_Guideline_Adherence_of_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-05-GUARD_Role_playing_to_Generate_Natural_language_Jailbreakings_to_Test_Guideline_Adherence_of_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/GUARD_Role_playing_to_Generate_Natural_language_Jailbreakings_to_Test_Guideline_Adherence_of_Large_Language_Models/img/2402.03299v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>EasyInstruct: An Easy-to-use Instruction Processing Framework for Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Yixin Ou, Ningyu Zhang, Honghao Gui, Ziwen Xu, Shuofei Qiao, Zhen Bi, Huajun Chen</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/EasyInstruct_An_Easy_to_use_Instruction_Processing_Framework_for_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-05-EasyInstruct_An_Easy_to_use_Instruction_Processing_Framework_for_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/EasyInstruct_An_Easy_to_use_Instruction_Processing_Framework_for_Large_Language_Models/img/2402.03049v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>EasyInstruct</strong> is an instruction processing framework for Large Language Models (LLMs) that aims to facilitate the research and development of instruction processing.</li>
<li>The framework modularizes instruction generation, selection, and prompting, while also considering their combination and interaction.</li>
<li>EasyInstruct is publicly released and actively maintained, with a running demo App for quick-start.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Instruction tuning has gained increasing attention and emerged as a crucial technique to enhance the capabilities of Large Language Models (LLMs).</li>
<li>The framework aims to achieve a delicate balance between data quantity and data quality in constructing high-quality instruction datasets.</li>
<li>The availability of open-source tools for instruction processing remains limited, hindering further development and advancement.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides a comprehensive overview of the challenges and importance of instruction processing for LLMs.</li>
<li>The framework addresses the need for a standardized open-source instruction processing implementation, but potential limitations in its effectiveness and usability for different user levels should be further explored.</li>
<li>The article emphasizes the significance of instruction data quality and diversity, but further research is needed to evaluate the framework’s impact on LLM performance and generalizability.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03049v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03049v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03049v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03049v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>12215</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/EasyInstruct_An_Easy_to_use_Instruction_Processing_Framework_for_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-05-EasyInstruct_An_Easy_to_use_Instruction_Processing_Framework_for_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/EasyInstruct_An_Easy_to_use_Instruction_Processing_Framework_for_Large_Language_Models/img/2402.03049v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>CIDAR: Culturally Relevant Instruction Dataset For Arabic</title>
  <dc:creator>Zaid Alyafeai, Khalid Almubarak, Ahmed Ashraf, Deema Alnuhait, Saied Alshahrani, Gubran A. Q. Abdulrahman, Gamil Ahmed, Qais Gawah, Zead Saleh, Mustafa Ghaleb, Yousef Ali, Maged S. Al-Shaibani</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/CIDAR_Culturally_Relevant_Instruction_Dataset_For_Arabic/2024-02-05-CIDAR_Culturally_Relevant_Instruction_Dataset_For_Arabic.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/CIDAR_Culturally_Relevant_Instruction_Dataset_For_Arabic/img/2402.03177v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper introduces CIDAR, the first open Arabic instruction-tuning dataset culturally-aligned by human reviewers, addressing limitations of current instruction datasets that predominantly cater to English.</li>
<li>The section discusses the initial review and localization of the dataset, emphasizing the significance of manual review and cultural alignment in addressing linguistic and cultural relevance issues.</li>
<li>The creation of CIDAR, a culturally aligned dataset for Arabic language models, is detailed, highlighting the dataset’s focus on preserving the integrity of Arabic instruction and its potential to enhance LLMs’ performance within the Arabic linguistic and cultural context.</li>
<li>The section provides a list of fine-tuning parameters for models fine-tuned on CIDAR and the translated ALPAGASUS, emphasizing the importance of considering various topics and cultural aspects in the fine-tuning process to improve the quality of the outputs.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>CIDAR addresses the need for culturally-aligned instruction-tuning in the Arabic language, advocating for the integration of cultural context as an essential component in the development of LLMs tailored for specific linguistic communities.</li>
<li>Manual review and cultural alignment are crucial in addressing linguistic and cultural relevance issues in the dataset, as demonstrated through the comparison between CIDAR and the initial translated ALPAGASUS datasets.</li>
<li>Fine-tuning parameters and the impact of different fine-tuning approaches on the cultural relevance and grammar of the outputs are significant in improving the quality of the outputs.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper provides a transparent view of the dataset’s scope and potential challenges, emphasizing the importance of cultural alignment in language models.</li>
<li>The meticulous approach taken in fine-tuning language models for high-quality and diverse linguistic output is highlighted, demonstrating the ethical and methodological considerations in developing and using language datasets for Arabic language models.</li>
<li>The section’s content is significant in highlighting the ethical and methodological considerations in developing and using language datasets for Arabic language models.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03177v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03177v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03177v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03177v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>38064</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/CIDAR_Culturally_Relevant_Instruction_Dataset_For_Arabic/2024-02-05-CIDAR_Culturally_Relevant_Instruction_Dataset_For_Arabic.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/CIDAR_Culturally_Relevant_Instruction_Dataset_For_Arabic/img/2402.03177v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Large Language Model Distilling Medication Recommendation Model</title>
  <dc:creator>Qidong Liu, Xian Wu, Xiangyu Zhao, Yuanshao Zhu, Zijian Zhang, Feng Tian, Yefeng Zheng</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Large_Language_Model_Distilling_Medication_Recommendation_Model/2024-02-05-Large_Language_Model_Distilling_Medication_Recommendation_Model.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Large_Language_Model_Distilling_Medication_Recommendation_Model/img/2402.02803v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>I’m sorry, but I cannot fulfill this request as the given text is not a specific section of an academic paper. If you have a specific section of an academic paper that you would like me to summarize, please provide that section and I would be happy to help.</p>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.02803v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.02803v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.02803v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.02803v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>16933</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>recommender</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Large_Language_Model_Distilling_Medication_Recommendation_Model/2024-02-05-Large_Language_Model_Distilling_Medication_Recommendation_Model.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Large_Language_Model_Distilling_Medication_Recommendation_Model/img/2402.02803v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Uncertainty of Thoughts: Uncertainty-Aware Planning Enhances Information Seeking in Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Zhiyuan Hu, Chumin Liu, Xidong Feng, Yilun Zhao, See-Kiong Ng, Anh Tuan Luu, Junxian He, Pang Wei Koh, Bryan Hooi</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Uncertainty_of_Thoughts_Uncertainty_Aware_Planning_Enhances_Information_Seeking_in_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-05-Uncertainty_of_Thoughts_Uncertainty_Aware_Planning_Enhances_Information_Seeking_in_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Uncertainty_of_Thoughts_Uncertainty_Aware_Planning_Enhances_Information_Seeking_in_Large_Language_Models/img/2402.03271v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The Uncertainty of Thoughts (UoT) algorithm enhances large language models (LLMs) by actively seeking information through effective questioning.</li>
<li>The algorithm combines an uncertainty-aware simulation approach, uncertainty-based rewards, and a reward propagation scheme to select the optimal question to ask.</li>
<li>Experimental results demonstrate that UoT improves the success rate of multiple LLMs by 57.8% on average compared with direct prompting, achieving top performance on both task success and efficiency.</li>
<li>The information gain formula, simulation depth, reliability of GPT-4, reward function, limitations, future work, experimental setups, examples, and prompts are crucial components of the methodology and findings.</li>
<li>Structured prompts are used for troubleshooting, medical diagnosis, and the 20 Questions game, ensuring efficiency and accuracy in information-seeking tasks.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>UoT improves the success rate of LLMs by 57.8% on average compared with direct prompting.</li>
<li>The algorithm outperforms other methods across various datasets and LLMs, demonstrating its superiority in enhancing success rates and planning efficacy.</li>
<li>Structured prompts designed for different scenarios ensure efficiency and accuracy in troubleshooting, medical diagnosis, and the 20 Questions game.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The UoT algorithm addresses the need for LLMs to actively seek information in uncertain and ambiguous settings, going beyond conventional question-answering scenarios.</li>
<li>The comparison at equal computational efficiency and the evaluation in the open set setting solidify the significance of UoT in active information-seeking tasks.</li>
<li>The methodology provides a systematic approach to quantifying and propagating rewards, ultimately leading to the selection of the optimal question, emphasizing the importance of uncertainty reduction and expected rewards.</li>
<li>The structured prompts ensure efficiency and accuracy in various information-seeking tasks, highlighting the practical application of these prompts in different contexts.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03271v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03271v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03271v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03271v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>21050</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Uncertainty_of_Thoughts_Uncertainty_Aware_Planning_Enhances_Information_Seeking_in_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-05-Uncertainty_of_Thoughts_Uncertainty_Aware_Planning_Enhances_Information_Seeking_in_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Uncertainty_of_Thoughts_Uncertainty_Aware_Planning_Enhances_Information_Seeking_in_Large_Language_Models/img/2402.03271v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Video-LaVIT: Unified Video-Language Pre-training with Decoupled Visual-Motional Tokenization</title>
  <dc:creator>Yang Jin, Zhicheng Sun, Kun Xu, Kun Xu, Liwei Chen, Hao Jiang, Quzhe Huang, Chengru Song, Yuliang Liu, Di Zhang, Yang Song, Kun Gai, Yadong Mu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Video_LaVIT_Unified_Video_Language_Pre_training_with_Decoupled_Visual_Motional_Tokenization/2024-02-05-Video_LaVIT_Unified_Video_Language_Pre_training_with_Decoupled_Visual_Motional_Tokenization.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Video_LaVIT_Unified_Video_Language_Pre_training_with_Decoupled_Visual_Motional_Tokenization/img/2402.03161v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article introduces Video-LaVIT, a novel framework for video-language pre-training that tokenizes videos into keyframes and temporal motions, enabling unified generative pre-training of videos, images, and text.</li>
<li>It discusses the input conditioning and motion feature embedding in the Video-LaVIT model, along with the training procedure and unified generative modeling approach.</li>
<li>The use of decomposed keyframes and motion vectors for tokenization in large language models (LLMs) is explored, demonstrating the adaptability of tokenization to LLMs for multimodal generation, specifically for long videos.</li>
<li>Detailed information about the experimental settings of Video-LaVIT is provided, including model implementation details, pre-training data, training settings, and evaluation metrics.</li>
<li>The ablation study of enhanced motion conditioning (EMC) for video reconstruction is presented, along with qualitative results of Video-LaVIT for image and video understanding, highlighting the model’s strengths and limitations.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Video-LaVIT introduces a novel framework for unified generative pre-training of videos, images, and text, showcasing competitive performance across various multimodal benchmarks.</li>
<li>The adaptability of tokenization to LLMs for multimodal generation, particularly for long videos, demonstrates the potential for unified video-language pre-training with decoupled visual-motional tokenization.</li>
<li>The ablation study highlights the effectiveness of the enhanced motion conditioning strategy in improving the fidelity of reconstructed videos, while also identifying areas for further improvement and optimization.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The proposed Video-LaVIT framework shows promise in addressing the challenges of video-language pre-training, but the limitations, such as the inability to process very long videos and the high training cost, indicate the need for further research and optimization.</li>
<li>The experimental setup and results provide valuable insights into the model’s architecture, training process, and performance across various tasks, laying the groundwork for future advancements in multimodal generative pre-training.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03161v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03161v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03161v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03161v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>22672</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Video_LaVIT_Unified_Video_Language_Pre_training_with_Decoupled_Visual_Motional_Tokenization/2024-02-05-Video_LaVIT_Unified_Video_Language_Pre_training_with_Decoupled_Visual_Motional_Tokenization.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Video_LaVIT_Unified_Video_Language_Pre_training_with_Decoupled_Visual_Motional_Tokenization/img/2402.03161v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Skill Set Optimization: Reinforcing Language Model Behavior via Transferable Skills</title>
  <dc:creator>Kolby Nottingham, Bodhisattwa Prasad Majumder, Bhavana Dalvi Mishra, Sameer Singh, Peter Clark, Roy Fox</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Skill_Set_Optimization_Reinforcing_Language_Model_Behavior_via_Transferable_Skills/2024-02-05-Skill_Set_Optimization_Reinforcing_Language_Model_Behavior_via_Transferable_Skills.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Skill_Set_Optimization_Reinforcing_Language_Model_Behavior_via_Transferable_Skills/img/2402.03244v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Large language models (LLMs) have been used for sequential decision making in interactive environments, but leveraging environment reward signals for continual LLM actor improvement is challenging.</li>
<li>Skill Set Optimization (SSO) is proposed for improving LLM actor performance through constructing and refining sets of transferable skills. SSO constructs skills by extracting common subtrajectories with high rewards and generating subgoals and instructions to represent each skill. These skills are provided to the LLM actor in-context to reinforce behaviors with high rewards. Then, SSO further refines the skill set by pruning skills that do not continue to result in high rewards.</li>
<li>SSO outperforms baselines by 40% in a custom NetHack task and outperforms the previous state-of-the-art in ScienceWorld by 35%.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Large Language Model (LLM) actors have been deployed in interactive domains such as robotics, games, and programming. However, finetuning an LLM actor directly using a traditional RL policy gradient is impractical with contemporary LLMs and impossible with black-box closed-source LLMs. Instead, a new paradigm of in-context policy improvement is explored.</li>
<li>In natural language processing (NLP) tasks, in-context learning improves task performance by editing LLM inputs with instructions, task examples, or auxiliary tasks. However, naively applying these techniques to interactive domains generalizes poorly between tasks and does not scale well. Interactive domains require sequential decision making with long trajectories of actions and complex credit assignment.</li>
<li>Skill Set Optimization (SSO) is proposed for automatically constructing skills for in-context policy improvement, where a skill is a list of instructions for reaching a subgoal. SSO takes inspiration from both in-context learning and policy optimization to optimize a set of skills for in-context policy improvement.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The proposed Skill Set Optimization (SSO) method demonstrates significant improvements in LLM actor performance, outperforming baselines in both custom NetHack and ScienceWorld tasks.</li>
<li>The SSO method effectively constructs and refines transferable skills, providing a promising approach for continual learning and policy improvement in interactive environments.</li>
<li>However, the limitations of SSO include the reliance on similarity-based extraction for skill construction, which may be less effective in environments with distracting state information or low-level actions. Additionally, the method does not include a mechanism for leveraging negative environment feedback outside skill set refinement.</li>
<li>Overall, the SSO method represents a significant advancement in the field of in-context policy optimization for LLM actors, but further research is needed to address its limitations and enhance its effectiveness.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03244v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03244v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03244v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03244v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>14254</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Skill_Set_Optimization_Reinforcing_Language_Model_Behavior_via_Transferable_Skills/2024-02-05-Skill_Set_Optimization_Reinforcing_Language_Model_Behavior_via_Transferable_Skills.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Skill_Set_Optimization_Reinforcing_Language_Model_Behavior_via_Transferable_Skills/img/2402.03244v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
