<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Bayesian beagle</title>
<link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Quarto blog of LLM-generated summaries of Arxiv preprints</description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.450</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Large Language Models for Robotics: Opportunities, Challenges, and Perspectives</title>
  <dc:creator>Jiaqi Wang, Zihao Wu, Yiwei Li, Hanqi Jiang, Peng Shu, Enze Shi, Huawen Hu, Chong Ma, Yiheng Liu, Xuhui Wang, Yincheng Yao, Xuan Liu, Huaqin Zhao, Zhengliang Liu, Haixing Dai, Lin Zhao, Bao Ge, Xiang Li, Tianming Liu, Shu Zhang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Large_Language_Models_for_Robotics_Opportunities_Challenges_and_Perspectives/2024-01-09-Large_Language_Models_for_Robotics_Opportunities_Challenges_and_Perspectives.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Large_Language_Models_for_Robotics_Opportunities_Challenges_and_Perspectives/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04334v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="large-language-models-for-robotics-opportunities-challenges-and-perspectives" class="level1">
<h1>Large Language Models for Robotics: Opportunities, Challenges, and Perspectives</h1>
<section id="takeaways" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="takeaways">Takeaways:</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>LLMs</strong> have been increasingly integrated into robotic task planning due to their advanced reasoning and language comprehension capabilities.</li>
<li>The integration of <strong>multimodal GPT-4V</strong> has shown promise in enhancing robot performance in embodied tasks, as demonstrated by diverse datasets.</li>
<li>LLM-centric embodied intelligence holds potential for various applications, such as precision agriculture, healthcare, and brain-computer interfaces.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="i-introduction" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="i-introduction">I Introduction</h2>
<ul>
<li>Large pre-trained models have demonstrated remarkable capabilities across complex tasks in various domains.</li>
<li>The utilization of <strong>instruction tuning</strong> and <strong>alignment tuning</strong> has become the primary approach to adapt LLMs for specific objectives.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="ii-related-work" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="ii-related-work">II Related Work</h2>
<section id="ii-a-llm-for-robotics" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="ii-a-llm-for-robotics">II-A LLM for Robotics</h3>
<ul>
<li>LLMs exhibit exceptional natural language understanding and commonsense reasoning capabilities, contributing to enhanced comprehension and execution for robots.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="ii-b-multimodal-task-planning-with-llms" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="ii-b-multimodal-task-planning-with-llms">II-B Multimodal Task Planning with LLMs</h3>
<ul>
<li>Multimodal LLMs excel in interpreting and correlating multiple data streams, broadening their role from language processing to more integrative functions.</li>
</ul>
</section>
</section>
<section id="iii-scope-of-robotic-tasks" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="iii-scope-of-robotic-tasks">III Scope of Robotic Tasks</h2>
<section id="iii-a-planning" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="iii-a-planning">III-A Planning</h3>
<section id="iii-a1-natural-language-understanding" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="iii-a1-natural-language-understanding">III-A1 Natural Language Understanding</h4>
<ul>
<li>LLMs excel in interpreting natural language instructions and integrating multimodal information to create actionable guidance for virtual agents.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="iii-a2-complex-task-reasoning-and-decision-making" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="iii-a2-complex-task-reasoning-and-decision-making">III-A2 Complex Task Reasoning and Decision-making</h4>
<ul>
<li>LLMs advance complex task reasoning and decision-making through reinforcement learning and collaboration with other modalities.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="iii-a3-human-robot-interaction" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="iii-a3-human-robot-interaction">III-A3 Human-robot interaction</h4>
<ul>
<li>Integration of reinforcement learning with human feedback enables robots to continuously improve their task execution.</li>
</ul>
</section>
</section>
<section id="iii-b-manipulation" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="iii-b-manipulation">III-B Manipulation</h3>
<section id="iii-b1-natural-language-understanding" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="iii-b1-natural-language-understanding">III-B1 Natural Language Understanding</h4>
<ul>
<li>LLMs help robots make common-sense analyses and enhance adaptability to new scenarios, agents, and tasks.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="iii-b2-interactive-strategies" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="iii-b2-interactive-strategies">III-B2 Interactive Strategies</h4>
<ul>
<li>The use of LLMs in robot control focuses on generating interactive reward codes and extracting operants and constraints from LLMs.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="iii-b3-modular-approaches" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="iii-b3-modular-approaches">III-B3 Modular Approaches</h4>
<ul>
<li>Modular approaches enhance system flexibility and adaptability to new tasks and environments.</li>
</ul>
</section>
</section>
<section id="iii-c-reasoning" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="iii-c-reasoning">III-C Reasoning</h3>
<section id="iii-c1-natural-language-understanding" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="iii-c1-natural-language-understanding">III-C1 Natural Language Understanding</h4>
<ul>
<li>LLMs provide common sense insights crucial for various tasks, avoiding the need for costly data gathering and model training.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="iii-c2-complex-task-reasoning-and-decision-making" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="iii-c2-complex-task-reasoning-and-decision-making">III-C2 Complex Task Reasoning and Decision-making</h4>
<ul>
<li>LLMs leverage high-level semantic knowledge to enhance task execution and demonstrate effective performance, even in tasks with intricate settings or specific requirements.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="iii-c3-interactive-strategies" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="iii-c3-interactive-strategies">III-C3 Interactive Strategies</h4>
<ul>
<li>LLMs augment interactive multimodal perception and the development of advanced architectures and interaction patterns.</li>
</ul>
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section id="iv-gpt-4v-empowered-embodied-task-planning" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="iv-gpt-4v-empowered-embodied-task-planning">IV GPT-4V Empowered Embodied Task Planning</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>GPT-4V</strong> has demonstrated impressive performance in multimodal task planning across diverse environments and scenarios.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="v-experimental-results" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="v-experimental-results">V Experimental Results</h2>
<ul>
<li>The matching score for the generated task plans consistently reflects a high level of agreement between the LLM-generated plans and the ground truth demonstrations.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="vi-limitation-discussion-and-future-work" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="vi-limitation-discussion-and-future-work">VI Limitation, Discussion and Future Work</h2>
<ul>
<li>Challenges include homogenous generated plans, the need for carefully crafted prompts, and the closed-source nature of the <strong>GPT-4V API</strong>.</li>
<li>Future work focuses on addressing these challenges and developing more robust AGI robotic systems.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="vii-conclusion" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="vii-conclusion">VII Conclusion</h2>
<ul>
<li>LLMs demonstrate impressive reasoning, language understanding, and multimodal processing abilities that can significantly enhance robotic comprehension and task execution.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h2>
<p>The paper provides a comprehensive overview and evaluation of LLMs and multimodal LLMs in robotic tasks. However, it would benefit from addressing potential biases in the evaluation process and considering the ethical implications of implementing advanced LLMs in robotics. Additionally, the critique would be enhanced by acknowledging potential limitations in the generalization of study results to real-world applications.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-10</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04334v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04334v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04334v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04334v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>14055</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Large_Language_Models_for_Robotics_Opportunities_Challenges_and_Perspectives/2024-01-09-Large_Language_Models_for_Robotics_Opportunities_Challenges_and_Perspectives.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04334v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Chain-of-Table: Evolving Tables in the Reasoning Chain for Table Understanding</title>
  <dc:creator>Zilong Wang, Hao Zhang, Chun-Liang Li, Julian Martin Eisenschlos, Vincent Perot, Zifeng Wang, Lesly Miculicich, Yasuhisa Fujii, Jingbo Shang, Chen-Yu Lee, Tomas Pfister</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Chain_of_Table_Evolving_Tables_in_the_Reasoning_Chain_for_Table_Understanding/2024-01-09-Chain_of_Table_Evolving_Tables_in_the_Reasoning_Chain_for_Table_Understanding.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Chain_of_Table_Evolving_Tables_in_the_Reasoning_Chain_for_Table_Understanding/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04398v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="chain-of-table-evolving-tables-in-the-reasoning-chain-for-table-understanding" class="level1">
<h1>Chain-of-Table: Evolving Tables in the Reasoning Chain for Table Understanding</h1>
<section id="key-findings" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="key-findings">Key Findings</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Table-based reasoning</strong> requires extraction of underlying semantics from both free-form questions and semi-structured tabular data.</li>
<li>The proposed <strong>Chain-of-Table framework</strong> achieves new state-of-the-art performance on WikiTQ, FeTaQA, and TabFact benchmarks across multiple LLM choices.</li>
<li>The framework <strong>outperforms</strong> generic reasoning and program-aided reasoning methods on TabFact and WikiTQ.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="abstract" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="abstract">Abstract</h2>
<p>The paper discusses the challenges of table-based reasoning and introduces the Chain-of-Table framework to leverage tabular data in the reasoning chain. It explains the use of in-context learning to iteratively generate operations and update the table, leading to a chain showing the reasoning process for a given tabular problem. The study also presents the outperformance of Chain-of-Table on multiple benchmarks.</p>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>The introduction highlights the importance of table understanding and the promising direction of table-based reasoning with large language models (LLMs). The authors discuss the limitations of existing approaches and propose the Chain-of-Table framework as a solution.</p>
</section>
<section id="related-work" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="related-work">Related Work</h2>
<p>The section provides an overview of previous methods for fine-tuning language models for table understanding and program-aided reasoning for solving table-based tasks. It points out the shortcomings of existing methods in addressing complex table scenarios and sets the context for the proposed Chain-of-Table framework.</p>
</section>
<section id="chain-of-table-reasoning" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="chain-of-table-reasoning">Chain-of-Table Reasoning</h2>
<p>The paper delves into the Chain-of-Table reasoning, discussing the problem formulation, overview, dynamic planning, argument generation, and final query stages. It explains the specific table operations used in the framework and presents an ablation study to demonstrate their effectiveness.</p>
</section>
<section id="experiments" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="experiments">Experiments</h2>
<p>The results of the experiments on WikiTQ, TabFact, and FeTaQA benchmarks are presented, along with comparisons with baseline methods. The performance analysis under different operation chain lengths and table sizes is discussed, showing the effectiveness of Chain-of-Table across various scenarios.</p>
</section>
<section id="efficiency-analysis-of-chain-of-table" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="efficiency-analysis-of-chain-of-table">Efficiency Analysis of Chain-of-Table</h2>
<p>The efficiency of the Chain-of-Table framework is analyzed in terms of the number of required generated samples compared to baseline methods. The study shows the improved efficiency of Chain-of-Table in generating queries for tabular reasoning.</p>
</section>
<section id="case-study" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="case-study">Case Study</h2>
<p>A case study is presented to illustrate the tabular reasoning process in Chain-of-Table, showcasing how the framework facilitates correct answers by dynamically planning an operation chain and accurately storing intermediate results.</p>
</section>
<section id="conclusion" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>The paper concludes by emphasizing the enhanced reasoning capability of LLMs with Chain-of-Table and the potential for leveraging tabular structure to express intermediate thoughts for table-based reasoning. Additionally, it highlights the role of Chain-of-Table in instructing LLMs to dynamically plan operation chains for improved table understanding.</p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level1">
<h1>Critique</h1>
<p>The paper provides valuable insights into the challenges of table-based reasoning and offers a promising framework with the Chain-of-Table. However, it would benefit from including a more in-depth discussion of potential limitations or constraints of the proposed framework, as well as addressing any potential biases or shortcomings in the experimental design and data analysis. Additionally, the paper could expand on the scalability and generalizability of the proposed framework to various real-world applications and datasets.</p>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-10</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04398v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04398v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04398v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04398v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>9507</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Chain_of_Table_Evolving_Tables_in_the_Reasoning_Chain_for_Table_Understanding/2024-01-09-Chain_of_Table_Evolving_Tables_in_the_Reasoning_Chain_for_Table_Understanding.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04398v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>TransportationGames: Benchmarking Transportation Knowledge of (Multimodal) Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Xue Zhang, Xiangyu Shi, Xinyue Lou, Rui Qi, Yufeng Chen, Jinan Xu, Wenjuan Han</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/TransportationGames_Benchmarking_Transportation_Knowledge_of_(Multimodal)_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-09-TransportationGames_Benchmarking_Transportation_Knowledge_of_(Multimodal)_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/TransportationGames_Benchmarking_Transportation_Knowledge_of_(Multimodal)_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04471v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="major-takeaways" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-takeaways">Major Takeaways</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li><p><strong>TransportationGames</strong> is a comprehensive evaluation benchmark designed to assess the capabilities of (M)LLMs in executing transportation-related tasks. It categorizes these tasks into three skill levels based on widely recognized Bloom’s cognitive models: Transportation knowledge memorization, understanding, and applying.</p></li>
<li><p>Evaluation results show that while some models perform well in certain tasks, there is still much <strong>room for improvement</strong> overall. This suggests that (M)LLMs may not possess reliable transportation knowledge and struggle with transportation-related tasks.</p></li>
<li><p>The study not only identifies the performance of various (M)LLMs but also analyzes the key factors affecting model performance. It hopes that the release of TransportationGames can serve as a foundation for future research, thereby accelerating the implementation and application of (M)LLMs in the <strong>transportation domain</strong>.</p></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<ul>
<li>Large language models (LLMs) and multimodal large language models (MLLMs) have shown exceptional general capabilities and are increasingly being utilized across various professional domains.</li>
<li>Evaluation benchmarks are crucial for assessing (M)LLMs and gaining insights into their strengths and weaknesses. Domain-specific benchmarks are especially important for driving practical progress and responsible implementation.</li>
<li>There is a lack of systematic evaluation benchmarks for the transportation domain, prompting the introduction of TransportationGames to assess (M)LLMs in transportation-related tasks.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="benchmark-construction" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="benchmark-construction">Benchmark Construction</h2>
<ul>
<li>TransportationGames is organized using the first three levels in <strong>Bloom’s Taxonomy</strong> to evaluate (M)LLMs. It includes 10 tasks based on diverse sub-domains in the transportation domain, employing multiple-choice, “True/False” judge, and text generation formats.</li>
<li>The tasks are categorized into three skill levels: Transportation knowledge memorization, understanding, and applying, to offer a systematic outline of the skillset necessary for transportation-related tasks.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="experiments" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="experiments">Experiments</h2>
<ul>
<li>The evaluation results of LLMs on the text-only dataset of TransportationGames show varying performance across different models. Similarly, MLLMs exhibit differing performance on the multimodal dataset.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="analysis" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis">Analysis</h2>
<ul>
<li>The study observes that the format error rate of some models is zero, indicating excellent instruction-following ability. There is still much <strong>room for improvement</strong> for some tasks, especially in multimodal scenarios.</li>
<li>The choice of BaseModel significantly affects model performance, and scaling up the model size can improve performance with similar BaseModels.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="conclusion" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<ul>
<li>The release of TransportationGames serves as a foundation for future research and hopes to accelerate the implementation and application of (M)LLMs in the field of transportation.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Data Leakage:</strong> The study mentions the potential issue of data leakage as the data is collected from the internet. This could impact the fairness of the evaluation.</li>
<li><strong>Model and Task Selection:</strong> Due to time constraints, only a small portion of common models were tested. Additionally, the selection of evaluation tasks may not fully represent all aspects of the transportation domain.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-10</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04471v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04471v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04471v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04471v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7381</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/TransportationGames_Benchmarking_Transportation_Knowledge_of_(Multimodal)_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-09-TransportationGames_Benchmarking_Transportation_Knowledge_of_(Multimodal)_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04471v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>MERA: A Comprehensive LLM Evaluation in Russian</title>
  <dc:creator>Alena Fenogenova, Artem Chervyakov, Nikita Martynov, Anastasia Kozlova, Maria Tikhonova, Albina Akhmetgareeva, Anton Emelyanov, Denis Shevelev, Pavel Lebedev, Leonid Sinev, Ulyana Isaeva, Katerina Kolomeytseva, Daniil Moskovskiy, Elizaveta Goncharova, Nikita Savushkin, Polina Mikhailova, Denis Dimitrov, Alexander Panchenko, Sergei Markov</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MERA_A_Comprehensive_LLM_Evaluation_in_Russian/2024-01-09-MERA_A_Comprehensive_LLM_Evaluation_in_Russian.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MERA_A_Comprehensive_LLM_Evaluation_in_Russian/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-mera-a-comprehensive-llm-evaluation-in-russian" class="level1">
<h1>Summary of “MERA: A Comprehensive LLM Evaluation in Russian”</h1>
<section id="major-takeaways" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-takeaways">Major Takeaways</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>MERA</strong> is a widely used assessment tool for evaluating language proficiency in Russian as a foreign language.</li>
<li>The evaluation encompasses four key language skills: <strong>listening, reading, writing, and speaking</strong>, providing a comprehensive analysis of a learner’s language abilities.</li>
<li>The MERA evaluation aims to standardize the assessment process and provide reliable results for individuals and institutions seeking to gauge Russian language proficiency.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<ul>
<li>MERA is a widely recognized assessment tool used to evaluate proficiency in the Russian language.</li>
<li>It offers a comprehensive evaluation of language skills, including listening, reading, writing, and speaking.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="key-features-of-mera" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="key-features-of-mera">Key Features of MERA</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Comprehensive Evaluation</strong>: MERA assesses proficiency in all four language skills, providing a holistic view of an individual’s language abilities.</li>
<li><strong>Standardization</strong>: The evaluation aims to standardize the assessment process, ensuring consistent and reliable results.</li>
<li><strong>Different Levels</strong>: MERA offers evaluations at various levels, accommodating learners at different stages of language proficiency.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="components-of-the-evaluation" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="components-of-the-evaluation">Components of the Evaluation</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Listening</strong>: This component assesses the ability to comprehend spoken Russian, including understanding conversations and speeches.</li>
<li><strong>Reading</strong>: The reading component evaluates comprehension of written Russian texts, including articles and literary works.</li>
<li><strong>Writing</strong>: MERA assesses writing skills, including grammar, vocabulary usage, and overall coherence in written expression.</li>
<li><strong>Speaking</strong>: The speaking component evaluates oral proficiency, including pronunciation, fluency, and communication skills.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h2>
<p>The paper could benefit from providing more specific details about the development and validation of the MERA evaluation tool. Additionally, it would be helpful to include data on the reliability and validity of the assessment to support its widespread usage. There may also be a need for further research on the effectiveness of MERA in accurately gauging Russian language proficiency in diverse contexts and learner populations.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-10</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04531v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04531v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04531v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04531v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>19</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MERA_A_Comprehensive_LLM_Evaluation_in_Russian/2024-01-09-MERA_A_Comprehensive_LLM_Evaluation_in_Russian.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>TechGPT-2.0: A large language model project to solve the task of knowledge graph construction</title>
  <dc:creator>Jiaqi Wang, Yuying Chang, Zhong Li, Ning An, Qi Ma, Lei Hei, Haibo Luo, Yifei Lu, Feiliang Ren</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/TechGPT_2.0_A_large_language_model_project_to_solve_the_task_of_knowledge_graph_construction/2024-01-09-TechGPT_2.0_A_large_language_model_project_to_solve_the_task_of_knowledge_graph_construction.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/TechGPT_2.0_A_large_language_model_project_to_solve_the_task_of_knowledge_graph_construction/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="major-takeaways" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-takeaways">Major Takeaways</h3>
<ul>
<li>The <strong>abstract</strong> provides a general overview of the document, stating that it contains a template for PRIME AI Style without specific details.</li>
<li>The document consists of various <strong>sections</strong> including “Introduction,” “Headings,” “Examples of citations, figures, tables, references,” and “Conclusion.” Each section contains specific subheadings.</li>
<li>The <strong>examples of citations, figures, tables, references</strong> section includes details about citations, with references to specific sources, figures, and tables.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h3>
<ul>
<li>The introduction provides some general text, including comments on various topics, but lacks specific details about the content.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="headings-first-level" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="headings-first-level">Headings: First Level</h3>
<ul>
<li>This section discusses <strong>Ullamcorper placerat ipsum</strong> and provides a brief overview of the content but lacks specific details.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="headings-second-level" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="headings-second-level">Headings: Second Level</h3>
<ul>
<li>This section delves into <strong>Fusce mauris</strong> and discusses <strong>Sed bibendum</strong> and provides an overview but lacks specific details.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="headings-third-level" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="headings-third-level">Headings: Third Level</h3>
<ul>
<li>This section discusses <strong>Suspendisse vel felis</strong> and provides an overview but lacks specific details.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="examples-of-citations-figures-tables-references" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="examples-of-citations-figures-tables-references">Examples of Citations, Figures, Tables, References</h3>
<ul>
<li>The section details <strong>citations</strong>, reference <strong>documentation</strong>, and includes references to specific sources, <strong>figures</strong>, and <strong>tables</strong>.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="conclusion" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="conclusion">Conclusion</h3>
<ul>
<li>The conclusion is placeholder text and lacks specific details.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<p>The document lacks specific details and content, providing only general placeholders for various sections. It also lacks clarity in communicating the intended content, making it difficult for readers to understand the actual purpose or substance of the document. Additionally, there is inconsistency in formatting and a lack of detailed examples, making it challenging for readers to apply the provided template effectively. More specific and substantive content would greatly enhance the usefulness and clarity of this document.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-10</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04507v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04507v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04507v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04507v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>1974</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/TechGPT_2.0_A_large_language_model_project_to_solve_the_task_of_knowledge_graph_construction/2024-01-09-TechGPT_2.0_A_large_language_model_project_to_solve_the_task_of_knowledge_graph_construction.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Exploring Prompt-Based Methods for Zero-Shot Hypernym Prediction with Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Mikhail Tikhomirov, Natalia Loukachevitch</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Exploring_Prompt_Based_Methods_for_Zero_Shot_Hypernym_Prediction_with_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-09-Exploring_Prompt_Based_Methods_for_Zero_Shot_Hypernym_Prediction_with_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Exploring_Prompt_Based_Methods_for_Zero_Shot_Hypernym_Prediction_with_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04515v1/extracted/5337813/scheme1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="main-takeaways" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="main-takeaways">Main Takeaways</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The study explores a <strong>zero-shot approach to hypernymy prediction</strong> using large language models (LLMs), demonstrating a strong correlation between the effectiveness of language model prompts and classic patterns.</li>
<li>The article investigates prompts for predicting <strong>co-hyponyms</strong> and improving hypernymy predictions by augmenting prompts with additional information through automatically identified co-hyponyms, leading to significant improvements in prediction quality.</li>
<li>The research also develops an <strong>iterative approach for predicting higher-level concepts</strong>, further improving the quality of hypernym chain prediction on the BLESS dataset.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h3>
<ul>
<li>Taxonomies play a crucial role in knowledge organization, and extracting taxonomic relationships from text data has been a focus of extensive research.</li>
<li><strong>Hypernym acquisition</strong> techniques include linear patterns, unsupervised and supervised vector-based techniques, and large language models based on neural transformer architectures, allowing for the study of novel methods for hypernym prediction.</li>
<li>The article investigates the research questions related to the consistency of language models on a set of prompts, the benefits of co-hyponym prompts for hypernym prediction, and the possibility of improving hypernym chain prediction using prompts.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="related-works" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="related-works">Related Works</h3>
<section id="pattern-based-approaches" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="pattern-based-approaches">Pattern-based approaches</h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Pattern-based approach</strong> involves exploiting certain lexico-syntactic patterns to detect hypernym relations in text, with efforts to increase recall and precision of extracted relationships.</li>
<li>Strategies to improve recall of patterns include using extended sets of patterns and applying Singular Value Decomposition to reduce the dimensionality of the matrix describing ppmi weights for words met in the patterns.</li>
<li><strong>Co-hyponym patterns</strong> are also used as an additional source of information for hypernym detection.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="unsupervised-vector-based-approaches" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="unsupervised-vector-based-approaches">Unsupervised vector-based approaches</h4>
<ul>
<li>This approach is based on the methods of distributional semantics and focuses on the distributional inclusion hypothesis, distributional exclusivity hypothesis, and distributional informativeness hypothesis.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="zero-shot-prompts-for-large-language-models" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="zero-shot-prompts-for-large-language-models">Zero-shot prompts for large language models</h4>
<ul>
<li>Large language models like BERT and GPT are utilized for predicting hypernyms based on classical lexico-syntactic patterns, with studies highlighting the importance of unambiguous prompts encoding hypernymy and the competitive nature of the most frequent prompts in pretraining corpora.</li>
</ul>
</section>
</section>
<section id="approach" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="approach">Approach</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study focuses on an approach to exploiting prompts and maps a pair of terms and a prompt type to a single sentence, estimating the probabilities of hypernyms using language models.</li>
<li>The primary idea is to experiment with prompts combinations, including <strong>combinations of hypernym prompts, combinations of hypernym and co-hyponym prompts, and iterative application of hypernym prompts</strong>.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="datasets-and-models" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="datasets-and-models">Datasets and Models</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study experiments with datasets from the hypernymysuite benchmark and evaluates prompts and models in two different task settings of hypernym prediction.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="single-prompts-experiments" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="single-prompts-experiments">Single prompts experiments</h3>
<section id="hypernym-prompts" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="hypernym-prompts">Hypernym prompts</h4>
<ul>
<li>The investigation of 76 prompts for hypernymy prediction highlighted that the performance varies significantly across different prompts and large language models, with <strong>selective variant of the hypernym probability estimation being superior to the full variant</strong>.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="co-hyponym-prompts" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="co-hyponym-prompts">Co-hyponym prompts</h4>
<ul>
<li>The study considered four types of co-hyponym prompts based on enumeration patterns, and the evaluation results on 11 prompts demonstrated that the prompt “such as hypo, cohypo, and others of the same type” showed the best quality for both the full and selective approaches.</li>
</ul>
</section>
</section>
<section id="combinations" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="combinations">Combinations</h3>
<section id="combinations-of-hypernyms-prompts" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="combinations-of-hypernyms-prompts">Combinations of hypernyms prompts</h4>
<ul>
<li>The study investigated if combining different hypernym prompts could enhance hypernym prediction, but estaurs that this approach did not improve the ranking quality for most models.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="co-hyponym-augmented-prompts" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="co-hyponym-augmented-prompts">Co-hyponym-augmented prompts</h4>
<ul>
<li>The concept of combining co-hyponyms with hypernyms prompts was analyzed, highlighting different variations with some significantly improving the quality of hypernymy predictions.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="iterative-approach-to-ranking-a-list-of-hypernyms" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="iterative-approach-to-ranking-a-list-of-hypernyms">Iterative approach to ranking a list of hypernyms</h4>
<ul>
<li>An iterative approach was developed for hypernym predictions, demonstrating overall improvements in quality on the BLESS dataset.</li>
</ul>
</section>
</section>
<section id="conclusion" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="conclusion">Conclusion</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study recommends using the probability estimate of the entire sequence and answers the three research questions posed.</li>
<li>The best quality on the BLESS dataset (MAP 0.8 from 0.7 with straightforward approach) was achieved by using the full method, co-hyponym-augmented prompt “hypo, cohypo are an hyper that,” and the iterative approach.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<p>The article provides comprehensive insights into the zero-shot hypernym prediction approach using large language models. However, the evaluation method for these datasets is noted to be not entirely correct, and there are recommendations to improve the evaluation process. Additionally, the study could benefit from further discussion on the potential limitations and challenges associated with the proposed methods.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-10</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04515v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04515v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04515v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04515v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7734</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Exploring_Prompt_Based_Methods_for_Zero_Shot_Hypernym_Prediction_with_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-09-Exploring_Prompt_Based_Methods_for_Zero_Shot_Hypernym_Prediction_with_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04515v1/extracted/5337813/scheme1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Fighting Fire with Fire: Adversarial Prompting to Generate a Misinformation Detection Dataset</title>
  <dc:creator>Shrey Satapara, Parth Mehta, Debasis Ganguly, Sandip Modha</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Fighting_Fire_with_Fire_Adversarial_Prompting_to_Generate_a_Misinformation_Detection_Dataset/2024-01-09-Fighting_Fire_with_Fire_Adversarial_Prompting_to_Generate_a_Misinformation_Detection_Dataset.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Fighting_Fire_with_Fire_Adversarial_Prompting_to_Generate_a_Misinformation_Detection_Dataset/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04481v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><p><strong>Language models</strong> such as GPT, Bard, and Llama have advanced capabilities to generate highly convincing yet potentially misleading content, leading to concerns about the spread of fake news and misinformation via social media.</p></li>
<li><p>Traditional fact-checking mechanisms depend on validating content against reliable information from verified sources, which is a resource-intensive task, especially with the potential of large language models to generate misinformation at scale.</p></li>
<li><p>The paper proposes an <strong>adversarial prompting approach</strong> to generate a dataset for identifying misinformation, leveraging large language models to create a robust fake news dataset that captures various misinformation patterns, including fabrication, misrepresentation, false attribution, and inaccurate quantities.</p></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="dataset-construction" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="dataset-construction">Dataset Construction</h3>
<ul>
<li><p>The research leverages large language models to generate both factually correct and misleading summaries of news articles, with types of misinformation including <strong>fabrication</strong>, <strong>false attribution</strong>, <strong>inaccurate numerical quantities</strong>, and <strong>misrepresentation</strong>. This dataset aims to aid in training models for misinformation detection and fact verification.</p></li>
<li><p>The dataset contains about 5000 correct and 1000 incorrect summaries across four categories and covers diverse topics such as sports, movies, technology, and political events.</p></li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="evaluation-of-misinformation-detection" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="evaluation-of-misinformation-detection">Evaluation of Misinformation Detection</h3>
<ul>
<li><p>The paper presents two experimental setups for evaluating misinformation detection on the dataset: one as a standalone fact-checking task, and the other as a traditional fact-checking setup where summaries are verified against existing articles or a knowledge base.</p></li>
<li><p>Experimental results indicate that large language models perform significantly better than traditional machine learning models such as <strong>SVC</strong> or <strong>LSTMs</strong> in both setups. <strong>BERT</strong> and <strong>RoBERTa</strong> show the best performance, especially when provided with a reference article during training.</p></li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="future-work" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="future-work">Future Work</h3>
<ul>
<li><p>The research highlights the importance of pinpointing specific types of incorrectness in misinformation, suggesting the need for more robust models to identify and combat misinformation effectively.</p></li>
<li><p>Future work may involve extending the dataset to cover multiple languages and further improving the capability of machine learning models to detect and classify misinformation.</p></li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<p>The paper provides valuable insights into the generation of a misinformation detection dataset using large language models but lacks in-depth discussion on the potential ethical implications of using adversarial prompting and distributing a dataset that includes misleading information. Additionally, transparency regarding the creation of misleading content and the potential impact on society is essential and should be addressed in future work.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-10</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04481v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04481v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04481v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04481v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6577</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Fighting_Fire_with_Fire_Adversarial_Prompting_to_Generate_a_Misinformation_Detection_Dataset/2024-01-09-Fighting_Fire_with_Fire_Adversarial_Prompting_to_Generate_a_Misinformation_Detection_Dataset.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04481v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Rewriting the Code: A Simple Method for Large Language Model Augmented Code Search</title>
  <dc:creator>Haochen Li, Xin Zhou, Zhiqi Shen</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Rewriting_the_Code_A_Simple_Method_for_Large_Language_Model_Augmented_Code_Search/2024-01-09-Rewriting_the_Code_A_Simple_Method_for_Large_Language_Model_Augmented_Code_Search.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Rewriting_the_Code_A_Simple_Method_for_Large_Language_Model_Augmented_Code_Search/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04514v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-rewriting-the-code-a-simple-method-for-large-language-model-augmented-code-search" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-of-rewriting-the-code-a-simple-method-for-large-language-model-augmented-code-search">Summary of “Rewriting the Code: A Simple Method for Large Language Model Augmented Code Search”</h2>
<section id="major-takeaways" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-takeaways">Major Takeaways</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Code search</strong> is a common software development activity aimed at retrieving relevant code snippets from a codebase based on natural language queries. The discrepancy in grammatical rules between natural language and code constraints search retrieval performance.</li>
<li>The Generation-Augmented Retrieval (GAR) framework showed limited improvement due to the significant stylistic difference between exemplar code and true code.</li>
<li>The proposed <strong>Rewrites the Code (ReCo)</strong> method significantly improved retrieval accuracy for both sparse and dense retrieval systems across diverse search scenarios, demonstrating the effectiveness of style normalization in code search.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h3>
<ul>
<li>Traditional code search methods suffer from vocabulary mismatch problems due to the grammatical discrepancy between programming languages and natural languages. Dense retrieval systems offer potential semantic connections but struggle with rare terminological associations.</li>
<li>The paper proposes the Generation-Augmented Retrieval (GAR) framework, where Large Language Models (LLMs) generate exemplar code snippets to augment natural language queries for code search. However, LLM-augmented GAR showed limited performance improvement due to stylistic deviations between generated and true code snippets.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="methodology" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="methodology">Methodology</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>ReCo:</strong> The paper introduces a method that not only generates exemplar codes based on the query but also rewrites the codes in the codebase. This process involves summarizing the code into a natural language description and then using this description to generate a rewritten code that aligns with the exemplar code’s style. Experimental results demonstrated significant retrieval accuracy improvements with ReCo across various search scenarios.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="code-style-similarity" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="code-style-similarity">Code Style Similarity</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper proposes a novel evaluation metric, <strong>Code Style Similarity (CSSim)</strong>, to quantify the disparity in code style. This metric evaluates style from three dimensions: variable naming, API invocation, and code structure, based on edit distance. Empirical findings revealed superior explanatory power of CSSim in measuring the style deviation of code compared to existing metrics.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="experimental-setups" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="experimental-setups">Experimental Setups</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper evaluated ReCo across various search scenarios and programming languages, demonstrating its effectiveness in boosting retrieval performance. Comparison among evaluation metrics, impact of LLMs, and the number of generated codes were investigated to validate the superiority of CSSim and the effectiveness of ReCo.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="discussion" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="discussion">Discussion</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper highlights the potential impact of ReCo on various code-related tasks and proposes future work to develop specific models for code style normalization. The authors intend to train models to improve the efficiency of ReCo in practical applications.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<p>The paper’s approach in introducing ReCo and CSSim is innovative and addresses a significant limitation in code search with LLM-augmented methods. However, the experimental results are limited to simulated settings, and the real-world impact of ReCo in production systems needs to be further explored. Additionally, the paper could benefit from a deeper discussion on potential drawbacks or limitations of the ReCo method, as well as considerations for efficiency and scalability in real-time search systems.</p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-10</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04514v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04514v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04514v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04514v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8696</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Rewriting_the_Code_A_Simple_Method_for_Large_Language_Model_Augmented_Code_Search/2024-01-09-Rewriting_the_Code_A_Simple_Method_for_Large_Language_Model_Augmented_Code_Search.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04514v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Know Your Needs Better: Towards Structured Understanding of Marketer Demands with Analogical Reasoning Augmented LLMs</title>
  <dc:creator>Junjie Wang, Dan Yang, Binbin Hu, Yue Shen, Ziqi Liu, Wen Zhang, Jinjie Gu, Zhiqiang Zhang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Know_Your_Needs_Better_Towards_Structured_Understanding_of_Marketer_Demands_with_Analogical_Reasoning_Augmented_LLMs/2024-01-09-Know_Your_Needs_Better_Towards_Structured_Understanding_of_Marketer_Demands_with_Analogical_Reasoning_Augmented_LLMs.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Know_Your_Needs_Better_Towards_Structured_Understanding_of_Marketer_Demands_with_Analogical_Reasoning_Augmented_LLMs/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04319v1/x2.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="major-takeaways" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-takeaways">Major Takeaways</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper introduces a new approach for user targeting that leverages Large Language Models (LLMs) to gain a structured understanding of marketers’ demands.</li>
<li>The proposed framework, ARALLM, consisting of Analogical Reasoning based Prompting and Reasoning-Augmented Multi-Task Model Distillation, shows superior performance in the NL2SELL task through extensive experiments on real-world datasets.</li>
<li>The Analogical Reasoning based Prompting method significantly outperforms other prompting methods, especially in terms of structural accuracy, demonstrating the effectiveness of using analogical examples to provide a logical structure for reasoning.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h3>
<ul>
<li>User targeting has gained significant attention in real-world applications, and current approaches mainly fall into model-based and rule-based methods. However, the gap between marketers’ demands and the capabilities of current models remains a challenge.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="structured-understanding-of-marketer-demands" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="structured-understanding-of-marketer-demands">Structured Understanding of Marketer Demands</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper proposes a novel language, SELL, and aims to transform natural language demands into SELL to enhance current user targeting systems.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="methods" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="methods">Methods</h3>
<ul>
<li>The Analogical Reasoning based Prompting method is introduced, leveraging a reasoning library to provide references for unknown demands through analogical reasoning.</li>
<li>A framework called ARALLM, comprising Analogical Reasoning based Prompting and Reasoning-Augmented Multi-Task Model Distillation, is proposed to address the NL2SELL task.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="experiments" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="experiments">Experiments</h3>
<ul>
<li>Results demonstrate the superiority of the proposed ARALLM framework through extensive experiments on real-world datasets, showcasing better performance in the NL2SELL task compared to baseline methods.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="application" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="application">Application</h3>
<ul>
<li>The ARALLM framework has been deployed online for user targeting, and the system’s operation time is significantly shorter with promising feedback from marketers.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="related-work" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="related-work">Related Work</h3>
<ul>
<li>Previous studies on user targeting have mainly focused on intricate architectures, overlooking the natural and significant gap between marketers’ demands and the capabilities of current models.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="conclusion-and-future-work" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="conclusion-and-future-work">Conclusion and Future Work</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper presents a novel approach for user targeting and suggests future work on exploring more automated construction methods for reasoning libraries and SELL datasets.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<ul>
<li>While the paper provides a comprehensive approach to structured understanding of marketer demands, the complexity of the proposed Analogical Reasoning based Prompting method may limit its practical applicability in real-world industrial scenarios. Further, the heavy reliance on expert knowledge and manual calibration raises concerns about scalability and generalizability.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the paper contributes to advancing the understanding of marketer demands using LLMs and analogical reasoning, but there are potential limitations in terms of practical implementation and scalability.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-10</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04319v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04319v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04319v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04319v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>9552</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>recommender</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Know_Your_Needs_Better_Towards_Structured_Understanding_of_Marketer_Demands_with_Analogical_Reasoning_Augmented_LLMs/2024-01-09-Know_Your_Needs_Better_Towards_Structured_Understanding_of_Marketer_Demands_with_Analogical_Reasoning_Augmented_LLMs.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04319v1/x2.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Improving the Robustness of Knowledge-Grounded Dialogue via Contrastive Learning</title>
  <dc:creator>Jiaan Wang, Jianfeng Qu, Kexin Wang, Zhixu Li, Wen Hua, Ximing Li, An Liu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Improving_the_Robustness_of_Knowledge_Grounded_Dialogue_via_Contrastive_Learning/2024-01-09-Improving_the_Robustness_of_Knowledge_Grounded_Dialogue_via_Contrastive_Learning.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Improving_the_Robustness_of_Knowledge_Grounded_Dialogue_via_Contrastive_Learning/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04361v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="main-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="main-findings">Main Findings</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Robustness Challenges</strong>: The paper highlights the robustness challenges faced by knowledge-grounded dialogue (KGD) systems in real-world applications, such as misspellings, abbreviations, and incomplete/erroneous knowledge facts in knowledge graphs (KGs).</li>
<li><strong>Contrastive Learning Framework</strong>: The authors propose an entity-based contrastive learning framework (EnCo) to improve the robustness of KGD models by creating positive and negative samples, which involve semantic-irrelevant and semantic-relevant perturbations, respectively.</li>
<li><strong>Performance Results</strong>: Experimental results on three benchmark datasets demonstrate that the EnCo framework achieves new state-of-the-art performance in terms of automatic evaluation scores, and it outperforms comparison models in both noisy and few-shot settings.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h3>
<p>The paper introduces the concept of knowledge-grounded dialogue (KGD) and the challenges it faces in real-world applications due to various noises in dialogue context and knowledge graphs. It also discusses the rapid development of large language models (LLMs) and the need to improve the robustness of KGD systems.</p>
</section>
<section id="methodology" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="methodology">Methodology</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Positive Sample Construction</strong>: The paper describes the process of creating positive samples using paraphrasing and truncation from the vanilla samples, along with the entity-guided paraphrasing approach.</li>
<li><strong>Negative Sample Construction</strong>: The authors detail the construction of negative samples involving semantic-relevant perturbations using entity information and the entity-guided negative augmentation strategy.</li>
<li><strong>Contrastive Learning Framework</strong>: The proposed EnCo framework utilizes contrastive learning to train the KGD model to distinguish perturbations in positive and negative samples.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="experiments" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="experiments">Experiments</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Implementation Details</strong>: The authors provide implementation details, including the use of PyTorch, Huggingface Transformers library, and model training settings.</li>
<li><strong>Experimental Setups</strong>: The experiments are conducted on three public KGD datasets, and the authors compare the performance of EnCo with multiple baselines.</li>
<li><strong>Main Results</strong>: Tables are presented to show the results on the benchmark datasets, indicating the effectiveness of the EnCo framework.</li>
<li><strong>Robustness Study</strong>: The paper includes a study on the model’s performance when faced with real-world noises, showing the robustness of the EnCo framework.</li>
<li><strong>Ablation Results, Few-Shot Results, and Human Study</strong>: Various experiments and human studies are conducted to evaluate the effectiveness of the proposed method in different scenarios.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="conclusion" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="conclusion">Conclusion</h3>
<p>The paper concludes by summarizing the contributions and effectiveness of the EnCo framework in addressing robustness challenges in KGD models.</p>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper lacks a detailed discussion on potential limitations or drawbacks of the proposed EnCo framework.</li>
<li>The human study results, while supportive, could benefit from a larger and more diverse set of evaluators to ensure the reliability of the findings.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the paper presents a comprehensive approach to improving the robustness of KGD models through contrastive learning and provides experimental evidence of its effectiveness. However, further exploration of potential limitations and broader validation of human study results could strengthen the paper’s findings.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-10</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04361v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04361v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04361v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04361v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8188</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Improving_the_Robustness_of_Knowledge_Grounded_Dialogue_via_Contrastive_Learning/2024-01-09-Improving_the_Robustness_of_Knowledge_Grounded_Dialogue_via_Contrastive_Learning.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04361v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Critique of Critique</title>
  <dc:creator>Shichao Sun, Junlong Li, Weizhe Yuan, Ruifeng Yuan, Wenjie Li, Pengfei Liu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/The_Critique_of_Critique/2024-01-09-The_Critique_of_Critique.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/The_Critique_of_Critique/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04518v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary</h3>
<p><strong>Major Findings</strong> - MetaCritique, a framework for evaluating critiques, is proposed in this paper. Two aspects, factuality and comprehensiveness, are evaluated using precision and recall scores. - The framework uses Atomic Information Units (AIUs) to evaluate critiques at a more fine-grained level and provides natural language rationale to support each judgment. - A meta-evaluation dataset covering four tasks (question answering, reasoning, entailment, and summarization) is created to demonstrate the feasibility and effectiveness of MetaCritique. The framework achieved near-human performance and identified high-quality critiques leading to improved results.</p>
<p><strong>Key Concepts</strong> - <strong>MetaCritique</strong>: A framework for evaluating critiques from two aspects - factuality and comprehensiveness using precision and recall scores. - <strong>Atomic Information Units (AIUs)</strong>: Fundamental segments of informative critique used to evaluate critique at a fine-grained level. - <strong>Meta-evaluation dataset</strong>: Dataset covering four tasks used to demonstrate the feasibility and effectiveness of MetaCritique.</p>
<p><strong>Feasibility and Effectiveness</strong> - GPT-4 is used to generate reference and extract AIUs, and it achieves remarkable performance, justifying its utilization for MetaCritique. - GPT-4 demonstrates high performance in executing AIU-level tasks, indicating its suitability for evaluating critiques via the MetaCritique framework. - MetaCritique achieves a better correlation with human judgments compared to other baselines, demonstrating its effectiveness in evaluating critiques. - MetaCritique identifies superior critiques leading to better refined outcomes, indicating its potential to enhance generative AI substantially.</p>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<ul>
<li>The creative tasks are not suitable for the recall principle, especially when there are multiple high-quality answers, which poses a limitation to the framework.</li>
<li>The availability of reference answers or critiques remains a challenge. While GPT-4 serves as a reference, it is important to acknowledge potential errors.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="limitations" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="limitations">Limitations</h3>
<ul>
<li>The limitations of the framework in handling creative tasks and the availability of reference answers or critiques are identified as potential areas for improvement in future work.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-10</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04518v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04518v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04518v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04518v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8182</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/The_Critique_of_Critique/2024-01-09-The_Critique_of_Critique.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04518v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>SonicVisionLM: Playing Sound with Vision Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Zhifeng Xie, Shengye Yu, Mengtian Li, Qile He, Chaofeng Chen, Yu-Gang Jiang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SonicVisionLM_Playing_Sound_with_Vision_Language_Models/2024-01-09-SonicVisionLM_Playing_Sound_with_Vision_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SonicVisionLM_Playing_Sound_with_Vision_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04394v1/extracted/5335104/image/timestamps.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="key-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="key-findings">Key Findings</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><p><strong>SonicVisionLM Framework</strong>: The paper proposes a novel framework, SonicVisionLM, which leverages vision language models to generate a wide range of sound effects for silent videos. This approach identifies events in the video using a vision language model to suggest sounds that match the content, transforming the task of aligning image and audio into more manageable sub-problems.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Components of SonicVisionLM</strong>: The framework consists of three key components - video-to-text, text-based interaction, and text-to-audio generation. The video-to-text component focuses on generating sound effects for on-screen events, the text-based interaction component allows users to make changes to the text and timestamps, and the text-to-audio generation component accepts text and timestamp conditions to generate diverse, time-synchronized, and controllable sounds.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Performance and Results</strong>: SonicVisionLM demonstrates state-of-the-art results in both conditional and unconditional video-sound generation tasks. It achieves enhanced synchronization with visuals, improved alignment between audio and video components, and surpasses existing methods in various metrics such as IoU, Onset Acc, and Time Acc.</p></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="method-summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="method-summary">Method Summary</h3>
<ul>
<li><p><strong>Preliminaries</strong>: The paper introduces the audio diffusion model, latent diffusion model (LDM), and the process of generating audio from text embeddings using the LDM and vocoder.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Visual-to-Audio Event Understanding Module</strong>: This module utilizes a vision language model to generate descriptions of sounds based on the visual content in videos.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Sound Event Timestamp Detection Module</strong>: Here, a sound event timestamp detection module is used to detect the timing of sound events in the video, and the process and network structure are detailed.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Time-controllable Latent Diffusion Model</strong>: This section describes the proposed time-controllable adapter and the process of incorporating time-controllable embeddings for guiding the generation of diverse sounds.</p></li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="evaluation-and-results" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="evaluation-and-results">Evaluation and Results</h3>
<ul>
<li><p><strong>Conditional and Unconditional Generation Task Results</strong>: SonicVisionLM demonstrates superior performance in both conditional and unconditional video-sound generation tasks compared to existing methods. The framework achieves higher accuracy, diversity, and synchronization in generating sounds for videos.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Ablation Study</strong>: The ablation study validates the effectiveness of the time-controllable adapter in enhancing sound quality, diversity, and synchronization.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Multi-soundtracks Generation</strong>: The paper includes an example demonstrating SonicVisionLM’s ability to generate multiple soundtracks for a video, including both on-screen and off-screen sounds.</p></li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper lacks a direct comparison with a broader range of existing methods, limiting the comprehensive assessment of SonicVisionLM’s performance against various approaches in the field.</li>
<li>While the paper showcases promising results, it is essential to address potential limitations, such as the complexity of the visual understanding and timestamp detection parts, to provide a more balanced view of the framework’s capabilities.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the paper provides valuable insights into the effective generation of sound for silent videos using vision language models, offering a comprehensive framework and showcasing significant advancements in video-sound generation tasks.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-10</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04394v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04394v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04394v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04394v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7641</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>recommender</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SonicVisionLM_Playing_Sound_with_Vision_Language_Models/2024-01-09-SonicVisionLM_Playing_Sound_with_Vision_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04394v1/extracted/5335104/image/timestamps.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>RePLan: Robotic Replanning with Perception and Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Marta Skreta, Zihan Zhou, Jia Lin Yuan, Kourosh Darvish, Alán Aspuru-Guzik, Animesh Garg</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/RePLan_Robotic_Replanning_with_Perception_and_Language_Models/2024-01-08-RePLan_Robotic_Replanning_with_Perception_and_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/RePLan_Robotic_Replanning_with_Perception_and_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04157v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-replan-robotic-replanning-with-perception-and-language-models" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-of-replan-robotic-replanning-with-perception-and-language-models">Summary of “RePLan: Robotic Replanning with Perception and Language Models”</h3>
<section id="key-findings" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="key-findings"><strong>Key Findings</strong></h4>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Advancements in large language models (LLMs) have enabled robots to successfully carry out open-ended tasks</strong>. The authors note that traditional methods rely on extensive domain knowledge and complex reward engineering, while Large Language Models (LLMs) show considerable promise in robot planning.</li>
<li><strong>Vision Language Models (VLMs) prove to be crucial in interpreting the environment and facilitating ongoing task updates based on real-time observations</strong>. The integration of visual cues with linguistic context enables robots to better interpret their surrounding environment and adapt to unforeseen obstacles.</li>
<li><strong>RePLan, a novel framework that utilizes LLMs and VLMs, has shown significant success in enabling robotic systems to autonomously adapt to unforeseen obstacles while accomplishing open-ended, long-horizon goals</strong>. The study conducted using RePLan across four environments containing seven long-horizon tasks demonstrated its effectiveness in successfully tackling multi-stage tasks, with a notable 4x improvement over the current leading method.</li>
</ol>
<hr>
</section>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction"><strong>Introduction</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Designing embodied agents to execute multi-stage, long-horizon tasks is challenging, requiring manipulation skills, perceptive reasoning, and high-level planning with minimal human intervention.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="robot-control-with-physically-grounded-language-models" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="robot-control-with-physically-grounded-language-models"><strong>Robot Control with Physically Grounded Language Models</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Language models have shown promise in robot planning. However, they lack physical grounding, while Vision Language Models (VLMs) combine visual and linguistic context to enable robots to interpret their surroundings accurately.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="long-horizon-robot-planning" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="long-horizon-robot-planning"><strong>Long-horizon Robot Planning</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Traditional methods such as Task and Motion Planning (TAMP) and learning approaches like Hierarchical Reinforcement Learning (HRL) and Imitation Learning (IL) necessitate substantial domain expertise and large datasets for task learning. Large Language Models (LLMs) have potential in robot planning but face challenges in reasoning over extended periods without considering important details.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="language-to-reward-shaping" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="language-to-reward-shaping"><strong>Language to Reward Shaping</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Directly inferring rewards from natural language inputs using language-driven reward-shaping approaches has shown utility in various domains, including negotiation and gaming, facilitating desired behavior learning through reinforcement learning.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="replan-model-structure-and-details" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="replan-model-structure-and-details"><strong>RePLan: Model Structure and Details</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>RePLan comprises five modules: a High-Level LLM Planner, a VLM Perceiver, a Low-Level LLM Planner, a Motion Controller, and an LLM Verifier. These modules collaborate to enable the robot to adapt and replan based on feedback from the environment.</li>
<li>The High-Level Planner generates subtasks, the Perceiver provides physical grounding, the Low-Level Planner converts high-level tasks to low-level rewards, the Motion Controller instructs the robot, and the Verifier ensures the correctness of the plans.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="experiments" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="experiments"><strong>Experiments</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The study included seven long-horizon tasks across four distinct environments, each testing the robot’s ability to adapt to unforeseen obstacles and accomplish open-ended goals.</li>
<li>RePLan demonstrated a significant 4x improvement over the current leading method, achieving successful adaptation in almost 90% of the tested tasks.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="error-cases-and-additional-experiments" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="error-cases-and-additional-experiments"><strong>Error Cases and Additional Experiments</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The study presented real-world scenarios, providing insights into error cases and additional experiments, such as VLM ablation and GPT-4V experiments, highlighting the method’s strengths and limitations.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique"><strong>Critique</strong></h3>
<p>The paper provides valuable insights into the utilization of language and vision models for robotic planning. However, it would benefit from a more detailed comparison with existing methods and a comprehensive discussion of the potential limitations and challenges associated with the proposed framework. Additionally, while the experiments are comprehensive, the real-world applicability of RePLan in varied environments and scenarios could be further explored.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-10</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04157v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04157v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04157v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04157v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>12338</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/RePLan_Robotic_Replanning_with_Perception_and_Language_Models/2024-01-08-RePLan_Robotic_Replanning_with_Perception_and_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04157v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>FlightLLM: Efficient Large Language Model Inference with a Complete Mapping Flow on FPGAs</title>
  <dc:creator>Shulin Zeng, Jun Liu, Guohao Dai, Xinhao Yang, Tianyu Fu, Hongyi Wang, Wenheng Ma, Hanbo Sun, Shiyao Li, Zixiao Huang, Yadong Dai, Jintao Li, Zehao Wang, Ruoyu Zhang, Kairui Wen, Xuefei Ning, Yu Wang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/FlightLLM_Efficient_Large_Language_Model_Inference_with_a_Complete_Mapping_Flow_on_FPGAs/2024-01-08-FlightLLM_Efficient_Large_Language_Model_Inference_with_a_Complete_Mapping_Flow_on_FPGAs.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/FlightLLM_Efficient_Large_Language_Model_Inference_with_a_Complete_Mapping_Flow_on_FPGAs/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03868v2/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="flightllm-efficient-large-language-model-inference-with-a-complete-mapping-flow-on-fpgas" class="level1">
<h1>FlightLLM: Efficient Large Language Model Inference with a Complete Mapping Flow on FPGAs</h1>
<section id="major-takeaways" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-takeaways">Major Takeaways</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Efficiency Enhancement</strong>: FlightLLM addresses the efficiency limitations of Large Language Models (LLMs) by leveraging FPGA-specific resources to achieve higher energy and cost efficiency compared to commercial GPUs.</li>
<li><strong>Complete Mapping Flow</strong>: The paper proposes a complete mapping flow for LLM inference on FPGAs, highlighting innovations in computation and memory overhead solutions.</li>
<li><strong>Performance Comparison</strong>: FlightLLM outperforms SOTA accelerators, achieving better latency and throughput compared to GPUs and other FPGA-based accelerators.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="abstract" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="abstract">Abstract</h2>
<p>The paper introduces FlightLLM, a solution for efficient Large Language Model (LLM) inference on FPGAs. It addresses the challenges of heavy computation and memory overheads by leveraging FPGA-specific resources. FlightLLM achieves higher energy and cost efficiency compared to commercial GPUs and outperforms SOTA accelerators.</p>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<ul>
<li>Recent developments in Large Language Models (LLMs) have highlighted their significant impact across various domains.</li>
<li>LLMs are widely used in latency-sensitive scenarios, necessitating efficient computation and memory management.</li>
<li>Compression techniques such as sparsification and quantization are employed to mitigate computation and memory overheads, but current hardware platforms struggle to efficiently support these methods.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="background-and-related-work" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="background-and-related-work">Background and Related Work</h2>
<ul>
<li>Transformer-based LLMs achieve state-of-the-art performance across Natural Language Processing (NLP) tasks. The transformer model architecture consists of cascaded transformer blocks with Multi-Head Attention (MHA) and Feed Forward Network (FFN) networks.</li>
<li>Efficient transformer models leverage compression techniques such as sparsification and quantization to reduce computation and memory overheads. Previous works have focused on specialized architectures to accelerate sparse attention and optimize linear layers with mixed-precision quantization.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="computing-architecture" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="computing-architecture">Computing Architecture</h2>
<ul>
<li>FlightLLM’s overall architecture includes a task scheduler, memory controller, and multiple computing cores equipped with a unified Matrix Processing Engine (MPE), Memory Management Unit (MMU), Special Function Unit (SFU), and Instruction Scheduler.</li>
<li>The configurable sparse DSP chain and always-on-chip decode scheme enhance computation efficiency and memory bandwidth, while supporting different sparsity patterns. FlightLLM also supports mixed-precision quantization and length adaptive compilation to reduce instruction storage overhead.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="always-on-chip-decode" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="always-on-chip-decode">Always-on-chip Decode</h2>
<ul>
<li>The on-chip decode scheme in FlightLLM enables efficient memory bandwidth utilization by keeping activations in on-chip memory during the decode stage, reducing frequent access to off-chip memory.</li>
<li>Mixed-precision support using a dedicated dequantization unit helps optimize compactly stored mixed-precision data and reduce memory access overhead.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="length-adaptive-compilation" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="length-adaptive-compilation">Length Adaptive Compilation</h2>
<ul>
<li>FlightLLM proposes a length adaptive compilation approach to reduce the instruction storage overhead by allowing different lengths of prefill or decode to share the same instructions within threshold ranges, optimizing memory utilization.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="analytical-model-for-rtl-generation" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analytical-model-for-rtl-generation">Analytical Model for RTL Generation</h2>
<ul>
<li>FlightLLM uses an analytical model to optimize hardware resource utilization and dynamically adjust the computing parallelism and buffer size to generate corresponding RTL code for implementation on different FPGA platforms.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="evaluation" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="evaluation">Evaluation</h2>
<ul>
<li>FlightLLM is evaluated on state-of-the-art LLMs such as OPT-6.7B and LLaMA2-7B, achieving better latency, throughput, energy efficiency, and cost efficiency compared to both commercial GPUs and SOTA accelerators.</li>
<li>The latency breakdown analysis and multi-batch performance comparisons highlight FlightLLM’s efficient hardware performance.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="conclusion" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>The paper introduces FlightLLM as a promising approach for efficient LLM inference on FPGAs, enabling higher energy and cost efficiency compared to commercial GPUs and SOTA accelerators. FlightLLM demonstrates optimizations in computation efficiency, memory bandwidth utilization, and latency reductions, making it a competitive solution for LLM inference.</p>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h2>
<ul>
<li>The paper does not provide a detailed discussion of potential limitations or trade-offs with FlightLLM’s approach, which could help provide a more comprehensive understanding of its applicability and potential constraints.</li>
<li>While the evaluation results are promising, it would be useful to compare FlightLLM’s performance against a wider range of FPGA-based LLM accelerators to provide a more comprehensive picture of its comparative advantages.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the paper effectively presents FlightLLM as a compelling solution for efficient LLM inference, highlighting innovations in FPGA-based acceleration and performance optimizations.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-10</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.03868v2">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.03868v2</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03868v2">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03868v2</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>12121</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/FlightLLM_Efficient_Large_Language_Model_Inference_with_a_Complete_Mapping_Flow_on_FPGAs/2024-01-08-FlightLLM_Efficient_Large_Language_Model_Inference_with_a_Complete_Mapping_Flow_on_FPGAs.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03868v2/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>MARG: Multi-Agent Review Generation for Scientific Papers</title>
  <dc:creator>Mike D&#39;Arcy, Tom Hope, Larry Birnbaum, Doug Downey</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MARG_Multi_Agent_Review_Generation_for_Scientific_Papers/2024-01-08-MARG_Multi_Agent_Review_Generation_for_Scientific_Papers.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MARG_Multi_Agent_Review_Generation_for_Scientific_Papers/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04259v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="major-takeaways" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-takeaways">Major Takeaways</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper introduces MARG, a multi-agent approach for generating peer-review feedback for scientific papers.</li>
<li>MARG uses multiple large language model (LLM) instances with specialized agents to enhance feedback quality and reduce token constraints.</li>
<li>MARG substantially improves the ability of GPT-4, reducing the rate of generic comments and generating more helpful feedback.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h3>
<p>The paper discusses the limitations of large language models (LLMs) in comprehending and producing long, highly technical scientific papers. It introduces the task of automatically generating actionable peer-review feedback for scientific papers, which comprises several reasoning challenges.</p>
</section>
<section id="multi-agent-review-generation" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="multi-agent-review-generation">Multi-Agent Review Generation</h3>
<ul>
<li>MARG is proposed as a method using multiple instances of LLMs to generate actionable peer-review feedback.</li>
<li>The specialized variant of MARG, MARG-S, involves using aspect-specific “expert” LLM agents to improve feedback on experiments, clarity, and impact.</li>
<li>MARG-S substantially outperforms baseline methods in generating specific and helpful feedback, with an improvement of 2.2x in generating good comments per review.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="related-work" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="related-work">Related Work</h3>
<ul>
<li>Prior work on automatic review generation primarily used smaller models or focused on template-filling instead of generating nuanced free-form comments.</li>
<li>MARG-S is compared to a recent method proposed by Liang et al., which truncates long papers and struggles with input size limitations.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="automated-evaluation-and-baseline-methods" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="automated-evaluation-and-baseline-methods">Automated Evaluation and Baseline Methods</h3>
<ul>
<li>MARG-S outperforms baseline methods in recall but generates more comments, leading to lower precision and Jaccard scores.</li>
<li>LiZCa, a baseline method, shows high recall in the most lenient setting but rapidly drops for stricter settings.</li>
<li>MARG-S exhibits high efficiency in recall improvement but takes significantly longer to generate reviews compared to other methods.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="user-study" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="user-study">User Study</h3>
<ul>
<li>MARG-S generates more good comments, has the highest proportion of fully accurate comments, and is significantly more specific compared to other methods.</li>
<li>Participants perceive MARG-S reviews as slightly longer than desired, but they find MARG-S comments to be highly specific, accurate, and helpful.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="relationships-between-factors" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="relationships-between-factors">Relationships between Factors</h3>
<ul>
<li>High specificity of comments in MARG-S is not associated with extreme positive or negative user ratings, contradicting the expectation of pushing ratings to extremes.</li>
<li>High specificity weakly corresponds to higher accuracy, and accuracy significantly predicts overall rating.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<p>The user study was conducted with a small number of participants, and the findings may not be generalizable. Additionally, the paper could provide more discussion on the potential biases or limitations of the study.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-10</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04259v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04259v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04259v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04259v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>41968</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MARG_Multi_Agent_Review_Generation_for_Scientific_Papers/2024-01-08-MARG_Multi_Agent_Review_Generation_for_Scientific_Papers.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.04259v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Butterfly Effect of Altering Prompts: How Small Changes and Jailbreaks Affect Large Language Model Performance</title>
  <dc:creator>Abel Salinas, Fred Morstatter</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/The_Butterfly_Effect_of_Altering_Prompts_How_Small_Changes_and_Jailbreaks_Affect_Large_Language_Model_Performance/2024-01-08-The_Butterfly_Effect_of_Altering_Prompts_How_Small_Changes_and_Jailbreaks_Affect_Large_Language_Model_Performance.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/The_Butterfly_Effect_of_Altering_Prompts_How_Small_Changes_and_Jailbreaks_Affect_Large_Language_Model_Performance/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03729v1/extracted/5335133/figures/aggregate/aggregate-labels-styles-only.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="major-takeaways" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-takeaways">Major Takeaways</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><p>Prompting variations, including output format, perturbations, jailbreaks, and tipping, significantly impact the predictions and accuracy of Large Language Models (LLMs) across various text classification tasks.</p></li>
<li><p>Even minor changes to prompts, such as adding a space or using different output formats like JSON or CSV, can cause LLMs to change their answers and impact their accuracy.</p></li>
<li><p>Jailbreaks, used to bypass LLM content filters for sensitive topics, can lead to substantial changes in predictions and considerable performance losses.</p></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="summary-of-sections" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-of-sections">Summary of Sections</h3>
<section id="introduction" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h4>
<ul>
<li>Large Language Models (LLMs) have become popular for labeling data, with prompt construction being a crucial process involving decisions on wording, output format, and jailbreaks for sensitive topics.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="related-work" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="related-work">Related Work</h4>
<ul>
<li>Prompt generation and its impact on LLM behavior has been recognized in related literature, highlighting the importance of variations in prompts and prompt ensembles for robust insights.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="methodology" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="methodology">Methodology</h4>
<ul>
<li>The study explores prompt variations in output formats, perturbations, jailbreaks, and tipping across 11 text classification tasks, using OpenAI’s ChatGPT.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="results" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="results">Results</h4>
<ul>
<li>Prompt variations lead to changes in LLM predictions, with formatting specifications, minor perturbations, and jailbreaks affecting accuracy. The similarity of predictions across different prompt variations is explored, and the correlation between prompt variations and annotator disagreement is studied, revealing the minimal impact of confusion on prediction changes.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="conclusion" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="conclusion">Conclusion</h4>
<ul>
<li>Overall, prompt variations, particularly formatting changes and jailbreaks, have a significant impact on LLM predictions and accuracy, with implications for future work on generating LLMs resilient to prompt variations.</li>
</ul>
</section>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<p>The study provides a comprehensive analysis of how prompt variations affect LLM performance. However, the findings should be interpreted with caution due to the study’s reliance on a specific LLM model (ChatGPT) and prompt variations that may not generalize to all LLMs. Additionally, the impact of these prompt variations on real-world applications and user interactions with LLMs remains to be explored. Further research could involve wider experimentation across different LLMs and application scenarios to validate the generalizability of these findings.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-10</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.03729v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.03729v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03729v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03729v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6734</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/The_Butterfly_Effect_of_Altering_Prompts_How_Small_Changes_and_Jailbreaks_Affect_Large_Language_Model_Performance/2024-01-08-The_Butterfly_Effect_of_Altering_Prompts_How_Small_Changes_and_Jailbreaks_Affect_Large_Language_Model_Performance.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03729v1/extracted/5335133/figures/aggregate/aggregate-labels-styles-only.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Assessing AI Detectors in Identifying AI-Generated Code: Implications for Education</title>
  <dc:creator>Wei Hung Pan, Ming Jie Chok, Jonathan Leong Shan Wong, Yung Xin Shin, Yeong Shian Poon, Zhou Yang, Chun Yong Chong, David Lo, Mei Kuan Lim</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Assessing_AI_Detectors_in_Identifying_AI_Generated_Code_Implications_for_Education/2024-01-08-Assessing_AI_Detectors_in_Identifying_AI_Generated_Code_Implications_for_Education.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Assessing_AI_Detectors_in_Identifying_AI_Generated_Code_Implications_for_Education/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03676v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="assessing-ai-detectors-in-identifying-ai-generated-code-implications-for-education" class="level1">
<h1>Assessing AI Detectors in Identifying AI-Generated Code: Implications for Education</h1>
<section id="key-findings" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="key-findings">Key Findings</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Existing AIGC Detectors perform poorly</strong> in distinguishing between human-written code and AI-generated code, indicating the inherent weaknesses of current detectors. This underscores the need for further research and development in this domain to enhance their efficacy.</li>
<li>Variations in the prompts used to generate AI-generated content significantly impact the <strong>sensitivity and accuracy</strong> of AIGC Detectors, particularly the GLTR model.</li>
<li>A need for <strong>comprehensive guidelines and policies</strong> to safeguard the responsible and ethical usage of AI in the educational context is emphasized. Educators are encouraged to consider the <strong>integration of generative AI</strong> into education processes, the automation level, and its ethical focus.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="abstract" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="abstract">Abstract</h2>
<p>The paper presents an empirical study evaluating the performance of AI-generated content (AIGC) detectors in distinguish AI-generated code from human-written code. A dataset comprising programming problems and corresponding human-written and AI-generated Python solutions was collected from various online sources. 13 variations of prompts were used to instruct an AI model to generate outputs, and the performance of five AIGC detectors was evaluated. Results indicate that existing detectors perform poorly in distinguishing AI-generated from human-written code.</p>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<ul>
<li>Large Language Models (LLMs) have advanced to the point of generating human-like code, raising concerns in programming education about potential academic misconduct.</li>
<li>Accessibility of LLMs has implications for educational assessment and academic dishonesty, thereby compelling educators to utilize AIGC Detectors to ascertain student integrity.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="background-and-motivations" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="background-and-motivations">Background and Motivations</h2>
<ul>
<li>Software Engineering (SE) and Computer Science (CS) education are significantly impacted by the emergence of generative AI, introducing complexities and challenges in educational assessment and evaluation.</li>
<li>There is a noticeable impact on academic dishonesty due to growing student reliance on AI-driven solutions.</li>
<li>Educators find themselves compelled to utilize AIGC Detectors, while the limitations of these detectors in recognizing AI-generated code remain uncertain.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="empirical-study-design-and-methodology" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="empirical-study-design-and-methodology">Empirical Study Design and Methodology</h2>
<ul>
<li>The study includes the research questions, methodology, process overview, and data collection details.</li>
<li>Research questions revolve around the accuracy and limitations of existing AIGC Detectors in detecting AI-generated code, evaluating their effectiveness and potential vulnerabilities with different code variants.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="results" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="results">Results</h2>
<ul>
<li>Existing AIGC Detectors perform poorly in distinguishing between human-written and AI-generated code, indicating the inherent weaknesses of current detectors. GLTR demonstrates the highest sensitivity and significant variability across different code variants.</li>
<li>Limitations of AIGC Detectors include their struggle in detecting AI-generated code accurately, highlighting the need for ongoing research and development to enhance their reliability.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="discussion" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="discussion">Discussion</h2>
<ul>
<li>Suggestions are provided for SE and CS educators to address the challenges and opportunities presented by the integration of AI into education.</li>
<li>Key areas for improvement include defining objectives, considering automation levels, focusing on ethical considerations, continuous evaluation, and comprehensive policies.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="threats-to-validity" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="threats-to-validity">Threats to Validity</h2>
<ul>
<li>The study acknowledges challenges related to prompts used for AIGC generation, verification of human-written code, and the impact of vague queries on AIGC Detector performance.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="conclusion-and-future-work" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="conclusion-and-future-work">Conclusion and Future Work</h2>
<ul>
<li>Promising opportunities exist for AIGC Detector tools to positively impact education, but challenges need to be addressed. Ethical guidelines and ongoing tool refinement are vital for responsible AI usage in education.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="data-availability" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="data-availability">Data Availability</h2>
<p>The replication package, including associated data, has been made publicly available for transparency and reproducibility.</p>
</section>
<section id="critique-and-potential-problems" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique-and-potential-problems">Critique and Potential Problems</h2>
<ul>
<li>The study’s reliance on one specific type of AI model, ChatGPT, might limit the generalizability of the findings to other AI models.</li>
<li>The study could benefit from a more diverse range of programming languages and problem types to better assess the performance of AIGC Detectors in a broader context.</li>
<li>The implications of the findings on educational practice and student learning outcomes could be further elucidated for a more comprehensive understanding of the study’s practical significance.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-10</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.03676v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.03676v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03676v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03676v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>12715</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>programming</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Assessing_AI_Detectors_in_Identifying_AI_Generated_Code_Implications_for_Education/2024-01-08-Assessing_AI_Detectors_in_Identifying_AI_Generated_Code_Implications_for_Education.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03676v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>LLMs for Robotic Object Disambiguation</title>
  <dc:creator>Connie Jiang, Yiqing Xu, David Hsu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLMs_for_Robotic_Object_Disambiguation/2024-01-07-LLMs_for_Robotic_Object_Disambiguation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLMs_for_Robotic_Object_Disambiguation/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03388v1/extracted/5332947/ManeuveringOccludingFig.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Pre-trained large language models (LLMs) demonstrate capability in solving complex decision making challenges in robotics</strong> such as object disambiguation tasks within tabletop environments. The model efficiently identifies and retrieves a desired object from a cluttered scene.</li>
<li>The LLMs are capable of efficiently disambiguating any object from any arbitrarily large tabletop scene by harnessing the “common sense” knowledge embedded in the model.</li>
<li><strong>Few-shot prompt engineering significantly improves the LLM’s ability to pose disambiguating queries</strong>, allowing the model to generate and navigate down a precise decision tree to the correct object, even when faced with identical options.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="i-introduction" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="i-introduction">I Introduction</h3>
<ul>
<li>Several challenges in disambiguating objects from a scene.
<ul>
<li>Developing a multi-step plan for disambiguation.</li>
<li>Inferring new features if the scene description provided is insufficient.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Previous methods of solving this task have limitations.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="ii-related-work" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="ii-related-work">II Related Work</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Prior methods</strong> of disambiguation include enumeration, greedy approach, and attribute-guided disambiguation.</li>
<li><strong>Growing research</strong> on the use of LLMs in robotics, specifically for decision making, is evident.</li>
<li><strong>Advantages</strong> of using LLMs for disambiguation tasks in robotics are highlighted.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="iii-problem-formulation" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="iii-problem-formulation">III Problem Formulation</h3>
<ul>
<li>Generalizing user requests to interpret and respond to any reasonable, generalized request.</li>
<li>Maneuvering occluding objects, such as relocating obstructing objects to access the desired one.</li>
<li><strong>Disambiguating the target object</strong> stands as the primary focus with a detailed description of this task and its limitations.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="iv-proposed-method" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="iv-proposed-method">IV Proposed Method</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Few-shot prompt-engineering approach</strong> proposed to enable the LLM to generate its own features.</li>
<li><strong>Results</strong> from employing this approach and an example of results are provided to illustrate the improvement in the model’s ability to infer features.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="v-experiments" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="v-experiments">V Experiments</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Comparison</strong> of the model’s performance with four baseline methods, including optimal split, enumeration, human performance, and POMDP-ATTR.</li>
<li>Conducted experiments in twelve distinct scenes to evaluate the model’s performance and accuracy.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="vi-results" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="vi-results">VI Results</h3>
<ul>
<li>The effective performance of the proposed model is highlighted, detailing its <strong>efficiency and success rate</strong> in disambiguating target objects.</li>
<li><strong>Visual representations</strong> of the results are used to present the findings effectively.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="vii-next-steps" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="vii-next-steps">VII Next Steps</h3>
<ul>
<li>Plans for <strong>completing the visual portion</strong> of the pipeline and further details on zero-shot and few-shot prompting are outlined as the next steps for the research.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<ul>
<li>While the study demonstrates the effectiveness of LLMs for object disambiguation, limitations in inferring unspecified features are highlighted, posing potential challenges in more complex scenes.</li>
<li>The comparison with baseline methods provides a benchmark, but the study could benefit from a more extensive comparison with a wider range of existing methods in the field.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-10</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.03388v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.03388v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03388v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03388v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5796</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLMs_for_Robotic_Object_Disambiguation/2024-01-07-LLMs_for_Robotic_Object_Disambiguation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03388v1/extracted/5332947/ManeuveringOccludingFig.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Grimoire is All You Need for Enhancing Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Ding Chen, Shichao Song, Qingchen Yu, Zhiyu Li, Wenjin Wang, Feiyu Xiong, Bo Tang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Grimoire_is_All_You_Need_for_Enhancing_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-07-Grimoire_is_All_You_Need_for_Enhancing_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Grimoire_is_All_You_Need_for_Enhancing_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03385v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><p><strong>SleIcl Method</strong>: The paper introduces a method called SleIcl for enhancing the performance of weak language models by utilizing strong language models to learn from representative samples and distill skills for solving specific tasks, known as grimoire.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Grimoire Types</strong>: The paper explores four representative sample selection methods and a zero-shot approach, alongside two grimoire generation templates, resulting in the creation of 10 types of single grimoires.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Performance Improvement</strong>: The study demonstrates that the SleIcl method substantially enhances the performance of weak language models with varying parameter sizes on diverse tasks, with smaller models exhibiting more pronounced improvements. On certain datasets, weak language models, with the aid of the method, outperformed GPT4-1106-preview in zero-shot scenarios.</p></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="related-works" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="related-works">Related Works</h3>
<ul>
<li><p><strong>In-context Learning of Large Language Model</strong>: The paper discusses the significance of In-context Learning (ICL) in enhancing the performance of large language models on specific tasks. It emphasizes the importance of data structure and the influence of contextual learning on the model’s latent concepts and specific functions.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Prompt Engineering of Demo Examples</strong>: The construction and ordering of demonstration examples significantly impact ICL performance. The study explores the characteristics, ordering, and selection strategies of demonstration examples.</p></li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<p>The paper provides a comprehensive exploration of the SleIcl method and its applicability in enhancing the performance of weak language models. However, it could benefit from a more in-depth analysis of the potential limitations or challenges in implementing the proposed SleIcl method. Additionally, concrete examples or case studies showcasing the real-world application of the SleIcl method would enhance the practical understanding of its effectiveness.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-10</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.03385v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.03385v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03385v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03385v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7777</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Grimoire_is_All_You_Need_for_Enhancing_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-07-Grimoire_is_All_You_Need_for_Enhancing_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03385v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>An Investigation of Large Language Models for Real-World Hate Speech Detection</title>
  <dc:creator>Keyan Guo, Alexander Hu, Jaden Mu, Ziheng Shi, Ziming Zhao, Nishant Vishwamitra, Hongxin Hu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/An_Investigation_of_Large_Language_Models_for_Real_World_Hate_Speech_Detection/2024-01-07-An_Investigation_of_Large_Language_Models_for_Real_World_Hate_Speech_Detection.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/An_Investigation_of_Large_Language_Models_for_Real_World_Hate_Speech_Detection/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Key Takeaways</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated strong performance in identifying hate speech, even surpassing benchmark machine learning models in some cases.</li>
<li>The choice of <strong>prompting strategies</strong> significantly impacts the effectiveness of LLMs in detecting hate speech, with a carefully crafted reasoning prompt showing the most promising results.</li>
<li>LLMs show proficiency in detecting hate speech in English but underperform in non-English text, highlighting the need for further investigation into multilingual hate speech detection.</li>
</ul>
<section id="introduction" class="level1">
<h1>Introduction</h1>
<ul>
<li>Hate speech is a significant issue in online spaces, and existing methods for detecting it are limited in capturing contextual nuances.</li>
<li>Large language models (LLMs) have shown promise in addressing this limitation due to their extensive training on natural language data, but there is a lack of studies on effectively prompting LLMs for hate speech detection.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="background-and-related-work" class="level1">
<h1>Background and Related Work</h1>
<section id="hate-speech-detection" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="hate-speech-detection">Hate Speech Detection</h2>
<ul>
<li>Hate speech online has become a critical threat, with current AI/ML detectors primarily relying on supervised learning techniques and facing limitations in capturing the contextual diversity of hate speech.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="llms-and-prompts-based-hate-speech-detection" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="llms-and-prompts-based-hate-speech-detection">LLMs and Prompts-based Hate Speech Detection</h2>
<ul>
<li>LLMs, like ChatGPT, have shown proficiency in natural language tasks, and prompting strategies have been found effective in guiding LLMs for specific tasks.</li>
<li>Prior studies have explored LLMs for hate speech detection but there is a need for a more comprehensive understanding of LLMs’ proficiency, especially with varied prompting strategies.</li>
</ul>
</section>
</section>
<section id="hate-speech-datasets" class="level1">
<h1>Hate Speech Datasets</h1>
<ul>
<li>The study employs five diverse hate speech datasets, each with specific characteristics and compositions, providing a comprehensive basis for evaluation.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="prompt-engineering-for-hate-speech-detection" class="level1">
<h1>Prompt-engineering for Hate Speech Detection</h1>
<ul>
<li>The study introduces four diverse prompting strategies - general prompt, general prompt with hate speech definition, few-shot learning prompt, and chain-of-thought prompt.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="measuring-the-effectiveness-of-prompting-strategies" class="level1">
<h1>Measuring the Effectiveness of Prompting Strategies</h1>
<section id="llm-based-general-prompting-strategy-vs.-baselines" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="llm-based-general-prompting-strategy-vs.-baselines">LLM-based General Prompting Strategy vs.&nbsp;Baselines</h2>
<ul>
<li>LLMs consistently outperform benchmark models, demonstrating higher accuracy and F1 scores in hate speech detection.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="analysis-of-different-prompts" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-of-different-prompts">Analysis of Different Prompts</h2>
<ul>
<li>Different prompts show varying levels of effectiveness, with the chain-of-thought reasoning prompt outperforming others, indicating the high impact of prompt design on model performance.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="effectiveness-of-llms-against-multilingual-hate-speech" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="effectiveness-of-llms-against-multilingual-hate-speech">Effectiveness of LLMs against multilingual hate speech</h2>
<ul>
<li>LLMs show proficiency in detecting hate speech in English but underperform in non-English text, highlighting the need for further investigation into multilingual hate speech detection.</li>
</ul>
</section>
</section>
<section id="conclusion-and-future-work" class="level1">
<h1>Conclusion and Future Work</h1>
<ul>
<li>The study fills an important gap in exploring effective LLM prompting strategies for hate speech detection, with potential future research in multilingual settings and multimodal hate speech detection.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Critique and Potential Problems</strong> - The study is limited to specific prompting strategies and datasets, potentially overlooking other effective strategies and diverse hate speech instances. - The findings may not be generalizable to all LLMs or applicable to all hate speech contexts.</p>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-10</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.03346v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.03346v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03346v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03346v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6521</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/An_Investigation_of_Large_Language_Models_for_Real_World_Hate_Speech_Detection/2024-01-07-An_Investigation_of_Large_Language_Models_for_Real_World_Hate_Speech_Detection.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
