<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Bayesian beagle</title>
<link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Quarto blog of LLM-generated summaries of Arxiv preprints</description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.450</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Generating Unsupervised Abstractive Explanations for Rumour Verification</title>
  <dc:creator>Iman Munire Bilal, Preslav Nakov, Rob Procter, Maria Liakata</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Generating_Unsupervised_Abstractive_Explanations_for_Rumour_Verification/2024-01-23-Generating_Unsupervised_Abstractive_Explanations_for_Rumour_Verification.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Generating_Unsupervised_Abstractive_Explanations_for_Rumour_Verification/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12713v1/extracted/5363941/detailed_overview.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-the-article" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-of-the-article"><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong></h3>
<p>The article discusses the task of rumour verification in social media, emphasizing the importance of generating explanations for automated veracity decisions. The authors introduce an unsupervised approach to produce model-centric abstractive explanations by leveraging post-hoc explainability methods and template-guided summarization. Their experiments demonstrate that the generated explanations are more informative and align closely with the predicted rumour veracity compared to using only the highest ranking posts in the thread.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The shift from black-box classifiers to generating explanations improves the interpretability of rumour verification models, especially in rapidly evolving situations such as natural disasters or terror attacks.</li>
<li>The unsupervised framework for generating abstractive explanations using template-guided summarization is a novel approach for the task of rumour verification.</li>
<li>Large Language Models (LLMs) can effectively evaluate the generated explanatory summaries, achieving sufficient agreement with humans and allowing for scalable evaluation of the explanations.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<p>The article presents a comprehensive and innovative approach to the generation of abstractive explanations for rumour verification, addressing the critical need for interpretability in automated veracity decisions. However, it is essential to consider several limitations and potential areas for further research:</p>
<ul>
<li><p><strong>Summarization of Threads:</strong> The method used to summarize conversation trees by concatenating individual posts might lead to a loss of context and information present in nested replies, potentially impacting the fidelity of the generated summaries.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Human Evaluation:</strong> While the article demonstrates good agreement between Large Language Models (LLMs) and human annotators, the reliability and stability of using LLMs as evaluators for explanation summaries are in the early stages. It is important to investigate the impact of prompt design and model stability over time.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Task Limitation:</strong> Currently, the explanations are solely constructed from information present in the thread, and it might be beneficial to explore incorporating external sources for richer explanations, enhancing the explanatory quality.</p></li>
</ul>
<p>The article makes a significant contribution to the field of rumour verification and interpretability of automated veracity decisions, but further research addressing the outlined limitations could enhance the robustness and applicability of the proposed approach.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-24</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12713v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12713v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12713v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12713v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8243</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Generating_Unsupervised_Abstractive_Explanations_for_Rumour_Verification/2024-01-23-Generating_Unsupervised_Abstractive_Explanations_for_Rumour_Verification.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12713v1/extracted/5363941/detailed_overview.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Transformer-Based Models Are Not Yet Perfect At Learning to Emulate Structural Recursion</title>
  <dc:creator>Dylan Zhang, Curt Tigges, Zory Zhang, Stella Biderman, Maxim Raginsky, Talia Ringer</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Transformer_Based_Models_Are_Not_Yet_Perfect_At_Learning_to_Emulate_Structural_Recursion/2024-01-23-Transformer_Based_Models_Are_Not_Yet_Perfect_At_Learning_to_Emulate_Structural_Recursion.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Transformer_Based_Models_Are_Not_Yet_Perfect_At_Learning_to_Emulate_Structural_Recursion/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12947v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-the-article" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-of-the-article">Summary of the Article:</h3>
<p>The article investigates the ability of transformer-based models to learn structural recursion from examples, focusing on the programming language domain. It introduces a general framework to connect abstract concepts of structural recursion with concrete sequence modeling problems and the behaviors of learned models. The study identifies issues where the models trained to emulate recursive computations fail to capture the recursion fully, fitting short-cut algorithms instead. The research highlights the difficulty for state-of-the-art large language models (LLMs) to mine recursive rules from in-context demonstrations and emulate step-wise computation of recursive functions.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Transformer-based models trained to emulate recursive computations cannot fully capture the recursion and instead fit short-cut algorithms.</li>
<li>State-of-the-art large language models (LLMs) struggle to mine recursive rules from in-context demonstrations and to emulate the step-wise computation of recursive functions.</li>
<li>The research introduces a general framework for representing and reasoning about structural recursion with sequence models, paving the path towards understanding how to better handle recursion with sequence models.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article provides a comprehensive investigation of the challenges and limitations faced by transformer-based models in learning to emulate structural recursion. The findings shed light on the inability of these models to fully capture the recursive behavior and instead resort to fitting short-cut algorithms. The identification of these issues offers valuable insights into the limitations of current transformer-based models in solving tasks involving structural recursion. However, the article could benefit from further exploration of potential solutions or alternative approaches to address these limitations. Additionally, it would be valuable to include a discussion on the implications of these findings for the field of sequence modeling and the development of more effective and reliable models for tasks involving recursion.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-24</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12947v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12947v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12947v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12947v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>28644</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Transformer_Based_Models_Are_Not_Yet_Perfect_At_Learning_to_Emulate_Structural_Recursion/2024-01-23-Transformer_Based_Models_Are_Not_Yet_Perfect_At_Learning_to_Emulate_Structural_Recursion.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12947v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Red Teaming Visual Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Mukai Li, Lei Li, Yuwei Yin, Masood Ahmed, Zhenguang Liu, Qi Liu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Red_Teaming_Visual_Language_Models/2024-01-23-Red_Teaming_Visual_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Red_Teaming_Visual_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12915v1/x2.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong></p>
<p>The article delves into the exploration of Vision-Language Models (VLMs) and their susceptibility to generating harmful or inaccurate content under specific scenarios, known as Red Teaming. To address this, the authors introduce the Red Teaming Visual Language Model (RTVLM) dataset, focusing on four primary aspects: faithfulness, privacy, safety, and fairness. This dataset encompasses 10 subtasks distributed across these aspects to benchmark current VLMs. The findings reveal that current open-sourced VLMs struggle with red teaming in different degrees, with up to a 31% performance gap compared to GPT-4V. Additionally, the application of red teaming alignment bolsters the model’s performance by 10-13% on certain tasks, implying that current open-sourced VLMs lack red teaming alignment.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Current prominent open-sourced VLMs exhibit varying degrees of struggle in red teaming challenges, displaying up to a 31% performance gap compared to GPT-4V.</li>
<li>The current VLMs lack red teaming alignment. Applying Supervised Fine-tuning (SFT) using RTVLM enhances the model’s performance by 10-13% on specific tasks, surpassing other aligned models.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article makes significant contributions by introducing the RTVLM dataset and shedding light on the vulnerabilities of VLMs, especially in the context of red teaming. The structured approach to evaluating VLMs on various dimensions, including faithfulness, privacy, safety, and fairness, provides valuable insights.</p>
<p>However, a potential shortcoming of the article is the exclusive focus on open-sourced VLMs. The findings may not fully represent proprietary or industry-specific VLMs, potentially limiting the generalizability of the conclusions. Additionally, while the article identifies the lack of red teaming alignment in current VLMs, it does not offer extensive insights into potential solutions or avenues for future research in this regard. Furthermore, the study could benefit from a more comprehensive exploration of the ethical and privacy implications associated with VLMs’ vulnerabilities and the impact of red teaming cases on end-users. Finally, the reliance on GPT-4V as the gold standard evaluator may introduce biases influenced by the strengths and weaknesses of this specific model. Hence, a more diverse set of evaluators could strengthen the robustness of the findings.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-24</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12915v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12915v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12915v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12915v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6809</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Red_Teaming_Visual_Language_Models/2024-01-23-Red_Teaming_Visual_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12915v1/x2.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Chatterbox: Robust Transport for LLM Token Streaming under Unstable Network</title>
  <dc:creator>Hanchen Li, Yuhan Liu, Yihua Cheng, Siddhant Ray, Kuntai Du, Junchen Jiang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Chatterbox_Robust_Transport_for_LLM_Token_Streaming_under_Unstable_Network/2024-01-23-Chatterbox_Robust_Transport_for_LLM_Token_Streaming_under_Unstable_Network.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Chatterbox_Robust_Transport_for_LLM_Token_Streaming_under_Unstable_Network/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12961v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong> The article discusses the challenges of LLM token streaming under unstable network conditions, where the rendering of tokens can be significantly delayed due to packet loss. The study highlights the increased stall ratios in current applications, including ChatGPT, Claude, and Bard, under unstable network conditions. To address this issue, the article proposes a novel transport layer scheme, named , which involves adding newly generated tokens and unacknowledged tokens into outgoing packets. Through simulations under various network conditions, the proposed scheme reduces the stall ratio by 71.0% compared to the TCP method commonly used by ChatGPT Streaming API. It also outperforms a custom packet duplication scheme by 31.6%. The study concludes that enables LLM Chatbots to respond more effectively under unstable network conditions.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLM token streaming experiences increased stall ratios in real-world applications, such as ChatGPT, Claude, and Bard, under unstable network conditions.</li>
<li>The proposed transport layer scheme reduces the stall ratio by 71.0% compared to the TCP method used by ChatGPT Streaming API and by 31.6% compared to a custom packet duplication scheme.</li>
<li>The novel transport scheme, , ensures that each packet contains sufficient information for rendering new tokens independently, thus avoiding stalls caused by missing packets.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article effectively addresses the challenges of LLM token streaming under unstable network conditions and proposes a novel transport scheme to mitigate stall ratios. However, the study lacks an in-depth exploration of the trade-offs involved in the proposed scheme. While significantly reduces stall ratios, it is essential to evaluate the potential increase in redundancy and transmission overhead associated with including unacknowledged tokens in outgoing packets. Additionally, the article acknowledges limitations in cases where not all unacked tokens can fit into one packet; however, it does not provide a comprehensive discussion of potential alternative solutions or further strategies to address this issue. Moreover, the study primarily focuses on the transmission aspect of token streaming, and further research could explore the integration of the proposed scheme with scheduling algorithms and quality of experience (QoE) models to enhance the overall LLM Chatbot performance under limited resources. Overall, while the proposed scheme shows promising results in reducing stall ratios, further investigations are necessary to address its limitations and explore potential synergies with other system optimizations.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-24</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12961v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12961v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12961v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12961v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6833</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Chatterbox_Robust_Transport_for_LLM_Token_Streaming_under_Unstable_Network/2024-01-23-Chatterbox_Robust_Transport_for_LLM_Token_Streaming_under_Unstable_Network.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12961v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>SLANG: New Concept Comprehension of Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Lingrui Mei, Shenghua Liu, Yiwei Wang, Baolong Bi, Xueqi Chen</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SLANG_New_Concept_Comprehension_of_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-23-SLANG_New_Concept_Comprehension_of_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SLANG_New_Concept_Comprehension_of_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12585v1/extracted/5363597/figures/example.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong> The article discusses the challenges posed by the dynamic nature of language, particularly in the context of slang and memes on the Internet, for large language models (LLMs). Traditionally, LLMs are trained on static datasets, making it difficult for them to keep up with the rapid linguistic evolution evident in online communities. To address this challenge, the researchers propose a new benchmark called SLANG and a methodology named FOCUS, which utilizes causal inference to enhance LLMs’ comprehension of evolving new concepts on the internet. The empirical analysis shows that the FOCUS methodology outperforms traditional models in interpreting Internet slang and memes.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The FOCUS methodology, grounded in causal inference, outperforms traditional models in terms of precision and relevance in the interpretation of Internet slang and memes.</li>
<li>The SLANG benchmark is introduced to evaluate language models’ adaptability to linguistic evolution and vocabulary changes, focusing on coherence and accuracy in the face of dynamic and unconventional language use, such as slang and idiomatic expressions.</li>
<li>The article provides evidence that the FOCUS approach is not only effective in interpreting direct language use but also excels in interpreting hypothetical, contextually modified scenarios, demonstrating its robustness and versatility in navigating the multifaceted nature of language.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article presents a comprehensive approach to addressing the challenges faced by LLMs in understanding evolving language, especially in the context of internet slang and memes. The proposed FOCUS methodology and SLANG benchmark offer valuable contributions to enhancing LLMs’ adaptability and comprehension of dynamic language. However, the article lacks a discussion of potential limitations or biases in the proposed methodology, and there is a need for further exploration of the generalizability of the findings to different types of language models and linguistic contexts. Additionally, the empirical analysis could benefit from a comparison with other state-of-the-art approaches in natural language processing to provide a more holistic evaluation of the proposed methodology. Overall, while the article offers valuable insights, further research and critical evaluation are necessary to fully ascertain the effectiveness and practical implications of the FOCUS methodology in enhancing LLM comprehension of evolving language.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-24</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12585v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12585v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12585v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12585v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8576</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SLANG_New_Concept_Comprehension_of_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-23-SLANG_New_Concept_Comprehension_of_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12585v1/extracted/5363597/figures/example.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Assessing and Understanding Creativity in Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Yunpu Zhao, Rui Zhang, Wenyi Li, Di Huang, Jiaming Guo, Shaohui Peng, Yifan Hao, Yuanbo Wen, Xing Hu, Zidong Du, Qi Guo, Ling Li, Yunji Chen</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Assessing_and_Understanding_Creativity_in_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-23-Assessing_and_Understanding_Creativity_in_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Assessing_and_Understanding_Creativity_in_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12491v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-the-article" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-of-the-article">Summary of the Article:</h3>
<p>The article discusses the assessment and understanding of creativity in Large Language Models (LLMs) within the field of natural language processing. LLMs have exhibited a high level of creativity in various tasks, and this paper aims to establish an efficient framework for assessing their creativity. Through adapting the modified Torrance Tests of Creative Thinking, the research evaluates the creative performance of various LLMs across 7 tasks emphasizing 4 criteria: Fluency, Flexibility, Originality, and Elaboration. The study found that LLMs primarily fall short in originality but excel in elaboration. Moreover, the use of prompts and role-play settings significantly influences creativity, and collaboration among multiple LLMs enhances originality. The findings reveal a consensus between human evaluations and LLMs regarding the personality traits that influence creativity.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The primary deficiency in LLMs’ creativity lies in originality, while excelling in elaboration.</li>
<li>The use of prompts and role-play settings significantly influences creativity, with instructive prompts and chain of thought prompts enhancing creativity.</li>
<li>Collaboration among multiple LLMs enhances the level of creativity, with the most notable improvement in originality.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article provides valuable insights into assessing creativity in LLMs and highlights the impact of model design on creativity. However, the study has several limitations and potential areas for further research: - The evaluation largely focuses on the significant creative discrepancies between LLMs, prompting the need for a more comprehensive understanding of the nature of creativity in LLMs. - The study acknowledges the challenges of directly using traditional human-based evaluation methods for LLM creativity assessment, highlighting the need to address these challenges for a robust and sound assessment. - Future research should address the limitations of the framework, such as extending the evaluation to include multi-modal inputs and exploring the creativity of other types of generative models, such as image generation models and music generation models.</p>
<p>Therefore, while the article offers valuable insights into LLM creativity assessment, further research should focus on addressing the outlined limitations and providing a more comprehensive understanding of the nature of creativity in LLMs.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-24</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12491v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12491v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12491v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12491v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>12705</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Assessing_and_Understanding_Creativity_in_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-23-Assessing_and_Understanding_Creativity_in_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12491v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Context Matters: Pushing the Boundaries of Open-Ended Answer Generation with Graph-Structured Knowledge Context</title>
  <dc:creator>Somnath Banerjee, Amruit Sahoo, Sayan Layek, Avik Dutta, Rima Hazra, Animesh Mukherjee</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Context_Matters_Pushing_the_Boundaries_of_Open_Ended_Answer_Generation_with_Graph_Structured_Knowledge_Context/2024-01-23-Context_Matters_Pushing_the_Boundaries_of_Open_Ended_Answer_Generation_with_Graph_Structured_Knowledge_Context.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Context_Matters_Pushing_the_Boundaries_of_Open_Ended_Answer_Generation_with_Graph_Structured_Knowledge_Context/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12671v1/x2.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-the-article" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-of-the-article">Summary of the Article:</h3>
<p>In this article, the authors present a novel framework, GraphContextGen, to enhance the factual coherence and knowledge grounding of Large Language Models (LLMs) in the context of open-ended question answering systems. The study focuses on domain-specific community question answering platforms like AskUbuntu, Unix, and ServerFault. The framework combines graph-driven context retrieval with knowledge graph-based enhancement to improve the proficiency of LLMs in providing accurate and contextually relevant answers. Experimental evaluations demonstrate that GraphContextGen consistently outperforms dominant text-based retrieval systems across various LLMs with different parameter sizes. The findings highlight the significance of pairing context-rich data retrieval with LLMs for renewed knowledge sourcing and generation in AI systems.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The integration of graph-driven context retrieval and knowledge graph-based enhancement significantly improves the proficiency of LLMs, especially in domain-specific community question answering platforms.</li>
<li>GraphContextGen consistently outperforms dominant text-based retrieval systems across various LLMs with different parameter sizes.</li>
<li>The framework ensures factual coherence of the generated answers by aligning crucial entities with the gold answer.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article effectively demonstrates the effectiveness of the GraphContextGen framework in enhancing the proficiency of Large Language Models in generating accurate and contextually relevant answers. The systematic evaluation of the framework against dominant text-based retrieval systems and various LLMs with different parameter sizes provides substantial evidence of its robustness and adaptability. The article addresses a significant challenge in open-ended question answering systems and provides a practical solution for knowledge sourcing and generation in AI systems.</p>
<p>However, the article could benefit from a more detailed critical analysis of potential limitations, such as the computational complexity of the proposed framework, potential biases in the experimental setup, and the generalizability of the findings to broader domains beyond the specific community question answering platforms. Additionally, a discussion of potential ethical implications and the societal impact of the proposed advancements would enhance the comprehensive analysis of the article.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-24</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12671v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12671v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12671v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12671v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>9350</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Context_Matters_Pushing_the_Boundaries_of_Open_Ended_Answer_Generation_with_Graph_Structured_Knowledge_Context/2024-01-23-Context_Matters_Pushing_the_Boundaries_of_Open_Ended_Answer_Generation_with_Graph_Structured_Knowledge_Context.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12671v1/x2.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>From Understanding to Utilization: A Survey on Explainability for Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Haoyan Luo, Lucia Specia</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/From_Understanding_to_Utilization_A_Survey_on_Explainability_for_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-23-From_Understanding_to_Utilization_A_Survey_on_Explainability_for_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/From_Understanding_to_Utilization_A_Survey_on_Explainability_for_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12874v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong> The survey paper explores the domain of explainability for Large Language Models (LLMs), emphasizing the necessity for enhanced explainability to address concerns around transparency, ethical use, and trust. The paper categorizes existing explainability methods and discusses their application in improving model transparency, reliability, and ethical use. Special attention is given to pre-trained Transformer-based LLMs, and their unique interpretability challenges due to scale and complexity. The goal is to bridge the gap between theoretical understanding and practical application, offering insights for future research and development in the field of LLM explainability.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The Importance of Explainability for LLMs
<ul>
<li>LLMs’ “black-box” nature raises concerns about transparency, ethical use, and trust.</li>
<li>Explainability serves critical functions for end-users and developers, fostering trust and providing insights into unintended biases and areas for improvement.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Categorization of Explainability Methods
<ul>
<li>The paper categorizes explainability methods into Local Analysis and Global Analysis, addressing the challenge of interpreting large-scale LLMs.</li>
<li>Local Analysis methods encompass feature attribution analysis and dissecting Transformer blocks, providing detailed insights into model predictions and internal processing.</li>
<li>Global Analysis focuses on probing methods and mechanistic interpretability to understand model representations and inner workings.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Leveraging Explainability for Model Editing, Capability Enhancement, and Controllable Generation
<ul>
<li>Discusses methods for model editing, enhancing model capability, and controllable text generation using explainability insights to improve LLM performance.</li>
<li>Highlights specific applications such as improving the utilization of long text, In-Context Learning (ICL), reducing hallucination, and ethical alignment.</li>
</ul></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article effectively delves into the complex domain of explainability for Large Language Models (LLMs) and highlights the significance of enhancing LLMs’ transparency and ethical use. The categorization of explainability methods and their applications provides a comprehensive overview of the challenges and potential solutions in understanding and applying LLMs. However, the article could benefit from providing a more succinct and focused discussion on the limitations and challenges associated with existing explainability methods. Additionally, it might have been valuable to include a comparative analysis of different explainability approaches, shedding light on their relative effectiveness and practicality. Despite its comprehensive coverage, the article would have been strengthened by a critical analysis of potential biases or methodological limitations in the field, as well as unexplored areas that require further research or refinement. Overall, while the article effectively outlines the current landscape of LLM explainability, a more critical examination of the limitations and future research directions would have provided greater depth and insight.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-24</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12874v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12874v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12874v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12874v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8272</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/From_Understanding_to_Utilization_A_Survey_on_Explainability_for_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-23-From_Understanding_to_Utilization_A_Survey_on_Explainability_for_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12874v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Knowledge Distillation from Language-Oriented to Emergent Communication for Multi-Agent Remote Control</title>
  <dc:creator>Yongjun Kim, Sejin Seo, Jihong Park, Mehdi Bennis, Seong-Lyun Kim, Junil Choi</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Knowledge_Distillation_from_Language_Oriented_to_Emergent_Communication_for_Multi_Agent_Remote_Control/2024-01-23-Knowledge_Distillation_from_Language_Oriented_to_Emergent_Communication_for_Multi_Agent_Remote_Control.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Knowledge_Distillation_from_Language_Oriented_to_Emergent_Communication_for_Multi_Agent_Remote_Control/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12624v1/extracted/5362782/Fig_LEC_Summary.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong></p>
<p>The article compares emergent communication (EC) based on multi-agent deep reinforcement learning (MADRL) with language-oriented semantic communication (LSC) empowered by a pre-trained large language model (LLM). The comparison is made in the context of a multi-agent remote navigation task, using multimodal input data comprising location and channel maps. The study shows that EC incurs high training cost and struggles with multimodal data, while LSC yields high inference computing cost due to the large size of the LLM. To address these limitations, the authors propose a language-guided EC (LEC) framework by guiding EC training using LSC via knowledge distillation. The simulations demonstrate that LEC achieves faster travel time and improves MADRL training convergence compared to EC.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Emergent communication (EC) struggles with multimodal data and incurs high training cost, while language-oriented semantic communication (LSC) yields high inference computing cost due to the large size of the pre-trained large language model (LLM).</li>
<li>Language-guided EC (LEC) addresses the limitations of EC and LSC, achieving faster travel time and speeding up the MADRL training convergence by up to 61.8% compared to EC.</li>
<li>LEC demonstrates low computing costs during both training and inference, thanks to in-context learning of LSC and training convergence acceleration of knowledge distillation (KD) in EC.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article provides a comprehensive comparison between emergent communication (EC) and language-oriented semantic communication (LSC), along with the introduction of the innovative language-guided EC (LEC) framework. The study offers valuable insights into the strengths and weaknesses of each communication approach and illustrates the potential of combining EC with LSC using knowledge distillation.</p>
<p>One potential limitation of the study is its reliance on simulations to validate the proposed LEC framework. While the simulations demonstrate promising results, the real-world applicability of LEC may vary, especially in dynamic and complex environments. Additionally, the article focuses on a specific multi-agent remote navigation task, and the generalizability of LEC to other domains or tasks remains unclear. Further research should investigate the robustness and scalability of LEC across diverse real-world scenarios.</p>
<p>The article also highlights the high computing costs associated with LSC, which could limit its practical implementation in resource-constrained environments. Therefore, future studies should explore methods to optimize the computational efficiency of LSC without compromising its effectiveness.</p>
<p>Overall, the article presents an innovative approach to address the limitations of existing communication paradigms and offers valuable implications for the development of efficient multi-agent communication systems. However, further empirical studies and real-world validations are necessary to fully assess the practical utility and limitations of the proposed LEC framework.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-24</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12624v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12624v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12624v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12624v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5666</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Knowledge_Distillation_from_Language_Oriented_to_Emergent_Communication_for_Multi_Agent_Remote_Control/2024-01-23-Knowledge_Distillation_from_Language_Oriented_to_Emergent_Communication_for_Multi_Agent_Remote_Control.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12624v1/extracted/5362782/Fig_LEC_Summary.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The teachers are confused as well: A Multiple-Stakeholder Ethics Discussion on Large Language Models in Computing Education</title>
  <dc:creator>Kyrie Zhixuan Zhou, Zachary Kilhoffer, Madelyn Rose Sanfilippo, Ted Underwood, Ece Gumusel, Mengyi Wei, Abhinav Choudhry, Jinjun Xiong</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/The_teachers_are_confused_as_well_A_Multiple_Stakeholder_Ethics_Discussion_on_Large_Language_Models_in_Computing_Education/2024-01-23-The_teachers_are_confused_as_well_A_Multiple_Stakeholder_Ethics_Discussion_on_Large_Language_Models_in_Computing_Education.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/The_teachers_are_confused_as_well_A_Multiple_Stakeholder_Ethics_Discussion_on_Large_Language_Models_in_Computing_Education/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12453v1/extracted/5362997/mental_model_fig_3.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-the-article" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-of-the-article">Summary of the Article:</h3>
<p>Large Language Models (LLMs) have gained significant traction in recent years, impacting various aspects of people’s lives, including education. Concerns have arisen regarding the ethical implications of LLMs, particularly in higher education computer science. To address these concerns, the authors conducted a case study involving interviews with 20 stakeholders in higher education computer science. The study revealed that students have distinct mental models for interacting with LLMs, using them as writing tools, coding tools, and information retrieval tools, each with varying ethical considerations. Ethical issues raised by the participants included inaccurate LLM responses, hallucinations, biases, privacy leakage, and academic integrity concerns. Stakeholders emphasized the need for guidance and rules for LLM use in higher education, including teaching digital literacy, rethinking education, and implementing cautious and contextual policies. The research findings contribute to understanding the ethical challenges of LLMs in higher education and propose solutions for policy and governance.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Students use LLMs as writing tools, coding tools, and information retrieval tools, each with distinct ethical considerations.</li>
<li>Ethical concerns raised by stakeholders include inaccurate LLM responses, hallucinations, biases, privacy leakage, and academic integrity issues.</li>
<li>Stakeholders emphasized the necessity of guidance and rules for LLM use in higher education, including teaching digital literacy, rethinking education, and implementing cautious and contextual policies.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article provides valuable insights into the ethical considerations of LLMs in higher education. However, it predominantly focuses on the perspectives of stakeholders and does not delve into potential quantitative data to support the qualitative findings. Additionally, while the study identifies a range of ethical issues, it lacks a comprehensive exploration of possible solutions and their implications. Further research is needed to assess the efficacy of proposed solutions and to address the existing gaps in understanding the ethical implications of LLMs in computer science education. Moreover, the article could benefit from more in-depth discussions on the potential impact of LLMs on student learning outcomes and the effectiveness of academic assessment in the context of LLM usage.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-24</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12453v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12453v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12453v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12453v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>15657</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/The_teachers_are_confused_as_well_A_Multiple_Stakeholder_Ethics_Discussion_on_Large_Language_Models_in_Computing_Education/2024-01-23-The_teachers_are_confused_as_well_A_Multiple_Stakeholder_Ethics_Discussion_on_Large_Language_Models_in_Computing_Education.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12453v1/extracted/5362997/mental_model_fig_3.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>AutoRT: Embodied Foundation Models for Large Scale Orchestration of Robotic Agents</title>
  <dc:creator>Michael Ahn, Debidatta Dwibedi, Chelsea Finn, Montse Gonzalez Arenas, Keerthana Gopalakrishnan, Karol Hausman, Brian Ichter, Alex Irpan, Nikhil Joshi, Ryan Julian, Sean Kirmani, Isabel Leal, Edward Lee, Sergey Levine, Yao Lu, Isabel Leal, Sharath Maddineni, Kanishka Rao, Dorsa Sadigh, Pannag Sanketi, Pierre Sermanet, Quan Vuong, Stefan Welker, Fei Xia, Ted Xiao, Peng Xu, Steve Xu, Zhuo Xu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/AutoRT_Embodied_Foundation_Models_for_Large_Scale_Orchestration_of_Robotic_Agents/2024-01-23-AutoRT_Embodied_Foundation_Models_for_Large_Scale_Orchestration_of_Robotic_Agents.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/AutoRT_Embodied_Foundation_Models_for_Large_Scale_Orchestration_of_Robotic_Agents/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12963v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-the-article" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-of-the-article"><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong></h3>
<p>The article presents “AutoRT,” a system designed to leverage existing foundation models to scale up the deployment of operational robots in unseen scenarios with minimal human supervision. The system utilizes vision-language models (VLMs) for scene understanding, grounding, and leverages large language models (LLMs) for proposing diverse and novel instructions to be performed by a fleet of robots. This approach addresses the challenge of collecting large-scale, “in-the-wild” data grounded in the physical world. The system aims to guide the data collection of a fleet of robots, considering autonomy tradeoffs and safety while significantly scaling up data collection for robot learning. The system was demonstrated in real-world settings, proposing instructions to over 20 robots across multiple buildings and collecting 77,000 real robot episodes via teleoperation and autonomous robot policies.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>AutoRT demonstrates the scalability of robot deployment by allowing 1 human to supervise 3-5 mobile manipulators, resulting in the collection of diverse data for robot learning.</li>
<li>The data collected by AutoRT is significantly more diverse, and the use of LLMs allows for instruction following data collection robots that align with human preferences.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<p>The article presents a sophisticated system, AutoRT, for large-scale orchestration of robotic agents, showcasing its effectiveness in collecting diverse, real-world robot data. However, several limitations and challenges were identified during the article: 1. <strong>Dependence on Scripted and Learned Policies:</strong> The reliance on scripted and learned policies may limit the system’s ability to handle complex tasks or perform well in unseen settings, potentially affecting the throughput of successful episodes.</p>
<ol start="2" type="1">
<li><p><strong>Information Bottleneck and Model Limitations:</strong> Communication bandwidth between scene description and language model may introduce an information bottleneck, and foundation models face challenges in reasoning about embodiment-specific information, such as the physics of objects and robot capabilities.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Sparse Data and Learning Challenges:</strong> The highly diverse data collected by AutoRT may present a challenging learning problem, especially for existing state-of-the-art robot learning methods, requiring a balance between data quality and quantity.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Safety and Human Supervision:</strong> While constitutional prompting improves safety of tasks generated, it does not guarantee the robot’s adherence to the instructions, necessitating a significant degree of human supervision.</p></li>
</ol>
<p>In conclusion, while AutoRT presents a promising system for large-scale robotic data collection, addressing the identified limitations is crucial for its widespread and effective implementation. Future directions may involve advancing robust and diverse autonomous collect policies and exploring the integration of model improvement and data collection as a unified goal.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-24</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12963v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12963v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12963v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12963v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>12795</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/AutoRT_Embodied_Foundation_Models_for_Large_Scale_Orchestration_of_Robotic_Agents/2024-01-23-AutoRT_Embodied_Foundation_Models_for_Large_Scale_Orchestration_of_Robotic_Agents.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12963v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Towards Socially and Morally Aware RL agent: Reward Design With LLM</title>
  <dc:creator>Zhaoyue Wang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Towards_Socially_and_Morally_Aware_RL_agent_Reward_Design_With_LLM/2024-01-23-Towards_Socially_and_Morally_Aware_RL_agent_Reward_Design_With_LLM.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Towards_Socially_and_Morally_Aware_RL_agent_Reward_Design_With_LLM/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12459v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong> The article discusses the challenges of aligning Reinforcement Learning (RL) agents with human values, social norms, and moral principles. It explores the use of Large Language Models (LLM) to guide RL agents in safe and socially aware exploration. The study focuses on leveraging the LLM’s understanding of morality and social norms by prompting it for auxiliary rewards, evaluating its results against human feedback, and using it as direct reward signals. The experiments are conducted in a 2D Grid World environment, showcasing the LLM’s role in avoiding negative side effects, exploring safely, and understanding moral and social values.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Leveraging LLM for Safe Exploration:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The article demonstrates that LLM can guide RL agents to avoid negative side effects and explore with precaution, aligning the agent’s behavior with human values.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Language Model’s Understanding of Moral Values:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The study shows that the language model can converge to a globally optimal policy and differentiate between locally and globally optimal decisions based on moral values, suggesting its capability in understanding and guiding RL agents in moral decision-making.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Social Norms Understanding by the Language Model:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The experiments illustrate the language model’s understanding of social norms, as it provides guidance to the RL agent on appropriateness based on public and private contexts, demonstrating its potential in capturing context-dependent and ambiguous social norms.</li>
</ul></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article offers valuable insights into the use of LLM in guiding RL agents to align with human values and navigate complex moral and social scenarios. However, it has several limitations:</p>
<ol type="1">
<li><p><strong>Simplicity of the Environment:</strong> The experiments are conducted in a simple 2D Grid World with manually predetermined and static consequences, limiting the generalizability of the findings to more complex and dynamic environments.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Human Oversight and Bias:</strong> While the study showcases the alignment of LLM-generated rewards with human values, the article does not address potential biases or ethical considerations inherent in using language models for guiding decision-making in RL.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Limited Scalability:</strong> The future direction of testing the approach in larger and more complex environments is essential. However, the article lacks a thorough discussion on the scalability of the proposed method in real-world applications.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Unclear Interpretation of LLM’s Understanding:</strong> The deviation in the understanding of certain prompts by the language model raises questions about the interpretability and reliability of LLM-generated rewards in guiding RL agents.</p></li>
</ol>
<p>In conclusion, while the study offers promising avenues for socially and morally aware RL agents, further research addressing the identified limitations is crucial for real-world applicability and ethical considerations.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-24</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12459v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12459v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12459v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12459v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5148</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Towards_Socially_and_Morally_Aware_RL_agent_Reward_Design_With_LLM/2024-01-23-Towards_Socially_and_Morally_Aware_RL_agent_Reward_Design_With_LLM.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12459v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Benchmarking LLMs via Uncertainty Quantification</title>
  <dc:creator>Fanghua Ye, Mingming Yang, Jianhui Pang, Longyue Wang, Derek F. Wong, Emine Yilmaz, Shuming Shi, Zhaopeng Tu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Benchmarking_LLMs_via_Uncertainty_Quantification/2024-01-23-Benchmarking_LLMs_via_Uncertainty_Quantification.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Benchmarking_LLMs_via_Uncertainty_Quantification/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12794v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-the-article" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-of-the-article"><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong></h3>
<p>The article discusses the importance of uncertainty quantification in the evaluation of Large Language Models (LLMs) and proposes a new benchmarking approach that integrates uncertainty quantification. The study includes the examination of eight LLMs across five Natural Language Processing (NLP) tasks and introduces a novel evaluation metric, UAcc, which takes into account both prediction accuracy and prediction uncertainty. The findings reveal that LLMs with higher accuracy may exhibit lower certainty, larger-scale LLMs may display greater uncertainty compared to smaller ones, and instruction-finetuning tends to increase the uncertainty of LLMs.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs with higher accuracy may exhibit lower certainty.</li>
<li>Larger-scale LLMs may display greater uncertainty compared to their smaller counterparts.</li>
<li>Instruction-finetuning tends to increase the uncertainty of LLMs.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article successfully highlights the significance of incorporating uncertainty in the evaluation of LLMs, shedding light on the limitations of current evaluation platforms that neglect uncertainty. The proposed UAcc metric provides a more comprehensive assessment of LLMs by considering both prediction accuracy and uncertainty. However, the study does not provide a standardized methodology for benchmarking purpose, and the proposed approach may not be applicable to certain LLMs that are only accessible via their APIs. Additionally, it mainly focuses on language understanding abilities rather than generative potential, hence limiting its scope. Furthermore, the study does not delve into the evaluation of multi-modal foundation models, which represents an important area for future research.</p>
<p>Overall, while the article effectively demonstrates the importance of uncertainty quantification in LLM evaluation, it falls short in providing a standardized methodology for benchmarking purposes and addressing the generative capabilities of LLMs. Additionally, it overlooks the evaluation of multi-modal foundation models, which could impact the generalizability of the findings.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-24</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12794v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12794v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12794v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12794v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>12871</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Benchmarking_LLMs_via_Uncertainty_Quantification/2024-01-23-Benchmarking_LLMs_via_Uncertainty_Quantification.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12794v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Evaluation of large language models for assessing code maintainability</title>
  <dc:creator>Marc Dillmann, Julien Siebert, Adam Trendowicz</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Evaluation_of_large_language_models_for_assessing_code_maintainability/2024-01-23-Evaluation_of_large_language_models_for_assessing_code_maintainability.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Evaluation_of_large_language_models_for_assessing_code_maintainability/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12714v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-the-article" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-of-the-article">Summary of the Article:</h3>
<p>The article explores the use of large language models (LLMs) to assess code maintainability at a class level. It investigates the relationship between the cross-entropy of code generated by different LLMs and quality aspects such as readability, understandability, complexity, modularization, and overall maintainability. The study revealed a predictive relationship between cross-entropy and maintainability, especially when controlling for the number of logical lines of code (LLOC). However, the association reversed when not controlling for LLOC. The complexity of LLMs was found to influence the range of cross-entropy but did not significantly impact the predictability of maintainability aspects.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Cross-entropy computed by LLMs is a predictor of maintainability on a class level, particularly when controlling for LLOC.</li>
<li>The association between cross-entropy and maintainability reversed when not controlling for LLOC, indicating a potential confounding effect.</li>
<li>The complexity of LLMs affects the range of cross-entropy but does not play a significant role in predicting maintainability aspects.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article presents valuable insights into the use of LLMs for code maintainability assessment, highlighting the influence of cross-entropy and LLOC. However, it is crucial to acknowledge limitations in the study, such as its focus on a limited number of pretrained models and maintainability aspects, potentially affecting the generalizability of the findings. Methodological concerns, including the choice of evaluation metrics and assumptions about the use of LLMs as oracles, necessitate further exploration and validation. Additionally, the potential impact of data quality, selection bias, and construct validity on the study’s outcomes should be carefully considered in future research. Further investigations should address these limitations to enhance the robustness and applicability of the study’s findings.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-24</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12714v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12714v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12714v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12714v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6426</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Evaluation_of_large_language_models_for_assessing_code_maintainability/2024-01-23-Evaluation_of_large_language_models_for_assessing_code_maintainability.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12714v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>KAM-CoT: Knowledge Augmented Multimodal Chain-of-Thoughts Reasoning</title>
  <dc:creator>Debjyoti Mondal, Suraj Modi, Subhadarshi Panda, Rituraj Singh, Godawari Sudhakar Rao</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/KAM_CoT_Knowledge_Augmented_Multimodal_Chain_of_Thoughts_Reasoning/2024-01-23-KAM_CoT_Knowledge_Augmented_Multimodal_Chain_of_Thoughts_Reasoning.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/KAM_CoT_Knowledge_Augmented_Multimodal_Chain_of_Thoughts_Reasoning/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12863v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong></p>
<p>The article introduces KAM-CoT, a framework aimed at enhancing the reasoning capability and answer quality of language models in multimodal tasks. KAM-CoT integrates chain of thought (CoT) reasoning, knowledge graphs (KGs), and multiple modalities to achieve a deeper contextual understanding of multimodal tasks. By incorporating external knowledge from KGs during reasoning, the model reduces hallucinations and enhances the quality of answers. Experimental results show that KAM-CoT outperforms state-of-the-art methods on the ScienceQA dataset, achieving an average accuracy of 93.87% with only 280M trainable parameters at a time, demonstrating cost-efficiency and effectiveness.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>KAM-CoT integrates CoT reasoning, knowledge graphs, and multimodal capabilities to achieve a comprehensive understanding of multimodal tasks, resulting in improved answer quality and reduced hallucinations.</li>
<li>Experimental results demonstrate that KAM-CoT surpasses the performance of GPT-3.5 by 18% and GPT-4 by 10% on the ScienceQA dataset, achieving an average accuracy of 93.87% with only 280M trainable parameters, highlighting its cost-efficiency and effectiveness.</li>
<li>Fusion of different image encoders and the use of captions to extract graph nodes have shown to positively impact the model’s performance in reasoning and answering questions.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article presents an innovative framework, KAM-CoT, which successfully integrates CoT reasoning, knowledge graphs, and multimodal capabilities to enhance the reasoning and answer quality of language models in multimodal tasks. The experimental results demonstrate the superiority of KAM-CoT over existing state-of-the-art methods in terms of accuracy and cost-efficiency, highlighting its potential for practical applications in natural language processing tasks.</p>
<p>The article presents valuable insights and methodologies for improving multimodal reasoning and answer generation. However, some areas for improvement and future research could be identified, including: - Further exploration of the impact of different fusion mechanisms on the overall performance of the model. - The need for a more comprehensive analysis of the generalization capability of KAM-CoT across various domains and datasets beyond ScienceQA. - Potential performance analysis of the proposed model on larger datasets and comparison with a wider range of existing models.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-24</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12863v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12863v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12863v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12863v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8096</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/KAM_CoT_Knowledge_Augmented_Multimodal_Chain_of_Thoughts_Reasoning/2024-01-23-KAM_CoT_Knowledge_Augmented_Multimodal_Chain_of_Thoughts_Reasoning.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12863v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Raidar: geneRative AI Detection viA Rewriting</title>
  <dc:creator>Chengzhi Mao, Carl Vondrick, Hao Wang, Junfeng Yang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Raidar_geneRative_AI_Detection_viA_Rewriting/2024-01-23-Raidar_geneRative_AI_Detection_viA_Rewriting.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Raidar_geneRative_AI_Detection_viA_Rewriting/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12970v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-the-article" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-of-the-article">Summary of the Article:</h3>
<p>The article introduces “Raidar,” an approach to detect machine-generated text using large language models (LLMs) by prompting the models to rewrite text and calculating the editing distance of the output. The findings suggest that LLMs tend to make fewer modifications to AI-generated text than human-written text when prompted to rewrite the text. “Raidar” significantly improves the detection scores of existing AI content detection models across various domains. The method operates solely on word symbols, making it compatible with black-box LLMs and inherently robust on new content.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Large language models (LLMs) are more likely to modify human-written text than AI-generated text when tasked with rewriting.</li>
<li>“Raidar” significantly improves the F1 detection scores of existing AI content detection models across various domains, with gains of up to 29 points.</li>
<li>The method operates solely on word symbols, making it compatible with black-box LLMs and inherently robust on new content.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article provides valuable insights into the detection of machine-generated content using large language models, presenting a novel approach that enhances detection accuracy across various domains. However, while the “Raidar” method demonstrates effectiveness, there are aspects that require further exploration and clarification: - The article focuses on the quantitative performance of the “Raidar” method, but it does not delve into potential limitations or biases in the detection process. Further investigation into the robustness of the method, especially in the presence of adversarial attacks, is essential. - The study does not deeply investigate the potential ethical implications of its findings, particularly regarding the potential impact on natural language processing in various applications. - Additionally, the article highlights the effectiveness of the method across different datasets and domains, but it does not extensively discuss potential limitations or challenges that may arise when applying the method in real-world scenarios.</p>
<p>In conclusion, while the article presents a promising method for detecting machine-generated text, further research is needed to address potential limitations and ethical considerations associated with the implementation of this approach.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-24</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12970v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12970v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12970v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12970v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8701</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Raidar_geneRative_AI_Detection_viA_Rewriting/2024-01-23-Raidar_geneRative_AI_Detection_viA_Rewriting.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12970v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>ChatGraph: Chat with Your Graphs</title>
  <dc:creator>Yun Peng, Sen Lin, Qian Chen, Lyu Xu, Xiaojun Ren, Yafei Li, Jianliang Xu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ChatGraph_Chat_with_Your_Graphs/2024-01-23-ChatGraph_Chat_with_Your_Graphs.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ChatGraph_Chat_with_Your_Graphs/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12672v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong> The article introduces ChatGraph, a large language model (LLM)-based framework that enables users to interact with graphs through natural language, addressing the limitations of traditional graph analysis methods. The core of ChatGraph lies in generating chains of graph analysis APIs based on the understanding of texts and graphs inputted by the user. The framework is supported by three main modules: an API retrieval module, a graph-aware LLM module, and an API chain-oriented finetuning module. ChatGraph is demonstrated in four scenarios using real-world graphs, showcasing its usability and efficiency.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Traditional approaches for graph analysis rely on SPARQL-like languages or clicking-and-dragging interfaces, which may require high programming skills or have limited functionalities. ChatGraph, on the other hand, leverages a large language model (LLM) to enable users to interact with graphs through natural language, making it easier to use and more flexible than traditional methods.</li>
<li>The framework incorporates three key modules: an API retrieval module that searches for relevant APIs, a graph-aware LLM module that enables the LLM to comprehend graphs, and an API chain-oriented finetuning module that guides the LLM in generating API chains.</li>
<li>ChatGraph is the first chat-based LLM framework designed to interact with graphs, featuring powerful modules to support graph analysis through natural language. The demonstration showcases its usability and efficiency in four real-world scenarios using diverse graph datasets.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article presents a novel framework, ChatGraph, which offers a promising solution for individuals without high programming skills to interact with graphs through natural language. However, the demonstration primarily focuses on the technical aspects and usability of the framework, with limited discussion on potential challenges, limitations, or areas for further research.</p>
<p>One potential limitation is the dependency on large language models (LLMs), which could raise concerns regarding computational resources and potential biases or inaccuracies in the model’s outputs. Additionally, while the demonstration highlights the usability and efficiency of ChatGraph in real-world scenarios, further studies are needed to evaluate its performance on a broader range of graph analysis tasks and datasets. Moreover, the article could benefit from discussing the scalability of ChatGraph and its generalizability to diverse graph analysis domains beyond the showcased scenarios.</p>
<p>Overall, while ChatGraph shows promise in revolutionizing graph analysis, future research and practical applications will be crucial to fully assess its effectiveness, address potential limitations, and ensure its broad applicability across various real-world graph analysis tasks.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-24</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12672v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12672v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12672v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12672v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>3552</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ChatGraph_Chat_with_Your_Graphs/2024-01-23-ChatGraph_Chat_with_Your_Graphs.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12672v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>LLMCheckup: Conversational Examination of Large Language Models via Interpretability Tools</title>
  <dc:creator>Qianli Wang, Tatiana Anikina, Nils Feldhus, Josef van Genabith, Leonhard Hennig, Sebastian Möller</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLMCheckup_Conversational_Examination_of_Large_Language_Models_via_Interpretability_Tools/2024-01-23-LLMCheckup_Conversational_Examination_of_Large_Language_Models_via_Interpretability_Tools.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLMCheckup_Conversational_Examination_of_Large_Language_Models_via_Interpretability_Tools/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12576v1/extracted/5363462/figures/architecture_with_model_name.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong> The article introduces LLMCheckup, an interpretability tool designed to enhance user understanding of large language models (LLMs) through interactive dialogue-based explanations. LLMCheckup provides an accessible platform for users to converse with LLMs, enabling the models to generate self-explanations and recognize user intent without requiring fine-tuning. The tool incorporates a broad spectrum of explainable AI (XAI) tools, supports various input modalities, and offers tutorials for users with different levels of expertise in XAI. LLMCheckup is demonstrated with tasks such as fact checking and commonsense question answering, showcasing its effectiveness in enhancing model interpretability.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Conversational Interpretability:</strong> Moving beyond one-off explanations, LLMCheckup embraces dialogue-based explanations, facilitating a more effective understanding of model behavior through interactive conversations.</li>
<li><strong>Unified Framework:</strong> LLMCheckup streamlines interpretability processes by consolidating parsing, downstream task prediction, explanation generation, and response generation within a single framework, enhancing the accessibility and usability of XAI tools.</li>
<li><strong>Diverse Functionality:</strong> The tool supports multiple input modalities, including text, images, and audio, while also offering external information retrieval capabilities and customized inputs and prompts, providing a comprehensive and tailored user experience.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article offers a comprehensive overview of LLMCheckup, highlighting its potential to address the challenges associated with model interpretability. However, several limitations and considerations should be noted: 1. <strong>Language Limitations:</strong> The tool currently focuses on English language, and while it can be adapted for other languages, the effectiveness of multilingual LLMs in self-explanation and parsing tasks remains to be seen. 2. <strong>Model Limitations:</strong> Smaller LLMs may exhibit limitations in certain types of explanation generation and parsing, potentially impacting the tool’s performance for specific operations, requiring further investigation and potential enhancements. 3. <strong>Data-Centric Interpretability:</strong> LLMCheckup primarily focuses on model responses to single inputs, potentially limiting its applicability in scenarios where data-centric interpretability is required, such as medical report generation or gender-aware translation. 4. <strong>Usability for Custom Inputs:</strong> While the tool allows for customized inputs and prompts, the adaptability of model-generated explanations to users’ expertise levels may require further exploration for reliable simplicity. 5. <strong>Modalities for Explanations:</strong> While LLMCheckup supports multiple input modalities, the generation of explanations and responses is currently limited to text formats, potentially restricting its comprehensive analysis of image or audio inputs without converting them to textual format.</p>
<p>In conclusion, while LLMCheckup demonstrates significant potential in improving the interpretability of large language models, further research and development are needed to address its limitations and enhance its applicability across diverse language and modalities.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-24</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12576v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12576v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12576v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12576v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7746</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLMCheckup_Conversational_Examination_of_Large_Language_Models_via_Interpretability_Tools/2024-01-23-LLMCheckup_Conversational_Examination_of_Large_Language_Models_via_Interpretability_Tools.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12576v1/extracted/5363462/figures/architecture_with_model_name.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Multilingual and Fully Non-Autoregressive ASR with Large Language Model Fusion: A Comprehensive Study</title>
  <dc:creator>W. Ronny Huang, Cyril Allauzen, Tongzhou Chen, Kilol Gupta, Ke Hu, James Qin, Yu Zhang, Yongqiang Wang, Shuo-Yiin Chang, Tara N. Sainath</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Multilingual_and_Fully_Non_Autoregressive_ASR_with_Large_Language_Model_Fusion_A_Comprehensive_Study/2024-01-23-Multilingual_and_Fully_Non_Autoregressive_ASR_with_Large_Language_Model_Fusion_A_Comprehensive_Study.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Multilingual_and_Fully_Non_Autoregressive_ASR_with_Large_Language_Model_Fusion_A_Comprehensive_Study/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12789v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong></p>
<p>In the article “Multilingual and Fully Non-Autoregressive ASR with Large Language Model Fusion: A Comprehensive Study,” the authors address the latency issues associated with autoregressive nature in decoding within large language model (LLM) assisted automatic speech recognition (ASR) systems. They propose a non-autoregressive LLM-fused ASR system that leverages the Universal Speech Model (USM) and PaLM 2 language model, achieving significant average relative word error rate (WER) improvement of 10.8% on the FLEURS testset and 3.6% on YouTube captioning across all languages. The study also includes a comprehensive ablation study to analyze the impact of LLM size, context length, vocabulary size, and fusion methodology on ASR performance.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The non-autoregressive LLM-fused ASR system achieved an average relative WER improvement of 10.8% on the FLEURS testset and 3.6% on YouTube captioning across all languages.</li>
<li>The study analyzed factors such as LLM size, context length, vocabulary size, and fusion methodology, providing valuable insights into the factors influencing the effectiveness of large-scale LLM-fused speech recognition systems.</li>
<li>When examining the impact of LLM size, the study found that larger models can reduce the sensitivity to fusion weight, with optimal LM scoring weight shifting from 0.25 for a 128M LLM to 0.45 for a 340B LLM.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The study effectively addresses the issue of latency in large language model assisted ASR systems by proposing a non-autoregressive LLM-fused ASR system. The comprehensive ablation study provides significant insights into the impact of various parameters on ASR efficacy, contributing valuable knowledge to the field of multilingual ASR. However, while the study highlights the improvements in WER, it would benefit from a more detailed discussion on the potential limitations and challenges associated with the proposed non-autoregressive LLM-fused ASR system. Furthermore, a critical analysis of the computational costs and hardware requirements for implementing the proposed system would provide a more holistic view of its practical implications. Additionally, the study could further address the generalizability of the findings to different types of speech data and potential user experience considerations.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-24</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12789v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12789v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12789v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12789v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>3501</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Multilingual_and_Fully_Non_Autoregressive_ASR_with_Large_Language_Model_Fusion_A_Comprehensive_Study/2024-01-23-Multilingual_and_Fully_Non_Autoregressive_ASR_with_Large_Language_Model_Fusion_A_Comprehensive_Study.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12789v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>From Numbers to Words: Multi-Modal Bankruptcy Prediction Using the ECL Dataset</title>
  <dc:creator>Henri Arno, Klaas Mulier, Joke Baeck, Thomas Demeester</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/From_Numbers_to_Words_Multi_Modal_Bankruptcy_Prediction_Using_the_ECL_Dataset/2024-01-23-From_Numbers_to_Words_Multi_Modal_Bankruptcy_Prediction_Using_the_ECL_Dataset.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/From_Numbers_to_Words_Multi_Modal_Bankruptcy_Prediction_Using_the_ECL_Dataset/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12652v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong> The academic article introduces the ECL dataset, which combines textual and numerical data from corporate 10K filings with associated binary bankruptcy labels. The paper presents classical and neural bankruptcy prediction models developed using this dataset. It delves into the role of bankruptcy prediction models, the development of the ECL dataset, the experimental setup, bankruptcy prediction results, and the potential of large language models (LLMs) in bankruptcy prediction.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Complementary Information in Textual and Numerical Data:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The dataset demonstrates that the information from both textual and numerical data modalities is complementary for bankruptcy prediction.</li>
<li>The textual data, extracted from the management discussion and analysis (MD&amp;A), provides clear indications of bankruptcy consideration by companies. When explicit mentions of bankruptcy are absent, the numerical financial features become more informative for prediction.</li>
<li>Results show that models trained solely on binary labels cannot distinguish 10K records filed in the year preceding bankruptcy from records filed by financially unhealthy companies close to bankruptcy but not within one year.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Qualitative Analysis of Results:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Models trained on the combined predictions of textual and numerical data in an ensemble perform best overall.</li>
<li>The performance of models is evaluated based on various metrics, including the area under the receiver operating curve (ROC-AUC), average precision (AP), cumulative accuracy profile ratio (CAP ratio), and recall@100 for each classifier. The class imbalance in the dataset influences the high values on ROC-AUC and CAP ratio.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>The Potential of LLMs for Text-Based Bankruptcy Prediction:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The study explores the use of large language models (LLMs), specifically GPT-3.5, for text-based bankruptcy prediction.</li>
<li>The results show that the GPT-3.5 model’s zero-shot bankruptcy prediction results are poor. However, it demonstrates value by providing meaningful summaries of the text in the 10K filings for the bankruptcy prediction task.</li>
</ul></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article provides valuable insights into the complementary nature of textual and numerical data for bankruptcy prediction, shedding light on the limitations of binary label-based models. However, the study does not adequately address the issue of small sample size for positive bankruptcy cases, potentially affecting the generalizability of the results. Additionally, the discussion regarding the potential of LLMs seems limited, with a need for further exploration of their capabilities and limitations. Furthermore, the article focuses on the technical aspects of the models without delving into the broader impact of the findings on bankruptcy prediction and financial decision-making. Overall, the study opens up avenues for future research but could benefit from addressing these limitations for a more comprehensive analysis.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-24</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12652v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12652v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12652v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12652v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8352</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/From_Numbers_to_Words_Multi_Modal_Bankruptcy_Prediction_Using_the_ECL_Dataset/2024-01-23-From_Numbers_to_Words_Multi_Modal_Bankruptcy_Prediction_Using_the_ECL_Dataset.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.12652v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
