<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Bayesian beagle</title>
<link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Quarto blog of LLM-generated summaries of Arxiv preprints</description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.450</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Learning or Self-aligning? Rethinking Instruction Fine-tuning</title>
  <dc:creator>Mengjie Ren, Boxi Cao, Hongyu Lin, Liu Cao, Xianpei Han, Ke Zeng, Guanglu Wan, Xunliang Cai, Le Sun</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Learning_or_Self_aligning_Rethinking_Instruction_Fine_tuning/2024-02-28-Learning_or_Self_aligning_Rethinking_Instruction_Fine_tuning.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Learning_or_Self_aligning_Rethinking_Instruction_Fine_tuning/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18243v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Instruction Fine-tuning (IFT) is a critical phase in building large language models (LLMs).</li>
<li>Previous works mainly focus on the IFT’s role in the transfer of behavioral norms and the learning of additional world knowledge.</li>
<li>Surprisingly, attempts to learn additional world knowledge through IFT often struggle to yield positive impacts and can even lead to markedly negative effects.</li>
<li>Maintaining internal knowledge consistency before and after IFT is a critical factor for achieving successful IFT.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>IFT data consistent with model parameter knowledge leads to superior IFT outcomes.</li>
<li>Using IFT data that aligns with model parameter knowledge yet is erroneous yields better performance than employing those that are correct but incongruent with model parameter knowledge.</li>
<li>Ensuring that the model does not learn world knowledge conflicting with parameter knowledge during IFT enhances the effectiveness of IFT.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study focuses on the role of Instruction Fine-tuning (IFT) in large language models (LLMs) and its impact on the transfer of behavioral norms and additional world knowledge.</li>
<li>The findings reveal that the core function of IFT is not to learn domain-specific world knowledge, but to facilitate self-aligning instruction with the already existing parameter knowledge of LLMs.</li>
<li>The study provides guidance for future IFT data construction, model training, and model evaluation, shedding light on the future direction of data construction, model learning, and model evaluation for IFT.</li>
<li>The limitations of the study include the focus on multiple-choice questions and the use of models with about 10B parameters, which may limit the generalizability of the findings. Further research on larger models and free-style generation is recommended.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18243v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18243v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18243v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18243v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7107</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Learning_or_Self_aligning_Rethinking_Instruction_Fine_tuning/2024-02-28-Learning_or_Self_aligning_Rethinking_Instruction_Fine_tuning.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18243v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Exploring Advanced Methodologies in Security Evaluation for LLMs</title>
  <dc:creator>Jun Huang, Jiawei Zhang, Qi Wang, Weihong Han, Yanchun Zhang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Exploring_Advanced_Methodologies_in_Security_Evaluation_for_LLMs/2024-02-28-Exploring_Advanced_Methodologies_in_Security_Evaluation_for_LLMs.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Exploring_Advanced_Methodologies_in_Security_Evaluation_for_LLMs/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.17970v1/extracted/5433502/fig_llm.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Large Language Models (LLMs) have advanced capabilities to handle complex language patterns and generate coherent text, images, audios, and videos.</li>
<li>The rapid expansion of LLMs has raised security and ethical concerns, emphasizing the need for ongoing research into security evaluation during their development and deployment.</li>
<li>The article provides a comprehensive analysis of commonly used evaluation metrics, advanced evaluation frameworks, and the routine evaluation processes for LLMs.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The proliferation of LLMs has raised security and ethical concerns, necessitating ongoing research into security evaluation during their development and deployment.</li>
<li>The article provides a comprehensive analysis of commonly used evaluation metrics, advanced evaluation frameworks, and the routine evaluation processes for LLMs.</li>
<li>The research highlights the need for more dedicated attention to security threats and evaluations of LLMs, particularly in the area of multimodal LLMs.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides a comprehensive overview of evaluation metrics, evaluation frameworks, and evaluation processes for LLMs, addressing the need for more research in the area of multimodal LLMs.</li>
<li>However, the article lacks a specific implementation plan necessary for conducting a security evaluation, and the discussion of known evaluation frameworks is not comprehensive.</li>
<li>Future research should focus on the development of automated evaluation platforms, comprehensive coverage of threats, and dedicated research into the unique vulnerabilities and security complexities of multimodal LLMs.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.17970v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.17970v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.17970v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.17970v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5922</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Exploring_Advanced_Methodologies_in_Security_Evaluation_for_LLMs/2024-02-28-Exploring_Advanced_Methodologies_in_Security_Evaluation_for_LLMs.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.17970v1/extracted/5433502/fig_llm.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>ChatSpamDetector: Leveraging Large Language Models for Effective Phishing Email Detection</title>
  <dc:creator>Takashi Koide, Naoki Fukushi, Hiroki Nakano, Daiki Chiba</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ChatSpamDetector_Leveraging_Large_Language_Models_for_Effective_Phishing_Email_Detection/2024-02-28-ChatSpamDetector_Leveraging_Large_Language_Models_for_Effective_Phishing_Email_Detection.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ChatSpamDetector_Leveraging_Large_Language_Models_for_Effective_Phishing_Email_Detection/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18093v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The study introduces ChatSpamDetector, a system that uses large language models (LLMs) to detect phishing emails.</li>
<li>The system provides detailed reasoning for its phishing determinations, assisting users in making informed decisions about how to handle suspicious emails.</li>
<li>Evaluation using a comprehensive phishing email dataset confirmed that the system using GPT-4 has superior detection capabilities with an accuracy of 99.70%.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>ChatSpamDetector uses large language models (LLMs) to detect phishing emails and provides detailed reasoning for its determinations.</li>
<li>The system achieved an accuracy of 99.70% in detecting phishing emails, outperforming other models and baseline systems.</li>
<li>LLMs have the capability to extract key indicators from the headers and body of emails, prioritize them, and generate accurate responses, confirming their effectiveness in phishing detection.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The study excluded phishing emails that do not contain links in their body, limiting the scope of the research.</li>
<li>The default parameters for each LLM were used, but adjusting these parameters could change the results.</li>
<li>LLMs can enhance their outputs through Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) by searching for information from external knowledge bases, which could further improve accuracy.</li>
</ul>
<p>The study introduces a novel system, ChatSpamDetector, that effectively uses large language models to detect phishing emails. The system’s high accuracy and detailed reasoning for its determinations make it a valuable tool for users to make informed decisions about handling suspicious emails. However, the study has limitations in the scope of phishing emails analyzed and the parameters used for the large language models. Additionally, the potential for further improvement using Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) to enhance response accuracy is highlighted. Overall, the study provides valuable insights into the effectiveness of large language models in phishing email detection.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18093v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18093v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18093v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18093v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8456</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ChatSpamDetector_Leveraging_Large_Language_Models_for_Effective_Phishing_Email_Detection/2024-02-28-ChatSpamDetector_Leveraging_Large_Language_Models_for_Effective_Phishing_Email_Detection.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18093v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>How to think step-by-step: A mechanistic understanding of chain-of-thought reasoning</title>
  <dc:creator>Subhabrata Dutta, Joykirat Singh, Soumen Chakrabarti, Tanmoy Chakraborty</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/How_to_think_step_by_step_A_mechanistic_understanding_of_chain_of_thought_reasoning/2024-02-28-How_to_think_step_by_step_A_mechanistic_understanding_of_chain_of_thought_reasoning.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/../bayesian-beagle.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study investigates the neural sub-structures within Large Language Models (LLMs) that facilitate Chain-of-Thought (CoT) reasoning from a mechanistic point of view.</li>
<li>It identifies the components of the language model that are most important for a given task and explores the depth at which the model starts following the context provided as input.</li>
<li>The section discusses the attention heads in the language model (LLM) and their role in generating answers for different subtasks, as well as the use of fictional and false ontologies in the PrOntoQA dataset to prompt reasoning in large language models.</li>
<li>It presents Figure 14, illustrating the information flow through attention heads towards answer-writing heads in LLaMA-27B for subtask 5.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Large Language Models (LLMs) deploy multiple parallel pathways of answer generation for step-by-step reasoning.</li>
<li>The tasks are not structurally well-differentiated in the language model, and a good majority of heads share the importance of all three subtasks.</li>
<li>The model employs multiple pathways to compute answers, collecting information from different segments of the input.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The findings have implications for understanding the neural functional components involved in CoT reasoning and provide insights into the complex reasoning capabilities of LLMs.</li>
<li>The identification of parallel pathways for answer generation and the functional rift within the model layers contribute to a deeper understanding of LLMs’ reasoning processes.</li>
<li>The insights contribute to a deeper understanding of the circuitry of step-by-step generation in language models and can inform future research on language modeling and contribute to the development of more interpretable and reliable models.</li>
<li>The visual representation of the information flow highlights the complexity and multi-layered nature of the model’s processing, emphasizing the intricate mechanisms involved in generating responses and predicting specific tokens.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18312v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18312v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18312v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18312v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>24207</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/How_to_think_step_by_step_A_mechanistic_understanding_of_chain_of_thought_reasoning/2024-02-28-How_to_think_step_by_step_A_mechanistic_understanding_of_chain_of_thought_reasoning.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>MEGAnno+: A Human-LLM Collaborative Annotation System</title>
  <dc:creator>Hannah Kim, Kushan Mitra, Rafael Li Chen, Sajjadur Rahman, Dan Zhang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MEGAnno+_A_Human_LLM_Collaborative_Annotation_System/2024-02-28-MEGAnno+_A_Human_LLM_Collaborative_Annotation_System.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MEGAnno+_A_Human_LLM_Collaborative_Annotation_System/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18050v1/extracted/5429938/fig/architecture.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>MEGAnno+ is a collaborative annotation system that advocates for human-LLM collaboration to produce reliable and high-quality labels.</li>
<li>The system offers effective LLM agent and annotation management, convenient and robust LLM annotation, and exploratory verification of LLM labels by humans.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs can label data faster and cheaper than humans for various NLP tasks, but they may fall short in understanding complex, sociocultural, or domain-specific context.</li>
<li>LLMs have limitations and may produce biased labels, making human intervention in the data annotation process necessary.</li>
<li>MEGAnno+ is a human-LLM collaborative annotation system that offers effective management of LLM agents, annotations, and artifacts, convenient and robust interfacing with LLMs to obtain labels, and selective, exploratory verification of LLM labels by humans.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Designing an annotation task: The article suggests that designing an annotation task and prompt similar to more widely used and standardized NLP tasks is beneficial.</li>
<li>Consistency and reliability of LLM annotators: The article highlights the need to understand that LLM annotators and human annotators should not be treated the same, and annotation tools should carefully design their data models and workflows to accommodate both types of annotators.</li>
<li>Limitations: The post-processing mechanism may not be robust to cover all tasks and prompts entered by the user, and the ability to capture metadata is contingent on the LLM model used.</li>
<li>Future work: The authors plan to add more LLM agents, support customized extraction of metadata, and improve prompt template UI for data-aware in-context learning.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the article provides valuable insights into the collaborative annotation system and highlights the need for careful consideration of the limitations and challenges associated with LLM annotation. The article’s emphasis on future work and ethical considerations demonstrates a thoughtful approach to addressing potential problems and shortcomings in the field of human-LLM collaborative annotation.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18050v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18050v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18050v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18050v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5302</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MEGAnno+_A_Human_LLM_Collaborative_Annotation_System/2024-02-28-MEGAnno+_A_Human_LLM_Collaborative_Annotation_System.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18050v1/extracted/5429938/fig/architecture.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>LLM Task Interference: An Initial Study on the Impact of Task-Switch in Conversational History</title>
  <dc:creator>Akash Gupta, Ivaxi Sheth, Vyas Raina, Mark Gales, Mario Fritz</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLM_Task_Interference_An_Initial_Study_on_the_Impact_of_Task_Switch_in_Conversational_History/2024-02-28-LLM_Task_Interference_An_Initial_Study_on_the_Impact_of_Task_Switch_in_Conversational_History.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLM_Task_Interference_An_Initial_Study_on_the_Impact_of_Task_Switch_in_Conversational_History/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18216v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The study investigates the impact of task-switch in conversational history on large language models (LLMs).</li>
<li>The authors find that task-switches can lead to significant performance degradation in LLMs.</li>
<li>The study makes the first attempt to formalize the study of vulnerabilities and interference of tasks in conversational LLMs caused by task-switches in the conversational history.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The study formalizes the risk of performance degradation of LLMs due to task-switch.</li>
<li>The impact of task-switch on diverse datasets with more than 15 different task-switches is presented.</li>
<li>The study measures the task-switch sensitivity for popular LLMs of different sizes, observing that very large (175B) and small (7B) LLMs can both be susceptible to performance degradation from task-switch.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The study provides valuable insights into the vulnerabilities of LLMs to task-switches in conversational history, shedding light on the potential limitations of these models.</li>
<li>The limitations of the study include the inability to perform task sensitivity analysis on closed models and the maximum token length constraint, which limited the analysis over extremely long conversations.</li>
<li>Future work could focus on aligning humans and the model as a metric, which was out of the scope for this paper. Additionally, further research is needed to address the potential biases and vulnerabilities of LLMs to undesired information leakage from the conversation history.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18216v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18216v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18216v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18216v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5440</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLM_Task_Interference_An_Initial_Study_on_the_Impact_of_Task_Switch_in_Conversational_History/2024-02-28-LLM_Task_Interference_An_Initial_Study_on_the_Impact_of_Task_Switch_in_Conversational_History.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18216v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Hire a Linguist!: Learning Endangered Languages with In-Context Linguistic Descriptions</title>
  <dc:creator>Kexun Zhang, Yee Man Choi, Zhenqiao Song, Taiqi He, William Yang Wang, Lei Li</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Hire_a_Linguist!_Learning_Endangered_Languages_with_In_Context_Linguistic_Descriptions/2024-02-28-Hire_a_Linguist!_Learning_Endangered_Languages_with_In_Context_Linguistic_Descriptions.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Hire_a_Linguist!_Learning_Endangered_Languages_with_In_Context_Linguistic_Descriptions/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18025v1/extracted/5435348/figs/resource_comparison.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<p>The article introduces LingoLLM, a novel approach for enabling large language models (LLMs) to process and translate endangered languages. LingoLLM integrates linguistic descriptions such as grammar books and dictionaries, which are often more available for endangered languages than extensive corpora. The authors demonstrate the effectiveness of LingoLLM on multiple tasks across eight endangered and/or low-resource languages. The results show significant improvements in translation, conversation understanding, mathematical reasoning, word reordering, and keyword-to-text tasks.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LingoLLM significantly improves translation capability from GPT-4’s to BLEU for 9 out of 10 translation directions.</li>
<li>LingoLLM improves LLMs’ ability to select correct responses, achieving performance comparable to high-resource language inputs.</li>
<li>LingoLLM significantly improves the mathematical reasoning ability of LLMs on Manchu, solving 75% of the problems.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides valuable insights into the potential of linguistic knowledge in the age of LLMs for endangered languages.</li>
<li>The limitations of the study include the experiment being limited to 8 languages and potential contamination in reasoning tasks.</li>
<li>The impact statement highlights the importance of LingoLLM in preserving endangered languages and promoting linguistic equity.</li>
</ul>
<p>The article provides a comprehensive and innovative approach to addressing the challenges of processing and translating endangered languages using LLMs. However, the limitations and potential biases in the study should be carefully considered in future research.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18025v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18025v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18025v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18025v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7035</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Hire_a_Linguist!_Learning_Endangered_Languages_with_In_Context_Linguistic_Descriptions/2024-02-28-Hire_a_Linguist!_Learning_Endangered_Languages_with_In_Context_Linguistic_Descriptions.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18025v1/extracted/5435348/figs/resource_comparison.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>A Survey on Recent Advances in LLM-Based Multi-turn Dialogue Systems</title>
  <dc:creator>Zihao Yi, Jiarui Ouyang, Yuwen Liu, Tianhao Liao, Zhe Xu, Ying Shen</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_Survey_on_Recent_Advances_in_LLM_Based_Multi_turn_Dialogue_Systems/2024-02-28-A_Survey_on_Recent_Advances_in_LLM_Based_Multi_turn_Dialogue_Systems.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_Survey_on_Recent_Advances_in_LLM_Based_Multi_turn_Dialogue_Systems/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18013v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides an overview of large language models (LLMs) and their application in multi-turn dialogue systems, discussing the limitations of conventional dialogue systems and delving into different types of LLMs, such as decoder-only and encoder-only architectures, as well as specific LLM models like GPT and BERT series.</li>
<li>It discusses the encoder-decoder Transformer architecture, focusing on BART and T5 models, fine-tuning methods, and mitigating fine-tuning instabilities through methods like Regularization Fine-tuning (R3F), SMART, and Free Large-Batch Adversarial Training (FreeLB), as well as prompt engineering and LLM Based Task-oriented Dialogue Systems.</li>
<li>The article also covers pipeline-based methods in task-oriented dialogue (TOD) systems, highlighting natural language understanding, dialogue state tracking, policy learning, and natural language generation, and the challenges and advancements in each module.</li>
<li>It discusses the development and application of LLMs in multi-turn dialogue systems, emphasizing the significance of LLMs in advancing dialogue systems and addressing challenges such as emotionalization, personalization, multi-task dialogue systems, multi-model dialogue systems, bias identification, and privacy protection.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Large language models (LLMs) play a crucial role in advancing multi-turn dialogue systems, addressing challenges such as emotionalization, personalization, and bias identification.</li>
<li>The article highlights the significance of pre-training and fine-tuning methods for Transformer models, showcasing their potential in natural language processing tasks and dialogue systems.</li>
<li>Pipeline-based methods in task-oriented dialogue systems are essential for natural language understanding, dialogue state tracking, policy learning, and natural language generation, contributing to the overall effectiveness of dialogue systems.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides a comprehensive overview of LLMs and their application in dialogue systems, but it could benefit from more in-depth discussions on the ethical implications and potential biases associated with LLM-based dialogue systems.</li>
<li>While the article covers various pre-training and fine-tuning methods, it would be valuable to include a comparative analysis of their effectiveness in different dialogue system applications.</li>
<li>The discussion on pipeline-based methods in task-oriented dialogue systems is informative, but further exploration of real-world applications and case studies would enhance the practical relevance of the article.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18013v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18013v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18013v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18013v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>18047</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_Survey_on_Recent_Advances_in_LLM_Based_Multi_turn_Dialogue_Systems/2024-02-28-A_Survey_on_Recent_Advances_in_LLM_Based_Multi_turn_Dialogue_Systems.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18013v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Exploring Multi-Document Information Consolidation for Scientific Sentiment Summarization</title>
  <dc:creator>Miao Li, Jey Han Lau, Eduard Hovy</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Exploring_Multi_Document_Information_Consolidation_for_Scientific_Sentiment_Summarization/2024-02-28-Exploring_Multi_Document_Information_Consolidation_for_Scientific_Sentiment_Summarization.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Exploring_Multi_Document_Information_Consolidation_for_Scientific_Sentiment_Summarization/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18005v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article explores the capability of modern natural language generation systems to consolidate information from multiple documents and generate plausible summaries, especially when the source documents contain opinionated information.</li>
<li>The authors propose a three-layer framework of sentiment consolidation in meta-review generation and validate it through human annotation. They also introduce evaluation metrics to assess the quality of generated meta-reviews and find empirical validation of the sentiment consolidation framework when integrated as prompts for language models (LLMs) in extensive experiments.</li>
<li>The authors conclude that integrating the sentiment consolidation framework into LLMs can improve the generation of meta-reviews and propose future work to adapt the framework to other domains and investigate its application to fine-tuned models.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Notable strides have been made in abstractive text summarization with the advancement of large language models (LLMs) over recent years.</li>
<li>The proposed three-layer framework of sentiment consolidation in meta-review generation is validated through human annotation and empirical experiments.</li>
<li>Integration of the sentiment consolidation framework into LLMs improves the generation of meta-reviews.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides valuable insights into the potential of integrating sentiment consolidation logic into language models for generating meta-reviews.</li>
<li>The proposed framework and evaluation metrics offer a systematic approach to assess the quality of generated meta-reviews.</li>
<li>However, the limitations of the study, such as the lack of publicly available peer review data and the focus on English texts, should be addressed in future research.</li>
<li>The authors emphasize the importance of manual verification and review of generated results, highlighting the ethical considerations of relying solely on machine-generated meta-reviews.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18005v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18005v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18005v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18005v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6260</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Exploring_Multi_Document_Information_Consolidation_for_Scientific_Sentiment_Summarization/2024-02-28-Exploring_Multi_Document_Information_Consolidation_for_Scientific_Sentiment_Summarization.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18005v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Multi-FAct: Assessing Multilingual LLMs’ Multi-Regional Knowledge using FActScore</title>
  <dc:creator>Sheikh Shafayat, Eunsu Kim, Juhyun Oh, Alice Oh</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Multi_FAct_Assessing_Multilingual_LLMs_Multi_Regional_Knowledge_using_FActScore/2024-02-28-Multi_FAct_Assessing_Multilingual_LLMs_Multi_Regional_Knowledge_using_FActScore.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Multi_FAct_Assessing_Multilingual_LLMs_Multi_Regional_Knowledge_using_FActScore/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18045v1/extracted/5436549/figures/GPT3.5-FS-EN.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper evaluates multilingual Large Language Models’ (LLMs) factual accuracy across languages and geographic regions.</li>
<li>A novel pipeline for multilingual factuality evaluation, adapting FActScore for diverse languages, is introduced.</li>
<li>English consistently outperforms other languages in factual accuracy and quantity of generated facts.</li>
<li>Multilingual models demonstrate a bias towards factual information from Western continents.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>English consistently maintains an advantage in both factual accuracy and the quantity of generated facts compared to other languages when generating identical content.</li>
<li>Content produced by multilingual language models tends to exhibit a stronger performance for factual information originating from Western regions, such as America and Europe, across the languages.</li>
<li>The findings highlight the influence of output length differences on the number of correct and hallucinated facts across languages, despite similar FActScore values.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study reveals a Western-centric bias in the factual content distribution across languages, emphasizing the need for enhanced assessment methods in evaluating multilingual factual accuracy.</li>
<li>The paper’s methodology has limitations, such as small sample bias and varying durations national leaders have been in power, potentially biasing internet corpora in their favor.</li>
<li>Future research should aim to distinguish between specific, valuable facts and generic, less informative ones and examine the consistency of model-generated facts across different languages.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18045v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18045v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18045v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18045v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5903</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Multi_FAct_Assessing_Multilingual_LLMs_Multi_Regional_Knowledge_using_FActScore/2024-02-28-Multi_FAct_Assessing_Multilingual_LLMs_Multi_Regional_Knowledge_using_FActScore.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18045v1/extracted/5436549/figures/GPT3.5-FS-EN.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Rethinking the Bounds of LLM Reasoning: Are Multi-Agent Discussions the Key?</title>
  <dc:creator>Qineng Wang, Zihao Wang, Ying Su, Hanghang Tong, Yangqiu Song</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Rethinking_the_Bounds_of_LLM_Reasoning_Are_Multi_Agent_Discussions_the_Key/2024-02-28-Rethinking_the_Bounds_of_LLM_Reasoning_Are_Multi_Agent_Discussions_the_Key.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Rethinking_the_Bounds_of_LLM_Reasoning_Are_Multi_Agent_Discussions_the_Key/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18272v1/extracted/5436554/assets/pic/fig1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<p>Recent progress in LLMs discussion suggests that multi-agent discussion improves the reasoning abilities of LLMs. In this work, a novel group discussion framework is proposed to enrich the set of discussion mechanisms. The results show that a single-agent LLM with strong prompts can achieve almost the same performance as the best existing discussion approach on a wide range of reasoning tasks and backbone LLMs. Multi-agent discussion performs better than a single agent only when there is no demonstration in the prompt. Further study reveals the common interaction mechanisms of LLMs during the discussion.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>A single-agent LLM with strong prompts can achieve almost the same performance as the best existing discussion approach on a wide range of reasoning tasks and backbone LLMs.</li>
<li>Multi-agent discussion performs better than a single agent only when there is no demonstration in the prompt.</li>
<li>Common interaction mechanisms of LLMs during the discussion were revealed.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study provides valuable insights into the effectiveness of multi-agent discussions for reasoning tasks.</li>
<li>The findings suggest that prompt engineering can significantly boost reasoning performance in large language models.</li>
<li>The study highlights the potential for multi-agent discussions to enhance reasoning abilities in scenarios where expert knowledge or detailed examples are insufficient.</li>
<li>The research also identifies two common types of errors in multi-agent discussions: Judge Mistake and Wrong Answer Propagation.</li>
<li>The study provides a comprehensive and fair assessment of the performance of a strong single agent and multi-agent discussions, offering valuable insights for future research.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18272v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18272v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18272v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18272v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>9233</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Rethinking_the_Bounds_of_LLM_Reasoning_Are_Multi_Agent_Discussions_the_Key/2024-02-28-Rethinking_the_Bounds_of_LLM_Reasoning_Are_Multi_Agent_Discussions_the_Key.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18272v1/extracted/5436554/assets/pic/fig1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Large Language Models As Evolution Strategies</title>
  <dc:creator>Robert Tjarko Lange, Yingtao Tian, Yujin Tang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Large_Language_Models_As_Evolution_Strategies/2024-02-28-Large_Language_Models_As_Evolution_Strategies.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Large_Language_Models_As_Evolution_Strategies/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18381v1/extracted/5437812/figures/f3_context_buffer.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Large language models (LLMs) are investigated to determine if they can implement evolutionary optimization algorithms.</li>
<li>A novel prompting strategy is introduced to enable LLMs to propose improvements to the mean statistic for black-box optimization.</li>
<li>Empirical findings show that the setup allows for an LLM-based evolution strategy, EvoLLM, to outperform baseline algorithms on synthetic BBOB functions and small neuroevolution tasks.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs can act as ‘plug-in’ in-context recombination operators for evolutionary optimization algorithms.</li>
<li>EvoLLM robustly outperforms baseline algorithms such as random search and Gaussian Hill Climbing on synthetic BBOB functions and small neuroevolution tasks.</li>
<li>The performance of EvoLLM is influenced by the model size, prompt strategy, and context construction.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study provides valuable insights into the potential of LLMs for implementing evolutionary optimization algorithms.</li>
<li>The findings suggest that LLMs can be leveraged for autonomous optimization, but further research is needed to understand the impact of pretraining and fine-tuning protocols on EvoLLM’s performance.</li>
<li>The study highlights the importance of careful solution representation and context construction for LLM-based optimization.</li>
<li>The potential ethical considerations of using LLMs for autonomous optimization purposes are acknowledged, emphasizing the need for careful monitoring of their agency.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18381v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18381v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18381v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18381v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7331</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Large_Language_Models_As_Evolution_Strategies/2024-02-28-Large_Language_Models_As_Evolution_Strategies.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18381v1/extracted/5437812/figures/f3_context_buffer.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>LeMo-NADe: Multi-Parameter Neural Architecture Discovery with LLMs</title>
  <dc:creator>Md Hafizur Rahman, Prabuddha Chakraborty</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LeMo_NADe_Multi_Parameter_Neural_Architecture_Discovery_with_LLMs/2024-02-28-LeMo_NADe_Multi_Parameter_Neural_Architecture_Discovery_with_LLMs.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LeMo_NADe_Multi_Parameter_Neural_Architecture_Discovery_with_LLMs/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18443v1/extracted/5438029/Figure/Overview.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Building efficient neural network architectures for edge devices is challenging due to parameters like power consumption, model size, and inferencing speed.</li>
<li>LeMo-NADe is a framework designed to automatically discover new neural network architectures based on user-defined parameters, an expert system, and an LLM trained on open-domain knowledge.</li>
<li>The framework was validated using CIFAR-10, CIFAR-100, and ImageNet16-120 datasets with GPT-4 Turbo and Gemini as the LLM component, showing rapid discovery of intricate neural network models.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Traditional NAS frameworks are limited by predefined search spaces, while LeMo-NADe does not rely on such spaces, allowing for the discovery of novel neural network architectures.</li>
<li>LeMo-NADe is capable of prioritizing metrics besides accuracy, making it optimal for different IoT/Edge requirements.</li>
<li>The framework outperforms traditional NAS techniques in terms of efficiency and performance across diverse application settings.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Traditional NAS techniques focus primarily on improving task accuracy with little emphasis on additional parameters such as frames-per-second, power consumption, and emissions, which are increasingly relevant.</li>
<li>The use of LLMs for neural architecture discovery raises questions about the generalization of the discovered architectures and the potential biases in the open-domain knowledge used to train the LLM.</li>
<li>The framework’s reliance on an expert system and user-defined metrics may introduce subjectivity and bias into the neural architecture discovery process.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18443v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18443v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18443v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18443v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5440</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LeMo_NADe_Multi_Parameter_Neural_Architecture_Discovery_with_LLMs/2024-02-28-LeMo_NADe_Multi_Parameter_Neural_Architecture_Discovery_with_LLMs.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18443v1/extracted/5438029/Figure/Overview.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Retrieval-based Full-length Wikipedia Generation for Emergent Events</title>
  <dc:creator>Jiebin Zhang, Eugene J. Yu, Qinyu Chen, Chenhao Xiong, Dawei Zhu, Han Qian, Mingbo Song, Xiaoguang Li, Qun Liu, Sujian Li</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Retrieval_based_Full_length_Wikipedia_Generation_for_Emergent_Events/2024-02-28-Retrieval_based_Full_length_Wikipedia_Generation_for_Emergent_Events.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Retrieval_based_Full_length_Wikipedia_Generation_for_Emergent_Events/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18264v1/extracted/5437378/figures/intro.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper addresses the challenge of quickly generating comprehensive and accurate Wikipedia documents for emerging events.</li>
<li>It introduces a new benchmark, WikiGenBen, consisting of 309 events paired with their corresponding retrieved web pages for generating evidence.</li>
<li>The study simulates a real-world scenario where structured full-length Wikipedia documents are generated for emergent events using input retrieved from web sources.</li>
<li>The authors design a comprehensive set of systematic evaluation metrics and baseline methods to evaluate the capability of Large Language Models (LLMs) in generating factual full-length Wikipedia documents.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Wikipedia serves as an important reference for various NLP tasks, but the task of automatically generating Wikipedia content in real-world scenarios has not been fully explored.</li>
<li>The retrieval-based generation of full-length Wikipedia articles is a common scenario ideally suited for the Retrieve-then-Read (RR) and Retrieve-Plan-Retrieve-Read (RPRR) methods.</li>
<li>The study finds that the number of retrieved documents, the type of retriever used, and the source of related documents all impact the informativeness and faithfulness of the generated Wikipedia articles.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study highlights the complexity of balancing various metrics in the generation of Wikipedia articles, emphasizing the need for refining task segmentation methods to enhance performance.</li>
<li>The authors acknowledge limitations in their section-by-section generation approach, potential redundancy, and the challenge of direct citation by LLMs, suggesting the need for further exploration of post-citation methods.</li>
<li>The paper raises ethical considerations and asserts that the research does not present any ethical issues, adhering to the ACL Ethics Policy.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18264v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18264v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18264v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18264v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6608</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Retrieval_based_Full_length_Wikipedia_Generation_for_Emergent_Events/2024-02-28-Retrieval_based_Full_length_Wikipedia_Generation_for_Emergent_Events.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18264v1/extracted/5437378/figures/intro.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Cause and Effect: Can Large Language Models Truly Understand Causality?</title>
  <dc:creator>Swagata Ashwani, Kshiteesh Hegde, Nishith Reddy Mannuru, Mayank Jindal, Dushyant Singh Sengar, Krishna Chaitanya Rao Kathala, Dishant Banga, Vinija Jain, Aman Chadha</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Cause_and_Effect_Can_Large_Language_Models_Truly_Understand_Causality/2024-02-28-Cause_and_Effect_Can_Large_Language_Models_Truly_Understand_Causality.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Cause_and_Effect_Can_Large_Language_Models_Truly_Understand_Causality/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18139v1/extracted/5423783/model_accuracy_across_datasets.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article introduces the Context-Aware Reasoning Enhancement with Counterfactual Analysis (CARE-CA) framework to enhance causal reasoning and explainability in Large Language Models (LLMs).</li>
<li>The framework combines explicit causal detection with ConceptNet and implicit causal detection through LLMs, along with a layer of counterfactual explanations to accentuate LLMs’ understanding of causality.</li>
<li>Evaluation of benchmark datasets shows improved performance across all metrics, and the introduction of CausalNet, a new dataset, is aimed at facilitating further research in this domain.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The CARE-CA framework combines explicit and implicit causal reasoning to enhance LLMs’ understanding of causality.</li>
<li>Evaluation of benchmark datasets shows improved performance across all metrics, such as accuracy, precision, recall, and F1 scores.</li>
<li>The introduction of CausalNet, a new dataset, is aimed at facilitating further research in the domain of causal reasoning.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides a comprehensive approach to enhancing LLMs’ causal reasoning faculties, but it is limited to English language models, limiting its generalizability across languages and cultures.</li>
<li>The computational resources required by the CARE-CA framework may limit accessibility for those with constrained computational budgets, pointing to a need for optimization strategies.</li>
<li>The article acknowledges the ethical responsibilities of conducting research with LLMs and strives to prevent the propagation of bias within the CausalNet dataset. However, further research is required to improve transparency and explain the model’s reasoning processes, especially for non-expert users.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18139v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18139v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18139v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18139v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5773</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Cause_and_Effect_Can_Large_Language_Models_Truly_Understand_Causality/2024-02-28-Cause_and_Effect_Can_Large_Language_Models_Truly_Understand_Causality.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18139v1/extracted/5423783/model_accuracy_across_datasets.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>An Iterative Associative Memory Model for Empathetic Response Generation</title>
  <dc:creator>Zhou Yang, Zhaochun Ren, Yufeng Wang, Chao Chen, Haizhou Sun, Xiaofei Zhu, Xiangwen Liao</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/An_Iterative_Associative_Memory_Model_for_Empathetic_Response_Generation/2024-02-28-An_Iterative_Associative_Memory_Model_for_Empathetic_Response_Generation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/An_Iterative_Associative_Memory_Model_for_Empathetic_Response_Generation/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.17959v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Empathetic response generation is the task of understanding the cognitive and emotional states in dialogue utterances and generating appropriate responses.</li>
<li>Existing approaches overlook the associated words between dialogue utterances, leading to inaccurate understanding of emotional and cognitive states.</li>
<li>The proposed Iterative Associative Memory Model (IAMM) employs a second-order interaction attention mechanism to iteratively capture vital associated words between dialogue utterances and situations, dialogue history, and a memory module, thereby accurately and nuancedly comprehending the utterances.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>IAMM outperforms the baselines on most metrics, demonstrating better performance in emotion accuracy, diversity, and human evaluation.</li>
<li>Ablation studies show that both explicit and implicit associative information have considerable influence on emotion accuracy and diversity.</li>
<li>IAMM focusing on associative relationships has stronger emotion recognition and expression abilities, further demonstrating the effectiveness of iterative associations.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The proposed IAMM demonstrates superior performance in accurately understanding emotions and expressing more empathetic responses compared to the baselines.</li>
<li>The model effectively captures associated words and utilizes them to generate informative and relevant responses.</li>
<li>The analysis of associated words reveals that the model pays attention to common words with low emotions, while its most highly weighted words have high emotion intensity or are less common.</li>
<li>The limitations of the work include the reliance on text-based empathetic comprehension mechanisms and the lack of situation information in some datasets. Future work may explore multimodal empathetic comprehension mechanisms and effective construction of situation information.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.17959v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.17959v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.17959v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.17959v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6504</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/An_Iterative_Associative_Memory_Model_for_Empathetic_Response_Generation/2024-02-28-An_Iterative_Associative_Memory_Model_for_Empathetic_Response_Generation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.17959v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Editing Factual Knowledge and Explanatory Ability of Medical Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Derong Xu, Ziheng Zhang, Zhihong Zhu, Zhenxi Lin, Qidong Liu, Xian Wu, Tong Xu, Xiangyu Zhao, Yefeng Zheng, Enhong Chen</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Editing_Factual_Knowledge_and_Explanatory_Ability_of_Medical_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-28-Editing_Factual_Knowledge_and_Explanatory_Ability_of_Medical_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Editing_Factual_Knowledge_and_Explanatory_Ability_of_Medical_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18099v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Model editing aims to modify the behaviors of large language models (LLMs) by precisely manipulating specific knowledge while keeping other knowledge unaffected.</li>
<li>The proposed MedLaSA strategy employs causal tracing to identify the precise location of knowledge in neurons and introduces scalable adapters into the dense layers of LLMs.</li>
<li>Extensive experiments on medical LLMs demonstrate the editing efficiency of MedLaSA, without affecting irrelevant knowledge that is not edited.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Model editing methods struggle with the specialization and complexity of medical knowledge.</li>
<li>MedLaSA significantly outperforms existing cutting-edge methods in editing medical LLMs.</li>
<li>The removal of Scaling Rank (SR) leads to a decline in all metrics, indicating its crucial role in maintaining the overall performance.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The proposed MedLaSA method effectively addresses the challenges of specialization and complexity of medical knowledge in model editing.</li>
<li>However, the method may have a negative impact on Generality and lacks consideration for batch editing and sequence editing.</li>
<li>The datasets used for medical model editing do not consider more robust evaluations, such as portability, and the number of samples for medical model editing is relatively small.</li>
<li>The performance of MedLaSA on encyclopedic data remains to be explored.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18099v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18099v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18099v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18099v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6898</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Editing_Factual_Knowledge_and_Explanatory_Ability_of_Medical_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-28-Editing_Factual_Knowledge_and_Explanatory_Ability_of_Medical_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18099v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Making Them Ask and Answer: Jailbreaking Large Language Models in Few Queries via Disguise and Reconstruction</title>
  <dc:creator>Tong Liu, Yingjie Zhang, Zhe Zhao, Yinpeng Dong, Guozhu Meng, Kai Chen</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Making_Them_Ask_and_Answer_Jailbreaking_Large_Language_Models_in_Few_Queries_via_Disguise_and_Reconstruction/2024-02-28-Making_Them_Ask_and_Answer_Jailbreaking_Large_Language_Models_in_Few_Queries_via_Disguise_and_Reconstruction.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Making_Them_Ask_and_Answer_Jailbreaking_Large_Language_Models_in_Few_Queries_via_Disguise_and_Reconstruction/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18104v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The academic article “Making Them Ask and Answer: Jailbreaking Large Language Models in Few Queries via Disguise and Reconstruction” explores the vulnerability of large language models (LLMs) to jailbreak attacks, particularly in the context of harmful or toxic responses. The authors propose a theoretical foundation in LLM security and develop a black-box jailbreak method named DRA (Disguise and Reconstruction Attack) to exploit this vulnerability. The method involves disguising harmful instructions through puzzle-based obfuscation and word-level character split, prompting the model to reconstruct the disguised content, and manipulating the context to facilitate the reconstruction of harmful instructions. The authors evaluate DRA across various open-source and close-source models, showcasing state-of-the-art jailbreak success rates and attack efficiency.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The vulnerability of LLMs to jailbreak attacks is attributed to biases inherent in the fine-tuning process, which results in a diminished ability to reject harmful content in completions compared to queries.</li>
<li>The DRA method, which combines disguise, payload reconstruction, and context manipulation, demonstrates superior attack success rates and efficiency compared to state-of-the-art baselines across various LLMs.</li>
<li>The ablation study highlights the critical role of disguise, payload reconstruction, and context manipulation in bypassing the safeguard of LLMs.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article effectively identifies and analyzes the vulnerability of LLMs to jailbreak attacks, providing a novel approach to exploit this vulnerability.</li>
<li>The empirical evaluation of the DRA method demonstrates its effectiveness and efficiency in bypassing LLM safeguards.</li>
<li>The ablation study provides valuable insights into the nuanced interplay between disguise, payload reconstruction, and context manipulation in bypassing LLM safeguards.</li>
<li>The article could benefit from a more detailed discussion of potential ethical considerations and implications of the proposed jailbreak method.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the article makes a significant contribution to the understanding of LLM vulnerabilities and provides a novel approach to exploit these vulnerabilities for jailbreak attacks. Further research and discussions on the ethical implications of such methods are warranted.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18104v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18104v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18104v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18104v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>10757</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Making_Them_Ask_and_Answer_Jailbreaking_Large_Language_Models_in_Few_Queries_via_Disguise_and_Reconstruction/2024-02-28-Making_Them_Ask_and_Answer_Jailbreaking_Large_Language_Models_in_Few_Queries_via_Disguise_and_Reconstruction.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18104v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Towards Generalist Prompting for Large Language Models by Mental Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Haoxiang Guan, Jiyan He, Shuxin Zheng, En-Hong Chen, Weiming Zhang, Nenghai Yu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Towards_Generalist_Prompting_for_Large_Language_Models_by_Mental_Models/2024-02-28-Towards_Generalist_Prompting_for_Large_Language_Models_by_Mental_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Towards_Generalist_Prompting_for_Large_Language_Models_by_Mental_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18252v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Large language models (LLMs) have shown impressive performance on various tasks, but still require specially designed prompting methods for optimal performance.</li>
<li>The article introduces the concept of generalist prompting, aiming to achieve optimal or near-optimal performance on a wide range of tasks without manual selection and customization of prompts.</li>
<li>MeMo (Mental Models) is proposed as a simple-designed prompting method that effectively fulfills the criteria of generalist prompting, achieving state-of-the-art results on diverse tasks in zero-shot settings.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The evolution of artificial intelligence (AI) models towards generalist capabilities has followed a distinct trajectory, with LLMs capable of handling a wide range of natural language processing tasks.</li>
<li>MeMo, as a generalist prompting method, achieves or is near to the state-of-the-art performance on diverse tasks with LLMs in zero-shot settings, eliminating manual selection and customization of prompts.</li>
<li>MeMo leverages the concept of mental models to enable LLMs to autonomously select and apply suitable mental models for problem-solving, surpassing existing prompting methods that require task-specific customization.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>MeMo suffers from high computational costs due to the long prompt that informs LLMs with the knowledge of mental models.</li>
<li>The approach relies on the availability and quality of exemplars, which can affect the selection and application of mental models.</li>
<li>The article does not guarantee the correctness or consistency of the mental models that LLMs employ, which can lead to errors or contradictions in some cases.</li>
<li>Future work could investigate how to verify and refine the mental models that LLMs generate, as well as how to enable LLMs to understand and apply mental models more accurately.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18252v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18252v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18252v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18252v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6820</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Towards_Generalist_Prompting_for_Large_Language_Models_by_Mental_Models/2024-02-28-Towards_Generalist_Prompting_for_Large_Language_Models_by_Mental_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18252v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Prospect Personalized Recommendation on Large Language Model-based Agent Platform</title>
  <dc:creator>Jizhi Zhang, Keqin Bao, Wenjie Wang, Yang Zhang, Wentao Shi, Wanhong Xu, Fuli Feng, Tat-Seng Chua</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Prospect_Personalized_Recommendation_on_Large_Language_Model_based_Agent_Platform/2024-02-28-Prospect_Personalized_Recommendation_on_Large_Language_Model_based_Agent_Platform.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/../bayesian-beagle.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article presents a clear and well-documented LATEX document formatted for publication by ACM in a conference proceedings or journal publication.</li>
<li>It explains many common variations and formatting elements an author may use in the preparation of their work.</li>
<li>The “acmart” document class can be used to prepare articles for any ACM publication, and the article provides insight and instruction into recent changes to the article template.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>ACM’s consolidated article template, introduced in 2017, provides a consistent LATEX style for use across ACM publications, incorporating accessibility and metadata-extraction functionality.</li>
<li>The “acmart” document class can be used to prepare different kinds of documentation, such as a double-blind initial submission of a full-length technical paper, a two-page SIGGRAPH Emerging Technologies abstract, a “camera-ready” journal article, a SIGCHI Extended Abstract, and more.</li>
<li>The article explains the primary parameter given to the “acmart” document class, which is the template style corresponding to the kind of publication or SIG publishing the work.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides a comprehensive guide for authors new to publishing with ACM, but it lacks a detailed discussion of the potential challenges or limitations of using the “acmart” document class.</li>
<li>The article does not address any methodological issues, conflicting evidence, or areas that require further research or clarification.</li>
<li>It would be beneficial to include a section discussing the potential biases or limitations of using the “acmart” document class and the impact on the publication process.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18240v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18240v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18240v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18240v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>4979</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>recommender</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Prospect_Personalized_Recommendation_on_Large_Language_Model_based_Agent_Platform/2024-02-28-Prospect_Personalized_Recommendation_on_Large_Language_Model_based_Agent_Platform.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
