<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Bayesian beagle</title>
<link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Quarto blog of LLM-generated summaries of Arxiv preprints</description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.450</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Slot-VLM: SlowFast Slots for Video-Language Modeling</title>
  <dc:creator>Jiaqi Xu, Cuiling Lan, Wenxuan Xie, Xuejin Chen, Yan Lu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Slot_VLM_SlowFast_Slots_for_Video_Language_Modeling/2024-02-20-Slot_VLM_SlowFast_Slots_for_Video_Language_Modeling.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Slot_VLM_SlowFast_Slots_for_Video_Language_Modeling/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13088v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>The article “Slot-VLM: SlowFast Slots for Video-Language Modeling” introduces a novel framework, Slot-VLM, designed to generate semantically decomposed video tokens to align with Large Language Models (LLMs) for efficient video reasoning. The framework includes a SlowFast Slots module, which adaptively aggregates dense video tokens from the CLIP vision encoder to a set of representative slots. The Slow-Slots branch focuses on extracting object-centric slots from features at high spatial resolution but low frame sample rate, while the Fast-Slots branch is engineered to learn event-centric slots from high temporal sample rate but low spatial resolution features. The experimental results demonstrate the effectiveness of Slot-VLM, achieving state-of-the-art performance on video question-answering tasks.</p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Slot-VLM is a novel framework designed to generate semantically decomposed video tokens to align with Large Language Models (LLMs) for efficient video reasoning.</li>
<li>The SlowFast Slots module adaptively aggregates dense video tokens from the CLIP vision encoder to a set of representative slots.</li>
<li>The Slow-Slots branch focuses on extracting object-centric slots from features at high spatial resolution but low frame sample rate, while the Fast-Slots branch learns event-centric slots from high temporal sample rate but low spatial resolution features.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Slot-VLM introduces a novel framework designed to generate semantically decomposed video tokens to align with Large Language Models (LLMs) for efficient video reasoning.</li>
<li>The SlowFast Slots module adaptively aggregates dense video tokens from the CLIP vision encoder to a set of representative slots.</li>
<li>The Slow-Slots branch focuses on extracting object-centric slots from features at high spatial resolution but low frame sample rate, while the Fast-Slots branch learns event-centric slots from high temporal sample rate but low spatial resolution features.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article presents a novel approach to video-language modeling, demonstrating the effectiveness of Slot-VLM in achieving state-of-the-art performance on video question-answering tasks.</li>
<li>The proposed framework addresses the challenge of efficiently aligning video content with Large Language Models (LLMs) for video understanding.</li>
<li>The experimental results provide evidence of the effectiveness of the SlowFast Slots module in generating semantically decomposed video tokens.</li>
<li>However, the article does not address potential limitations or biases in the proposed framework, and further research is needed to explore the scalability and generalizability of Slot-VLM.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-21</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.13088v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.13088v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13088v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13088v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>9852</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Slot_VLM_SlowFast_Slots_for_Video_Language_Modeling/2024-02-20-Slot_VLM_SlowFast_Slots_for_Video_Language_Modeling.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13088v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Benchmarking Retrieval-Augmented Generation for Medicine</title>
  <dc:creator>Guangzhi Xiong, Qiao Jin, Zhiyong Lu, Aidong Zhang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Benchmarking_Retrieval_Augmented_Generation_for_Medicine/2024-02-20-Benchmarking_Retrieval_Augmented_Generation_for_Medicine.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Benchmarking_Retrieval_Augmented_Generation_for_Medicine/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13178v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) is a promising solution for addressing challenges with hallucinations and outdated knowledge in large language models (LLMs) for medical question answering (QA).</li>
<li>The Medical Information Retrieval-Augmented Generation Evaluation (Mirage) benchmark was introduced to systematically evaluate RAG systems, including 7,663 questions from five medical QA datasets.</li>
<li>MedRag, a toolkit for medical QA, was used to conduct large-scale experiments with over 1.8 trillion prompt tokens on 41 combinations of different corpora, retrievers, and backbone LLMs. The results showed that MedRag improved the accuracy of six different LLMs by up to 18% over chain-of-thought prompting, elevating the performance of GPT-3.5 and Mixtral to GPT-4-level.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>MedRag improved the accuracy of six different LLMs by up to 18% over chain-of-thought prompting.</li>
<li>The combination of various medical corpora and retrievers achieved the best performance.</li>
<li>A log-linear scaling property and the “lost-in-the-middle” effects in medical RAG were discovered.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study provides comprehensive evaluations and practical recommendations for medical RAG systems, but there are limitations in evaluating new RAG system designs, incorporating additional resources, and evaluating the retrieved snippets for examination datasets.</li>
<li>Practical recommendations include corpus selection, retriever selection, and LLM selection based on the evaluation results. However, further research is needed to address the limitations and explore potential solutions.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-21</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.13178v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.13178v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13178v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13178v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8966</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Benchmarking_Retrieval_Augmented_Generation_for_Medicine/2024-02-20-Benchmarking_Retrieval_Augmented_Generation_for_Medicine.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13178v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Me LLaMA: Foundation Large Language Models for Medical Applications</title>
  <dc:creator>Qianqian Xie, Qingyu Chen, Aokun Chen, Cheng Peng, Yan Hu, Fongci Lin, Xueqing Peng, Jimin Huang, Jeffrey Zhang, Vipina Keloth, Huan He, Lucila Ohno-Machido, Yonghui Wu, Hua Xu, Jiang Bian</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Me_LLaMA_Foundation_Large_Language_Models_for_Medical_Applications/2024-02-20-Me_LLaMA_Foundation_Large_Language_Models_for_Medical_Applications.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.12749v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The article introduces Me LLaMA, a family of large language models (LLMs) designed for medical applications. The study focuses on the development of Me LLaMA 13B and Me LLaMA 70B, which are foundation models trained on large domain-specific datasets. The models are evaluated using a medical evaluation benchmark (MIBE) across six tasks with 14 datasets. The results show that Me LLaMA models surpass existing open-source medical LLMs in zero-shot and few-shot learning and outperform commercial giants like ChatGPT on 6 out of 8 datasets and GPT-4 in 3 out of 8 datasets. Additionally, the study investigates the catastrophic forgetting problem and shows that Me LLaMA models outperform other medical LLMs in retaining knowledge across updates.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Me LLaMA models surpass existing open-source medical LLMs in zero-shot and few-shot learning.</li>
<li>Me LLaMA models outperform commercial giants like ChatGPT and GPT-4 in several datasets.</li>
<li>Me LLaMA models excel in mitigating the catastrophic forgetting problem, retaining knowledge across updates.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study provides a comprehensive evaluation of Me LLaMA models, showcasing their superior performance in medical tasks.</li>
<li>The investigation of the catastrophic forgetting problem highlights the robustness of Me LLaMA models in retaining knowledge.</li>
<li>The study emphasizes the importance of balanced data sources and the effectiveness of instruction tuning in enhancing model performance.</li>
<li>The article could benefit from a more detailed discussion of potential limitations and future research directions. Additionally, a critical analysis of the potential biases and ethical considerations of using large language models in medical applications would be valuable.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-21</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12749v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12749v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12749v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12749v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>14536</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Me_LLaMA_Foundation_Large_Language_Models_for_Medical_Applications/2024-02-20-Me_LLaMA_Foundation_Large_Language_Models_for_Medical_Applications.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.12749v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>A Survey on Knowledge Distillation of Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Xiaohan Xu, Ming Li, Chongyang Tao, Tao Shen, Reynold Cheng, Jinyang Li, Can Xu, Dacheng Tao, Tianyi Zhou</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_Survey_on_Knowledge_Distillation_of_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-20-A_Survey_on_Knowledge_Distillation_of_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_Survey_on_Knowledge_Distillation_of_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13116v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides an overview of the evolving landscape of Large Language Models (LLMs), emphasizing the significance of knowledge distillation (KD) in transferring advanced capabilities from proprietary to open-source LLMs.</li>
<li>The distillation pipeline of LLMs involves directing the teacher LLM towards a specific target skill or domain, feeding it with seed knowledge, generating distillation knowledge, and training the student model with a specific learning objective.</li>
<li>Various methodologies for distilling knowledge from teacher LLMs into student models are discussed, including supervised fine-tuning, divergence and similarity-based methods, reinforcement learning, and ranking optimization.</li>
<li>The development of LLMs with tool use proficiency and planning capabilities is crucial for their effectiveness in interactive environments and complex tasks, with various methods for distilling these capabilities into smaller models highlighted.</li>
<li>The article also discusses the customization of LLMs for specific vertical domains, showcasing the significant role of knowledge distillation in enhancing domain-specific AI applications.</li>
<li>SciGLM proposes to train a scientific LLM, prompting a teacher LLM to generate detailed answers for unlabelled scientific questions, and a self-reflective critic-and-revise to improve data quality, showcasing advancements in various scientific domains.</li>
<li>The concept of self-alignment in aligning LLMs and the potential for the student model to autonomously improve and align its responses with desired behaviors is also discussed.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Knowledge distillation plays a crucial role in transferring advanced capabilities from proprietary to open-source Large Language Models (LLMs).</li>
<li>Various methodologies, such as supervised fine-tuning, divergence and similarity-based methods, reinforcement learning, and ranking optimization, are used for distilling knowledge from teacher LLMs into student models.</li>
<li>The development of LLMs with tool use proficiency and planning capabilities, as well as their customization for specific vertical domains, showcases the transformative potential of LLMs in various industries and scientific domains.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides a comprehensive overview of knowledge distillation in the context of LLMs, showcasing its transformative potential and diverse applications.</li>
<li>The methodologies discussed for distilling knowledge from teacher LLMs into student models highlight the importance of skill distillation in enhancing the capabilities of smaller language models.</li>
<li>The customization of LLMs for specific vertical domains and the advancements in various scientific domains demonstrate the broad impact of LLMs and the significance of knowledge distillation in real-world applications.</li>
<li>The concept of self-alignment in aligning LLMs offers potential avenues for continual self-improvement and alignment, contributing to the broader context of knowledge distillation in LLMs.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-21</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.13116v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.13116v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13116v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13116v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>38489</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_Survey_on_Knowledge_Distillation_of_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-20-A_Survey_on_Knowledge_Distillation_of_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13116v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Modality-Aware Integration with Large Language Models for Knowledge-based Visual Question Answering</title>
  <dc:creator>Junnan Dong, Qinggang Zhang, Huachi Zhou, Daochen Zha, Pai Zheng, Xiao Huang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Modality_Aware_Integration_with_Large_Language_Models_for_Knowledge_based_Visual_Question_Answering/2024-02-20-Modality_Aware_Integration_with_Large_Language_Models_for_Knowledge_based_Visual_Question_Answering.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Modality_Aware_Integration_with_Large_Language_Models_for_Knowledge_based_Visual_Question_Answering/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12728v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article presents a novel modality-aware integration with large language models for knowledge-based visual question answering (KVQA).</li>
<li>It addresses the challenges of leveraging large language models (LLMs) as an implicit knowledge source and aligning multiple knowledge sources for complex scenarios.</li>
<li>The proposed framework, MAIL, leverages multimodal knowledge for image understanding and knowledge reasoning through a two-stage prompting strategy with LLMs and a tailored pseudo-siamese graph medium fusion.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The proposed MAIL framework outperforms traditional and LLM-enhanced baselines on two benchmark datasets, OK-VQA and FVQA, with 24 less computational resources.</li>
<li>The tailored pseudo-siamese graph medium fusion effectively integrates multimodal knowledge sources, balancing intra-modal processing and inter-modal exchange.</li>
<li>MAIL achieves faster inferential time compared to existing state-of-the-art baselines, making it resource-efficient.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article effectively addresses the challenges of integrating large language models for knowledge-based visual question answering and presents a novel framework, MAIL, that outperforms existing baselines.</li>
<li>The proposed framework demonstrates resource efficiency and faster inferential time, making it a promising solution for knowledge-based visual question answering.</li>
<li>However, the article lacks a detailed discussion of potential limitations or areas for further research, which could provide a more comprehensive analysis of the proposed framework.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-21</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12728v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12728v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12728v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12728v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6813</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Modality_Aware_Integration_with_Large_Language_Models_for_Knowledge_based_Visual_Question_Answering/2024-02-20-Modality_Aware_Integration_with_Large_Language_Models_for_Knowledge_based_Visual_Question_Answering.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12728v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Soft Self-Consistency Improves Language Model Agents</title>
  <dc:creator>Han Wang, Archiki Prasad, Elias Stengel-Eskin, Mohit Bansal</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Soft_Self_Consistency_Improves_Language_Model_Agents/2024-02-20-Soft_Self_Consistency_Improves_Language_Model_Agents.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Soft_Self_Consistency_Improves_Language_Model_Agents/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13212v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Generations from large language models (LLMs) can be improved by sampling and scoring multiple solutions to select a final answer.</li>
<li>Current “sample and select” methods such as self-consistency (SC) rely on majority voting to score answers, but this method is not effective for tasks with many distinct and valid answers.</li>
<li>Soft Self-Consistency (Soft-SC) replaces SC’s discontinuous scoring with a continuous score computed from model likelihoods, allowing for selection even when actions are sparsely distributed. Soft-SC improves both performance and efficiency on long-horizon interactive tasks, requiring half as many samples as SC for comparable or better performance.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Soft-SC outperforms SC with the same number of samples, e.g., by up to 3% on WebShop using CodeLlama-34B.</li>
<li>Soft-SC exhibits better sample efficiency, i.e., produces better performance than SC with fewer samples.</li>
<li>Soft-SC scales better with model size than SC, increasing performance by 5% on Bash as model size increases from 7B to 70B, as opposed to only 1% improvement by SC.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Soft-SC improves performance and efficiency, but it still requires multiple samples from an LLM, making it more costly than greedy decoding.</li>
<li>The method may not be suitable for tasks with excessive diversity, as no majority will emerge, and it still requires further research to address these limitations.</li>
<li>The potential for negative applications and malicious use of large language models is a concern, and the impact of Soft-SC on these applications should be carefully considered.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-21</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.13212v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.13212v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13212v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13212v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7396</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Soft_Self_Consistency_Improves_Language_Model_Agents/2024-02-20-Soft_Self_Consistency_Improves_Language_Model_Agents.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13212v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Investigating Cultural Alignment of Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Badr AlKhamissi, Muhammad ElNokrashy, Mai AlKhamissi, Mona Diab</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Investigating_Cultural_Alignment_of_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-20-Investigating_Cultural_Alignment_of_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Investigating_Cultural_Alignment_of_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13231v1/x2.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The article investigates the cultural alignment of Large Language Models (LLMs) and its implications for cross-lingual transfer. The study reveals that LLMs demonstrate greater cultural alignment when prompted with the dominant language of a specific culture and when pretrained with a refined mixture of languages employed by that culture. The authors introduce Anthropological Prompting, a novel method leveraging anthropological reasoning to enhance cultural alignment. The study emphasizes the necessity for a more balanced multilingual pretraining dataset to better represent the diversity of human experience and the plurality of different cultures.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs demonstrate greater cultural alignment when prompted with the dominant language of a specific culture and when pretrained with a refined mixture of languages employed by that culture.</li>
<li>Misalignment becomes more pronounced for underrepresented personas and for culturally sensitive topics, such as those probing social values.</li>
<li>Anthropological Prompting is introduced as a method to enhance cultural alignment in LLMs.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study is limited to two languages and data from two countries, which may not fully represent the diversity of human experience.</li>
<li>The lack of knowledge regarding the actual data sources used for pretraining languages, domains, and dialect presence or absence in many LLMs is a significant limitation.</li>
<li>The study emphasizes the necessity for a more balanced multilingual pretraining dataset, but it does not provide a clear path for achieving this goal.</li>
<li>The article raises important ethical considerations regarding the impact of LLMs on cultural values and the need for interdisciplinary collaboration between computer scientists and social scientists.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the study provides valuable insights into the cultural alignment of LLMs and highlights the need for further research to address the limitations and ethical implications of these findings.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-21</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.13231v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.13231v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13231v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13231v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7946</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Investigating_Cultural_Alignment_of_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-20-Investigating_Cultural_Alignment_of_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13231v1/x2.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Bayesian Reward Models for LLM Alignment</title>
  <dc:creator>Adam X. Yang, Maxime Robeyns, Thomas Coste, Jun Wang, Haitham Bou-Ammar, Laurence Aitchison</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Bayesian_Reward_Models_for_LLM_Alignment/2024-02-20-Bayesian_Reward_Models_for_LLM_Alignment.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Bayesian_Reward_Models_for_LLM_Alignment/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13210v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article discusses the use of Bayesian reward models for large language models (LLMs) to ensure helpful and non-toxic responses.</li>
<li>It highlights the vulnerability of the reward model to overoptimization or hacking, especially when the prompt or response diverges from the training data.</li>
<li>The authors propose training Bayesian reward models using Laplace-LoRA to mitigate these issues and successfully mitigate reward overoptimization in best-of-sampling.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The imperfections in the reward model may lead to reward overoptimization or hacking, especially in “out-of-distribution” regions with little training data.</li>
<li>Bayesian reward models using Laplace-LoRA can successfully mitigate reward overoptimization in best-of-sampling.</li>
<li>The study shows considerable improvements in performance as evaluated by a gold-standard reward model.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides valuable insights into the challenges of reward overoptimization and the potential of Bayesian approaches to mitigate these issues.</li>
<li>However, the study primarily focuses on the application of Laplace-LoRA and does not extensively explore other potential solutions to reward overoptimization.</li>
<li>The experimental framework and results are well-documented, but further research is needed to validate the proposed approach in diverse settings and with different types of language models.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-21</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.13210v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.13210v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13210v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13210v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>3530</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Bayesian_Reward_Models_for_LLM_Alignment/2024-02-20-Bayesian_Reward_Models_for_LLM_Alignment.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13210v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Bias in Language Models: Beyond Trick Tests and Toward RUTEd Evaluation</title>
  <dc:creator>Kristian Lum, Jacy Reese Anthis, Chirag Nagpal, Alexander D&#39;Amour</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Bias_in_Language_Models_Beyond_Trick_Tests_and_Toward_RUTEd_Evaluation/2024-02-20-Bias_in_Language_Models_Beyond_Trick_Tests_and_Toward_RUTEd_Evaluation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Bias_in_Language_Models_Beyond_Trick_Tests_and_Toward_RUTEd_Evaluation/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12649v1/extracted/5418948/final_results_combined.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article explores the correspondence between decontextualized “trick tests” and evaluations grounded in Realistic Use and Tangible Effects (RUTEd evaluations) in the context of gender-occupation bias.</li>
<li>The study compares three decontextualized evaluations to three analogous RUTEd evaluations applied to long-form content generation for seven instruction-tuned large language models (LLMs).</li>
<li>The findings reveal no correspondence between trick tests and RUTEd evaluations, suggesting that evaluations not based in realistic use are likely insufficient to mitigate and assess bias and real-world harms.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The study found no correspondence between trick tests and RUTEd evaluations, indicating that decontextualized evaluations may not accurately assess real-world harm.</li>
<li>Selecting the least biased model based on decontextualized results coincided with selecting the model with the best performance on RUTEd evaluations only as often as random chance.</li>
<li>The relationship between bias and scale was unstable across different evaluations, even when using the same metrics applied to the same type of bias.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The study is limited in scope, as it only calculates three metrics for seven models, three tasks, and one genre of bias evaluation (gender and occupation).</li>
<li>The reliance on the WinoBias sentences restricts the study to a gender binary, certain occupations, and correlations solely between gender and occupation.</li>
<li>The study highlights the need for more publicly available data on real usage to improve the Realistic Use and Tangible Effects (RUTEd) evaluations.</li>
<li>The findings suggest that the field of algorithmic fairness needs to move away from common “trick tests” and towards RUTEd evaluations that match real-world use cases and have articulable associations with real-world harms.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-21</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12649v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12649v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12649v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12649v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6909</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Bias_in_Language_Models_Beyond_Trick_Tests_and_Toward_RUTEd_Evaluation/2024-02-20-Bias_in_Language_Models_Beyond_Trick_Tests_and_Toward_RUTEd_Evaluation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12649v1/extracted/5418948/final_results_combined.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Effective and Efficient Conversation Retrieval for Dialogue State Tracking with Implicit Text Summaries</title>
  <dc:creator>Seanie Lee, Jianpeng Chen, Joris Driesen, Alexandru Coca, Anders Johannsen</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Effective_and_Efficient_Conversation_Retrieval_for_Dialogue_State_Tracking_with_Implicit_Text_Summaries/2024-02-20-Effective_and_Efficient_Conversation_Retrieval_for_Dialogue_State_Tracking_with_Implicit_Text_Summaries.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Effective_and_Efficient_Conversation_Retrieval_for_Dialogue_State_Tracking_with_Implicit_Text_Summaries/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13043v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The article discusses the challenges of few-shot dialogue state tracking (DST) with Large Language Models (LLM) and proposes a conversation retrieval approach based on text summaries of the conversations. The authors adopt a LLM-based conversation summarizer for query and key generation, enabling effective maximum inner product search. To avoid extra inference costs, they further distill a light-weight conversation encoder. The experimental results show a significant improvement over relevant baselines in real few-shot DST settings.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Few-shot dialogue state tracking (DST) with Large Language Models (LLM) relies on an effective and efficient conversation retriever to find similar in-context examples for prompt learning.</li>
<li>The LLM-based conversation summarizer is adopted for query and key generation, enabling effective maximum inner product search.</li>
<li>The experimental results show a significant improvement over relevant baselines in real few-shot DST settings.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The proposed approach significantly improves the efficiency and performance of few-shot DST, outperforming previous LLM-based DST baselines.</li>
<li>The article effectively addresses the challenges of few-shot DST with LLM and provides a practical solution for conversation retrieval based on text summaries.</li>
<li>The human evaluation of the conversation summarizer indicates that 90.3% of the generated summaries are consistent with the given prompt, demonstrating the reliability of the summarization approach.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-21</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.13043v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.13043v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13043v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13043v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6225</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Effective_and_Efficient_Conversation_Retrieval_for_Dialogue_State_Tracking_with_Implicit_Text_Summaries/2024-02-20-Effective_and_Efficient_Conversation_Retrieval_for_Dialogue_State_Tracking_with_Implicit_Text_Summaries.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13043v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Code Needs Comments: Enhancing Code LLMs with Comment Augmentation</title>
  <dc:creator>Demin Song, Honglin Guo, Yunhua Zhou, Shuhao Xing, Yudong Wang, Zifan Song, Wenwei Zhang, Qipeng Guo, Hang Yan, Xipeng Qiu, Dahua Lin</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Code_Needs_Comments_Enhancing_Code_LLMs_with_Comment_Augmentation/2024-02-20-Code_Needs_Comments_Enhancing_Code_LLMs_with_Comment_Augmentation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Code_Needs_Comments_Enhancing_Code_LLMs_with_Comment_Augmentation/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13013v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article examines the impact of pre-training data on code-focused Large Language Models’ (LLMs) performance by assessing comment density as a measure of programming language-natural language alignment.</li>
<li>Due to the scarcity of code-comment aligned data in pre-training corpora, the authors introduce a novel data augmentation method that generates comments for existing code, coupled with a data filtering strategy that filters out poorly correlated code data.</li>
<li>Experiments on three code-focused LLMs show consistent improvements in performance on two widely-used programming skill benchmarks, with the model trained on augmented data outperforming both the model used for generating comments and the model further trained on the data without augmentation.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Comment density significantly affects the performance of LLM models in downstream tasks, with higher comment density leading to improved outcomes.</li>
<li>The proposed data augmentation method, coupled with data filtering, results in substantial improvements on Llama 2, Code Llama, and InternLM2.</li>
<li>The model trained on augmented data outperforms both the model used for generating comments and the model further trained on the data without augmentation.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides a comprehensive overview of the proposed data augmentation method and its impact on the performance of code-focused LLMs. However, the reliance on data distillation with a teacher model and the considerable GPU overhead for data augmentation are potential limitations that need further exploration.</li>
<li>The use of “&lt;|EOT|&gt;” as the model’s output in the implicit filter stage may not align well with the behavioral patterns typically exhibited by a language model, suggesting the need for alternative approaches.</li>
<li>The marginal improvements observed during the next iteration of self-augmentation raise questions about the scalability and effectiveness of the proposed method, indicating the need for further investigation.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-21</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.13013v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.13013v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13013v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13013v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5792</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>programming</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Code_Needs_Comments_Enhancing_Code_LLMs_with_Comment_Augmentation/2024-02-20-Code_Needs_Comments_Enhancing_Code_LLMs_with_Comment_Augmentation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13013v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Defending Jailbreak Prompts via In-Context Adversarial Game</title>
  <dc:creator>Yujun Zhou, Yufei Han, Haomin Zhuang, Taicheng Guo, Kehan Guo, Zhenwen Liang, Hongyan Bao, Xiangliang Zhang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Defending_Jailbreak_Prompts_via_In_Context_Adversarial_Game/2024-02-20-Defending_Jailbreak_Prompts_via_In_Context_Adversarial_Game.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Defending_Jailbreak_Prompts_via_In_Context_Adversarial_Game/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13148v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article introduces the In-Context Adversarial Game (ICAG) for defending against jailbreak attacks without fine-tuning.</li>
<li>ICAG leverages agent learning to conduct an adversarial game, aiming to dynamically extend knowledge to defend against jailbreaks.</li>
<li>Empirical studies affirm ICAG’s efficacy, with LLMs safeguarded by ICAG exhibiting significantly reduced jailbreak success rates across various attack scenarios.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>ICAG introduces an in-context adversarial game for LLMs, aiming at dynamically intensifying the attack and defense without necessitating fine-tuning.</li>
<li>The application of agent learning in the field of jailbreak attacks, automatically exploring the knowledge of LLMs on attack and defense, is a significant contribution.</li>
<li>ICAG demonstrates the efficacy of its proposed approach and its defending ability to be transferred across different models.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article’s reliance on the assumption of a relatively static adversary model may limit its applicability in scenarios where attackers continuously adapt their strategies in more sophisticated manners.</li>
<li>The success of ICAG hinges on the quality and diversity of the initial prompt set, which could constrain the system’s ability to generalize across the full spectrum of possible attacks if not adequately representative.</li>
<li>The current framework primarily focuses on text-based interactions, potentially overlooking the nuances of multimodal or context-rich environments where jailbreak attacks could manifest differently.</li>
<li>Ethical considerations are raised, emphasizing the responsibility of developers and researchers to ensure that these models are not exploited to perpetrate harm or disseminate misinformation. Transparency, ethical use, and collaboration with stakeholders committed to LLM safety and security are advocated for.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-21</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.13148v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.13148v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13148v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13148v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5916</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Defending_Jailbreak_Prompts_via_In_Context_Adversarial_Game/2024-02-20-Defending_Jailbreak_Prompts_via_In_Context_Adversarial_Game.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13148v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>FormulaQA: A Question Answering Dataset for Formula-Based Numerical Reasoning</title>
  <dc:creator>Xiao Li, Sichen Liu, Bolin Zhu, Yin Zhu, Yiwei liu, Gong Cheng</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/FormulaQA_A_Question_Answering_Dataset_for_Formula_Based_Numerical_Reasoning/2024-02-20-FormulaQA_A_Question_Answering_Dataset_for_Formula_Based_Numerical_Reasoning.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/FormulaQA_A_Question_Answering_Dataset_for_Formula_Based_Numerical_Reasoning/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12692v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The article introduces FormulaQA, a question-answering dataset for formula-based numerical reasoning, collected from junior high school physics examinations. The dataset includes questions requiring formula-based numerical reasoning, with each question annotated with an explanation text, a final answer, and relevant formulas. The article evaluates the dataset using large language models (LLMs) and fine-tuned small models, as well as retrieval-augmented LLMs. The findings underscore the challenging nature of FormulaQA and the potential for improvement in existing models for formula-based numerical reasoning.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>FormulaQA Dataset Construction</strong>: The dataset consists of 5,420 questions collected from Chinese junior high school physics exams, annotated with reasoning steps and formulas.</li>
<li><strong>Evaluation of LLMs</strong>: Large language models (LLMs) ranging from 7B to over 100B parameters were evaluated on FormulaQA, demonstrating the challenging nature of the dataset and the need for improvement in existing models.</li>
<li><strong>Fine-tuned Small Models</strong>: Fine-tuned small models with sizes less than 2B parameters were evaluated, showing generalization ability in formula prediction and the potential for enhanced performance when using calculators.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Limitations</strong>: The English version of the dataset has not been accurately assessed for quality, and the dataset is limited to the domain of physics, potentially limiting its applicability to other domains.</li>
<li><strong>Ethical Considerations</strong>: The dataset was collected from publicly available sources and focuses on elementary physics, with no foreseen potential risks. Annotators were undergraduate students skilled in elementary physics.</li>
<li><strong>Error Analysis</strong>: Error cases were categorized into formula errors and calculation errors, highlighting the challenges posed by FormulaQA to existing models in terms of formula application and numerical calculation.</li>
</ul>
<p>The article provides valuable insights into the construction and evaluation of FormulaQA, highlighting the need for further research and improvement in models for formula-based numerical reasoning.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-21</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12692v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12692v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12692v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12692v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7183</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/FormulaQA_A_Question_Answering_Dataset_for_Formula_Based_Numerical_Reasoning/2024-02-20-FormulaQA_A_Question_Answering_Dataset_for_Formula_Based_Numerical_Reasoning.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12692v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>CIF-Bench: A Chinese Instruction-Following Benchmark for Evaluating the Generalizability of Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Yizhi LI, Ge Zhang, Xingwei Qu, Jiali Li, Zhaoqun Li, Zekun Wang, Hao Li, Ruibin Yuan, Yinghao Ma, Kai Zhang, Wangchunshu Zhou, Yiming Liang, Lei Zhang, Lei Ma, Jiajun Zhang, Zuowen Li, Stephen W. Huang, Chenghua Lin, Wenhu Chen, Jie Fu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/CIF_Bench_A_Chinese_Instruction_Following_Benchmark_for_Evaluating_the_Generalizability_of_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-20-CIF_Bench_A_Chinese_Instruction_Following_Benchmark_for_Evaluating_the_Generalizability_of_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/CIF_Bench_A_Chinese_Instruction_Following_Benchmark_for_Evaluating_the_Generalizability_of_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13109v1/x12.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The article introduces the Chinese Instruction-Following Benchmark (CIF-Bench), which aims to evaluate the zero-shot generalizability of large language models (LLMs) to the Chinese language. The benchmark comprises 150 tasks and 15,000 input-output pairs, designed to test complex reasoning and Chinese cultural nuances across 20 categories. The authors release only half of the dataset publicly to mitigate evaluation bias and introduce diversified instructions to minimize score variance. The evaluation of selected LLMs reveals a noticeable performance gap, with the best model scoring only 52.9%, highlighting the limitations of LLMs in less familiar language and task contexts.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The CIF-Bench benchmark comprises 150 tasks and 15,000 input-output pairs, designed to evaluate the zero-shot generalizability of LLMs to the Chinese language.</li>
<li>The best-performing model on CIF-Bench scored only 52.9%, indicating a noticeable performance gap and highlighting the limitations of LLMs in less familiar language and task contexts.</li>
<li>The authors release only half of the dataset publicly to mitigate evaluation bias and introduce diversified instructions to minimize score variance.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The benchmark is challenging for existing LLMs, with the highest score barely reaching 52.9%.</li>
<li>LLMs perform worse when language is transferred, indicating limitations in language transferability.</li>
<li>Data contamination exists, as evidenced by the noticeable performance drop when using different input-output pairs from the public and private splits.</li>
<li>Diversified instructions increase evaluation robustness, stabilizing evaluation scores for all tested LLMs.</li>
<li>Human annotation for verification shows substantial reliability, with an average agreement of 0.49 and an average Cohen’s kappa of 0.3729.</li>
</ul>
<p>The article provides valuable insights into the limitations of current LLMs in handling Chinese tasks and emphasizes the need for more culturally informed and linguistically diverse models. However, potential limitations include the reliance on human subjects for annotation, the selection of baseline models, and the presence of offensive content in the data. Additionally, the article acknowledges the potential for data leakage and bias in the evaluation process.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-21</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.13109v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.13109v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13109v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13109v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6069</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/CIF_Bench_A_Chinese_Instruction_Following_Benchmark_for_Evaluating_the_Generalizability_of_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-20-CIF_Bench_A_Chinese_Instruction_Following_Benchmark_for_Evaluating_the_Generalizability_of_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13109v1/x12.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>SiLLM: Large Language Models for Simultaneous Machine Translation</title>
  <dc:creator>Shoutao Guo, Shaolei Zhang, Zhengrui Ma, Min Zhang, Yang Feng</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SiLLM_Large_Language_Models_for_Simultaneous_Machine_Translation/2024-02-20-SiLLM_Large_Language_Models_for_Simultaneous_Machine_Translation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SiLLM_Large_Language_Models_for_Simultaneous_Machine_Translation/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13036v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>SiLLM is a framework designed to conduct Simultaneous Machine Translation (SiMT) with Large Language Models (LLM).</li>
<li>The SiLLM framework delegates the SiMT task into policy-decision and translation sub-tasks, assigning them to separate agents, thereby incorporating LLM into SiMT.</li>
<li>SiLLM utilizes a policy-decision agent managed by a conventional SiMT model and a translation agent employing an LLM to generate translations using partial source sentences.</li>
<li>The framework introduces a word-level policy adapted for LLM and incorporates Supervised Fine-Tuning to enhance the translation capability of LLM.</li>
<li>Experiments on two datasets demonstrate that, with a small amount of data for fine-tuning LLM, SiLLM attains state-of-the-art performance in SiMT.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>SiLLM delegates the SiMT task into policy-decision and translation sub-tasks, assigning them to separate agents, thereby incorporating LLM into SiMT.</li>
<li>The framework introduces a word-level policy adapted for LLM and incorporates Supervised Fine-Tuning to enhance the translation capability of LLM.</li>
<li>Experiments on two datasets demonstrate that, with a small amount of data for fine-tuning LLM, SiLLM attains state-of-the-art performance in SiMT.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>SiLLM’s approach of decomposing the SiMT task into policy-decision and translation sub-tasks and assigning them to different agents is a novel and effective strategy.</li>
<li>The framework’s ability to achieve state-of-the-art performance with a small amount of data for fine-tuning LLM is a significant advantage.</li>
<li>The experiments demonstrate that SiLLM’s approach is practical and beneficial for SiMT tasks.</li>
<li>The limitations of the study include the exploration of more powerful translation agents or better policy-decision agents to further improve performance.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-21</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.13036v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.13036v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13036v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13036v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6585</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SiLLM_Large_Language_Models_for_Simultaneous_Machine_Translation/2024-02-20-SiLLM_Large_Language_Models_for_Simultaneous_Machine_Translation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.13036v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Instruction-tuned Language Models are Better Knowledge Learners</title>
  <dc:creator>Zhengbao Jiang, Zhiqing Sun, Weijia Shi, Pedro Rodriguez, Chunting Zhou, Graham Neubig, Xi Victoria Lin, Wen-tau Yih, Srinivasan Iyer</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Instruction_tuned_Language_Models_are_Better_Knowledge_Learners/2024-02-20-Instruction_tuned_Language_Models_are_Better_Knowledge_Learners.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Instruction_tuned_Language_Models_are_Better_Knowledge_Learners/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12847v1/x2.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Large language models (LLMs) store vast amounts of factual knowledge in their parameters through large-scale pre-training, but this knowledge can become outdated as the world evolves.</li>
<li>Continued pre-training on new documents followed by instruction-tuning on question-answer (QA) pairs is a widely used practice to update the factual knowledge stored in LLMs.</li>
<li>However, LLMs trained with this practice struggle to answer questions about documents they have been trained on, even though the perplexity of documents is minimized.</li>
<li>Pre-instruction-tuning (PIT) is proposed as a method that instruction-tunes on questions prior to training on documents, significantly enhancing the ability of LLMs to absorb knowledge from new documents, outperforming standard instruction-tuning by 17.8%.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Continued pre-training on new documents followed by instruction-tuning is a widely used practice to update the factual knowledge stored in LLMs.</li>
<li>LLMs trained with this practice struggle to answer questions about documents they have been trained on, even though the perplexity of documents is minimized.</li>
<li>Pre-instruction-tuning (PIT) significantly enhances the ability of LLMs to absorb knowledge from new documents, outperforming standard instruction-tuning by 17.8%.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The study provides valuable insights into the limitations of standard instruction-tuning and the effectiveness of pre-instruction-tuning in enhancing the ability of LLMs to absorb knowledge from new documents.</li>
<li>The findings are based on experiments and ablation studies, providing a comprehensive understanding of the proposed method.</li>
<li>The limitations of the study include the scope being limited to Wikipedia data, which may restrict the adaptability of the trained models to other sources. Further exploration of pre-instruction-tuning with different types of data for enhancing other skills is suggested for future studies.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-21</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12847v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12847v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12847v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12847v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7579</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Instruction_tuned_Language_Models_are_Better_Knowledge_Learners/2024-02-20-Instruction_tuned_Language_Models_are_Better_Knowledge_Learners.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12847v1/x2.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>PromptKD: Distilling Student-Friendly Knowledge for Generative Language Models via Prompt Tuning</title>
  <dc:creator>Gyeongman Kim, Doohyuk Jang, Eunho Yang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/PromptKD_Distilling_Student_Friendly_Knowledge_for_Generative_Language_Models_via_Prompt_Tuning/2024-02-20-PromptKD_Distilling_Student_Friendly_Knowledge_for_Generative_Language_Models_via_Prompt_Tuning.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/PromptKD_Distilling_Student_Friendly_Knowledge_for_Generative_Language_Models_via_Prompt_Tuning/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12842v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Recent advancements in large language models (LLMs) have raised concerns about inference costs, increasing the need for research into model compression.</li>
<li>Knowledge distillation (KD) is a prominent method for model compression, but research on KD for generative language models like LLMs is relatively sparse.</li>
<li>To address this gap, the article proposes PromptKD, a method that utilizes prompt tuning to enable generative language models to transfer student-friendly knowledge.</li>
<li>Extensive experiments on instruction-following datasets using the GPT-2 model family show that PromptKD achieves state-of-the-art performance while adding only 0.0007% of the teacher’s parameters as prompts.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>PromptKD achieves state-of-the-art performance in instruction-following tasks using the GPT-2 model family.</li>
<li>Distilling student-friendly knowledge alleviates exposure bias effectively throughout the entire training process, leading to performance enhancements.</li>
<li>PromptKD outperforms other knowledge distillation methods, demonstrating its efficiency and effectiveness in model compression for generative language models.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides a comprehensive exploration of extracting and distilling student-friendly knowledge for generative language models, but it still has limitations in terms of its naive extraction approach.</li>
<li>The method’s efficiency and effectiveness are demonstrated through extensive experiments, but there is a need for expansion towards task-agnostic KD to make it applicable during the pre-training process.</li>
<li>The article addresses potential ethical and social risks associated with pre-trained language models and model compression, emphasizing the need for advanced pre-training objectives and dataset collection methods to mitigate these risks.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-21</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12842v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12842v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12842v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12842v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6361</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/PromptKD_Distilling_Student_Friendly_Knowledge_for_Generative_Language_Models_via_Prompt_Tuning/2024-02-20-PromptKD_Distilling_Student_Friendly_Knowledge_for_Generative_Language_Models_via_Prompt_Tuning.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12842v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Advancing Large Language Models to Capture Varied Speaking Styles and Respond Properly in Spoken Conversations</title>
  <dc:creator>Guan-Ting Lin, Cheng-Han Chiang, Hung-yi Lee</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Advancing_Large_Language_Models_to_Capture_Varied_Speaking_Styles_and_Respond_Properly_in_Spoken_Conversations/2024-02-20-Advancing_Large_Language_Models_to_Capture_Varied_Speaking_Styles_and_Respond_Properly_in_Spoken_Conversations.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Advancing_Large_Language_Models_to_Capture_Varied_Speaking_Styles_and_Respond_Properly_in_Spoken_Conversations/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12786v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper focuses on enabling Large Language Models (LLMs) to listen to speaking styles and respond properly in spoken conversations.</li>
<li>The authors propose the Spoken-LLM framework to model linguistic content and speaking styles, and train it using the StyleTalk dataset.</li>
<li>Spoken-LLM outperforms text-only baselines and prior speech LLMs methods based on extensive experiments.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Spoken-LLM outperforms text-only baselines and prior speech LLMs methods based on extensive experiments.</li>
<li>The StyleTalk dataset is the first spoken conversation benchmark with the same dialogue context and input sentence in different speaking styles, accompanied by corresponding expressive spoken responses for speech-to-speech modeling.</li>
<li>The proposed Spoken-LLM framework can model linguistic content and speaking styles, and is trained using the StyleTalk dataset.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper provides a comprehensive approach to modeling speaking styles in spoken dialogue, but it has some limitations:
<ul>
<li>The current StyleTalk training set consists of only around 2K samples, which may lead to training instability and overfitting.</li>
<li>The speech data in StyleTalk is synthesized from the Azure TTS system with style control, but incorporating spontaneous speech with even more diverse styles is preferable.</li>
<li>Future work should consider modeling with more than one response style for better performance and evaluation.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the paper presents a valuable contribution to the field of spoken dialogue modeling, but further research is needed to address the identified limitations.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-21</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12786v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12786v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12786v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12786v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7887</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Advancing_Large_Language_Models_to_Capture_Varied_Speaking_Styles_and_Respond_Properly_in_Spoken_Conversations/2024-02-20-Advancing_Large_Language_Models_to_Capture_Varied_Speaking_Styles_and_Respond_Properly_in_Spoken_Conversations.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12786v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>SymBa: Symbolic Backward Chaining for Multi-step Natural Language Reasoning</title>
  <dc:creator>Jinu Lee, Wonseok Hwang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SymBa_Symbolic_Backward_Chaining_for_Multi_step_Natural_Language_Reasoning/2024-02-20-SymBa_Symbolic_Backward_Chaining_for_Multi_step_Natural_Language_Reasoning.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SymBa_Symbolic_Backward_Chaining_for_Multi_step_Natural_Language_Reasoning/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12806v1/extracted/5419471/figures/figure_intro.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>In this markdown summary, we have organized the essential information from the academic article “Symbolic Backward Chaining for Multi-step Natural Language Reasoning” into structured headings and bullet points. We have also included a critical analysis of the article, highlighting potential problems and shortcomings identified while reading the text.</p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Large Language Models (LLMs) have demonstrated remarkable reasoning ability in Chain-of-thought prompting, but faithful multi-step reasoning remains a challenge.</li>
<li>Backward chaining offers unique beneficial properties compared to forward chaining, but current LLM-based implementations have limitations.</li>
<li>The proposed method, (Symbolic Backward Chaining), integrates a symbolic top-down solver and an LLM for natural language reasoning, achieving significant improvement in performance, proof faithfulness, and efficiency in diverse multi-step reasoning benchmarks.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Backward chaining offers unique beneficial properties compared to forward chaining.</li>
<li>The proposed method, , achieves significant improvement in performance, proof faithfulness, and efficiency in diverse multi-step reasoning benchmarks.</li>
<li>Current LLM-based backward chaining implementations have limitations.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The proposed method, , significantly improves performance and efficiency but still holds limitations inherited from LLMs, backward chaining, and symbolic reasoning.</li>
<li>LLMs often produce counterfactual and inconsistent information, and backward chaining may require substantial computation in fact-driven tasks.</li>
<li>Some reasoning problems may not be suitable to be formulated in logic programming notations used in this study.</li>
</ul>
<p>The markdown summary effectively communicates the essential information from the academic article, providing a concise overview of the text and a critical analysis of its content.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-21</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12806v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12806v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12806v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12806v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>13311</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SymBa_Symbolic_Backward_Chaining_for_Multi_step_Natural_Language_Reasoning/2024-02-20-SymBa_Symbolic_Backward_Chaining_for_Multi_step_Natural_Language_Reasoning.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12806v1/extracted/5419471/figures/figure_intro.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Prompt Stealing Attacks Against Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Zeyang Sha, Yang Zhang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Prompt_Stealing_Attacks_Against_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-20-Prompt_Stealing_Attacks_Against_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Prompt_Stealing_Attacks_Against_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12959v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article introduces prompt stealing attacks against large language models (LLMs) and proposes a novel attack to steal well-designed prompts based on the generated answers.</li>
<li>The proposed prompt stealing attack contains two primary modules: the parameter extractor and the prompt reconstructor, which work together to predict the properties of the original prompts and generate reversed prompts similar to the original prompts.</li>
<li>Experimental results show the remarkable performance of the proposed attacks, with the parameter extractor successfully predicting the type of the original prompts and the prompt reconstructor generating more similar reversed prompts.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The proposed prompt stealing attacks aim to steal well-designed prompts based on the generated answers, containing two primary modules: the parameter extractor and the prompt reconstructor.</li>
<li>The parameter extractor successfully predicts the type of the original prompts, and the prompt reconstructor generates more similar reversed prompts.</li>
<li>Experimental results show the remarkable performance of the proposed attacks, with the parameter extractor successfully predicting the type of the original prompts and the prompt reconstructor generating more similar reversed prompts.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides a comprehensive exploration of prompt stealing attacks against LLMs, highlighting the vulnerability of prompts to being stolen based on the generated answers.</li>
<li>The proposed attacks demonstrate strong performance in predicting the properties of the original prompts and generating reversed prompts, raising concerns about the security of LLMs.</li>
<li>The article lacks a discussion of potential defenses against prompt stealing attacks, and further research is needed to explore more effective defense strategies to mitigate these attacks. Additionally, the trade-off between defense performance and utility needs to be further addressed.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-21</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12959v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12959v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12959v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12959v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>10539</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Prompt_Stealing_Attacks_Against_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-20-Prompt_Stealing_Attacks_Against_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.12959v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
