<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Bayesian beagle</title>
<link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Quarto blog of LLM-generated summaries of Arxiv preprints</description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.450</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>DCA-Bench: A Benchmark for Dataset Curation Agents</title>
  <dc:creator>Benhao Huang, Yingzhuo Yu, Jin Huang, Xingjian Zhang, Jiaqi Ma</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/DCA_Bench_A_Benchmark_for_Dataset_Curation_Agents/2024-06-11-DCA_Bench_A_Benchmark_for_Dataset_Curation_Agents.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/DCA_Bench_A_Benchmark_for_Dataset_Curation_Agents/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07275v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level1">
<h1>Summary:</h1>
<p>The paper introduces DCA-Bench, a benchmark for evaluating the capability of large language models (LLMs) in detecting hidden dataset quality issues. The benchmark consists of 91 diverse real-world dataset quality issues from eight open dataset platforms. The authors propose an automatic pipeline for evaluating the success of LLM agents using another LLM agent as an Evaluator. The Evaluator is shown to align well with human evaluation, allowing for reliable automatic evaluation on the proposed benchmark. The paper also presents experiments on several baseline LLM agents, demonstrating the complexity of the task and the need for further exploration and innovation in applying LLMs to real-world dataset curation.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level1">
<h1>Major Findings:</h1>
<ol type="1">
<li>DCA-Bench is a comprehensive benchmark for evaluating LLM agents’ capability to discover data quality issues across online dataset platforms.</li>
<li>The proposed benchmark includes 91 representative samples from 8 online dataset platforms, classified into 4 types with 18 tags according to their various content and difficulty.</li>
<li>The benchmark provides multiple difficulty levels with four levels of hints for each test case, making the task more achievable and gauging the information required for the Curator to detect these issues.</li>
<li>The paper introduces an automatic and accurate evaluation scheme using GPT4 to replace human annotators, demonstrating that the LLM-based Evaluator empirically aligns well with human evaluation.</li>
<li>The proposed benchmark can also serve as a testbed for evaluating LLMs’ capability of problem discovery in addition to problem-solving, which is a critical area that has been under-explored.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level1">
<h1>Analysis and Critique:</h1>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper provides a well-structured and comprehensive benchmark for evaluating LLM agents in dataset curation. However, the benchmark is limited to text-based datasets and does not consider other modalities such as images or audios.</li>
<li>The paper focuses on the initial step of the curation pipeline, which is detecting data quality issues. However, it does not address the subsequent steps of fixing or improving the detected issues.</li>
<li>The paper demonstrates the complexity of the task and the need for further exploration and innovation in applying LLMs to real-world dataset curation. However, it does not provide specific</li>
</ol>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-06-12</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.07275v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.07275v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07275v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07275v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8553</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/DCA_Bench_A_Benchmark_for_Dataset_Curation_Agents/2024-06-11-DCA_Bench_A_Benchmark_for_Dataset_Curation_Agents.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07275v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Ollabench: Evaluating LLMs’ Reasoning for Human-centric Interdependent Cybersecurity</title>
  <dc:creator>Tam n. Nguyen</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Ollabench_Evaluating_LLMs_Reasoning_for_Human_centric_Interdependent_Cybersecurity/2024-06-11-Ollabench_Evaluating_LLMs_Reasoning_for_Human_centric_Interdependent_Cybersecurity.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Ollabench_Evaluating_LLMs_Reasoning_for_Human_centric_Interdependent_Cybersecurity/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.06863v1/extracted/5657620/figures/hic.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper introduces OllaBench, a novel evaluation framework for assessing Large Language Models (LLMs) in the context of human-centric interdependent cybersecurity. OllaBench evaluates LLMs based on their accuracy, wastefulness, and consistency in answering scenario-based information security compliance and non-compliance questions. The framework is built on a foundation of 24 cognitive behavioral theories and empirical evidence from 38 peer-reviewed papers. OllaBench was used to evaluate 21 LLMs, including both open-weight and commercial models from various organizations. The results reveal that while commercial LLMs have the highest overall accuracy scores, there is significant room for improvement. Smaller low-resolution open-weight LLMs are not far behind in performance, and there are significant differences in token efficiency and consistency among the evaluated models.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Commercial LLMs have the highest overall accuracy scores, but there is still room for improvement.</li>
<li>Smaller low-resolution open-weight LLMs are not far behind in performance compared to commercial LLMs.</li>
<li>There are significant differences in token efficiency and consistency among the evaluated models.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>OllaBench provides a valuable tool for researchers and solution developers in the field of human-centric interdependent cybersecurity. However, there are some potential limitations and areas for improvement:</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>The evaluation framework focuses primarily on accuracy, wastefulness, and consistency. While these are important metrics, other aspects such as fairness, transparency, and robustness should also be considered in future iterations.</li>
<li>The evaluation is based on a specific set of scenario-based questions. While these questions are designed to cover a wide range of information security compliance and non-compliance scenarios, they may not capture all possible situations that LLMs might encounter in real-world applications.</li>
<li>The evaluation does not consider the potential impact of different training data or model architectures on the performance of LLMs. Future work could explore how these factors influence the accuracy, wastefulness, and consistency of LLMs.</li>
<li>The evaluation does not account for the potential biases that may be present in the LLMs. Biases in LLMs can have significant implications for their performance and fairness, and should be addressed in future evalu</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-06-12</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.06863v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.06863v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.06863v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.06863v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7305</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Ollabench_Evaluating_LLMs_Reasoning_for_Human_centric_Interdependent_Cybersecurity/2024-06-11-Ollabench_Evaluating_LLMs_Reasoning_for_Human_centric_Interdependent_Cybersecurity.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.06863v1/extracted/5657620/figures/hic.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>A Probabilistic Framework for LLM Hallucination Detection via Belief Tree Propagation</title>
  <dc:creator>Bairu Hou, Yang Zhang, Jacob Andreas, Shiyu Chang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_Probabilistic_Framework_for_LLM_Hallucination_Detection_via_Belief_Tree_Propagation/2024-06-11-A_Probabilistic_Framework_for_LLM_Hallucination_Detection_via_Belief_Tree_Propagation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_Probabilistic_Framework_for_LLM_Hallucination_Detection_via_Belief_Tree_Propagation/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.06950v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper presents a probabilistic framework, Belief Tree Propagation (BTProp), for LLM hallucination detection. The method introduces a belief tree of logically related statements by recursively decomposing a parent statement into child statements with three decomposition strategies. It then builds a hidden Markov tree model to integrate the LLM’s belief scores in these statements in a principled way. Experiment results show that BTProp improves baselines by 3%-9% (evaluated by AUROC and AUC-PR) on multiple hallucination detection benchmarks.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>BTProp introduces a belief tree of logically related statements by recursively decomposing a parent statement into child statements with three decomposition strategies.</li>
<li>BTProp builds a hidden Markov tree model to integrate the LLM’s belief scores in these statements in a principled way.</li>
<li>Experiment results show that BTProp improves baselines by 3%-9% (evaluated by AUROC and AUC-PR) on multiple hallucination detection benchmarks.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The paper presents a novel approach to LLM hallucination detection, which is a significant problem in the field. The use of a belief tree and a hidden Markov tree model is an innovative approach to integrating the LLM’s belief scores in a principled way. The experimental results are promising, showing significant improvements over baselines.</p>
<p>However, there are some potential limitations to this approach. The reliance on a belief tree and a hidden Markov tree model may make the approach computationally expensive, which could limit its applicability in real-world scenarios. Additionally, the approach may be sensitive to the quality of the LLM’s belief scores, which could be affected by factors such as the quality of the training data and the complexity of the task.</p>
<p>Further research is needed to address these limitations and to evaluate the approach in a wider range of scenarios. It would also be interesting to explore the potential of this approach for other tasks, such as text summarization and question answering, where LLM hallucination is also a significant problem.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-06-12</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.06950v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.06950v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.06950v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.06950v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>10310</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_Probabilistic_Framework_for_LLM_Hallucination_Detection_via_Belief_Tree_Propagation/2024-06-11-A_Probabilistic_Framework_for_LLM_Hallucination_Detection_via_Belief_Tree_Propagation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.06950v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Validating LLM-Generated Programs with Metamorphic Prompt Testing</title>
  <dc:creator>Xiaoyin Wang, Dakai Zhu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Validating_LLM_Generated_Programs_with_Metamorphic_Prompt_Testing/2024-06-11-Validating_LLM_Generated_Programs_with_Metamorphic_Prompt_Testing.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Validating_LLM_Generated_Programs_with_Metamorphic_Prompt_Testing/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.06864v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper proposes a novel solution called metamorphic prompt testing to address the challenge of validating LLM-generated code without canonical solutions or ground truth output. The approach leverages the intuition that intrinsic consistency always exists among correct code pieces but may not exist among flawed code pieces. The technique involves varying a given prompt to multiple prompts with paraphrasing and asking the LLM to acquire multiple versions of generated code. The semantic relations are then cross-validated to detect inconsistencies and flaws in the code. The evaluation on HumanEval shows that metamorphic prompt testing is able to detect 75% of the erroneous programs generated by GPT-4, with a false positive rate of 8.6%.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The proposed metamorphic prompt testing technique is able to detect 75% of the erroneous programs generated by GPT-4, with a false positive rate of 8.6%.</li>
<li>The approach does not require any canonical solutions or ground truth output, making it a promising solution for validating LLM-generated code.</li>
<li>The technique leverages the intuition that intrinsic consistency always exists among correct code pieces but may not exist among flawed code pieces, allowing for the detection of flaws in the code.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The proposed technique relies on the ability to generate multiple versions of code from a given prompt, which may not always be possible or practical.</li>
<li>The technique assumes that the LLM is capable of generating code with intrinsic consistency, which may not always be the case.</li>
<li>The evaluation of the technique is limited to the HumanEval dataset, and further evaluation on other datasets and LLMs is needed to establish its generalizability.</li>
<li>The technique does not address the issue of generating code that is semantically correct but does not meet the requirements of the prompt, which is a common challenge in LLM-generated code.</li>
<li>The technique does not provide a mechanism for correcting the detected flaws in the code, which is an important aspect of code validation.</li>
</ol>
<p>Overall, the proposed metamorphic prompt testing technique is a promising solution for validating LLM-generated code, but further research is needed to address its limitations and establish its generalizability</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-06-12</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.06864v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.06864v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.06864v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.06864v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6738</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Validating_LLM_Generated_Programs_with_Metamorphic_Prompt_Testing/2024-06-11-Validating_LLM_Generated_Programs_with_Metamorphic_Prompt_Testing.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.06864v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Anomaly Detection on Unstable Logs with GPT Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Fatemeh Hadadi, Qinghua Xu, Domenico Bianculli, Lionel Briand</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Anomaly_Detection_on_Unstable_Logs_with_GPT_Models/2024-06-11-Anomaly_Detection_on_Unstable_Logs_with_GPT_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Anomaly_Detection_on_Unstable_Logs_with_GPT_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07467v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper explores the use of Large Language Models (LLMs), specifically GPT-3, for anomaly detection on unstable logs, which are logs that change due to software evolution. The authors compare the performance of fine-tuned GPT-3 with alternative models and find that it fares slightly better than supervised baselines when evaluated on unstable logs. The difference between GPT-3 and other supervised approaches tends to become more significant as the degree of changes in log sequences increases. However, the practical significance of this difference is unclear in all cases. The authors also compare prompt engineering (with GPT-4) and fine-tuning, finding that the latter provides significantly superior performance on both stable and unstable logs.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Fine-tuned GPT-3 fares slightly better than supervised baselines for anomaly detection on unstable logs (ADUL) on the two-version dataset of LOGEVOL-Hadoop.</li>
<li>As the degree of changes in logs increases, the difference between fine-tuned GPT-3 and other supervised approaches tends to become more significant.</li>
<li>Fine-tuning GPT-3 provides significantly superior performance on both stable and unstable logs compared to prompt engineering with GPT-4.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The paper presents an interesting application of LLMs for anomaly detection on unstable logs. The comparison of fine-tuned GPT-3 with alternative models and the exploration of prompt engineering are valuable contributions. However, the paper could benefit from a more detailed analysis of the practical significance of the observed differences between GPT-3 and other supervised approaches. Additionally, the paper could discuss potential limitations and biases in the data used for training and evaluation, as well as potential implications for the generalizability of the findings.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-06-12</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.07467v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.07467v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07467v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07467v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>11408</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Anomaly_Detection_on_Unstable_Logs_with_GPT_Models/2024-06-11-Anomaly_Detection_on_Unstable_Logs_with_GPT_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07467v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>3D-Properties: Identifying Challenges in DPO and Charting a Path Forward</title>
  <dc:creator>Yuzi Yan, Yibo Miao, Jialian Li, Yipin Zhang, Jian Xie, Zhijie Deng, Dong Yan</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/3D_Properties_Identifying_Challenges_in_DPO_and_Charting_a_Path_Forward/2024-06-11-3D_Properties_Identifying_Challenges_in_DPO_and_Charting_a_Path_Forward.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/3D_Properties_Identifying_Challenges_in_DPO_and_Charting_a_Path_Forward/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07327v1/extracted/5659467/figure/main_text/toy_model_diagram.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>This paper examines the empirical efficacy of Direct Preference Optimization (DPO) and compares it to the RLHF-PPO method for aligning large language models (LLMs) with human preferences. The authors identify three 3D-properties of DPO’s learning outcomes: a drastic drop in the likelihood of rejected responses, degradation into LLM unlearning, and the dispersion effect on unseen responses. These findings are supported by experiments with both a toy model and practical LLMs on tasks such as mathematical problem-solving and instruction following. The authors propose regularization methods to mitigate the issues caused by 3D-properties and improve the training stability and final performance of DPO. They also investigate the impact of the distribution of the paired preference data on DPO’s effectiveness.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>DPO exhibits 3D-properties in its learning outcomes, including a drastic drop in the likelihood of rejected responses, degradation into LLM unlearning, and the dispersion effect on unseen responses.</li>
<li>The authors propose regularization methods, such as adjusting positive and negative weights adaptively and incorporating SFT loss, to improve the stability of DPO and mitigate the issues caused by 3D-properties.</li>
<li>The distribution of the paired preference data significantly influences DPO’s effectiveness, with on-policy DPO exhibiting the best performance.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper provides a comprehensive examination of DPO’s empirical efficacy and a systematic comparison with RLHF-PPO, which is valuable for understanding the strengths and weaknesses of both methods.</li>
<li>The identification of 3D-properties in DPO’s learning outcomes is an important contribution, as it helps explain some of the challenges associated with using DPO for aligning LLMs with human preferences.</li>
<li>The proposed regularization methods are a promising approach to improving the stability of DPO and mitigating the issues caused by 3D-properties. However, further research is needed to evaluate their effectiveness in practice.</li>
<li>The investigation into the impact of the distribution of the paired preference data on DPO’s effectiveness is an interesting direction for future research.</li>
<li>One limitation of the paper is that</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-06-12</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.07327v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.07327v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07327v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07327v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8028</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/3D_Properties_Identifying_Challenges_in_DPO_and_Charting_a_Path_Forward/2024-06-11-3D_Properties_Identifying_Challenges_in_DPO_and_Charting_a_Path_Forward.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07327v1/extracted/5659467/figure/main_text/toy_model_diagram.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Single-Codec: Single-Codebook Speech Codec towards High-Performance Speech Generation</title>
  <dc:creator>Hanzhao Li, Liumeng Xue, Haohan Guo, Xinfa Zhu, Yuanjun Lv, Lei Xie, Yunlin Chen, Hao Yin, Zhifei Li</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Single_Codec_Single_Codebook_Speech_Codec_towards_High_Performance_Speech_Generation/2024-06-11-Single_Codec_Single_Codebook_Speech_Codec_towards_High_Performance_Speech_Generation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Single_Codec_Single_Codebook_Speech_Codec_towards_High_Performance_Speech_Generation/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07422v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper introduces Single-Codec, a single-codebook speech codec designed to improve the efficiency and robustness of large language models (LLMs) in text-to-speech (TTS) systems. Unlike multi-codebook codecs, Single-Codec employs a disentangled VQ-VAE to decouple speech into a time-invariant embedding and a phonetically-rich discrete sequence. The encoder is enhanced with contextual modeling using a BLSTM module, a hybrid sampling module to alleviate distortion, and a resampling module to encourage discrete units to carry more phonetic information.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Single-Codec demonstrates higher reconstruction quality with a lower bandwidth of only 304bps compared to multi-codebook codecs such as EnCodec and TiCodec.</li>
<li>The effectiveness of Single-Codec is validated by LLM-TTS experiments, showing improved naturalness and intelligibility.</li>
<li>The use of a BLSTM module for contextual modeling, a hybrid sampling module, and a resampling module enhances the performance and applicability of Single-Codec in speech synthesis.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>While Single-Codec shows promising results in improving the efficiency and robustness of LLMs in TTS systems, there are some potential limitations and areas for further research.</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper does not provide a detailed comparison of Single-Codec with other state-of-the-art single-codebook codecs, making it difficult to assess its relative performance.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential impact of the lower bandwidth on the quality of the synthesized speech, which could be a concern for some applications.</li>
<li>The paper does not explore the potential trade-offs between the different components of Single-Codec, such as the BLSTM module and the hybrid sampling module, which could be important for optimizing the performance of the codec.</li>
</ol>
<p>Overall, Single-Codec is a promising approach to improving the efficiency and robustness of LLMs in TTS systems, but further research is needed to fully understand its strengths and limitations.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-06-12</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.07422v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.07422v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07422v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07422v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>4062</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Single_Codec_Single_Codebook_Speech_Codec_towards_High_Performance_Speech_Generation/2024-06-11-Single_Codec_Single_Codebook_Speech_Codec_towards_High_Performance_Speech_Generation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07422v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Paying More Attention to Source Context: Mitigating Unfaithful Translations from Large Language Model</title>
  <dc:creator>Hongbin Zhang, Kehai Chen, Xuefeng Bai, Yang Xiang, Min Zhang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Paying_More_Attention_to_Source_Context_Mitigating_Unfaithful_Translations_from_Large_Language_Model/2024-06-11-Paying_More_Attention_to_Source_Context_Mitigating_Unfaithful_Translations_from_Large_Language_Model.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Paying_More_Attention_to_Source_Context_Mitigating_Unfaithful_Translations_from_Large_Language_Model/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07036v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>Summary:</p>
<p>The paper focuses on the issue of unfaithful translations in large language models (LLMs) due to insufficient focus on the source context. The authors propose three methods to address this issue: reweight attention, contrastive decoding, and target-constrained tuning. The reweight attention method adjusts the attention weight of the source context to help models focus on the source context during generation. Contrastive decoding reduces the influence of target prefixes, and target-constrained tuning encourages LLMs to avoid excessive dependence on specific target prefixes. The experimental results show that the proposed methods improve translation performance across several language pairs in the proposed unfaithful translation test sets, outperforming baseline methods and effectively reducing the phenomenon of hallucinatory and unfaithful translations.</p>
<p>Major Findings:</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>The reweight attention method outperforms vanilla zeroshot prompting, showing an average improvement of 2.1 BLEU and 4.7 COMET.</li>
<li>The contrastive decoding strategy significantly improves the translation performance of LLMs, outperforming the baseline with an average improvement of 1.2 BLEU and 3.3 COMET.</li>
<li>The proposed target-constrained tuning consistently outperforms vanilla instruction tuning, with an average gain of 1.05 BLEU and 0.58 COMET.</li>
</ol>
<p>Analysis and Critique:</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>The proposed methods are effective in addressing the issue of unfaithful translations in LLMs, but they incur a higher computational cost compared to the standard settings.</li>
<li>The proposed methods have not been tested with other generation strategies, such as beam search, top-k sampling, or nucleus sampling.</li>
<li>The proposed methods have not been evaluated on other seq2seq tasks, such as summarization.</li>
<li>The proposed methods have not been tested on other LLMs, such as ChatGPT or GPT-4.</li>
<li>The proposed methods have not been evaluated on other language pairs, such as low-resource or distant languages.</li>
<li>The proposed methods have not been evaluated on other evaluation metrics, such as BLEURT or METEOR.</li>
<li>The proposed methods have not been evaluated on other test</li>
</ol>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-06-12</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.07036v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.07036v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07036v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07036v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>10716</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Paying_More_Attention_to_Source_Context_Mitigating_Unfaithful_Translations_from_Large_Language_Model/2024-06-11-Paying_More_Attention_to_Source_Context_Mitigating_Unfaithful_Translations_from_Large_Language_Model.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07036v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Limited Out-of-Context Knowledge Reasoning in Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Peng Hu, Changjiang Gao, Ruiqi Gao, Jiajun Chen, Shujian Huang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Limited_Out_of_Context_Knowledge_Reasoning_in_Large_Language_Models/2024-06-11-Limited_Out_of_Context_Knowledge_Reasoning_in_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Limited_Out_of_Context_Knowledge_Reasoning_in_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07393v1/extracted/5658916/IN_CONTEXT.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>This paper investigates the <strong>Out-of-Context Knowledge Reasoning (OCKR) capabilities</strong> of Large Language Models (LLMs), focusing on their ability to infer new knowledge from their training data rather than from the context or prompt. The study uses a synthetic dataset with seven representative OCKR tasks to evaluate the LLaMA2-13B-chat model. The results show that the model’s proficiency in OCKR is limited, regardless of whether the knowledge is trained in separate or adjacent settings. Training the model to reason with complete reasoning data did not result in significant improvement. However, training the model to perform explicit knowledge retrieval helped in only one of the tasks, indicating that the model’s limited OCKR capabilities are due to difficulties in retrieving relevant knowledge. The study also evaluates the model’s ability to transfer knowledge across languages and finds that it exhibits limited ability in this area as well.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The LLaMA2-13B-chat model shows limited OCKR ability, even with knowledge occurring adjacently during training.</li>
<li>Training the model with reasoning examples does not lead to significant improvement, suggesting that enhancing reasoning ability in general is insufficient for effective OCKR.</li>
<li>With the help of CoT, the model achieves over 90% accuracy in one task but does not surpass the random level in other two tasks. This indicates that the model can effectively retrieve attribute knowledge but struggles with correctly retrieving relational knowledge, which might be a limiting factor in OCKR.</li>
<li>In both the Separate and Adjacent settings, the performance in cross-lingual scenarios surpasses that of the monolingual, but the overall performance is still weak.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The study provides a comprehensive evaluation of the OCKR capabilities of LLMs, highlighting their limitations in this area. However, the study is limited to a few selected models, with the largest model being only 13B parameters. This limitation prevents the assessment of the capabilities of more advanced models, such as GPT-4. Additionally, the study only evaluates the models’ OCKR abilities using supervised fine-tuning and does not consider the impact of other training stages, such as reinforcement learning from human feedback. The</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-06-12</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.07393v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.07393v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07393v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07393v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5931</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Limited_Out_of_Context_Knowledge_Reasoning_in_Large_Language_Models/2024-06-11-Limited_Out_of_Context_Knowledge_Reasoning_in_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07393v1/extracted/5658916/IN_CONTEXT.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Reinforcement Learning from Human Feedback without Reward Inference: Model-Free Algorithm and Instance-Dependent Analysis</title>
  <dc:creator>Qining Zhang, Honghao Wei, Lei Ying</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Reinforcement_Learning_from_Human_Feedback_without_Reward_Inference_Model_Free_Algorithm_and_Instance_Dependent_Analysis/2024-06-11-Reinforcement_Learning_from_Human_Feedback_without_Reward_Inference_Model_Free_Algorithm_and_Instance_Dependent_Analysis.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Reinforcement_Learning_from_Human_Feedback_without_Reward_Inference_Model_Free_Algorithm_and_Instance_Dependent_Analysis/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07455v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>This paper presents a model-free RLHF (Reinforcement Learning from Human Feedback) algorithm called Batched Sequential Action Dueling (BASD) for episodic MDPs with general trajectory-wise rewards. The algorithm identifies the optimal policy directly from human preference information in a backward manner, employing a dueling bandit sub-routine that constantly duels actions to identify the superior one. The algorithm adopts a reward-free exploration and best-arm-identification-like adaptive stopping criteria to equalize the visitation among all states in the same decision step while moving to the previous step as soon as the optimal action is identifiable. The algorithm has a provable, instance-dependent sample complexity that resembles the result in classic RL, where the optimal policy is the Condorcet winner when human preferences are obtained with large batch sizes. The algorithm can be transformed into an explore-then-commit algorithm with logarithmic regret and generalized to discounted MDPs using a frame-based approach. The results show that RLHF is not significantly harder than classic RL and end-to-end RLHF may deliver improved performance by avoiding pitfalls in reward inferring such as overfit and distribution shift.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper proposes a model-free RLHF algorithm called Batched Sequential Action Dueling (BASD) for episodic MDPs with general trajectory-wise rewards.</li>
<li>The algorithm identifies the optimal policy directly from human preference information in a backward manner, employing a dueling bandit sub-routine that constantly duels actions to identify the superior one.</li>
<li>The algorithm adopts a reward-free exploration and best-arm-identification-like adaptive stopping criteria to equalize the visitation among all states in the same decision step while moving to the previous step as soon as the optimal action is identifiable.</li>
<li>The algorithm has a provable, instance-dependent sample complexity that resembles the result in classic RL, where the optimal policy is the Condorcet winner when human preferences are obtained with large batch sizes.</li>
<li>The algorithm can be transformed into an explore-then-commit algorithm with logarithmic regret and generalized to discounted MDPs</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-06-12</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.07455v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.07455v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07455v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07455v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>11143</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Reinforcement_Learning_from_Human_Feedback_without_Reward_Inference_Model_Free_Algorithm_and_Instance_Dependent_Analysis/2024-06-11-Reinforcement_Learning_from_Human_Feedback_without_Reward_Inference_Model_Free_Algorithm_and_Instance_Dependent_Analysis.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07455v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>RS-Agent: Automating Remote Sensing Tasks through Intelligent Agents</title>
  <dc:creator>Wenjia Xu, Zijian Yu, Yixu Wang, Jiuniu Wang, Mugen Peng</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/RS_Agent_Automating_Remote_Sensing_Tasks_through_Intelligent_Agents/2024-06-11-RS_Agent_Automating_Remote_Sensing_Tasks_through_Intelligent_Agents.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/RS_Agent_Automating_Remote_Sensing_Tasks_through_Intelligent_Agents/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07089v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper introduces RS-Agent, a large language model (LLM)-driven remote sensing intelligent agent designed to address the limitations of existing models in handling complex remote sensing applications and specialized expertise in professional domains. RS-Agent is powered by an LLM that acts as its “Central Controller,” enabling it to understand and respond to various problems intelligently. It integrates high-performance remote sensing image processing tools for multi-tool and multi-turn conversations and can answer professional questions by leveraging robust knowledge documents. Experiments conducted on several datasets, such as RSSDIVCS, RSVQA, and DOTAv1, demonstrate that RS-Agent delivers outstanding performance in scene classification, visual question answering, and object counting tasks.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>RS-Agent employs an LLM to understand the user’s requirements, acting as the central controller that accurately comprehends and interprets user intentions, adeptly analyzing the context and nuances of user inputs to discern the underlying needs and objectives behind queries.</li>
<li>RS-Agent can utilize multiple tools and engage in multi-turn conversations, integrating high-performance remote sensing image processing models. It can utilize a single model to address straightforward problems or sequentially invoke multiple models for continuous reasoning to tackle complex issues.</li>
<li>RS-Agent is capable of answering questions in specialized fields by employing Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) technology to broaden the Agent’s knowledge database by integrating a specialized knowledge repository, enabling it to address specific questions related to remote sensing.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper presents a promising approach to automating remote sensing tasks using an intelligent agent, RS-Agent. The integration of an LLM as the central controller and the incorporation of high-performance remote sensing tools enable RS-Agent to handle complex tasks and professional questions effectively.</li>
<li>The experimental results demonstrate RS-Agent’s superior performance in scene classification, visual question answering, and object counting tasks. However, the paper does not provide a comprehensive comparison with other state-of-the-art models in these tasks, which could help establish the RS-Agent’s performance relative to existing methods.</li>
<li>The paper could benefit from a more detailed discussion</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-06-12</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.07089v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.07089v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07089v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07089v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5913</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/RS_Agent_Automating_Remote_Sensing_Tasks_through_Intelligent_Agents/2024-06-11-RS_Agent_Automating_Remote_Sensing_Tasks_through_Intelligent_Agents.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07089v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>CAAP: Context-Aware Action Planning Prompting to Solve Computer Tasks with Front-End UI Only</title>
  <dc:creator>Junhee Cho, Jihoon Kim, Daseul Bae, Jinho Choo, Youngjune Gwon, Yeong-Dae Kwon</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/CAAP_Context_Aware_Action_Planning_Prompting_to_Solve_Computer_Tasks_with_Front_End_UI_Only/2024-06-11-CAAP_Context_Aware_Action_Planning_Prompting_to_Solve_Computer_Tasks_with_Front_End_UI_Only.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/CAAP_Context_Aware_Action_Planning_Prompting_to_Solve_Computer_Tasks_with_Front_End_UI_Only/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.06947v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary:</strong></p>
<p>The paper introduces an LLM-based agent that operates solely on the basis of screenshots for recognizing environments, while leveraging in-context learning to eliminate the need for collecting large datasets of human demonstration. The proposed method, named Context-Aware Action Planning (CAAP) prompting, encourages the agent to meticulously review the context in various angles. The agent achieves a success rate of 94.4% on 67 types of MiniWoB++ problems, utilizing only 1.48 demonstrations per problem type. The method offers the potential for broader applications, especially for tasks that require inter-application coordination on computers or smartphones.</p>
<p><strong>Major Findings:</strong></p>
<ol type="1">
<li>The proposed LLM-based agent operates exclusively through human-oriented front-end UI channels for both input and output, eliminating the constraints associated with HTML/DOM and application-specific API calls.</li>
<li>The CAAP prompting technique enhances the ICL ability of an LLM-based agent in managing complex desktop tasks by systematically structuring contextual information and leveraging syntactic patterns that trigger optimal CoT reasoning.</li>
<li>The paper proposes fairer metrics for comparing the performance of agents in the MiniWoB++ benchmark, addressing the issue of selectively chosen subgroups of tasks in previous studies.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></p>
<p>The paper presents a novel approach to LLM-based agents that addresses the limitations of existing methods reliant on HTML or DOM inputs and those that combine supervised learning (SL) and reinforcement learning (RL). The proposed agent operates solely on visual inputs and utilizes a large language model (LLM). The CAAP prompting approach is introduced to enhance the decision-making capabilities of ICL-based agents. The evaluations using the MiniWoB++ benchmark demonstrate the superiority of the proposed method. However, the scope of validation remains limited, and further research is needed to evaluate the agent across a broader array of benchmarks. Additionally, the agent’s reliance on visual observation data may lead to observation failures, as demonstrated in the case study. The paper also acknowledges the limitations of the benchmark directives and the need for more comprehensive assessment from a research perspective.</p>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-06-12</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.06947v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.06947v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.06947v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.06947v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>10877</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/CAAP_Context_Aware_Action_Planning_Prompting_to_Solve_Computer_Tasks_with_Front_End_UI_Only/2024-06-11-CAAP_Context_Aware_Action_Planning_Prompting_to_Solve_Computer_Tasks_with_Front_End_UI_Only.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.06947v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>McEval: Massively Multilingual Code Evaluation</title>
  <dc:creator>Linzheng Chai, Shukai Liu, Jian Yang, Yuwei Yin, Ke Jin, Jiaheng Liu, Tao Sun, Ge Zhang, Changyu Ren, Hongcheng Guo, Zekun Wang, Boyang Wang, Xianjie Wu, Bing Wang, Tongliang Li, Liqun Yang, Sufeng Duan, Zhoujun Li</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/McEval_Massively_Multilingual_Code_Evaluation/2024-06-11-McEval_Massively_Multilingual_Code_Evaluation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/McEval_Massively_Multilingual_Code_Evaluation/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07436v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level1">
<h1>Summary</h1>
<p>The paper introduces McEval, a massively multilingual code evaluation benchmark covering 40 programming languages with 16K test samples. The benchmark includes challenging code completion, understanding, and generation evaluation tasks with finely curated multilingual instruction corpora McEval-Instruct. The authors also introduce an effective multilingual coder mCoder trained on McEval-Instruct to support multilingual programming language generation.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li>McEval is the first massively multilingual code evaluation benchmark, covering 40 programming languages with 16K test samples.</li>
<li>The benchmark includes challenging code completion, understanding, and generation evaluation tasks with finely curated multilingual instruction corpora McEval-Instruct.</li>
<li>The authors introduce an effective multilingual coder mCoder trained on McEval-Instruct to support multilingual programming language generation.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper does not provide a detailed comparison of McEval with existing benchmarks, making it difficult to assess its advantages and limitations.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential biases in the data used for training mCoder, which could impact its performance on certain tasks or languages.</li>
<li>The paper does not provide a detailed analysis of the performance of mCoder on different tasks and languages, making it difficult to assess its strengths and weaknesses.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential applications of McEval and mCoder in real-world software development scenarios.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential ethical implications of using mCoder for code generation, such as the risk of generating code that violates software licenses or copyright laws.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-06-12</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.07436v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.07436v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07436v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07436v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7788</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/McEval_Massively_Multilingual_Code_Evaluation/2024-06-11-McEval_Massively_Multilingual_Code_Evaluation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07436v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Towards Human-AI Collaboration in Healthcare: Guided Deferral Systems with Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Joshua Strong, Qianhui Men, Alison Noble</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Towards_Human_AI_Collaboration_in_Healthcare_Guided_Deferral_Systems_with_Large_Language_Models/2024-06-11-Towards_Human_AI_Collaboration_in_Healthcare_Guided_Deferral_Systems_with_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Towards_Human_AI_Collaboration_in_Healthcare_Guided_Deferral_Systems_with_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07212v1/extracted/5644188/images/image.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>This paper presents a novel guided deferral system that utilizes large language models (LLMs) in computer-aided clinical diagnosis. The system not only defers cases to human decision-makers but also provides intelligent guidance. The study evaluates the classification and deferral performance of two distinct sources of predictions: verbalised and hidden-state predictions. The authors demonstrate that instruction-tuning an open-source, efficient, and small-scale LLM on the guard-railed generation of a large-scale version of the same LLM leads to improved classification performance and deferral performance, surpassing even that of the latter.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The proposed guided deferral system for LLMs in computer-aided clinical diagnosis not only defers cases to human decision-makers but also provides intelligent guidance, improving the overall decision-making process.</li>
<li>The study evaluates the classification and deferral performance of two distinct sources of predictions: verbalised and hidden-state predictions. The combination of these sources leads to a significant improvement in prediction performance.</li>
<li>Instruction-tuning an open-source, efficient, and small-scale LLM on the guard-railed generation of a large-scale version of the same LLM results in improved classification performance and deferral performance, surpassing even that of the larger model.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The paper presents an innovative approach to human-AI collaboration in healthcare by introducing a guided deferral system that leverages LLMs. The proposed system addresses the limitations of current deferral systems by providing intelligent guidance to human decision-makers. The study’s findings on the classification and deferral performance of verbalised and hidden-state predictions, as well as the benefits of instruction-tuning, are valuable contributions to the field.</p>
<p>However, the paper does not discuss potential limitations or biases in the proposed system. For instance, the reliance on LLMs for generating guidance may introduce biases or errors, which could impact the overall decision-making process. Additionally, the study does not address the potential challenges of implementing the proposed system in real-world clinical settings, such as the need for clinicians to understand the system’s capabilities and limitations.</p>
<p>Future research should focus on addressing these limitations and evaluating the proposed system in real-world</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-06-12</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.07212v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.07212v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07212v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07212v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>4804</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Towards_Human_AI_Collaboration_in_Healthcare_Guided_Deferral_Systems_with_Large_Language_Models/2024-06-11-Towards_Human_AI_Collaboration_in_Healthcare_Guided_Deferral_Systems_with_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07212v1/extracted/5644188/images/image.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>VideoLLaMA 2: Advancing Spatial-Temporal Modeling and Audio Understanding in Video-LLMs</title>
  <dc:creator>Zesen Cheng, Sicong Leng, Hang Zhang, Yifei Xin, Xin Li, Guanzheng Chen, Yongxin Zhu, Wenqi Zhang, Ziyang Luo, Deli Zhao, Lidong Bing</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/VideoLLaMA_2_Advancing_Spatial_Temporal_Modeling_and_Audio_Understanding_in_Video_LLMs/2024-06-11-VideoLLaMA_2_Advancing_Spatial_Temporal_Modeling_and_Audio_Understanding_in_Video_LLMs.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/VideoLLaMA_2_Advancing_Spatial_Temporal_Modeling_and_Audio_Understanding_in_Video_LLMs/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07476v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper presents VideoLLaMA 2, a set of Video Large Language Models (Video-LLMs) designed to enhance spatial-temporal modeling and audio understanding in video and audio-oriented tasks.</li>
<li>VideoLLaMA 2 incorporates a tailor-made Spatial-Temporal Convolution (STC) connector, which effectively captures the intricate spatial and temporal dynamics of video data.</li>
<li>The model also integrates an Audio Branch through joint training, enriching the multimodal understanding capabilities of the model by incorporating audio cues.</li>
<li>Comprehensive evaluations on multiple-choice video question answering (MC-VQA), open-ended video question answering (OE-VQA), and video captioning (VC) tasks demonstrate that VideoLLaMA 2 achieves competitive results among open-source models and even approaches some proprietary models on several benchmarks.</li>
<li>VideoLLaMA 2 also exhibits reasonable improvements in audio-only and audio-video question-answering (AQA &amp; OE-AVQA) benchmarks over existing models.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Effective Spatial-Temporal Modeling</strong>: VideoLLaMA 2’s STC connector effectively captures the intricate spatial and temporal dynamics of video data, improving the model’s performance in video-language tasks.</li>
<li><strong>Enhanced Audio Understanding</strong>: The integration of an Audio Branch through joint training significantly improves the model’s multimodal understanding capabilities by incorporating audio cues.</li>
<li><strong>Competitive Performance</strong>: VideoLLaMA 2 achieves competitive results among open-source models and even approaches some proprietary models on several benchmarks, setting a new standard for intelligent video analysis systems.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper provides a comprehensive evaluation of VideoLLaMA 2 on various video and audio understanding benchmarks, demonstrating its effectiveness in handling complex multimodal data.</li>
<li>However, the paper does not discuss potential limitations or shortcomings of the model, such as its performance in real-world scenarios or its generalizability to different types of video and audio data.</li>
<li>Additionally, the paper does not provide a detailed comparison with other state-</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-06-12</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.07476v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.07476v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07476v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07476v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5170</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/VideoLLaMA_2_Advancing_Spatial_Temporal_Modeling_and_Audio_Understanding_in_Video_LLMs/2024-06-11-VideoLLaMA_2_Advancing_Spatial_Temporal_Modeling_and_Audio_Understanding_in_Video_LLMs.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07476v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>DR-RAG: Applying Dynamic Document Relevance to Retrieval-Augmented Generation for Question-Answering</title>
  <dc:creator>Zijian Hei, Weiling Wei, Wenjie Ou, Juyi Qiao, Junming Jiao, Zhiqing Zhu, Guowen Song</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/DR_RAG_Applying_Dynamic_Document_Relevance_to_Retrieval_Augmented_Generation_for_Question_Answering/2024-06-11-DR_RAG_Applying_Dynamic_Document_Relevance_to_Retrieval_Augmented_Generation_for_Question_Answering.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/DR_RAG_Applying_Dynamic_Document_Relevance_to_Retrieval_Augmented_Generation_for_Question_Answering/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07348v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper introduces a novel two-stage retrieval framework called Dynamic-Relevant Retrieval-Augmented Generation (DR-RAG) to improve document retrieval recall and the accuracy of answers in question-answering (QA) systems. DR-RAG addresses the challenge of retrieving relevant documents with low relevance to the query, which are crucial for generating accurate answers. The framework employs a small classifier to determine the contribution of retrieved documents to answering the query and retrieve the relatively relevant documents. DR-RAG significantly improves the efficiency of the experiment by calling the large language models (LLMs) only once. The experimental results on multi-hop QA datasets demonstrate that DR-RAG can significantly improve the accuracy of the answers and achieve new progress in QA systems.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>DR-RAG is a two-stage retrieval framework that improves document retrieval recall and the accuracy of answers in QA systems.</li>
<li>A small classifier is applied to two different selection strategies to determine the contribution of the retrieved documents to answering the query and retrieve the relatively relevant documents.</li>
<li>DR-RAG calls the LLMs only once, significantly improving the efficiency of the experiment.</li>
<li>The experimental results on multi-hop QA datasets show that DR-RAG can significantly improve the accuracy of the answers and achieve new progress in QA systems.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The paper presents a promising approach to improving the performance of QA systems by addressing the challenge of retrieving relevant documents with low relevance to the query. The proposed DR-RAG framework demonstrates significant improvements in document retrieval recall and the accuracy of answers. However, the paper does not provide a detailed comparison with other state-of-the-art retrieval-augmented generation methods, which could have strengthened the evaluation of the proposed approach. Additionally, the paper does not discuss the potential limitations or shortcomings of the proposed framework, such as the scalability of the small classifier or the generalizability of the approach to other QA tasks. Further research is needed to address these limitations and evaluate the proposed framework in more diverse and challenging QA scenarios.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-06-12</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.07348v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.07348v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07348v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07348v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6121</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/DR_RAG_Applying_Dynamic_Document_Relevance_to_Retrieval_Augmented_Generation_for_Question_Answering/2024-06-11-DR_RAG_Applying_Dynamic_Document_Relevance_to_Retrieval_Augmented_Generation_for_Question_Answering.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07348v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>CoEvol: Constructing Better Responses for Instruction Finetuning through Multi-Agent Cooperation</title>
  <dc:creator>Renhao Li, Minghuan Tan, Derek F. Wong, Min Yang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/CoEvol_Constructing_Better_Responses_for_Instruction_Finetuning_through_Multi_Agent_Cooperation/2024-06-11-CoEvol_Constructing_Better_Responses_for_Instruction_Finetuning_through_Multi_Agent_Cooperation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/CoEvol_Constructing_Better_Responses_for_Instruction_Finetuning_through_Multi_Agent_Cooperation/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07054v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper proposes CoEvol, an LLM-based multi-agent cooperation framework for improving the quality of responses in instruction fine-tuning (IFT) data. The framework follows a debate-advise-edit-judge paradigm and employs a two-stage MAD strategy to maximize the diversity of perspectives within debate while minimizing the cost of agents. The proposed framework has been shown to be effective in evolving better IFT data through response augmentation.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>CoEvol is an innovative framework for improving IFT data quality through response enhancement, utilizing a two-stage MAD strategy to maximize the diversity of perspectives within debate while minimizing the cost of agents.</li>
<li>The framework follows a debate-advise-edit-judge paradigm, establishing a pipeline to harness the collective power of agents with distinct roles.</li>
<li>Experimental results demonstrate the efficacy of CoEvol in evolving better IFT data through response augmentation.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper focuses on improving the quality of responses in IFT data, which is a significant aspect of enhancing the applicability and generalization capabilities of pre-trained language models.</li>
<li>The proposed framework, CoEvol, leverages the potential of LLM-based multi-agents in collaboration to automatically edit responses, generating high-quality data for fine-tuning superior LLMs.</li>
<li>The paper’s limitations include the use of the same LLM for building multi-agents, which may lead to the accumulation of bias, and the need for further experiments to investigate the impact of agents based on different LLMs.</li>
<li>The paper does not explore the potential of the most powerful models like GPT-4 and Claude-3 when equipped with CoEvol, which could be a promising direction for future research.</li>
<li>The paper could benefit from a more comprehensive evaluation of the proposed framework, including human evaluations and comparisons with other data augmentation methods.</li>
<li>The paper could also provide more detailed examples of data evolution using CoEvol, as well as a more in-depth analysis of the evolving directions and their impact on the quality of IFT data.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-06-12</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.07054v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.07054v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07054v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07054v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6780</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/CoEvol_Constructing_Better_Responses_for_Instruction_Finetuning_through_Multi_Agent_Cooperation/2024-06-11-CoEvol_Constructing_Better_Responses_for_Instruction_Finetuning_through_Multi_Agent_Cooperation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07054v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Joint Demonstration and Preference Learning Improves Policy Alignment with Human Feedback</title>
  <dc:creator>Chenliang Li, Siliang Zeng, Zeyi Liao, Jiaxiang Li, Dongyeop Kang, Alfredo Garcia, Mingyi Hong</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Joint_Demonstration_and_Preference_Learning_Improves_Policy_Alignment_with_Human_Feedback/2024-06-11-Joint_Demonstration_and_Preference_Learning_Improves_Policy_Alignment_with_Human_Feedback.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Joint_Demonstration_and_Preference_Learning_Improves_Policy_Alignment_with_Human_Feedback/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.06874v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level1">
<h1>Summary:</h1>
<p>The paper presents a novel approach to aligning human preferences and values with AI systems, addressing the limitations of existing sequential methods such as RLHF. The proposed method, Alignment with Integrated Human Feedback (AIHF), integrates both human preference and demonstration data to train reward models and policies in a single stage. The authors demonstrate the efficiency of AIHF through extensive experiments involving alignment problems in LLMs and robotic control tasks in MuJoCo. The results show that AIHF outperforms existing alignment algorithms, particularly when the amount of high-quality preference data is limited.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level1">
<h1>Major Findings:</h1>
<ol type="1">
<li>AIHF is a single-stage approach that integrates both human preference and demonstration data to train reward models and policies, addressing the limitations of sequential methods like RLHF.</li>
<li>The proposed approach admits a suite of efficient algorithms that can be easily reduced to and leverage popular alignment algorithms such as RLHF and Directly Policy Optimization (DPO).</li>
<li>AIHF demonstrates superior performance in extensive experiments involving alignment problems in LLMs and robotic control tasks in MuJoCo, outperforming existing alignment algorithms, especially when the amount of high-quality preference data is limited.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level1">
<h1>Analysis and Critique:</h1>
<p>The paper presents a promising approach to addressing the challenges of aligning human preferences and values with AI systems. The proposed AIHF method offers a more efficient and effective alternative to existing sequential methods, such as RLHF. The authors provide a well-structured and coherent summary of their work, highlighting the major findings and contributions.</p>
<p>However, there are some potential limitations and areas for improvement. For instance, the paper does not discuss the potential biases that may arise from the integration of human preference and demonstration data. Additionally, the authors do not address the computational complexity of the proposed approach or compare it to existing methods. Furthermore, the paper does not provide a detailed analysis of the potential impact of AIHF on the overall performance and safety of AI systems.</p>
<p>In conclusion, the paper presents a valuable contribution to the field of AI alignment, offering a novel approach that addresses the limitations of existing methods. However, further research is needed to address the potential biases, computational complexity, and impact on AI system performance and safety.</p>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-06-12</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.06874v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.06874v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.06874v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.06874v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>10718</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Joint_Demonstration_and_Preference_Learning_Improves_Policy_Alignment_with_Human_Feedback/2024-06-11-Joint_Demonstration_and_Preference_Learning_Improves_Policy_Alignment_with_Human_Feedback.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.06874v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Advancing Annotation of Stance in Social Media Posts: A Comparative Analysis of Large Language Models and Crowd Sourcing</title>
  <dc:creator>Mao Li, Frederick Conrad</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Advancing_Annotation_of_Stance_in_Social_Media_Posts_A_Comparative_Analysis_of_Large_Language_Models_and_Crowd_Sourcing/2024-06-11-Advancing_Annotation_of_Stance_in_Social_Media_Posts_A_Comparative_Analysis_of_Large_Language_Models_and_Crowd_Sourcing.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Advancing_Annotation_of_Stance_in_Social_Media_Posts_A_Comparative_Analysis_of_Large_Language_Models_and_Crowd_Sourcing/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07483v1/extracted/5659896/figure/distribution.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>This study investigates the performance of eight open-source and proprietary Large Language Models (LLMs) in annotating the stance expressed in social media posts, benchmarking their performance against human annotators’ judgments. The explicitness of text expressing a stance plays a critical role in how faithfully LLMs’ stance judgments match humans’. The study argues that LLMs perform well when human annotators do, and when LLMs fail, it often corresponds to situations in which human annotators struggle to reach an agreement. The study concludes with recommendations for a comprehensive approach that combines the precision of human expertise with the scalability of LLM predictions.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The explicitness of text expressing a stance plays a critical role in how faithfully LLMs’ stance judgments match humans’.</li>
<li>LLMs perform well when human annotators do, and when LLMs fail, it often corresponds to situations in which human annotators struggle to reach an agreement.</li>
<li>A comprehensive approach that combines the precision of human expertise with the scalability of LLM predictions is recommended.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study does not provide a detailed methodology for the comparison of LLMs and human annotators, making it difficult to assess the validity of the findings.</li>
<li>The study does not discuss the potential biases of LLMs and human annotators, which could impact the accuracy of stance annotation.</li>
<li>The study does not provide a clear definition of “explicitness” and how it was measured, making it difficult to understand the relationship between explicitness and LLM performance.</li>
<li>The study does not discuss the potential limitations of using LLMs for stance annotation, such as the lack of contextual understanding and the potential for overfitting to training data.</li>
<li>The study does not discuss the potential ethical implications of using LLMs for stance annotation, such as the potential for bias and the impact on privacy.</li>
<li>The study does not provide a clear recommendation for how to improve the accuracy and comprehensiveness of automated stance detection, beyond combining human expertise and LLM predictions.</li>
<li>The study does not discuss the potential impact of LLMs on the field of social media analysis and the potential for LLMs to be used for malicious purposes.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-06-12</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.07483v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.07483v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07483v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07483v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7463</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Advancing_Annotation_of_Stance_in_Social_Media_Posts_A_Comparative_Analysis_of_Large_Language_Models_and_Crowd_Sourcing/2024-06-11-Advancing_Annotation_of_Stance_in_Social_Media_Posts_A_Comparative_Analysis_of_Large_Language_Models_and_Crowd_Sourcing.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07483v1/extracted/5659896/figure/distribution.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>GraphCoder: Enhancing Repository-Level Code Completion via Code Context Graph-based Retrieval and Language Model</title>
  <dc:creator>Wei Liu, Ailun Yu, Daoguang Zan, Bo Shen, Wei Zhang, Haiyan Zhao, Zhi Jin, Qianxiang Wang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/GraphCoder_Enhancing_Repository_Level_Code_Completion_via_Code_Context_Graph_based_Retrieval_and_Language_Model/2024-06-11-GraphCoder_Enhancing_Repository_Level_Code_Completion_via_Code_Context_Graph_based_Retrieval_and_Language_Model.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/GraphCoder_Enhancing_Repository_Level_Code_Completion_via_Code_Context_Graph_based_Retrieval_and_Language_Model/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07003v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper introduces GraphCoder, a retrieval-augmented code completion framework that leverages large language models’ (LLMs) general code knowledge and repository-specific knowledge via a graph-based retrieval-generation process. GraphCoder captures the context of the completion target more accurately through a code context graph (CCG) that consists of control-flow, data- and control-dependence between code statements. This structured approach is more effective than the sequence-based context used in existing retrieval-augmented methods. Experimental results demonstrate the effectiveness and efficiency of GraphCoder, with improvements in exact match (EM) for code and identifier match compared to baseline retrieval-augmented methods, while using less time and space.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>GraphCoder is a retrieval-augmented code completion framework that leverages LLMs’ general code knowledge and repository-specific knowledge via a graph-based retrieval-generation process.</li>
<li>GraphCoder captures the context of the completion target more accurately through a code context graph (CCG) that consists of control-flow, data- and control-dependence between code statements.</li>
<li>GraphCoder achieves higher exact match (EM) on average compared to baseline retrieval-augmented methods, with increases of 6.06 in code match and 6.23 in identifier match.</li>
<li>GraphCoder uses less time and space than baseline retrieval-augmented methods.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>GraphCoder presents a promising approach to repository-level code completion by leveraging both general and repository-specific knowledge. The use of a code context graph (CCG) to capture the context of the completion target more accurately is a significant improvement over existing retrieval-augmented methods that rely on sequence-based context. The experimental results demonstrate the effectiveness and efficiency of GraphCoder, with improvements in exact match (EM) for code and identifier match compared to baseline methods.</p>
<p>However, there are some potential limitations and areas for further research. The paper does not provide a detailed comparison of GraphCoder with other state-of-the-art code completion methods, which could provide a more comprehensive evaluation of its performance. Additionally, the paper does not discuss the scalability of GraphCoder to larger code re</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-06-12</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.07003v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.07003v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07003v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07003v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>9656</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>programming</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/GraphCoder_Enhancing_Repository_Level_Code_Completion_via_Code_Context_Graph_based_Retrieval_and_Language_Model/2024-06-11-GraphCoder_Enhancing_Repository_Level_Code_Completion_via_Code_Context_Graph_based_Retrieval_and_Language_Model.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2406.07003v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
