<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Bayesian beagle</title>
<link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Quarto blog of LLM-generated summaries of Arxiv preprints</description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.450</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>LUT Tensor Core: Lookup Table Enables Efficient Low-Bit LLM Inference Acceleration</title>
  <dc:creator>Zhiwen Mo, Lei Wang, Jianyu Wei, Zhichen Zeng, Shijie Cao, Lingxiao Ma, Naifeng Jing, Ting Cao, Jilong Xue, Fan Yang, Mao Yang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LUT_Tensor_Core_Lookup_Table_Enables_Efficient_Low_Bit_LLM_Inference_Acceleration/2024-08-12-LUT_Tensor_Core_Lookup_Table_Enables_Efficient_Low_Bit_LLM_Inference_Acceleration.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LUT_Tensor_Core_Lookup_Table_Enables_Efficient_Low_Bit_LLM_Inference_Acceleration/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06003v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level1">
<h1>Summary</h1>
<p>The paper introduces LUT Tensor Core, a software-hardware co-design optimized for low-bit LLM inference. The design aims to address the mpGEMM requirements in low-bit LLMs, which involve multiplying lower-precision weights with higher-precision activations. Current hardware does not natively support mpGEMM, leading to indirect and inefficient dequantization-based implementations.</p>
<p>LUT Tensor Core utilizes a lookup table (LUT)-based approach for mpGEMM, with software-based operator fusion and table symmetrization techniques to optimize table precompute and table storage, respectively. The hardware design features an elongated tiling shape to enhance table reuse and a bit-serial design to support various precision combinations in mpGEMM. Additionally, an end-to-end compilation stack with new instructions for LUT-based mpGEMM is proposed to enable efficient LLM compilation and optimizations.</p>
<p>Evaluation on low-bit LLMs (e.g., BitNet, LLAMA) shows that LUT Tensor Core achieves more than a magnitude of improvements on both compute density and energy efficiency.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li>LUT Tensor Core is a software-hardware co-design optimized for low-bit LLM inference, addressing the mpGEMM requirements.</li>
<li>The design utilizes a lookup table (LUT)-based approach for mpGEMM, with software-based operator fusion and table symmetrization techniques.</li>
<li>The hardware design features an elongated tiling shape and a bit-serial design to support various precision combinations in mpGEMM.</li>
<li>An end-to-end compilation stack with new instructions for LUT-based mpGEMM is proposed for efficient LLM compilation and optimizations.</li>
<li>LUT Tensor Core achieves significant improvements in compute density and energy efficiency on low-bit LLMs.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique</h2>
<p>While the paper presents a promising approach to address the mpGEMM requirements in low-bit LLMs, there are some potential limitations and areas for further research:</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential impact of the proposed design on model accuracy, which is a crucial aspect of LLM inference.</li>
<li>The evaluation is limited to a few low-bit LLMs, and it would be</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-13</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06003v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06003v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06003v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06003v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>10345</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LUT_Tensor_Core_Lookup_Table_Enables_Efficient_Low_Bit_LLM_Inference_Acceleration/2024-08-12-LUT_Tensor_Core_Lookup_Table_Enables_Efficient_Low_Bit_LLM_Inference_Acceleration.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06003v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Optimizing RAG Techniques for Automotive Industry PDF Chatbots: A Case Study with Locally Deployed Ollama Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Fei Liu, Zejun Kang, Xing Han</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Optimizing_RAG_Techniques_for_Automotive_Industry_PDF_Chatbots_A_Case_Study_with_Locally_Deployed_Ollama_Models/2024-08-12-Optimizing_RAG_Techniques_for_Automotive_Industry_PDF_Chatbots_A_Case_Study_with_Locally_Deployed_Ollama_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2408.05933v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The research focuses on optimizing Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) techniques for processing complex automotive industry documents using locally deployed Ollama models. The study proposes a multi-dimensional optimization approach based on the Langchain framework, addressing key challenges such as multi-column layouts and technical specifications. The proposed method introduces improvements in PDF processing, retrieval mechanisms, and context compression tailored to the unique characteristics of automotive industry documents. The study also designs custom classes supporting embedding pipelines and an agent supporting self-RAG based on LangGraph best practices. The proposed approach is evaluated using a proprietary dataset of typical automotive industry documents and compared against a naive RAG baseline across three datasets: the automotive industry dataset, QReCC, and CoQA. Results demonstrate significant improvements in context precision, context recall, answer relevancy, and faithfulness, with particularly notable performance on the automotive industry dataset.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The proposed multi-dimensional optimization approach for Ollama’s local RAG implementation effectively addresses key challenges in automotive document processing, including multi-column layouts and technical specifications.</li>
<li>The optimized RAG model and self-RAG agent outperform a naive RAG baseline across three datasets, with significant improvements in context precision, context recall, answer relevancy, and faithfulness.</li>
<li>The proposed approach provides an effective solution for deploying local RAG systems in the automotive sector, addressing the specific needs of PDF chatbots in industrial production environments.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The study presents a comprehensive approach to optimizing RAG techniques for automotive industry applications, specifically focusing on PDF chatbots deployed in local, low-performance environments. The research addresses critical challenges in processing complex automotive documentation and responding to industry-specific queries. The proposed method combines PDFMiner and Tabula to effectively handle multi-column layouts and complex tables prevalent in automotive technical documents, significantly improving information extraction accuracy. The Langchain-based RAG system, featuring a custom retriever ensemble and context compression pipeline, demonstrates substantial improvements in retrieving and utilizing automotive-specific information. The proposed AgenticRAG, enhanced with a custom function calling mechanism, shows superior performance in handling complex, multi-step queries typical in automotive engineering and manufacturing</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-13</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05933v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05933v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.05933v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.05933v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>14182</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Optimizing_RAG_Techniques_for_Automotive_Industry_PDF_Chatbots_A_Case_Study_with_Locally_Deployed_Ollama_Models/2024-08-12-Optimizing_RAG_Techniques_for_Automotive_Industry_PDF_Chatbots_A_Case_Study_with_Locally_Deployed_Ollama_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2408.05933v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Nob-MIAs: Non-biased Membership Inference Attacks Assessment on Large Language Models with Ex-Post Dataset Construction</title>
  <dc:creator>Cédric Eichler, Nathan Champeil, Nicolas Anciaux, Alexandra Bensamoun, Heber Hwang Arcolezi, José Maria De Fuentes</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Nob_MIAs_Non_biased_Membership_Inference_Attacks_Assessment_on_Large_Language_Models_with_Ex_Post_Dataset_Construction/2024-08-12-Nob_MIAs_Non_biased_Membership_Inference_Attacks_Assessment_on_Large_Language_Models_with_Ex_Post_Dataset_Construction.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Nob_MIAs_Non_biased_Membership_Inference_Attacks_Assessment_on_Large_Language_Models_with_Ex_Post_Dataset_Construction/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.05968v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level1">
<h1>Summary:</h1>
<p>The paper addresses the problem of assessing Membership Inference Attacks (MIAs) on Large Language Models (LLMs) with partially inferable training sets. The authors propose and validate algorithms to create “non-biased” and “non-classifiable” datasets for fairer MIA assessment. The experiments using the Gutenberg dataset on OpenLamma and Pythia show that neutralizing known biases alone is insufficient. The proposed methods produce non-biased ex-post datasets with AUC-ROC scores comparable to those previously obtained on genuinely random datasets, validating the approach. However, MIAs yield results close to random, with only one being effective on both random and the proposed datasets, but its performance decreases when bias is removed.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level1">
<h1>Major Findings:</h1>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper proposes and validates algorithms to create “non-biased” and “non-classifiable” datasets for fairer MIA assessment on LLMs with partially inferable training sets.</li>
<li>Neutralizing known biases alone is insufficient for accurate MIA assessment.</li>
<li>The proposed methods produce non-biased ex-post datasets with AUC-ROC scores comparable to those previously obtained on genuinely random datasets, validating the approach.</li>
<li>MIAs yield results close to random, with only one being effective on both random and the proposed datasets, but its performance decreases when bias is removed.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level1">
<h1>Analysis and Critique:</h1>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper addresses an important issue in the field of LLMs and copyright infringement, providing a method for fairer MIA assessment.</li>
<li>The proposed algorithms and experiments provide a valuable contribution to the field, offering a way to create “non-biased” and “non-classifiable” datasets.</li>
<li>However, the paper does not discuss the potential limitations or biases of the proposed methods, which could be a topic for future research.</li>
<li>The paper also does not discuss the potential implications of the findings for the development and use of LLMs, which could be an important area for further research.</li>
<li>The paper could benefit from a more detailed discussion of the potential applications and implications of the proposed methods, as well as a more thorough analysis of the limitations and biases of the proposed methods.</li>
</ol>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-13</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05968v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05968v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.05968v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.05968v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7404</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Nob_MIAs_Non_biased_Membership_Inference_Attacks_Assessment_on_Large_Language_Models_with_Ex_Post_Dataset_Construction/2024-08-12-Nob_MIAs_Non_biased_Membership_Inference_Attacks_Assessment_on_Large_Language_Models_with_Ex_Post_Dataset_Construction.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.05968v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>ConvKGYarn: Spinning Configurable and Scalable Conversational Knowledge Graph QA datasets with Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Ronak Pradeep, Daniel Lee, Ali Mousavi, Jeff Pound, Yisi Sang, Jimmy Lin, Ihab Ilyas, Saloni Potdar, Mostafa Arefiyan, Yunyao Li</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ConvKGYarn_Spinning_Configurable_and_Scalable_Conversational_Knowledge_Graph_QA_datasets_with_Large_Language_Models/2024-08-12-ConvKGYarn_Spinning_Configurable_and_Scalable_Conversational_Knowledge_Graph_QA_datasets_with_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ConvKGYarn_Spinning_Configurable_and_Scalable_Conversational_Knowledge_Graph_QA_datasets_with_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.05948v1/extracted/5786378/images/Flowchart.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper introduces ConvKGYarn, a novel method for generating large-scale, configurable conversational Knowledge Graph Question Answering (KGQA) datasets. The method leverages the structured representation of Knowledge Graphs (KGs) to produce adaptive conversational datasets that evolve with user information needs and KG-captured knowledge. ConvKGYarn generates high-quality KGQA datasets, as demonstrated by extensive evaluations. The datasets enable the assessment of models’ effectiveness in different facets of user interactions and linguistic phenomena.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>ConvKGYarn generates dynamic and scalable conversational datasets for KGQA, which can be used to evaluate and improve the performance of LLMs and QA systems.</li>
<li>The method allows for the creation of configurable and adaptive datasets that can keep pace with evolving user information needs and KG-captured knowledge.</li>
<li>Extensive evaluations demonstrate the high quality of the datasets generated by ConvKGYarn, which can be used to assess models’ effectiveness in various conversational scenarios.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>While ConvKGYarn offers a promising approach to generating high-quality KGQA datasets, there are some potential limitations and areas for improvement.</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>The method relies on the availability and quality of KGs, which may not always be up-to-date or comprehensive. This could limit the scope and accuracy of the generated datasets.</li>
<li>The method’s reliance on LLMs for predicate selection and question generation may introduce biases or errors, depending on the quality and training of the LLMs used.</li>
<li>The evaluation of the generated datasets is primarily based on human annotation, which can be subjective and time-consuming. More objective and automated evaluation methods could be explored to improve the efficiency and reliability of the evaluation process.</li>
</ol>
<p>Overall, ConvKGYarn presents a valuable contribution to the field of KGQA, offering a scalable and configurable method for generating high-quality datasets. However, further research is needed to address potential limitations and improve the method’s robustness and reliability.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-13</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05948v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05948v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.05948v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.05948v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>10786</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ConvKGYarn_Spinning_Configurable_and_Scalable_Conversational_Knowledge_Graph_QA_datasets_with_Large_Language_Models/2024-08-12-ConvKGYarn_Spinning_Configurable_and_Scalable_Conversational_Knowledge_Graph_QA_datasets_with_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.05948v1/extracted/5786378/images/Flowchart.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Hyperion: Unveiling DApp Inconsistencies using LLM and Dataflow-Guided Symbolic Execution</title>
  <dc:creator>Shuo Yang, Xingwei Lin, Jiachi Chen, Qingyuan Zhong, Lei Xiao, Renke Huang, Yanlin Wang, Zibin Zheng</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Hyperion_Unveiling_DApp_Inconsistencies_using_LLM_and_Dataflow_Guided_Symbolic_Execution/2024-08-12-Hyperion_Unveiling_DApp_Inconsistencies_using_LLM_and_Dataflow_Guided_Symbolic_Execution.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Hyperion_Unveiling_DApp_Inconsistencies_using_LLM_and_Dataflow_Guided_Symbolic_Execution/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06037v1/extracted/5786835/images/data1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper introduces Hyperion, a tool designed to automatically identify inconsistencies between front-end descriptions and back-end code implementation in DApps. The authors conducted an empirical study to identify seven types of inconsistencies, each exemplified by a real-world DApp. Hyperion leverages a fine-tuned large language model LLaMA2 to analyze DApp descriptions and employs dataflow-guided symbolic execution for contract bytecode analysis. The experiment on a ground truth dataset consisting of 54 DApps shows that Hyperion reaches 84.06% overall recall and 92.06% overall precision in reporting DApp inconsistencies. Hyperion was also implemented to analyze 835 real-world DApps, discovering 459 DApps containing at least one inconsistency.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Hyperion, a tool using LLM and dataflow-guided symbolic execution, was developed to automatically identify inconsistencies between front-end descriptions and back-end code implementation in DApps.</li>
<li>Seven types of inconsistencies were identified through an empirical study, each exemplified by a real-world DApp.</li>
<li>Hyperion reaches 84.06% overall recall and 92.06% overall precision in reporting DApp inconsistencies on a ground truth dataset consisting of 54 DApps.</li>
<li>Hyperion discovered 459 real-world DApps containing at least one inconsistency when implemented to analyze 835 real-world DApps.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The paper presents a novel approach to identifying inconsistencies in DApps, which is crucial for maintaining trustworthiness and preventing potential threats to users’ interests. The use of a fine-tuned large language model and dataflow-guided symbolic execution is a promising method for analyzing DApp descriptions and contract bytecode. However, the paper does not discuss the limitations or potential biases of the approach, nor does it address any methodological issues or conflicting evidence. Additionally, the paper does not provide any information on the potential for further research or clarification in this area.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-13</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06037v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06037v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06037v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06037v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>11199</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Hyperion_Unveiling_DApp_Inconsistencies_using_LLM_and_Dataflow_Guided_Symbolic_Execution/2024-08-12-Hyperion_Unveiling_DApp_Inconsistencies_using_LLM_and_Dataflow_Guided_Symbolic_Execution.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06037v1/extracted/5786835/images/data1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Animate, or Inanimate, That is the Question for Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Leonardo Ranaldi, Giulia Pucci, Fabio Massimo Zanzotto</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Animate_or_Inanimate_That_is_the_Question_for_Large_Language_Models/2024-08-12-Animate_or_Inanimate_That_is_the_Question_for_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06332v1/extracted/5787747/img/our_image.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study investigates whether Large Language Models (LLMs) can understand and generate language in a way that reflects human expectations, specifically in the context of animacy.</li>
<li>The research uses LLMs as subjects in psycholinguistic experiments designed for humans, focusing on their behaviors in answering infractions of selective constraints associated with animacy in typical and atypical settings.</li>
<li>The findings reveal that LLMs generally prefer sentences adhering to animacy-related constraints, similar to humans, and can adapt their awareness in atypical scenarios.</li>
<li>The study uses a systematic prompt-based approach for LLMs, analyzing their responses to animacy in situations where the animacy of an instance aligns with its more general type.</li>
<li>The results show that LLMs of the OpenAI family behave similarly to humans in both typical and atypical animacy tasks, while the Meta and Mistral families are catching up.</li>
<li>The study concludes that despite their lack of embodiment and senses, LLMs behave as humans in animacy understanding, even when lexical information does not entirely lead the decision.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs can understand and generate language in a way that reflects human expectations, specifically in the context of animacy.</li>
<li>LLMs generally prefer sentences adhering to animacy-related constraints, similar to humans, and can adapt their awareness in atypical scenarios.</li>
<li>LLMs of the OpenAI family behave similarly to humans in both typical and atypical animacy tasks, while the Meta and Mistral families are catching up.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study provides a comprehensive analysis of LLMs’ ability to understand and generate language in the context of animacy, using a systematic prompt-based approach.</li>
<li>The findings are significant as they demonstrate that LLMs can behave as humans in animacy understanding, even when lexical information does not entirely lead the decision.</li>
<li>However, the study does not address ethical topics, and the data comes from open-source benchmarks, which may not fully represent the complexity of human language and cognition.</li>
<li>Future research could extend the analysis to more languages and assess the impact of the in-context prompt on the models’ responses.</li>
<li>Additionally, analyzing the internal dynamics that support the models’ decisions could provide a better understanding</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-13</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06332v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06332v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06332v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06332v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6451</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Animate_or_Inanimate_That_is_the_Question_for_Large_Language_Models/2024-08-12-Animate_or_Inanimate_That_is_the_Question_for_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06332v1/extracted/5787747/img/our_image.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Can We Rely on LLM Agents to Draft Long-Horizon Plans? Let’s Take TravelPlanner as an Example</title>
  <dc:creator>Yanan Chen, Ali Pesaranghader, Tanmana Sadhu, Dong Hoon Yi</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Can_We_Rely_on_LLM_Agents_to_Draft_Long_Horizon_Plans_Lets_Take_TravelPlanner_as_an_Example/2024-08-12-Can_We_Rely_on_LLM_Agents_to_Draft_Long_Horizon_Plans_Lets_Take_TravelPlanner_as_an_Example.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/../bayesian-beagle.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level1">
<h1>Summary:</h1>
<p>The paper “Can We Rely on LLM Agents to Draft Long-Horizon Plans? Let’s Take TravelPlanner as an Example” investigates the performance of LLM-based agents in complex, long-horizon planning tasks using the TravelPlanner benchmark. The study addresses four key research questions: (1) the robustness of LLM agents to lengthy and noisy contexts, (2) the impact of few-shot prompting on performance, (3) the effectiveness of refinement in improving plans, and (4) the potential of feedback-aware fine-tuning (FAFT) for further improvement.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs often fail to attend to crucial parts of a long context, despite their ability to handle extensive reference information and few-shot examples.</li>
<li>LLMs still struggle with analyzing long plans and cannot provide accurate feedback for refinement.</li>
<li>Feedback-Aware Fine-Tuning (FAFT), which leverages both positive and negative feedback, results in substantial gains over Supervised Fine-Tuning (SFT).</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h2>
<p>The paper provides valuable insights into the limitations of LLM-based agents in complex planning tasks. However, the study is limited by the use of only GPT-3.5-Turbo as the Planner agent for RQ1 and RQ2 due to budget constraints. Further investigations are needed to explore the relationship between the magnitude of gains and the size of the FAFT training set, as well as the impact of the ratio of positive to negative samples on the final performance. Additionally, enhancing the feedback expressions could further improve the performance of FAFT. It would also be interesting to investigate RLHF techniques, such as DPO and PRO, to better utilize feedback.</p>
<p>The paper adheres to the original work’s specifications, utilizing their data, evaluation scripts, and definitions of commonsense. The authors strictly adhere to TravelPlanner’s guidelines, ensuring the integrity of the evaluation process by prohibiting any form of cheating in the validation and test sets. However, the extensive experiments required for this study have a significant environmental cost. Future endeavors can leverage these insights, potentially reducing the need for numerous large-scale comparisons. Models intended for production could undergo</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-13</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06318v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06318v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06318v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06318v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6085</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Can_We_Rely_on_LLM_Agents_to_Draft_Long_Horizon_Plans_Lets_Take_TravelPlanner_as_an_Example/2024-08-12-Can_We_Rely_on_LLM_Agents_to_Draft_Long_Horizon_Plans_Lets_Take_TravelPlanner_as_an_Example.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>A New Pipeline For Generating Instruction Dataset via RAG and Self Fine-Tuning</title>
  <dc:creator>Chih-Wei Song, Yu-Kai Lee, Yin-Te Tsai</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_New_Pipeline_For_Generating_Instruction_Dataset_via_RAG_and_Self_Fine_Tuning/2024-08-12-A_New_Pipeline_For_Generating_Instruction_Dataset_via_RAG_and_Self_Fine_Tuning.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2408.05911v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary:</strong></p>
<p>The paper proposes a pipeline for generating high-quality instruction datasets for fine-tuning large language models (LLMs) on specific domains using custom document collections. The pipeline leverages the power of LLMs and the Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) related framework to create relevant and contextually appropriate instructions. This approach overcomes the limitations of traditional dataset creation methods, which often rely on manual curation or web-scraping techniques that may introduce noise and irrelevant data. The pipeline offers a dynamic solution that can quickly adapt to updates or modifications in the domain-specific document collection, eliminating the need for complete retraining. Additionally, it addresses the challenge of data scarcity by enabling the generation of instruction datasets from a limited set of initial documents, rendering it suitable for unpopular or specialized domains where comprehensive datasets are scarce.</p>
<p><strong>Major Findings:</strong></p>
<ol type="1">
<li>The proposed pipeline combines LLMs with the Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) framework to construct domain-specific instruction datasets, harnessing the generative capabilities of LLMs and the information retrieval strengths of RAG.</li>
<li>The pipeline is dynamic and can quickly adapt to updates or modifications in the domain-specific document collection, eliminating the need for complete retraining.</li>
<li>The pipeline addresses the challenge of data scarcity by enabling the generation of instruction datasets from a limited set of initial documents, making it suitable for unpopular or specialized domains where comprehensive datasets are scarce.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></p>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper does not provide a comprehensive evaluation of the proposed pipeline, which makes it difficult to assess its effectiveness and generalizability across different domains.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential limitations or biases that may arise from using the proposed pipeline, such as the quality of the initial document collection or the potential for the LLM to generate inaccurate or misleading instructions.</li>
<li>The paper does not provide a detailed comparison of the proposed pipeline with other existing methods for generating instruction datasets, which would be useful for understanding its relative strengths and weaknesses.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential ethical implications of using the proposed pipeline, such as the potential for the generated instructions to perpetuate existing biases or inaccuracies in the initial document collection.</li>
<li>The paper does not provide a clear roadmap for future</li>
</ol>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-13</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05911v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05911v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.05911v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.05911v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5446</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_New_Pipeline_For_Generating_Instruction_Dataset_via_RAG_and_Self_Fine_Tuning/2024-08-12-A_New_Pipeline_For_Generating_Instruction_Dataset_via_RAG_and_Self_Fine_Tuning.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2408.05911v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Creating Arabic LLM Prompts at Scale</title>
  <dc:creator>Abdelrahman El-Sheikh, Ahmed Elmogtaba, Kareem Darwish, Muhammad Elmallah, Ashraf Elneima, Hassan Sawaf</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Creating_Arabic_LLM_Prompts_at_Scale/2024-08-12-Creating_Arabic_LLM_Prompts_at_Scale.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Creating_Arabic_LLM_Prompts_at_Scale/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.05882v1/extracted/5786068/ArabicTemplatesExamples.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper introduces two methods for creating Arabic prompts for Large Language Models (LLMs) at scale. The first method involves automatically translating existing English prompt datasets, such as PromptSource and Super-NaturalInstructions, and using machine translation quality estimation to retain high-quality translations. The second method entails creating natural language prompts on top of existing Arabic NLP datasets. Using these methods, the authors were able to create more than 67.4 million Arabic prompts covering various tasks, including summarization, headline generation, grammar checking, open/closed question answering, and creative writing. The paper also demonstrates that fine-tuning an open 7 billion parameter large language model, Qwen2 7B, enables it to outperform a state-of-the-art 70 billion parameter instruction-tuned model, Llama3 70B, in handling Arabic prompts.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The authors created more than 67.4 million Arabic prompts using two methods: translation of existing English prompt datasets and creating prompts on top of existing Arabic NLP datasets.</li>
<li>The paper shows that fine-tuning an LLM using the new data significantly improves LLM performance on a variety of tasks.</li>
<li>The authors demonstrate that fine-tuning the Qwen2 7B model using their newly created dataset of 800k samples led to statistically significant improvement over the Qwen2-Instruct 7B model.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper provides a valuable contribution to the field of LLM prompt engineering, particularly for Arabic language models.</li>
<li>The methods presented in the paper can be applied to other languages, making it a versatile approach to prompt creation.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential limitations or biases in the created prompts, which could be an area for further research.</li>
<li>The paper focuses on the ability of LLMs to follow instructions in performing a variety of tasks, but it does not measure their knowledge, which could be a potential area for future work.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential impact of the created prompts on the performance of LLMs in real-world applications.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-13</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05882v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05882v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.05882v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.05882v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>3273</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Creating_Arabic_LLM_Prompts_at_Scale/2024-08-12-Creating_Arabic_LLM_Prompts_at_Scale.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.05882v1/extracted/5786068/ArabicTemplatesExamples.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Multimodal Large Language Models for Phishing Webpage Detection and Identification</title>
  <dc:creator>Jehyun Lee, Peiyuan Lim, Bryan Hooi, Dinil Mon Divakaran</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Multimodal_Large_Language_Models_for_Phishing_Webpage_Detection_and_Identification/2024-08-12-Multimodal_Large_Language_Models_for_Phishing_Webpage_Detection_and_Identification.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2408.05941v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary:</strong></p>
<p>This paper explores the use of multimodal large language models (LLMs) for detecting phishing webpages. The authors propose a two-phase system that employs LLMs in both phases: the first phase focuses on brand identification, while the second verifies the domain. The study evaluates three state-of-the-art multimodal LLMs, namely GPT-4, GeminiPro 1.0, and Claude3, on their capability to assist with phishing detection. The results demonstrate that LLMs show promise in detecting phishing pages at high precision, while also providing explanations. The system also performs significantly better than a state-of-the-art brand-based phishing detection system and demonstrates robustness against two known adversarial attacks.</p>
<p><strong>Major Findings:</strong></p>
<ol type="1">
<li>Multimodal LLMs, such as GPT-4, GeminiPro 1.0, and Claude3, can be used to detect phishing webpages with high precision and provide interpretable evidence for the decisions.</li>
<li>The proposed two-phase system, which uses LLMs for both brand identification and domain verification, outperforms a state-of-the-art brand-based phishing detection system.</li>
<li>The LLM-based system demonstrates robustness against two known adversarial attacks, making it a promising approach for phishing detection.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></p>
<p>The paper presents an innovative approach to phishing detection using multimodal LLMs. The authors provide a comprehensive evaluation of the proposed system, demonstrating its effectiveness in detecting phishing webpages and its robustness against adversarial attacks. However, the study does not discuss the potential limitations or biases of the LLMs used in the system. Additionally, the paper does not address the potential challenges in maintaining and updating the LLMs as new phishing techniques emerge. Further research is needed to explore these aspects and ensure the long-term effectiveness of the proposed system.</p>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-13</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05941v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05941v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.05941v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.05941v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>17527</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Multimodal_Large_Language_Models_for_Phishing_Webpage_Detection_and_Identification/2024-08-12-Multimodal_Large_Language_Models_for_Phishing_Webpage_Detection_and_Identification.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2408.05941v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>A RAG-Based Question-Answering Solution for Cyber-Attack Investigation and Attribution</title>
  <dc:creator>Sampath Rajapaksha, Ruby Rani, Erisa Karafili</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_RAG_Based_Question_Answering_Solution_for_Cyber_Attack_Investigation_and_Attribution/2024-08-12-A_RAG_Based_Question_Answering_Solution_for_Cyber_Attack_Investigation_and_Attribution.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_RAG_Based_Question_Answering_Solution_for_Cyber_Attack_Investigation_and_Attribution/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06272v1/extracted/5786891/images/CyberThreaDQA.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper introduces a Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG)-based question-answering (QA) model for cyber-attack investigation and attribution. The model uses a knowledge base (KB) containing curated information about cyber-attacks and a Large Language Model (LLM) to provide answers to user queries. The model was tested with various types of questions and compared to OpenAI’s GPT-3.5 and GPT-4o LLMs. The RAG-based QA model outperformed the GPT models by providing the source of the answers and overcoming the hallucination limitations of the GPT models. The model also performed better when given few-shot examples rather than zero-shot instructions.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The RAG-based QA model outperforms OpenAI’s GPT models by providing the source of the answers and overcoming the hallucination limitations of the GPT models.</li>
<li>The RAG-based QA model generates better answers when given few-shot examples rather than zero-shot instructions.</li>
<li>The RAG-based QA model uses a KB containing curated information about cyber-attacks and a LLM to provide answers to user queries.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The paper presents a novel approach to cyber-attack investigation and attribution using a RAG-based QA model. The model’s ability to provide the source of the answers and overcome the hallucination limitations of the GPT models is a significant advantage. However, the paper does not provide a detailed comparison of the RAG-based QA model to other existing models for cyber-attack investigation and attribution. Additionally, the paper does not discuss the limitations of the RAG-based QA model, such as the potential for the model to generate incorrect answers if the KB contains incorrect information. Further research is needed to evaluate the effectiveness of the RAG-based QA model in real-world scenarios and to compare it to other existing models.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-13</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06272v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06272v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06272v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06272v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7723</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_RAG_Based_Question_Answering_Solution_for_Cyber_Attack_Investigation_and_Attribution/2024-08-12-A_RAG_Based_Question_Answering_Solution_for_Cyber_Attack_Investigation_and_Attribution.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06272v1/extracted/5786891/images/CyberThreaDQA.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Building Decision Making Models Through Language Model Regime</title>
  <dc:creator>Yu Zhang, Haoxiang Liu, Feijun Jiang, Weihua Luo, Kaifu Zhang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Building_Decision_Making_Models_Through_Language_Model_Regime/2024-08-12-Building_Decision_Making_Models_Through_Language_Model_Regime.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/../bayesian-beagle.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The article proposes a novel approach for decision-making problems using large language models (LLMs) called “Learning then Using” (LTU). This approach involves a two-stage process: the learning phase develops a robust foundational decision-making model by integrating diverse knowledge from various domains and decision-making contexts, and the using phase refines this foundation model for specific decision-making scenarios. The LTU method outperforms traditional supervised learning regimes in decision-making capabilities and generalization, as demonstrated by experiments in e-commerce domains such as advertising and search optimization.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The LTU approach, which combines broad pre-training with targeted fine-tuning, outperforms traditional supervised learning regimes in decision-making capabilities and generalization.</li>
<li>The LTU method is the first practical training architecture for both single-step and multi-step decision-making tasks combined with LLMs, which can be applied beyond game and robot domains.</li>
<li>The LTU approach provides a robust and adaptable framework for decision-making, enhancing the effectiveness and flexibility of various systems in tackling various challenges.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article does not provide a detailed comparison of the LTU approach with other existing methods for decision-making problems, such as reinforcement learning or planning algorithms.</li>
<li>The experiments conducted in the article are limited to e-commerce domains, and it is unclear how the LTU approach would perform in other domains or applications.</li>
<li>The article does not discuss the potential limitations or drawbacks of the LTU approach, such as the computational resources required for training large language models or the potential for overfitting.</li>
<li>The article does not provide a clear definition of what constitutes a “foundational decision-making model” or how it differs from other types of decision-making models.</li>
<li>The article does not discuss the potential ethical implications of using large language models for decision-making, such as the risk of bias or the need for transparency and accountability.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-13</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06087v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06087v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06087v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06087v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5229</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Building_Decision_Making_Models_Through_Language_Model_Regime/2024-08-12-Building_Decision_Making_Models_Through_Language_Model_Regime.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>TRIZ-GPT: An LLM-augmented method for problem-solving</title>
  <dc:creator>Liuqing Chen, Yaxuan Song, Shixian Ding, Lingyun Sun, Peter Childs, Haoyu Zuo</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/TRIZ_GPT_An_LLM_augmented_method_for_problem_solving/2024-08-12-TRIZ_GPT_An_LLM_augmented_method_for_problem_solving.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/TRIZ_GPT_An_LLM_augmented_method_for_problem_solving/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.05897v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary:</strong></p>
<p>The study explores the application of Large Language Models (LLMs) within the TRIZ-based problem-solving process. The authors construct TRIZ case collections and design a workflow that utilizes step-by-step reasoning and evaluation-validated prompt strategies to transform concrete problems into TRIZ problems and generate inventive solutions. The main contributions of the research include the development of TRIZ case collections, workflow design, and evaluations and case studies.</p>
<p><strong>Major Findings:</strong></p>
<ol type="1">
<li>The authors developed two TRIZ case collections: Collection A, which includes 37 classic TRIZ examples, and Collection B, which includes 10 cases published after April 2023.</li>
<li>A workflow was designed based on the fundamental approach of TRIZ for problem-solving, utilizing verified prompt strategies for critical stages of contradiction analysis and solution reasoning.</li>
<li>Evaluations and case studies were conducted to assess the TRIZ contradiction analysis and solution reasoning capabilities and determine the most applicable strategy. A comparative analysis of the performances of GPT-4 and GPT-3.5 during the contradiction analysis stage was also performed.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></p>
<p>The study presents a novel approach to addressing the challenges associated with the acquisition and application of TRIZ knowledge by leveraging the extensive knowledge bases and reasoning capabilities of LLMs. The use of TRIZ case collections and a specifically designed workflow allows for the transformation of concrete problems into TRIZ problems and the generation of inventive solutions. However, the study does not address potential limitations, unanswered questions, or biases that may have arisen during the research process. Additionally, the methodological issues, conflicting evidence, or areas that require further research or clarification are not discussed. The study could benefit from a more comprehensive analysis of the potential problems and shortcomings of the proposed approach.</p>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-13</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05897v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05897v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.05897v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.05897v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>9497</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/TRIZ_GPT_An_LLM_augmented_method_for_problem_solving/2024-08-12-TRIZ_GPT_An_LLM_augmented_method_for_problem_solving.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.05897v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Med42-v2: A Suite of Clinical LLMs</title>
  <dc:creator>Clément Christophe, Praveen K Kanithi, Tathagata Raha, Shadab Khan, Marco AF Pimentel</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Med42_v2_A_Suite_of_Clinical_LLMs/2024-08-12-Med42_v2_A_Suite_of_Clinical_LLMs.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/../bayesian-beagle.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>Med42-v2 is a suite of clinical large language models (LLMs) designed to overcome the limitations of generic models in healthcare settings. Built on the Llama3 architecture and fine-tuned with specialized clinical data, Med42-v2 models undergo multi-stage preference alignment to effectively respond to natural prompts. Unlike generic models, which are often preference-aligned to avoid answering clinical queries, Med42-v2 is specifically trained to engage with clinical queries. Med42-v2 demonstrates superior performance compared to the original Llama3 models in both 8B and 70B parameter configurations across various medical benchmarks.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Med42-v2 is a suite of clinical LLMs built on Llama3 architecture, fine-tuned with specialized medical instruction data.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Med42-v2 undergoes a multi-stage preference alignment process to enhance its ability to meet user expectations in healthcare settings.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Empirical evidence demonstrates Med42-v2’s superior performance over original Llama3 models in both 8B and 70B parameter configurations across various medical benchmarks.</strong></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Despite improvements, Med42-v2 may not entirely be free from issues like hallucinations, biases, and ethical concerns, which are particularly critical in the medical field.</li>
<li>The reliance on high-quality, domain-specific data means that any gaps or biases in the training data could impact the model’s effectiveness.</li>
<li>The future work involves developing a new evaluation framework to assess the clinical utility of LLMs by testing them on real-world use cases. This framework will focus on evaluating clinical data understanding, safety, and reasoning capabilities, providing a more comprehensive understanding of how these models perform in practical, high-stakes environments.</li>
<li>By rigorously testing LLMs in real-world scenarios, potential risks can be identified and mitigated, ensuring that models like Med42-v2 can be safely and effectively integrated into healthcare settings.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-13</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06142v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06142v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06142v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06142v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>2686</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Med42_v2_A_Suite_of_Clinical_LLMs/2024-08-12-Med42_v2_A_Suite_of_Clinical_LLMs.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Review-driven Personalized Preference Reasoning with Large Language Models for Recommendation</title>
  <dc:creator>Jieyong Kim, Hyunseo Kim, Hyunjin Cho, SeongKu Kang, Buru Chang, Jinyoung Yeo, Dongha Lee</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Review_driven_Personalized_Preference_Reasoning_with_Large_Language_Models_for_Recommendation/2024-08-12-Review_driven_Personalized_Preference_Reasoning_with_Large_Language_Models_for_Recommendation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Review_driven_Personalized_Preference_Reasoning_with_Large_Language_Models_for_Recommendation/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06276v1/extracted/5786810/FIG/intro.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper introduces Exp3rt, a novel LLM-based recommender designed to leverage rich preference information from user and item reviews for personalized preference reasoning. Exp3rt is fine-tuned through distillation from a teacher LLM to perform three key tasks: extracting and encapsulating essential subjective preferences from raw reviews, aggregating and summarizing them into user and item profiles, and generating detailed step-by-step reasoning followed by predicted rating. The proposed method aims to enhance rating prediction accuracy and provide faithful and reasonable explanations for recommendations.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Exp3rt effectively enhances rating prediction accuracy through review-driven personalized reasoning.</li>
<li>Exp3rt generates detailed step-by-step reasoning, providing faithful and logical explanations by utilizing rich preference information extracted from reviews.</li>
<li>Exp3rt can function independently as a recommender and seamlessly integrate with traditional CF-based recommenders as an item reranker within a multi-stage ranking pipeline.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>While Exp3rt shows promising results in enhancing rating prediction accuracy and explainability, there are some potential limitations and areas for improvement.</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>Dependence on review data: The performance of Exp3rt relies heavily on the availability and quality of review data. In cases where reviews are scarce or not representative of user preferences, the model’s performance may be compromised.</li>
<li>Computational cost: The use of LLMs for recommendation tasks can be computationally expensive, especially when dealing with large-scale datasets. This could limit the scalability of Exp3rt in real-world applications.</li>
<li>Generalizability: The proposed method has only been evaluated on two datasets, and its performance on other datasets or domains remains to be tested. Further experiments are needed to assess the generalizability of Exp3rt.</li>
<li>Potential biases: The use of review data for preference profiling may introduce biases, as reviews can be influenced by various factors such as user mood, context, or social desirability. These biases could affect the accuracy and fairness of the recommendations generated by Exp3rt.</li>
</ol>
<p>In conclusion, Exp3rt presents a novel approach to leveraging LLMs for recommendation tasks by focusing on personalized preference reasoning. While the proposed method shows promising results, further research</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-13</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06276v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06276v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06276v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06276v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>9253</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>recommender</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Review_driven_Personalized_Preference_Reasoning_with_Large_Language_Models_for_Recommendation/2024-08-12-Review_driven_Personalized_Preference_Reasoning_with_Large_Language_Models_for_Recommendation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06276v1/extracted/5786810/FIG/intro.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Mutual Reasoning Makes Smaller LLMs Stronger Problem-Solvers</title>
  <dc:creator>Zhenting Qi, Mingyuan Ma, Jiahang Xu, Li Lyna Zhang, Fan Yang, Mao Yang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Mutual_Reasoning_Makes_Smaller_LLMs_Stronger_Problem_Solvers/2024-08-12-Mutual_Reasoning_Makes_Smaller_LLMs_Stronger_Problem_Solvers.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Mutual_Reasoning_Makes_Smaller_LLMs_Stronger_Problem_Solvers/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06195v1/extracted/5786663/teaser.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level1">
<h1>Summary:</h1>
<p>The paper introduces rStar, a self-play mutual reasoning approach that significantly improves the reasoning capabilities of small language models (SLMs) without fine-tuning or superior models. rStar decouples reasoning into a self-play mutual generation-discrimination process. A target SLM augments the Monte Carlo Tree Search (MCTS) with a rich set of human-like reasoning actions to construct higher quality reasoning trajectories. Another SLM, with similar capabilities, acts as a discriminator to verify each trajectory generated by the target SLM. The mutually agreed reasoning trajectories are considered mutual consistent, thus more likely to be correct. Extensive experiments across five SLMs demonstrate rStar can effectively solve diverse reasoning problems, including GSM8K, GSM-Hard, MATH, SVAMP, and StrategyQA.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level1">
<h1>Major Findings:</h1>
<ol type="1">
<li>rStar boosts GSM8K accuracy from 12.51% to 63.91% for LLaMA2-7B, from 36.46% to 81.88% for Mistral-7B, and from 74.53% to 91.13% for LLaMA3-8B-Instruct.</li>
<li>rStar significantly enhances SLMs’ reasoning capabilities, matching or even surpassing the accuracy achieved after fine-tuning.</li>
<li>rStar outperforms state-of-the-art baselines, including single-round inference techniques like few-shot CoT, multi-round prompting approaches such as self-consistency, and self-improvement techniques such as RAP, ToT, self-evaluation and self-verification.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level1">
<h1>Analysis and Critique:</h1>
<ul>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential limitations or biases of the rStar approach.</li>
<li>The paper does not provide a detailed comparison with other self-improvement techniques for SLMs.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential impact of the rStar approach on the generalization capabilities of SLMs.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential impact of the rStar approach on the interpretability of SLMs.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential impact of the rStar approach on the fairness and robustness of SLMs.</li>
</ul>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-13</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06195v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06195v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06195v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06195v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7311</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Mutual_Reasoning_Makes_Smaller_LLMs_Stronger_Problem_Solvers/2024-08-12-Mutual_Reasoning_Makes_Smaller_LLMs_Stronger_Problem_Solvers.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06195v1/extracted/5786663/teaser.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Anchored Preference Optimization and Contrastive Revisions: Addressing Underspecification in Alignment</title>
  <dc:creator>Karel D&#39;Oosterlinck, Winnie Xu, Chris Develder, Thomas Demeester, Amanpreet Singh, Christopher Potts, Douwe Kiela, Shikib Mehri</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Anchored_Preference_Optimization_and_Contrastive_Revisions_Addressing_Underspecification_in_Alignment/2024-08-12-Anchored_Preference_Optimization_and_Contrastive_Revisions_Addressing_Underspecification_in_Alignment.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Anchored_Preference_Optimization_and_Contrastive_Revisions_Addressing_Underspecification_in_Alignment/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06266v1/extracted/5787579/figures/underspecifiedv3-6.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level1">
<h1>Summary</h1>
<p>The paper introduces two new methods to improve the alignment of large language models (LLMs) with human preferences: Contrastive Learning from AI Revisions (CLAIR) and Anchored Preference Optimization (APO). CLAIR is a data-creation method that generates more contrastive preference pairs, while APO is a family of alignment objectives with tailored training dynamics. The authors align Llama-3-8B-Instruct using various datasets and alignment objectives and measure MixEval-Hard scores, which correlate highly with human judgments. The results show that CLAIR preferences lead to the strongest performance, and APO consistently outperforms less controllable objectives. The best model, trained on 32K CLAIR preferences with APO, improves Llama-3-8B-Instruct by 7.65%, closing the gap with GPT-4-turbo by 45%.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li>The CLAIR preferences lead to the strongest performance out of all datasets, improving Llama-3-8B-Instruct by 7.65% and closing the gap with GPT-4-turbo by 45%.</li>
<li>APO consistently outperforms less controllable objectives, with the best model trained on 32K CLAIR preferences with APO.</li>
<li>The contrastiveness of CLAIR preferences is the major driver of performance.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper does not provide a detailed comparison with other alignment methods, such as Reinforcement Learning from Human or AI Feedback (RLHF/RLAIF).</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential limitations of CLAIR and APO, such as the need for a strong LLM to perform revisions or the potential for overfitting to the preference dataset.</li>
<li>The paper does not provide a clear explanation of how the APO objectives are selected for a given target model and preference dataset.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential impact of the choice of the target model on the alignment results.</li>
<li>The paper does not provide a detailed analysis of the impact of the size of the preference dataset on the alignment results.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential impact of the choice</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-13</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06266v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06266v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06266v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06266v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7233</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Anchored_Preference_Optimization_and_Contrastive_Revisions_Addressing_Underspecification_in_Alignment/2024-08-12-Anchored_Preference_Optimization_and_Contrastive_Revisions_Addressing_Underspecification_in_Alignment.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06266v1/extracted/5787579/figures/underspecifiedv3-6.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>FuxiTranyu: A Multilingual Large Language Model Trained with Balanced Data</title>
  <dc:creator>Haoran Sun, Renren Jin, Shaoyang Xu, Leiyu Pan, Supryadi, Menglong Cui, Jiangcun Dui, Yikun Lei, Lei Yang, Ling Shi, Juesi Xiao, Shaolin Zhu, Deyi Xiong</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/FuxiTranyu_A_Multilingual_Large_Language_Model_Trained_with_Balanced_Data/2024-08-12-FuxiTranyu_A_Multilingual_Large_Language_Model_Trained_with_Balanced_Data.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/FuxiTranyu_A_Multilingual_Large_Language_Model_Trained_with_Balanced_Data/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06273v1/extracted/5787567/content/fig/distribution.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>FuxiTranyu is a multilingual large language model with 8 billion parameters, trained from scratch on a balanced multilingual dataset covering 43 natural languages and 16 programming languages. The model aims to address the need for balanced and high-performing multilingual capabilities in the research community. In addition to the base model, two instruction-tuned models are developed: FuxiTranyu-8B-SFT and FuxiTranyu-8B-DPO. Extensive experiments demonstrate the competitive performance of FuxiTranyu against existing multilingual LLMs. Interpretability analyses suggest that FuxiTranyu is able to learn consistent multilingual representations across different languages.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>FuxiTranyu is a multilingual large language model with 8 billion parameters, trained from scratch on a balanced multilingual dataset covering 43 natural languages and 16 programming languages.</li>
<li>Two instruction-tuned models are developed: FuxiTranyu-8B-SFT and FuxiTranyu-8B-DPO.</li>
<li>Extensive experiments demonstrate the competitive performance of FuxiTranyu against existing multilingual LLMs.</li>
<li>Interpretability analyses suggest that FuxiTranyu is able to learn consistent multilingual representations across different languages.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper does not provide a detailed comparison of FuxiTranyu with other multilingual LLMs in terms of performance on specific tasks or benchmarks.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential limitations or biases of the model, such as the quality and diversity of the pre-training data or the impact of the model’s size on its performance.</li>
<li>The paper does not provide a detailed analysis of the model’s performance on low-resource languages or its ability to handle code-switching or other linguistic phenomena.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential applications or use cases of the model, such as its potential impact on natural language processing research or its potential for commercial or industrial use.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-13</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06273v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06273v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06273v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06273v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>9897</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/FuxiTranyu_A_Multilingual_Large_Language_Model_Trained_with_Balanced_Data/2024-08-12-FuxiTranyu_A_Multilingual_Large_Language_Model_Trained_with_Balanced_Data.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06273v1/extracted/5787567/content/fig/distribution.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>On Effects of Steering Latent Representation for Large Language Model Unlearning</title>
  <dc:creator>Dang Huu-Tien, Trung-Tin Pham, Hoang Thanh-Tung, Naoya Inoue</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/On_Effects_of_Steering_Latent_Representation_for_Large_Language_Model_Unlearning/2024-08-12-On_Effects_of_Steering_Latent_Representation_for_Large_Language_Model_Unlearning.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/On_Effects_of_Steering_Latent_Representation_for_Large_Language_Model_Unlearning/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06223v1/extracted/5787475/images/noise_sensitivity.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary:</strong></p>
<p>This paper explores the effectiveness of Representation Misdirection for Unlearning (RMU) in large language models (LLMs). RMU steers the model’s representation in the intermediate layer to a target random representation, which reduces token confidence and causes LLMs to generate incorrect or nonsensical responses. The authors investigate the influence of the coefficient on the alignment of forget-sample representations with the random direction and suggest optimal coefficient values for effective unlearning across different network layers. They also demonstrate that RMU unlearned models are robust against adversarial jailbreak attacks. However, RMU is less effective when applied to the middle and later layers in LLMs. To address this limitation, the authors propose Adaptive RMU, a simple yet effective alternative method that makes unlearning effective with most layers.</p>
<p><strong>Major Findings:</strong></p>
<ol type="1">
<li>RMU effectively degrades models’ accuracy on forget-tasks while only slightly affecting the performance on retain-tasks and demonstrates stronger robustness against adversarial jailbreak attacks.</li>
<li>The coefficient influences the alignment of forget-sample representations with the random direction, and the authors hint at the optimal coefficient values for effective unlearning across different network layers.</li>
<li>RMU is less effective when applied to the middle and later layers in LLMs, but Adaptive RMU, a variant that adaptively adjusts the coefficient value based on the norm of the forget representation, achieves higher drop-in-accuracy for forget knowledge, maintains high performance on general knowledge, and enables effective unlearning for most layers without incurring additional computational overhead.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></p>
<p>The paper provides a comprehensive analysis of RMU and its effectiveness in LLM unlearning. The authors’ theoretical and empirical findings contribute to a better understanding of the underlying causes and explanations for RMU’s performance. However, the paper does not discuss potential limitations or unanswered questions, such as the generalizability of the findings to other types of LLMs or the impact of different types of forget-tasks on the unlearning process. Additionally, the paper does not address potential biases or conflicting evidence that may arise in the unlearning process. Further research is needed to address these issues and provide a more complete picture of RMU’s effectiveness in LLM unlearning.</p>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-13</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06223v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06223v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06223v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06223v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7618</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/On_Effects_of_Steering_Latent_Representation_for_Large_Language_Model_Unlearning/2024-08-12-On_Effects_of_Steering_Latent_Representation_for_Large_Language_Model_Unlearning.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06223v1/extracted/5787475/images/noise_sensitivity.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Synthetic Patient-Physician Dialogue Generation from Clinical Notes Using LLM</title>
  <dc:creator>Trisha Das, Dina Albassam, Jimeng Sun</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Synthetic_Patient_Physician_Dialogue_Generation_from_Clinical_Notes_Using_LLM/2024-08-12-Synthetic_Patient_Physician_Dialogue_Generation_from_Clinical_Notes_Using_LLM.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Synthetic_Patient_Physician_Dialogue_Generation_from_Clinical_Notes_Using_LLM/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06285v1/extracted/5787210/images/pipeline.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level1">
<h1>Summary:</h1>
<p><strong>Summary:</strong></p>
<p>The article introduces SynDial, a novel approach for generating synthetic patient-physician dialogues from clinical notes using a single large language model (LLM) with a feedback loop mechanism. The method addresses data scarcity and privacy issues in training medical dialogue systems by leveraging publicly available clinical notes datasets such as MIMIC-IV and MTS-Dialogue. SynDial significantly outperforms existing baseline models in terms of extractiveness and factuality, making it a valuable tool for creating high-quality synthetic dialogue datasets.</p>
<p><strong>Major Findings:</strong></p>
<ol type="1">
<li>SynDial is a cost-effective approach compared to the state-of-the-art models like NoteChat, which rely on multiple LLM instances.</li>
<li>The method provides consistent results across multiple runs, ensuring robustness in the generated dialogues.</li>
<li>SynDial significantly outperforms existing baseline models in terms of extractiveness and factuality.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></p>
<p>The article presents a promising solution for advancing medical dialogue systems while maintaining patient privacy and reducing the dependency on real-world data. However, the initial phase of the research utilized only 80 samples from the MIMIC IV dataset, and the hypothesis that patient history significantly aids in generating dialogues for current visits was refuted by experimental results. Future work should focus on scaling up the dataset size and incorporating more advanced feedback mechanisms to further enhance the quality of the generated dialogues. Additionally, the impact of integrating synthetic dialogues from multiple sources to improve the performance of downstream tasks, such as the Conversation2Note task, should be explored.</p>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-13</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06285v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06285v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06285v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06285v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>3867</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Synthetic_Patient_Physician_Dialogue_Generation_from_Clinical_Notes_Using_LLM/2024-08-12-Synthetic_Patient_Physician_Dialogue_Generation_from_Clinical_Notes_Using_LLM.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.06285v1/extracted/5787210/images/pipeline.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
