<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Bayesian beagle</title>
<link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Quarto blog of LLM-generated summaries of Arxiv preprints</description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.450</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Stability Analysis of ChatGPT-based Sentiment Analysis in AI Quality Assurance</title>
  <dc:creator>Tinghui Ouyang, AprilPyone MaungMaung, Koichi Konishi, Yoshiki Seo, Isao Echizen</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Stability_Analysis_of_ChatGPT_based_Sentiment_Analysis_in_AI_Quality_Assurance/2024-01-15-Stability_Analysis_of_ChatGPT_based_Sentiment_Analysis_in_AI_Quality_Assurance.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Stability_Analysis_of_ChatGPT_based_Sentiment_Analysis_in_AI_Quality_Assurance/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.07441v1/extracted/5347321/fig11.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong></p>
<p>The paper delves into the quality assurance of a large language model (LLM) – specifically, a ChatGPT-based sentiment analysis system. It discusses the challenges posed by the complex architecture and vast parameters of LLM-based AI products, such as ChatGPT, and emphasizes the importance of AI quality management (AIQM) in ensuring the reliability and effectiveness of such products. The study comprises stability and robustness analyses, focusing on the uncertainty and operational factors, as well as the robustness of the ChatGPT-based sentiment analysis system against four types of perturbations. Experimental analysis using benchmark sentiment analysis datasets reveals uncertainty in the operation of ChatGPT and demonstrates its stability issues in handling conventional attacks.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><p><strong>Uncertainty in Operation:</strong> The study identifies uncertainty issues in the running of ChatGPT, attributed to factors such as non-deterministic responses, differences between using ChatGPT on the web and using the ChatGPT API, variance due to timing, and prompt engineering. These operational factors contribute to the instability of the system.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Robustness Analysis:</strong> The paper evaluates the robustness of the ChatGPT-based sentiment analysis system against four types of perturbations – typo, synonym, homoglyph, and homophone. The results demonstrate the system’s relatively good robustness against these perturbations, with synonym perturbation posing the strongest attack.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Quality Assurance Conclusions:</strong> The study concludes that the ChatGPT-based sentiment analysis system is robust against adversarial text perturbations, albeit exhibiting uncertainty due to continuous updates, timing differences, and other operational factors.</p></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article provides valuable insights into the stability and robustness of the ChatGPT-based sentiment analysis system. However, it focuses primarily on specific operational and robustness issues without deeply exploring potential solutions or mitigation strategies for the identified problems. Furthermore, while the study offers essential findings for AI quality management, it could benefit from discussing the broader implications of these stability and robustness issues for AI-based products and potential strategies to address them. Additionally, the limitations of the study, such as the specific focus on the ChatGPT-based sentiment analysis system and the need for broader applicability, require further consideration. While the study raises critical points relevant to AIQM, it would benefit from addressing these potential shortcomings and providing a more comprehensive outlook on the topic.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-17</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.07441v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.07441v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.07441v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.07441v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7475</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Stability_Analysis_of_ChatGPT_based_Sentiment_Analysis_in_AI_Quality_Assurance/2024-01-15-Stability_Analysis_of_ChatGPT_based_Sentiment_Analysis_in_AI_Quality_Assurance.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.07441v1/extracted/5347321/fig11.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Active Learning for NLP with Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Xuesong Wang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Active_Learning_for_NLP_with_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-14-Active_Learning_for_NLP_with_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Active_Learning_for_NLP_with_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.07367v1/extracted/5347142/cost_by_gpt_3.5.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-the-article" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-of-the-article">Summary of the Article:</h3>
<p>The article explores the use of Large Language Models (LLMs) for annotating samples in Active Learning (AL) to reduce labeling costs and enhance sample efficiency, particularly for Natural Language Processing (NLP) tasks. The study investigates the accuracy and cost of using LLMs, specifically GPT-3.5 and GPT-4, to label samples on different datasets. A mixed annotation strategy is proposed, combining LLM and human annotations, and its performance under various AL settings is evaluated. The results suggest that using LLMs as annotators in AL settings can be cost-efficient while maintaining high accuracy levels, showing potential for reducing annotation costs.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs, particularly GPT-3.5 and GPT-4, demonstrate cost efficiency and reasonable accuracy when used for annotating samples in AL, offering potential for reducing labeling costs.</li>
<li>A mixed annotation strategy, combining LLM and human annotations, yields similar or better results compared to using human annotations only, particularly on tasks such as news topic and movie review classifications.</li>
<li>The proposed consistency-based label fixing strategy shows potential for improving the accuracy of AL models by utilizing LLM annotations and correcting incorrectly labeled samples with human annotations.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article provides valuable insights into the potential of LLMs for annotating samples in AL, offering cost efficiency and maintaining accuracy. However, there are some limitations and potential areas for further investigation: - It’s important to acknowledge that the study is based on a limited number of experiments and runs, potentially requiring further validation and replication to ensure the generalizability of the findings. - The potential biases or limitations associated with using GPT-3.5 and GPT-4, such as their performance on new datasets and their behavior on specific tasks like question classification, deserve further investigation to ensure the robustness of the proposed approach. - The article does not address the ethical implications of relying on LLMs for annotation, including concerns related to bias, fairness, and transparency in the labeling process. Further research should consider addressing these ethical considerations when implementing LLMs in AL settings.</p>
<p>Overall, while the article presents promising findings regarding the use of LLMs in AL for NLP tasks, further research and comprehensive validation are necessary to fully assess the effectiveness and potential limitations of this approach.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-17</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.07367v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.07367v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.07367v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.07367v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>4673</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Active_Learning_for_NLP_with_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-14-Active_Learning_for_NLP_with_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.07367v1/extracted/5347142/cost_by_gpt_3.5.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>PersonalityChat: Conversation Distillation for Personalized Dialog Modeling with Facts and Traits</title>
  <dc:creator>Ehsan Lotfi, Maxime De Bruyn, Jeska Buhmann, Walter Daelemans</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/PersonalityChat_Conversation_Distillation_for_Personalized_Dialog_Modeling_with_Facts_and_Traits/2024-01-14-PersonalityChat_Conversation_Distillation_for_Personalized_Dialog_Modeling_with_Facts_and_Traits.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/PersonalityChat_Conversation_Distillation_for_Personalized_Dialog_Modeling_with_Facts_and_Traits/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.07363v1/extracted/5347114/imgs/personalitychat-pipe.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary of the Article:</strong> The article explores the use of Large Language Models (LLMs) to create a synthetic conversational dataset, PersonalityChat, personalized with both personas and Big-5 personality traits. The paper highlights the potential of LLMs in refining conversation datasets for personalized dialog models, demonstrating that personality traits can be utilized for personalized dialog modeling. Furthermore, the study compares the performance of models trained on the distilled PersonalityChat dataset with those trained on the crowd-sourced PersonaChat dataset, showing improved fluency and coherence in the small-model regime.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Creation of PersonalityChat Dataset:</strong>
<ul>
<li>PersonalityChat is a synthetic conversational dataset based on the popular PersonaChat dataset, conditioned on both personas and Big-5 personality traits.</li>
<li>The use of LLMs to predict personality traits for personas enables the curation of a dataset explicitly grounded in personality characteristics.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Trait-Based Personalization:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The study demonstrates that personality trait labels can influence and modify the ‘attitude’ of a dialog agent, showing the potential for trait-based personalization of generative dialogue models.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Performance Comparison:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Training on the distilled PersonalityChat dataset results in more fluent and coherent dialog agents in the small-model regime compared to training on the crowd-sourced PersonaChat dataset.</li>
</ul></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article effectively demonstrates the value of using LLMs to create a personalized conversational dataset and highlights the potential for utilizing personality traits in dialog modeling, offering insights into improving the performance of dialogue agents. However, some limitations should be considered, such as: 1. <strong>Biases and Limitations in Data Curation:</strong> The use of LLMs for dataset curation introduces potential biases, leading to less diverse and more predictable language distribution, which could affect the quality and diversity of the generated conversations. 2. <strong>Model Behavior and Trait Incorporation:</strong> The article acknowledges that while the models’ behavior can be influenced by trait labels, there is still room for improvement in incorporating traits into the generated dialogs, suggesting a need for further research and refinement. 3. <strong>Evaluation Limitations:</strong> The evaluation process, mainly relying on automatic metrics and single-trait labels, may not fully capture the models’ real-world conversational behavior and their responses to multiple trait labels.</p>
<p>In conclusion, while the article presents valuable findings, the study acknowledges certain shortcomings and areas for further development, including addressing biases in dataset curation and improving the incorporation of personality traits into the dialog agents’ responses. Future research could focus on refining dialog modeling techniques and enhancing the naturalness and coherence of personalized dialogue generation.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-17</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.07363v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.07363v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.07363v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.07363v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7867</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/PersonalityChat_Conversation_Distillation_for_Personalized_Dialog_Modeling_with_Facts_and_Traits/2024-01-14-PersonalityChat_Conversation_Distillation_for_Personalized_Dialog_Modeling_with_Facts_and_Traits.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.07363v1/extracted/5347114/imgs/personalitychat-pipe.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Towards Conversational Diagnostic AI</title>
  <dc:creator>Tao Tu, Anil Palepu, Mike Schaekermann, Khaled Saab, Jan Freyberg, Ryutaro Tanno, Amy Wang, Brenna Li, Mohamed Amin, Nenad Tomasev, Shekoofeh Azizi, Karan Singhal, Yong Cheng, Le Hou, Albert Webson, Kavita Kulkarni, S Sara Mahdavi, Christopher Semturs, Juraj Gottweis, Joelle Barral, Katherine Chou, Greg S Corrado, Yossi Matias, Alan Karthikesalingam, Vivek Natarajan</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Towards_Conversational_Diagnostic_AI/2024-01-11-Towards_Conversational_Diagnostic_AI.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Towards_Conversational_Diagnostic_AI/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05654v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary</h3>
<p>In the paper “Towards Conversational Diagnostic AI,” the authors introduce AMIE, an AI system optimized for diagnostic dialogue. They compare AMIE’s performance to that of primary care physicians (PCPs) in a study of text-based consultations with simulated patient actors. The study finds that AMIE demonstrated greater diagnostic accuracy and superior performance on several axes according to specialist physicians and patient actors. The evaluation framework encompasses history-taking, diagnostic accuracy, management reasoning, communication skills, and empathy. Additionally, the authors detail the datasets used to develop AMIE, including medical reasoning, long-form medical question answering, medical summarization, and real-world dialogue datasets. They describe a simulated learning environment for diagnostic dialogues, a self-play framework for iterative improvement, instruction fine-tuning, and a chain-of-reasoning strategy for online inference.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The AI system, AMIE, showed greater <strong>diagnostic accuracy</strong> and <strong>superior performance</strong> in multiple axes compared to primary care physicians in simulated text-based consultations.</li>
<li>AMIE was able to achieve higher conversation quality by surpassing PCPs in patient actor and specialist physician evaluations for various axes, including communication skills and empathy.</li>
<li>The study introduced a novel self-play environment for learning, and a chain-of-reasoning strategy for online inference, which significantly contributed to AMIE’s performance and capabilities.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="methods-and-results" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="methods-and-results">Methods and Results</h3>
<section id="amie-an-llm-based-ai-system-for-diagnostic-dialogue" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="amie-an-llm-based-ai-system-for-diagnostic-dialogue">AMIE: An LLM based AI System for Diagnostic Dialogue</h4>
<ul>
<li>The authors used diverse real-world datasets for training AMIE, including medical reasoning, long-form medical question answering, medical summarization, and real-world dialogue datasets.</li>
<li>They developed a simulated dialogue learning environment with a self-play framework for iterative improvement, an instruction fine-tuning process, and a chain-of-reasoning strategy for online inference.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="objective-structured-clinical-examination" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="objective-structured-clinical-examination">Objective Structured Clinical Examination</h4>
<ul>
<li>The study involved 20 PCPs and 20 validated patient actors in a randomized, double-blind crossover study with 149 case scenarios.</li>
<li>AMIE’s consultations outperformed PCPs in terms of <strong>conversation quality</strong> across multiple axes, as assessed by both patient actors and specialist physicians.</li>
</ul>
</section>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<p>The study has several limitations, including the use of a text-chat interface, which may not be representative of usual clinical consultation settings. The simulated patient actors may not fully reflect the complexity and nuances of real patients, and the study design may not fully capture the challenges of real-world clinical dialogue. Future research should aim to address these limitations and further validate AMIE’s performance in real-world clinical practice.</p>
<p>Overall, the paper contributes to the development of conversational diagnostic AI systems and highlights the potential of AI in improving the quality and accuracy of medical consultations. However, it is important to consider the limitations and contextual factors related to the study design and evaluation. More research is needed to translate AMIE to real-world clinical settings and to validate its performance in diverse healthcare contexts.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-12</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05654v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05654v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05654v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05654v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>18673</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Towards_Conversational_Diagnostic_AI/2024-01-11-Towards_Conversational_Diagnostic_AI.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05654v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Mutation-based Consistency Testing for Evaluating the Code Understanding Capability of LLMs</title>
  <dc:creator>Ziyu Li, Donghwan Shin</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Mutation_based_Consistency_Testing_for_Evaluating_the_Code_Understanding_Capability_of_LLMs/2024-01-11-Mutation_based_Consistency_Testing_for_Evaluating_the_Code_Understanding_Capability_of_LLMs.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Mutation_based_Consistency_Testing_for_Evaluating_the_Code_Understanding_Capability_of_LLMs/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05940v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-mutation-based-consistency-testing-for-evaluating-the-code-understanding-capability-of-llms" class="level1">
<h1>Summary of “Mutation-based Consistency Testing for Evaluating the Code Understanding Capability of LLMs”</h1>
<section id="overall-findings" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="overall-findings">Overall Findings</h2>
<ul>
<li>The study proposed a novel method called <em>Mutation-based Consistency Testing (MCT)</em> to evaluate the code understanding performance of Large Language Models (LLMs) by introducing code <em>mutations</em> to create mismatches between code and its natural language descriptions.</li>
<li>The study conducted a case study on popular LLMs, GPT-3.5 and GPT-4, using the HumanEval-X benchmark and found significant variation in their code understanding performance, with the models showing different strengths and weaknesses depending on the mutation type and programming language.</li>
<li>The results demonstrated the importance of prompt engineering, with one-shot prompts significantly improving the performance of LLMs in identifying subtle inconsistencies between code and its descriptions.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">1. Introduction</h2>
<ul>
<li>Large Language Models (LLMs) have gained attention in software engineering, yet existing benchmarks do not thoroughly assess the code understanding performance of LLMs, especially for subtle inconsistencies between code and its natural language descriptions.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="background" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="background">2. Background</h2>
<ul>
<li>Large Language Models (LLMs) are advanced Deep Learning systems that comprehend natural and programming languages. They have been used in various software engineering applications.</li>
<li>Existing benchmarks such as HumanEval-X assess the code generation ability of LLMs, but do not focus on code understanding, syntax, and semantics.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="approach" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="approach">3. Approach</h2>
<ul>
<li>The study proposed <em>Mutation-based Consistency Testing (MCT)</em> to assess the code understanding capability of LLMs using code mutations to create inconsistencies between code and its descriptions.</li>
<li>Details on prompt engineering and mutant generation were provided.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="case-study-design" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="case-study-design">4. Case Study Design</h2>
<ul>
<li>The case study aimed to evaluate the ability of different LLMs to detect inconsistencies between code and its descriptions, assess their performance across different programming languages, and investigate the impact of one-shot prompt engineering on their performance.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="case-study-results" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="case-study-results">5. Case Study Results</h2>
<ul>
<li>Findings included the impact of mutation operators and programming languages on LLM performance, the explanation of test results, and the impact of prompt engineering.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="threats-to-validity" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="threats-to-validity">5.5. Threats to Validity</h2>
<ul>
<li>Potential threats to validity included implementation bugs and the impact of input understanding on model performance.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="data-availability" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="data-availability">6. Data Availability</h2>
<ul>
<li>The replication package, including the MCT method implementation and execution results, is available for public access.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="related-work" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="related-work">7. Related Work</h2>
<ul>
<li>The study highlighted the existing literature on LLM testing, focusing on code generation and code understanding.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="conclusion" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="conclusion">8. Conclusion</h2>
<ul>
<li>The study concluded that MCT can effectively assess the code understanding capability of LLMs and offered suggestions for future research in this area.</li>
</ul>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper provides a comprehensive exploration of MCT for evaluating LLMs, but potential limitations include the small scale of the case study and reliance on GPT-3.5 and GPT-4, which may not fully represent all LLMs.</li>
</ul>
<p>The paper provides valuable insights into evaluating LLMs’ code understanding capability and introduces a novel method, MCT, to assess LLM performance in identifying subtle code inconsistencies. The findings have implications for future research and development of LLM-based software engineering, with potential for further exploration and refinement of the MCT approach.</p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-12</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05940v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05940v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05940v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05940v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>11106</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Mutation_based_Consistency_Testing_for_Evaluating_the_Code_Understanding_Capability_of_LLMs/2024-01-11-Mutation_based_Consistency_Testing_for_Evaluating_the_Code_Understanding_Capability_of_LLMs.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05940v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>CAT-LLM: Prompting Large Language Models with Text Style Definition for Chinese Article-style Transfer</title>
  <dc:creator>Zhen Tao, Dinghao Xi, Zhiyu Li, Liumin Tang, Wei Xu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/CAT_LLM_Prompting_Large_Language_Models_with_Text_Style_Definition_for_Chinese_Article_style_Transfer/2024-01-11-CAT_LLM_Prompting_Large_Language_Models_with_Text_Style_Definition_for_Chinese_Article_style_Transfer.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/CAT_LLM_Prompting_Large_Language_Models_with_Text_Style_Definition_for_Chinese_Article_style_Transfer/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05707v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><p><strong>Text Style Transfer</strong> plays a crucial role in NLP, but existing models are limited in their applicability to <strong>Chinese</strong> long texts, where LLMs have been shown to be effective in handling more complex NLP tasks.</p></li>
<li><p>The proposed Chinese Article-style Transfer framework (<strong>CAT-LLM</strong>) outperforms current research in terms of <strong>transfer accuracy</strong> and <strong>content preservation</strong>. CAT-LLM leverages a Text Style Definition (TSD) module to comprehensively analyze text features at both <strong>words and sentences levels</strong> and supports dynamic expansion of internal style trees.</p></li>
<li><p>Five Chinese articles with distinct styles were used to create parallel datasets using ChatGPT, <em>enhancing</em> the models’ performance evaluation accuracy and establishing a novel paradigm for evaluating subsequent research on article-style transfer.</p></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="methodology" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="methodology">Methodology</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Task Definition and The Whole Framework</strong>
<ul>
<li>The CAT-LLM framework is divided into five stages, including the usage of <strong>ChatGPT</strong> to transform <strong>style definition</strong> into stylishless text.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Text Style Definition Module</strong>
<ul>
<li>The TSD module computes the style of the style definition part from both words and sentences levels and provides precise style definitions.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Style-enhanced Prompt</strong>
<ul>
<li>A style-enhanced prompt is designed leveraging the style definition generated by the TSD module to enhance the <strong>zero-shot learning capability</strong> of LLMs.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="experiment" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="experiment">Experiment</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Datasets</strong>
<ul>
<li>Five literary works with diverse styles were selected, and their style transfer part and style definition part were used to create parallel Chinese article-style transfer datasets using ChatGPT.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Evaluation Metrics</strong>
<ul>
<li>Style transfer accuracy and content preservation were the primary focus, with <strong>BLEU-n</strong> and <strong>BERTScore</strong> being used to measure lexical and semantic similarity between texts.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Experimental Results</strong>
<ul>
<li>CAT-LLM achieved a better balance between style transfer and content preservation in each LLM transfer, showing competitive results in article-style transfer of various LLMs.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<p>The paper presents a comprehensive and innovative framework for Chinese article-style transfer utilizing LLMs. However, the evaluation metrics could be further expanded to include a wider variety of NLP tasks, and the ablation study could benefit from more in-depth analysis of the interactions between words level and sentences level style definitions.</p>
<p>Overall, the paper provides significant contributions to the advancement of Chinese article-style transfer and offers promising avenues for future research.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-12</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05707v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05707v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05707v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05707v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7518</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/CAT_LLM_Prompting_Large_Language_Models_with_Text_Style_Definition_for_Chinese_Article_style_Transfer/2024-01-11-CAT_LLM_Prompting_Large_Language_Models_with_Text_Style_Definition_for_Chinese_Article_style_Transfer.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05707v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Using Large Language Models for Commit Message Generation: A Preliminary Study</title>
  <dc:creator>Linghao Zhang, Jingshu Zhao, Chong Wang, Peng Liang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Using_Large_Language_Models_for_Commit_Message_Generation_A_Preliminary_Study/2024-01-11-Using_Large_Language_Models_for_Commit_Message_Generation_A_Preliminary_Study.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Using_Large_Language_Models_for_Commit_Message_Generation_A_Preliminary_Study/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05926v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Large language models (LLMs)</strong>, such as Llama 2 and ChatGPT, outperformed existing methods in <strong>human evaluations</strong> for commit message generation in 78% of the 366 samples.</li>
<li>LLMs demonstrated comparable performance to previous techniques on <strong>BLEU and Rouge-L metrics</strong> but showed a distinct advantage over all existing methods in <strong>human evaluation</strong>.</li>
<li>The study highlighted the limitations of existing metrics, <strong>BLEU and Rouge-L</strong>, in evaluating the quality of automatically generated commit messages, raising the need for more robust evaluation metrics.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="i-introduction" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="i-introduction">I Introduction</h3>
<ul>
<li>Commit messages are crucial in the Git version control system, but manually writing them is time-consuming, leading to the need for automatic generation methods.</li>
<li>Large Language Models (LLMs) have shown promise in various domains, but their application in <strong>commit message generation</strong> has been underexplored.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="ii-related-work" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="ii-related-work">II Related Work</h3>
<ul>
<li>Previous studies have proposed <strong>generation-based and retrieval-based methods</strong> for commit message generation, but this work introduces the novel application of LLMs to this task.</li>
<li>Existing methods provide baselines for <strong>evaluation and comparative analysis</strong> of LLMs.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="iii-research-design" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="iii-research-design">III Research Design</h3>
<ul>
<li>The research question focuses on exploring the feasibility and effectiveness of LLMs in <strong>commit message generation</strong>. The study uses a <strong>two-phase evaluation</strong> to assess the quality of generated commit messages.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="iii-a-overview-of-our-approach" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="iii-a-overview-of-our-approach">III-A Overview of Our Approach</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study leverages two LLMs, ChatGPT and Llama 2, to generate commit messages and implements a <strong>two-phase evaluation</strong> process.</li>
<li>The dataset used for the study is publicly available and contains pairs of code diffs and their corresponding commit messages.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="iii-b-selection-and-settings-of-llms" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="iii-b-selection-and-settings-of-llms">III-B Selection and Settings of LLMs</h3>
<ul>
<li>Two representative LLMs, ChatGPT and Llama 2, are selected for the study based on their generality and zero-shot prompting capabilities.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="iii-c-metrics-and-baselines-used-in-evaluation-phase-i" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="iii-c-metrics-and-baselines-used-in-evaluation-phase-i">III-C Metrics and Baselines used in Evaluation: Phase I</h3>
<ul>
<li>Evaluation metrics including <strong>BLEU and Rouge-L</strong> are employed to compare the quality of commit messages generated by LLMs with existing baseline models.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="iii-f-human-evaluation-phase-ii" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="iii-f-human-evaluation-phase-ii">III-F Human Evaluation: Phase II</h3>
<ul>
<li>A <strong>human evaluation</strong> is conducted to assess which method of commit message generation best fits the code differences, with LLMs outperforming other methods in human preference.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="iv-results-discussion" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="iv-results-discussion">IV Results &amp; Discussion</h3>
<ul>
<li>LLMs achieve decent scores compared to baseline models on the <strong>metrics evaluation</strong> and are preferred by humans in the <strong>human evaluation</strong>.</li>
<li>The study uncovers quality issues in <strong>human-written commit messages</strong>, highlighting the need for more robust evaluation metrics aligning with human judgment.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="v-limitations" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="v-limitations">V Limitations</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study points out limitations such as the closed-source nature of ChatGPT, the preliminary nature of the evaluation, and potential subjective biases in human evaluation.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="vi-conclusions-future-work" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="vi-conclusions-future-work">VI Conclusions &amp; Future Work</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study demonstrates the potential of LLMs for <strong>commit message generation</strong> and calls for the development of <strong>robust evaluation metrics</strong> aligning with human judgment.</li>
<li>Future work aims to explore more prompt strategies to improve LLM performance and develop <strong>LLM-integrated commit message generation methods</strong>.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<p>The study provides valuable insights into the use of LLMs for commit message generation and highlights important limitations of existing evaluation metrics. However, there are potential issues with the closed-source nature of ChatGPT, and the relatively small sample size in the human evaluation could introduce bias. Additionally, further research is needed to address the observed limitations and expand the scope of evaluation metrics.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-12</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05926v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05926v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05926v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05926v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5302</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Using_Large_Language_Models_for_Commit_Message_Generation_A_Preliminary_Study/2024-01-11-Using_Large_Language_Models_for_Commit_Message_Generation_A_Preliminary_Study.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05926v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>SH2: Self-Highlighted Hesitation Helps You Decode More Truthfully</title>
  <dc:creator>Jushi Kai, Tianhang Zhang, Hai Hu, Zhouhan Lin</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SH2_Self_Highlighted_Hesitation_Helps_You_Decode_More_Truthfully/2024-01-11-SH2_Self_Highlighted_Hesitation_Helps_You_Decode_More_Truthfully.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SH2_Self_Highlighted_Hesitation_Helps_You_Decode_More_Truthfully/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05930v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level1">
<h1>Summary</h1>
<section id="findings" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="findings">Findings</h2>
<ul>
<li>The paper introduces an inference-time <strong>method</strong>, SH2, to help large language models (LLMs) decode more truthfully by highlighting and hesitating on key tokens.</li>
<li>SH2 demonstrates significant and consistent improvements for LLMs on multiple hallucination tasks without requiring additional data or models.</li>
<li>Experimental results show that SH2 effectively helps LLMs elicit factual knowledge and distinguish hallucinated contexts.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="sections" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="sections">Sections</h2>
<section id="introduction" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h3>
<ul>
<li>Large language models (LLMs) exhibit text generation performance but suffer from hallucinations resulting in non-factual answers.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="related-work" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="related-work">Related Work</h3>
<ul>
<li>Existing approaches address LLM hallucinations through retrieval augmentation and decoding reformulation methods.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="self-highlighted-hesitation" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="self-highlighted-hesitation">Self-Highlighted Hesitation</h3>
<ul>
<li>Illustration of SH2 and its aim to help LLMs decode more truthfully by highlighting and hesitating on key tokens.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="experiment" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="experiment">Experiment</h3>
<ul>
<li>SH2 experimental results on multiple <strong>benchmarks</strong>, including TruthfulQA, FACTOR, and HaluEval-Sum utilizing LLaMA-7b and LLaMA2-7b.</li>
<li>SH2 outperforms other state-of-the-art methods on various tasks.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="analysis" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis">Analysis</h3>
<ul>
<li>Analysis of different choices of highlighted tokens and the effect of contrastive decoding on hesitations.</li>
</ul>
</section>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h2>
<p>The paper lacks an explicit comparison with existing literature in the discussion section, and there is a need to address potential limitations and challenges in practical deployment of the proposed SH2 method. Additionally, the authors should provide more thorough details on the hyperparameter selection process and how they affect the performance of the SH2 method.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-12</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05930v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05930v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05930v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05930v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7878</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SH2_Self_Highlighted_Hesitation_Helps_You_Decode_More_Truthfully/2024-01-11-SH2_Self_Highlighted_Hesitation_Helps_You_Decode_More_Truthfully.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05930v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>LLM-as-a-Coauthor: The Challenges of Detecting LLM-Human Mixcase</title>
  <dc:creator>Chujie Gao, Dongping Chen, Qihui Zhang, Yue Huang, Yao Wan, Lichao Sun</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLM_as_a_Coauthor_The_Challenges_of_Detecting_LLM_Human_Mixcase/2024-01-11-LLM_as_a_Coauthor_The_Challenges_of_Detecting_LLM_Human_Mixcase.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLM_as_a_Coauthor_The_Challenges_of_Detecting_LLM_Human_Mixcase/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05952v1/extracted/5342324/figure/intruduction_conversation.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-llm-as-a-coauthor-the-challenges-of-detecting-llm-human-mixcase" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-of-llm-as-a-coauthor-the-challenges-of-detecting-llm-human-mixcase">Summary of “LLM-as-a-Coauthor: The Challenges of Detecting LLM-Human Mixcase”</h3>
<section id="main-findings" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="main-findings">Main Findings</h4>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Current research predominantly addresses the detection of pure MGT without adequately addressing mixed scenarios including AI-revised Human-Written Text (HWT) or human-revised MGT.</strong></li>
<li>The paper introduces “mixcase,” a hybrid text form involving both machine-generated and human-generated content, and provides “MixSet,” the first dataset dedicated to studying these mixed modification scenarios.</li>
<li>Existing detectors struggle to identify mixcase as a separate class or MGT, particularly in dealing with subtle modifications and style adaptability.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h4>
<ul>
<li>The rapid advancement of Large Language Models (LLMs) has led to widespread applications in various fields, including revising Machine Generated Text (MGT) or enhancing Human Written Text (HWT).</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="related-works" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="related-works">Related works</h4>
<ul>
<li>Current MGT detection methods can be broadly categorized into <strong>metric-based</strong> and <strong>model-based</strong> methods.</li>
<li>The paper also highlights previous efforts in creating datasets for MGT detection but mentions the lack of consideration for potential mixcase scenarios.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="mixset-dataset" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="mixset-dataset">Mixset Dataset</h4>
<ul>
<li>The paper introduces MixSet, a dataset categorizing mixcase involving both AI-revised HWT and human-revised MGT scenarios, addressing the gap in previous research.</li>
<li>The dataset construction involved distinct operations in both HWT and MGT, and the analysis covered length distribution, self-BLEU scores, Levenshtein distance, and cosine similarity.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="experiments" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="experiments">Experiments</h4>
<ul>
<li>The paper conducts experiments to understand multiple facets of current detectors when encountering the MixSet, including zero-shot and fine-tuning settings.</li>
<li>The experiments aim to evaluate detection preferences, performance of retrained detectors, generalization ability, and the impact of the size of the training set on the detection ability.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="empirical-findings" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="empirical-findings">Empirical Findings</h4>
<ul>
<li>The findings show no clear classification preference in current detectors on mixcase with low consistency under different operations, and significant variability in the transfer capabilities of different detectors.</li>
<li>Increasing the number of mixcase samples in the training set effectively enhances the success rate of mixcase detection.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="conclusion" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="conclusion">Conclusion</h4>
<ul>
<li>The paper emphasizes the urgent need for the development of more sophisticated detectors capable of executing a finer-grained classification of mixcase.</li>
</ul>
</section>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<p>The paper provides valuable insights into the challenges of detecting LLM-human mixcase. However, there are potential limitations and problems that need to be considered: - <strong>Dataset Scale:</strong> The scale of the MixSet dataset is relatively small, potentially limiting the comprehensiveness of model training and evaluation. - <strong>Bias Introduced by Human Participation:</strong> The variability in human revision methods could affect the representativeness of the dataset and the generalization ability of detection models. - <strong>Generalization and Robustness:</strong> The detection methods’ ability to generalize across different revised operation subsets of MixSet and generative models needs further investigation.</p>
<p>Overall, while the paper makes important contributions to the study of mixed modification scenarios, addressing the identified limitations and potential problems could further strengthen the findings and implications of the research.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-12</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05952v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05952v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05952v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05952v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>10278</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLM_as_a_Coauthor_The_Challenges_of_Detecting_LLM_Human_Mixcase/2024-01-11-LLM_as_a_Coauthor_The_Challenges_of_Detecting_LLM_Human_Mixcase.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05952v1/extracted/5342324/figure/intruduction_conversation.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>TOFU: A Task of Fictitious Unlearning for LLMs</title>
  <dc:creator>Pratyush Maini, Zhili Feng, Avi Schwarzschild, Zachary C. Lipton, J. Zico Kolter</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/TOFU_A_Task_of_Fictitious_Unlearning_for_LLMs/2024-01-11-TOFU_A_Task_of_Fictitious_Unlearning_for_LLMs.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/TOFU_A_Task_of_Fictitious_Unlearning_for_LLMs/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.06121v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level1">
<h1>Summary</h1>
<p>The paper presents a benchmark task, Task of Fictitious Unlearning (TOFU), designed to evaluate unlearning methods for large language models (LLMs) to forget specific information post-training. The authors provide a dataset of synthetic author profiles and propose metrics to measure unlearning efficacy. They evaluate four baseline unlearning methods and find that existing methods are ineffective at achieving strong forget quality without significantly sacrificing model utility.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Protecting Private Data</strong>: Unlearning presents a way to protect private data after LLM training, which is essential for ensuring the safe and legal deployment of AI systems.</li>
<li><strong>Ineffectiveness of Baseline Methods</strong>: The study finds that current unlearning methods are weak attempts and struggle to achieve meaningful forget quality without significantly impacting model utility.</li>
<li><strong>Need for Improvement</strong>: The paper highlights the need for further development of unlearning approaches to effectively tune models to behave as if they were never trained on sensitive data.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="sections" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="sections">Sections</h2>
<ul>
<li>Introduction</li>
<li>New Task: Fictitious Author Question Answering</li>
<li>Baseline Unlearning Methods</li>
<li>Baseline Results</li>
<li>Motivation and Related Work</li>
<li>Discussion</li>
<li>Conclusion</li>
</ul>
</section>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level1">
<h1>Critique</h1>
<p>The paper provides valuable insights into the challenge of unlearning for LLMs. However, the following issues can be considered: - <strong>Limited Evaluation of Baseline Methods</strong>: The evaluation of the baseline unlearning methods could be limited in scope, potentially benefiting from more diverse and complex scenarios. - <strong>Simplistic Dataset</strong>: The synthetic author profiles dataset may not fully capture the complexity of real-world data, limiting the generalizability of the findings. - <strong>Narrow Focus on LLMs</strong>: The paper focuses solely on unlearning for LLMs, potentially overlooking potential applications in other machine learning domains.</p>
<p>Overall, while the paper makes significant contributions to the understanding of unlearning for LLMs, there is room for further exploration and refinement in the evaluation and application of unlearning methods.</p>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-12</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.06121v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.06121v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.06121v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.06121v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>15585</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/TOFU_A_Task_of_Fictitious_Unlearning_for_LLMs/2024-01-11-TOFU_A_Task_of_Fictitious_Unlearning_for_LLMs.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.06121v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Designing Heterogeneous LLM Agents for Financial Sentiment Analysis</title>
  <dc:creator>Frank Xing</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Designing_Heterogeneous_LLM_Agents_for_Financial_Sentiment_Analysis/2024-01-11-Designing_Heterogeneous_LLM_Agents_for_Financial_Sentiment_Analysis.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Designing_Heterogeneous_LLM_Agents_for_Financial_Sentiment_Analysis/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05799v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="major-takeaways" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-takeaways">Major Takeaways</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Paradigm Shift in LLM</strong>: The study underscores a shift from massive data acquisition to human alignment and strategic elicitation of existing pre-trained models in financial sentiment analysis (FSA).</li>
<li><strong>Design Framework for Heterogeneous LLM Agents</strong>: The paper proposes a design framework with specialized large language model (LLM) agents using prior domain knowledge to improve FSA.</li>
<li><strong>Performance Improvement</strong>: The study demonstrates that the proposed framework improves accuracies on FSA datasets, especially when the LLM agents produce substantial discussions.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper discusses the rapid advancements in large language models (LLMs) and their growing role in financial services, particularly in financial sentiment analysis (FSA).</li>
<li>It points out the importance of accurate FSA for investors and the reliance on sentiment analysis for various financial decision-making processes.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="related-work-and-design-process" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="related-work-and-design-process">Related Work and Design Process</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Use of LLMs for FSA</strong>: The paper reviews the evolution of FSA systems, detailing the incorporation of LLMs and their limitations in fully exploiting the potential of LLM knowledge in FSA.</li>
<li><strong>Prompt Engineering</strong>: The paper discusses the importance of prompt engineering in leveraging LLMs for downstream tasks, including FSA, and the challenges of designing effective prompts for specific tasks.</li>
<li><strong>Kernel Theory: Emotions and the Society of Mind</strong>: It elaborates on the significance of Minsky’s theory of mind and emotions in designing the heterogeneous agent discussion (HAD) framework.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="design-artifact-heterogeneous-agent-discussion-had" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="design-artifact-heterogeneous-agent-discussion-had">Design Artifact: Heterogeneous Agent Discussion (HAD)</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper presents the framework for HAD, involving the design of five different LLM agents and their respective prompts, based on error types identified in FSA datasets.</li>
<li>It discusses the empirical testing, ablation analysis, and case studies to evaluate the framework’s effectiveness in improving FSA accuracies.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="evaluation" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="evaluation">Evaluation</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Performance Improvement</strong>: The paper evaluates HAD’s performance on various FSA datasets, demonstrating consistent improvements in accuracies and F1 scores, particularly with GPT-3.5.</li>
<li><strong>Ablation Analysis</strong>: It conducts an ablation analysis, demonstrating the importance of different LLM agents in improving FSA accuracies, with some agents having a more significant impact than others.</li>
<li><strong>Case Study</strong>: The paper presents case studies to illustrate the quality of HAD outputs and how these outputs predict polarity differently from naive prompting.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="discussion-conclusion-and-future-work" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="discussion-conclusion-and-future-work">Discussion, Conclusion, and Future Work</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper discusses the implications of the study’s findings, its contributions, and potential future research directions, while also highlighting the limitations of the study.</li>
<li>It emphasizes the scalability, confidentiality of evaluation datasets, and identifies areas for future research.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study relies on proprietary LLMs and may warrant further validation with a wider set of models.</li>
<li>The evaluation datasets’ exposure to LLMs or potential biases in the training material may raise concerns about the generalizability of the findings.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-12</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05799v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05799v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05799v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05799v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8749</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Designing_Heterogeneous_LLM_Agents_for_Financial_Sentiment_Analysis/2024-01-11-Designing_Heterogeneous_LLM_Agents_for_Financial_Sentiment_Analysis.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05799v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Benefits of a Concise Chain of Thought on Problem-Solving in Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Matthew Renze, Erhan Guven</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/The_Benefits_of_a_Concise_Chain_of_Thought_on_Problem_Solving_in_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-11-The_Benefits_of_a_Concise_Chain_of_Thought_on_Problem_Solving_in_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/The_Benefits_of_a_Concise_Chain_of_Thought_on_Problem_Solving_in_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05618v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="major-takeaways" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-takeaways">Major Takeaways</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Concise Chain-of-Thought (CCoT) prompting</strong> reduces average response length by 48.70% for GPT-3.5 and GPT-4, while having negligible impact on problem-solving performance.</li>
<li>CCoT can lead to an <strong>average per-token cost reduction</strong> of 22.67% for large language models (LLMs).</li>
<li>While CCoT decreases response length significantly, it may incur a performance penalty of 27.69% on <strong>math problems</strong> for GPT-3.5.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h3>
<ul>
<li>Large Language Models (LLMs) have become essential in AI systems for problem-solving.</li>
<li><strong>Chain-of-Thought (CoT) prompting</strong> is a technique that guides LLMs to reason through a problem in a step-by-step manner, but it can lead to increased response length and costs.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="concise-prompting" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="concise-prompting">Concise Prompting</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Concise prompting</strong> reduces LLM response verbosity, lowering costs and improving efficiency, but it may negatively affect performance on certain tasks.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="concise-chain-of-thought-ccot" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="concise-chain-of-thought-ccot">Concise Chain-of-Thought (CCoT)</h3>
<ul>
<li>CCoT combines the effectiveness of CoT prompting with the efficiency of concise prompting, achieving shorter response length while maintaining problem-solving performance.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="methods" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="methods">Methods</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study used GPT-3.5 and GPT-4 with <strong>MCQA benchmarks</strong> to evaluate the impact of CCoT on response length and problem-solving performance.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="results" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="results">Results</h3>
<ul>
<li>CCoT reduced average response length by 48.70% for both <strong>GPT-3.5 and GPT-4</strong>.</li>
<li>CCoT did not significantly impact problem-solving performance but resulted in a performance penalty of 27.69% for GPT-3.5 on <strong>math problems</strong>.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="cost-analysis" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="cost-analysis">Cost Analysis</h3>
<ul>
<li>CCoT produced a <strong>total cost savings</strong> of 21.85% for GPT-3.5 and 23.49% for GPT-4.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="discussion" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="discussion">Discussion</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Limitations</strong> included testing only two LLMs and limited problem domains, and implications included cost savings and theoretical implications for studying LLM reasoning processes.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<p>The study’s limitations, such as the focus on only two LLMs and specific problem domains, limit the generalizability of the results. Additionally, the performance penalty on math problems for GPT-3.5 raises questions about the universality of CCoT’s effectiveness. Further research with a wider range of LLMs and problem types is necessary to confirm the applicability of CCoT across different contexts.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-12</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05618v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05618v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05618v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05618v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5216</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/The_Benefits_of_a_Concise_Chain_of_Thought_on_Problem_Solving_in_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-11-The_Benefits_of_a_Concise_Chain_of_Thought_on_Problem_Solving_in_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05618v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Extreme Compression of Large Language Models via Additive Quantization</title>
  <dc:creator>Vage Egiazarian, Andrei Panferov, Denis Kuznedelev, Elias Frantar, Artem Babenko, Dan Alistarh</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Extreme_Compression_of_Large_Language_Models_via_Additive_Quantization/2024-01-11-Extreme_Compression_of_Large_Language_Models_via_Additive_Quantization.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Extreme_Compression_of_Large_Language_Models_via_Additive_Quantization/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.06118v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="major-takeaways" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-takeaways">Major Takeaways</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><p><strong>High-Compression Achieved</strong>: The paper introduces the AQLM algorithm, which adapts the Additive Quantization (AQ) technique to achieve “extreme” compression of large language models (LLMs), outperforming all recently-proposed techniques in terms of accuracy at a given compression budget.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Superior Performance</strong>: AQLM outperforms previous state-of-the-art algorithms across the 2-4 bit compression range, with most significant improvements observed for extreme 2-bit quantization.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Empirical Evaluation</strong>: The paper provides a comprehensive empirical evaluation of the AQLM algorithm on the Llama 2 model family, showcasing superior results in terms of perplexity and zero-shot accuracy compared to other state-of-the-art post-training quantization (PTQ) algorithms.</p></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="abstract" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="abstract">Abstract</h3>
<p>The paper introduces the AQLM algorithm, which adapts the Additive Quantization (AQ) technique to achieve “extreme” compression of large language models (LLMs), outperforming all recently-proposed techniques in terms of accuracy at a given compression budget. The study evaluates AQLM on the Llama 2 model family and demonstrates superior results in terms of perplexity and zero-shot accuracy compared to other state-of-the-art post-training quantization (PTQ) algorithms.</p>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h3>
<ul>
<li>The rapid advancement of <strong>generative large language models</strong> (LLMs) has led to massive industrial and popular interest.</li>
<li>There is a strong interest in achieving methods for <strong>inference and fine-tuning on compressed LLMs</strong> that has led to the development of quantization techniques.</li>
<li>The <strong>general approach to LLM weight compression</strong> is described as “direct” quantization, which induces a compression-vs-accuracy trade-off.</li>
<li>The paper aims to improve the state-of-the-art in the high-compression range by extending <strong>Multi-Codebook Quantization (MCQ)</strong> to LLMs.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="aqlm-additive-quantization-for-llms" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="aqlm-additive-quantization-for-llms">AQLM: Additive Quantization for LLMs</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper introduces the AQLM algorithm, which adapts the <strong>Additive Quantization (AQ)</strong> technique to achieve “extreme” compression of large language models (LLMs).</li>
<li>AQLM is adapted to the layer-wise quantization problem by making it instance-aware, taking the layer input distributions into account into the codebook optimization.</li>
<li>The algorithm combines this approach with a block fine-tuning approach, allowing further reduction of quantization error across layers.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="experiments" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="experiments">Experiments</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study evaluates the AQLM algorithm in typical scenarios for post-training quantization of modern LLMs, focusing on the Llama 2 model family.</li>
<li>A comprehensive empirical evaluation showcases superior results in terms of perplexity and zero-shot accuracy compared to other state-of-the-art post-training quantization (PTQ) algorithms.</li>
<li>Ablation analysis validates various components of the AQLM algorithm, emphasizing the impact of initialization, fine-tuning, and the number of calibration samples on overall performance.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<p>The paper showcases a significant contribution by introducing the AQLM algorithm and providing a comprehensive evaluation of its performance. However, the computational complexity and sensitivity to parameters may be potential limitations that require further analysis in future work. Additionally, highlighting practical use cases or real-world applications of AQLM would enhance the impact of the research.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-12</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.06118v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.06118v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.06118v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.06118v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8909</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Extreme_Compression_of_Large_Language_Models_via_Additive_Quantization/2024-01-11-Extreme_Compression_of_Large_Language_Models_via_Additive_Quantization.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.06118v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Zero Resource Cross-Lingual Part Of Speech Tagging</title>
  <dc:creator>Sahil Chopra</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Zero_Resource_Cross_Lingual_Part_Of_Speech_Tagging/2024-01-11-Zero_Resource_Cross_Lingual_Part_Of_Speech_Tagging.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Zero_Resource_Cross_Lingual_Part_Of_Speech_Tagging/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05727v1/extracted/5331670/images/fdss.drawio.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="major-takeaways" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-takeaways">Major Takeaways</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Zero-resource cross-lingual part-of-speech (POS) tagging</strong> offers an effective approach for low-resource languages without labeled training data.</li>
<li>The study explores using the off-the-shelf alignment module and training a <strong>hidden Markov model (HMM)</strong> to predict POS tags, with English as the source language and French, German, and Spanish as target languages.</li>
<li>The findings suggest that projected alignment data in zero-resource languages can be beneficial for predicting POS tags.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h3>
<ul>
<li>Supervised machine learning methods have set high benchmarks for NLP tasks, but their success relies on annotated data which is not always available, especially for low-resource languages.</li>
<li>The study explores the use of fine-tuning cross-lingual multilingual pre-trained language models and utilizing parallel data to address the issue of insufficient annotated data in low-resource languages.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="methodology" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="methodology">Methodology</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study utilizes machine translation systems to translate and transfer labels from a source corpus to a target corpus in different languages.</li>
<li>Word alignment techniques, such as <strong>fastAlign</strong> and <strong>SimAlign</strong>, are employed to transfer labels of gold-annotated data to its translation, reducing noisy data.</li>
<li>An HMM is trained on the artificially generated corpus in the target language to predict POS tags, using the Viterbi algorithm for decoding.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="results" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="results">Results</h3>
<ul>
<li>The HMM performance on generated data is compared with the performance on labeled data, showing slightly lower F1 scores for POS tagging in Spanish, French, and German, emphasizing the significance of the results given the unavailability of labeled data.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="discussion" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="discussion">Discussion</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study indicates that errors in POS tagging occur due to incorrect or missing alignments, particularly with complex expressions and systematic differences between the tags of test and supervised texts in different languages.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="conclusion" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="conclusion">Conclusion</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study concludes that part-of-speech tagging in zero-resource settings can be achieved through the use of <strong>projected alignment data</strong>, which can be an effective approach for low-resource languages where labeled training data is not available.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study could benefit from a more detailed analysis of the limitations of the HMM approach and potential strategies for mitigating errors in POS tagging.</li>
<li>The study might consider discussing the implications of its findings for practical NLP applications and potential future research directions.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-12</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05727v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05727v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05727v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05727v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>3729</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Zero_Resource_Cross_Lingual_Part_Of_Speech_Tagging/2024-01-11-Zero_Resource_Cross_Lingual_Part_Of_Speech_Tagging.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05727v1/extracted/5331670/images/fdss.drawio.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Evidence to Generate (E2G): A Single-agent Two-step Prompting for Context Grounded and Retrieval Augmented Reasoning</title>
  <dc:creator>Md Rizwan Parvez</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Evidence_to_Generate_(E2G)_A_Single_agent_Two_step_Prompting_for_Context_Grounded_and_Retrieval_Augmented_Reasoning/2024-01-11-Evidence_to_Generate_(E2G)_A_Single_agent_Two_step_Prompting_for_Context_Grounded_and_Retrieval_Augmented_Reasoning.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Evidence_to_Generate_(E2G)_A_Single_agent_Two_step_Prompting_for_Context_Grounded_and_Retrieval_Augmented_Reasoning/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05787v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Evidence to Generate (E2G)</strong>, a single-agent two-step prompting framework, is introduced to overcome limitations of existing chain-of-thought (CoT) prompting methods. E2G leverages evidence from the context for robust and context-aware reasoning in large language models (LLMs).</li>
<li>E2G achieves remarkable results across a wide range of knowledge-intensive reasoning and generation tasks, surpassing baseline approaches with state-of-the-art LLMs, such as surpassing CoT and other CoT variants by significant margins.</li>
<li>E2G provides a novel approach to context-grounded and retrieval-augmented reasoning, addressing challenges such as grounding reasoning paths and reducing dependence on iterative prompting methods.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="key-sections-summarized" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="key-sections-summarized">Key Sections Summarized</h3>
<section id="introduction" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h4>
<ul>
<li>Chain-of-Thought (CoT) prompting revolutionized reasoning in LLMs but suffers from limitations in context awareness and hallucinations due to ungrounded internal reasoning.</li>
<li>Retrieval-augmented and context-based generation have improved LLM capabilities but face challenges in effective reasoning.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="evidence-to-generate-e2g-prompting" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="evidence-to-generate-e2g-prompting">Evidence to Generate (E2G) Prompting</h4>
<ul>
<li>E2G is a single-agent, two-step framework designed for context-aware reasoning, leveraging evidence from the context to guide the output generation process.</li>
<li>The E-step instructs the model to generate rationales or evidence from the context, while the G-step processes the evidence to derive the final answer.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="experimental-setup" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="experimental-setup">Experimental Setup</h4>
<ul>
<li>E2G is evaluated on eight context-intensive language tasks, showing robust performance improvements over existing approaches across various tasks and language models (LLMs).</li>
</ul>
</section>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<p>The paper presents a novel approach to addressing limitations in reasoning tasks for large language models. However, potential limitations or ethical considerations related to the generalization of the findings, model fine-tuning, and inconsistent retrieval accuracy in retrieval-augmented generation tasks are not fully addressed. Furthermore, the paper’s claim of robust performance gains requires further validation across different domains and languages. Additionally, the paper could benefit from transparency in the reporting of potential challenges and limitations encountered during the development and evaluation of the E2G framework.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-12</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05787v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05787v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05787v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05787v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7969</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Evidence_to_Generate_(E2G)_A_Single_agent_Two_step_Prompting_for_Context_Grounded_and_Retrieval_Augmented_Reasoning/2024-01-11-Evidence_to_Generate_(E2G)_A_Single_agent_Two_step_Prompting_for_Context_Grounded_and_Retrieval_Augmented_Reasoning.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05787v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Transformers are Multi-State RNNs</title>
  <dc:creator>Matanel Oren, Michael Hassid, Yossi Adi, Roy Schwartz</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Transformers_are_Multi_State_RNNs/2024-01-11-Transformers_are_Multi_State_RNNs.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Transformers_are_Multi_State_RNNs/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.06104v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-transformers-are-multi-state-rnns" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-of-transformers-are-multi-state-rnns">Summary of “Transformers are Multi-State RNNs”</h2>
<section id="main-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="main-findings">Main Findings</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Decoder-only transformers</strong> can be viewed as <strong>infinite multi-state RNNs (MSRNNs)</strong>, where the key and value vectors correspond to a multi-state that dynamically grows infinitely.</li>
<li>A <strong>novel policy, TOVA</strong> (Token Omission Via Attention), is introduced, which outperforms other baseline policies and can drastically reduce the memory consumption during inference.</li>
<li>Pretrained <strong>transformer decoder LLMs</strong> often behave in practice as <strong>finite MSRNNs</strong> and substantialy reduce the cache size with negligible performance degradation.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h3>
<ul>
<li>Transformers have replaced RNNs for NLP due to their direct access to each token in a sequence.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="background" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="background">Background</h3>
<section id="rnns" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="rnns">RNNs</h4>
<ul>
<li>RNNs process sequential data in a recurrent manner with a function that receives token representation and the hidden state from the previous time step.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="transformers" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="transformers">Transformers</h4>
<ul>
<li>Process sequential data non-recurrently and consist of self-attention and feed-forward mechanisms.</li>
</ul>
</section>
</section>
<section id="transformers-as-multi-state-rnns" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="transformers-as-multi-state-rnns">Transformers as Multi-State RNNs</h3>
<section id="multi-state-rnns" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="multi-state-rnns">Multi-State RNNs</h4>
<ul>
<li>Defined as an RNN with a state matrix instead of a vector, parameterized by a function. #### Transformers are Infinite MSRNNs</li>
<li>Transformers can be viewed as an MSRNN, where the number of single-states equals the number of input tokens.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="converting-pretrained-transformers-into-finite-msrnns" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="converting-pretrained-transformers-into-finite-msrnns">Converting Pretrained Transformers into Finite MSRNNs</h4>
<ul>
<li>Finite MSRNNs can be achieved by limiting the number of tokens processed at each step and using various compression policies.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="our-proposed-policy-tova" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="our-proposed-policy-tova">Our Proposed Policy: TOVA</h4>
<ul>
<li>TOVA is a simpler, more powerful MSRNN compression policy that retains the top states based on the attention weights of the last token only.</li>
</ul>
</section>
</section>
<section id="experimental-setup" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="experimental-setup">Experimental Setup</h3>
<ul>
<li>Long-range tasks including language modeling, long-range understanding, and text generation were used for evaluation.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="pretrained-transformers-act-as-finite-msrnns" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="pretrained-transformers-act-as-finite-msrnns">Pretrained Transformers Act as Finite MSRNNs</h3>
<ul>
<li>TOVA outperforms other policies in language modeling, long-range summarization, and performs well in text generation tasks.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="analysis" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis">Analysis</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>TOVA</strong> preserves recent tokens and some older tokens, shows a clear preference for the very first token, and highlights the importance of tokens such as punctuation and proper nouns.</li>
<li>Using TOVA enables a dramatic increase in the inference batch size.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="related-work" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="related-work">Related Work</h3>
<ul>
<li>Several works have bridged the gap between RNNs and transformers, introduced new RNN variants, and simplified transformers.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="conclusion" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="conclusion">Conclusion</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper concludes that transformer decoder LLMs often behave as finite MSRNNs and introduces TOVA as a simple compression policy that performs well with minimal memory consumption.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper’s evaluation framework focuses mainly on the English language, which may not generalize to languages with different characteristics.</li>
<li>The evaluation of long-text generation is acknowledged as being complex and was evaluated indirectly using GPT-4, which may not fully capture the entire text’s quality.</li>
</ul>
</section>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-12</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.06104v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.06104v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.06104v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.06104v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8490</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Transformers_are_Multi_State_RNNs/2024-01-11-Transformers_are_Multi_State_RNNs.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.06104v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Tuning LLMs with Contrastive Alignment Instructions for Machine Translation in Unseen, Low-resource Languages</title>
  <dc:creator>Zhuoyuan Mao, Yen Yu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Tuning_LLMs_with_Contrastive_Alignment_Instructions_for_Machine_Translation_in_Unseen_Low_resource_Languages/2024-01-11-Tuning_LLMs_with_Contrastive_Alignment_Instructions_for_Machine_Translation_in_Unseen_Low_resource_Languages.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Tuning_LLMs_with_Contrastive_Alignment_Instructions_for_Machine_Translation_in_Unseen_Low_resource_Languages/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05811v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-tuning-llms-with-contrastive-alignment-instructions-for-machine-translation-in-unseen-low-resource-languages" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-of-tuning-llms-with-contrastive-alignment-instructions-for-machine-translation-in-unseen-low-resource-languages">Summary of “Tuning LLMs with Contrastive Alignment Instructions for Machine Translation in Unseen, Low-resource Languages”</h3>
<section id="major-findings" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings</h4>
<ul>
<li>LLMs fine-tuned using contrastive alignment instructions (AlignInstruct) led to consistent improvements in translation quality across various translation directions involving English.</li>
<li>Discriminator-based instructions outperformed generative counterparts for cross-lingual instructions on previously unseen languages, showcasing the effectiveness of AlignInstruct.</li>
<li>AlignInstruct improved translation performance in 30 zero-shot directions not involving English.</li>
</ul>
</section>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h3>
<ul>
<li>Despite the success of LLMs in NLP tasks for prevalent languages, low-resource languages remain a significant challenge due to limited pre-training data.</li>
<li>Previous studies explored extending language support using continual pre-training or parameter efficient fine-tuning (PEFT) methods on monolingual tasks, but extending language support for cross-lingual tasks remains underexplored.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="methodology" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="methodology">Methodology</h3>
<ul>
<li>Baseline: MTInstruct involved fine-tuning LLMs using MT instructions, while AlignInstruct formulated a cross-lingual discriminator using statistical word alignments to provide cross-lingual supervision.</li>
<li>AlignInstruct was compared with two generative variants: HintInstruct and ReviseInstruct.</li>
<li>Statistical word alignments extracted from parallel corpora were utilized in the AlignInstruct method.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="experimental-settings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="experimental-settings">Experimental Settings</h3>
<ul>
<li>Experiments fine-tuned BLOOMZ models in up to 24 unseen languages, showing that MTInstruct effectively induced translation capabilities and AlignInstruct led to consistent improvements in translation quality.</li>
<li>Zero-shot translation evaluations demonstrated AlignInstruct’s improvements in translation quality, especially when exclusively fine-tuned with three unseen languages.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="evaluation-and-analysis" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="evaluation-and-analysis">Evaluation and Analysis</h3>
<ul>
<li>Various experimental configurations and curricula were explored: multi-task fine-tuning, pre-fine-tuning &amp; fine-tuning, and mixed fine-tuning, showing the efficacy of AlignInstruct in enhancing translation quality.</li>
<li>AlignInstruct consistently outperformed generative counterparts across metrics and model sizes.</li>
<li>Improved translation quality was observed for zero-shot directions not involving English.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="conclusion" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="conclusion">Conclusion</h3>
<ul>
<li>AlignInstruct’s strength over the MTInstruct baseline and other instruction variants was demonstrated in multilingual and zero-shot findings.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper does not compare translations in low-resource languages with best-performing multilingual NMT models, which could provide a benchmark for the proposed techniques.</li>
<li>The study focused primarily on enhancing the MTInstruct baseline through improved cross-lingual alignment within LLMs rather than delving into the best combination of techniques for MT fine-tuning in LLMs.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the study effectively demonstrates the efficacy of AlignInstruct for improving translation quality in unseen, low-resource languages, while raising opportunities for future exploration. However, it could benefit from additional comparisons with state-of-the-art multilingual NMT models and exploration of varied templates for MT instructions.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-12</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05811v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05811v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05811v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05811v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>9056</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Tuning_LLMs_with_Contrastive_Alignment_Instructions_for_Machine_Translation_in_Unseen_Low_resource_Languages/2024-01-11-Tuning_LLMs_with_Contrastive_Alignment_Instructions_for_Machine_Translation_in_Unseen_Low_resource_Languages.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05811v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Investigating Data Contamination for Pre-training Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Minhao Jiang, Ken Ziyu Liu, Ming Zhong, Rylan Schaeffer, Siru Ouyang, Jiawei Han, Sanmi Koyejo</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Investigating_Data_Contamination_for_Pre_training_Language_Models/2024-01-11-Investigating_Data_Contamination_for_Pre_training_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Investigating_Data_Contamination_for_Pre_training_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.06059v1/extracted/5332364/figure/factor.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="investigating-data-contamination-for-pre-training-language-models" class="level1">
<h1>Investigating Data Contamination for Pre-training Language Models</h1>
<section id="major-findings" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings</h2>
<ul>
<li>The study explores the impact of <strong>data contamination</strong> at the pre-training stage on language models’ performance on downstream tasks.</li>
<li>Both <strong>text contamination</strong> and <strong>ground-truth contamination</strong> from evaluation data are highlighted as influential factors in the study.</li>
<li>The study suggests that the <strong>n-gram-based contamination definitions</strong> used in recent reports are inadequate in identifying contamination accurately.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<ul>
<li>Concerns arise regarding potential <strong>data contamination</strong> in pre-training corpora, impacting the accuracy of language models’ capabilities on scientific analyses.</li>
<li>Prior LLM reports have explored contamination of evaluation data within the pre-training corpora, primarily focusing on n-gram-based definitions.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="contamination-definitions" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="contamination-definitions">Contamination Definitions</h2>
<ul>
<li>Existing studies have proposed <strong>n-gram-based definitions</strong> for data contamination, often centred on <strong>direct duplications</strong> present in both training and evaluation datasets.</li>
<li>The paper explores the limitations of these definitions and their focus on the <strong>evaluation level</strong> analysis, rather than pre-training level analysis.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="experimental-setup" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="experimental-setup">Experimental Setup</h2>
<ul>
<li>Pre-trained a series of GPT-2 models from scratch and evaluated various contamination factors, including text and ground-truth contamination.</li>
<li>Explored the effects of <strong>repeated contamination</strong> on model performance, finding a U-shaped performance trend with increasing contamination factors.</li>
<li>Critically analyzed the effects of <strong>filtering out contamination</strong> from the pre-training corpus according to existing definitions, revealing the inadequacy of such definitions in identifying effective contamination.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="scaling-up-with-a-larger-model" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="scaling-up-with-a-larger-model">Scaling Up with a Larger Model</h2>
<ul>
<li>Expanded the experiment to incorporate GPT-2-large to assess if the effects of data contamination observed in smaller-scale models persist in larger models.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="assessment-of-evaluation-level-contamination-analysis" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="assessment-of-evaluation-level-contamination-analysis">Assessment of Evaluation-Level Contamination Analysis</h2>
<ul>
<li>Examined existing categories for evaluation data contamination using Llama 2’s definitions, indicating that models may not be immune to contamination based on such categorical evaluations.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h2>
<ul>
<li>The study primarily focuses on GPT-2 models and does not explore a wider range of language models.</li>
<li>The limitations of existing contamination definitions are acknowledged, but alternative methods for more accurate detection are not proposed.</li>
</ul>
<p>In conclusion, the paper offers valuable insights into data contamination’s effects on language model capabilities and raises concerns about the adequacy of current contamination definitions. However, the approach’s practical applicability and potential solutions to improve contamination detection remain as open research questions.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-12</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.06059v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.06059v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.06059v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.06059v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>9968</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Investigating_Data_Contamination_for_Pre_training_Language_Models/2024-01-11-Investigating_Data_Contamination_for_Pre_training_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.06059v1/extracted/5332364/figure/factor.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Autocompletion of Chief Complaints in the Electronic Health Records using Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>K M Sajjadul Islam, Ayesha Siddika Nipu, Praveen Madiraju, Priya Deshpande</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Autocompletion_of_Chief_Complaints_in_the_Electronic_Health_Records_using_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-11-Autocompletion_of_Chief_Complaints_in_the_Electronic_Health_Records_using_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Autocompletion_of_Chief_Complaints_in_the_Electronic_Health_Records_using_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.06088v1/extracted/5342703/Auto_Completion_CC.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="major-takeaways" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-takeaways">Major Takeaways</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><p><strong>Chief Complaints</strong> are crucial in medical records and can be time-consuming to document, especially in busy emergency departments. Autocompletion tools using NLP techniques, specifically large language models (LLMs), improve efficiency and accuracy in generating Chief Complaints, which can aid in triage healthcare.</p></li>
<li><p>The study presents the utilization of various LLMs such as Long Short-Term Memory (LSTM) and Biomedical Generative Pretrained Transformers (BioGPT) to develop autocompletion tools for Chief Complaint documentation in healthcare settings.</p></li>
<li><p>Results show that <strong>BioGPT-Large</strong> exhibits superior performance compared to other models, achieving a remarkably low perplexity score of 1.65 when generating Chief Complaints, highlighting the effectiveness of utilizing LLMs for autocompletion in healthcare settings.</p></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="methodology" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="methodology">Methodology</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Dataset Description</strong>: Utilized a de-identified clinical corpus for predicting gout flares in emergency department patients using triage nurse Chief Complaint notes.</li>
<li><strong>Data Preprocessing</strong>: Split Chief Complaints into parts, filter out small sentences, and divide the dataset into training, validation, and test sets.</li>
<li><strong>A Neural Network Approach</strong>: Employed LSTM as a baseline model and fine-tuned BioGPT models, followed by prompt tuning using OpenAI API.</li>
<li><strong>Prompt Tuning</strong>: Incorporated the Few-Shot (FS) technique to create a prompt using the GPT-4.0 model for generating Chief Complaints.</li>
<li><strong>Results</strong>: Evaluated performance using perplexity measure, BERTScore, cosine similarity, and execution time. Large BioGPT models outperformed LSTM and other models, achieving higher scores on various evaluation metrics.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<p>The article provides a comprehensive overview of autocompleting Chief Complaints in Electronic Health Records using large language models. However, there are some potential limitations and areas for improvement in the study: - The study acknowledges the need for a Human-Centric evaluation, and it would be beneficial to include insights from domain experts to assess the clinical accuracy and relevance of the autocompleted Chief Complaints. - The discussion and future work section mention refining date-time representation and using a medical corpus for accuracy, but it would be helpful to explore potential ethical considerations, patient privacy concerns, and biases introduced by the language models.</p>
</section>
<section id="conclusion" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="conclusion">Conclusion</h3>
<p>The study demonstrates the effectiveness of utilizing LLMs, particularly <strong>BioGPT-Large</strong>, for autocompletion of Chief Complaint documentation in healthcare settings. The findings support the potential of NLP techniques to improve efficiency and accuracy in generating Chief Complaints, with implications for enhancing patient care in emergency departments.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-12</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.06088v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.06088v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.06088v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.06088v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>9543</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Autocompletion_of_Chief_Complaints_in_the_Electronic_Health_Records_using_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-11-Autocompletion_of_Chief_Complaints_in_the_Electronic_Health_Records_using_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.06088v1/extracted/5342703/Auto_Completion_CC.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>How to write a CHI paper (asking for a friend)</title>
  <dc:creator>Raquel Robinson, Alberto Alvarez, Elisa Mekler</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/How_to_write_a_CHI_paper_(asking_for_a_friend)/2024-01-11-How_to_write_a_CHI_paper_(asking_for_a_friend).html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/How_to_write_a_CHI_paper_(asking_for_a_friend)/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level1">
<h1>Summary</h1>
<section id="major-findings" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper presents the development of an AI tool called <strong>KITSUNE</strong> to support authors in formatting their work into the style of a CHI paper. It aims to provoke discussion about the <strong>writing conventions</strong> upheld by the CHI community and how these conventions shape the work produced.</li>
<li>The authors analyze the use of headings and writing conventions in ACM CHI papers from 1997 to 2019, addressing the changes over time and differences among different types of papers.</li>
<li>The paper raises questions about how the introduction of Large Language Models (LLMs) into academic writing fundamentally changes how conventions are upheld and how their presence may affect future writing.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="abstract" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="abstract">Abstract</h2>
<p>The paper introduces an AI tool called KITSUNE meant to promote discussion on <strong>writing conventions</strong> in CHI papers and their impact on the work produced. It highlights the trend in the use of headings and writing conventions in CHI papers and their differences among various paper types. The authors also question how the introduction of LLMs into academic writing will fundamentally change writing conventions.</p>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>The section outlines the significance of the ACM CHI conference and the aim to investigate changes in the structure and content of CHI papers. It emphasizes the need to analyze the use of headings, adoption of writing conventions, and various text features in ACM CHI papers from 1997 to 2019.</p>
</section>
<section id="related-work" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="related-work">Related Work</h2>
<p>The section reviews previous studies on writing conventions in ACM papers and highlights the analysis of headings and writing conventions. It emphasizes how writing conventions are used to improve the readability and organization of papers.</p>
</section>
<section id="method" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="method">Method</h2>
<p>The authors collected data from the ACM CHI conference website and conducted survey studies to analyze the use of headings and writing conventions in CHI papers. They explain the data preprocessing methods and the experiments performed using Python and the Jupyter Notebook environment.</p>
</section>
<section id="human-made-introduction" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="human-made-introduction">[Human-Made] Introduction</h2>
<p>The authors discuss the importance of genre conventions in the scientific community and the impact of these conventions on creative output and inclusivity, emphasizing how generative AI tools, like Large Language Models, are challenging established writing conventions.</p>
</section>
<section id="human-made-kitsune-the-tool" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="human-made-kitsune-the-tool">[Human-Made] KITSUNE: The Tool</h2>
<p>The section describes the development process of the KITSUNE tool using PyTorch and Scikit-learn with open source models from HuggingFace. It details the data scraping and training process, the model used, and provides preliminary output generated by KITSUNE.</p>
</section>
<section id="human-made-author-commentary" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="human-made-author-commentary">[Human-Made] Author Commentary</h2>
<p>The authors provide their individual commentaries on the impact of writing conventions at CHI, sharing perspectives on the reinforcement of conventions, the effects of writing conventions, and the need for discussions on conventions and styles within the community.</p>
</section>
<section id="human-made-conclusion" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="human-made-conclusion">[Human-Made] Conclusion</h2>
<p>The conclusion refrains from providing next steps, key takeaways, or implications of the work and instead encourages readers to generate writing conventions to prompt their own investigations in this area.</p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level1">
<h1>Critique</h1>
<p>The paper lacks a cohesive structure, making it challenging to discern the main contributions and findings. Some sections are ambiguously written and provide convoluted explanations. Additionally, while the authors aim to challenge writing conventions, it’s unclear how this work contributes to addressing the identified issues in a practical manner. The collaborative approach to writing the paper may cause confusion for readers, and the intentional deviation from conventions may hinder the clarity of the paper’s message. A more coherent and focused approach to addressing writing conventions in CHI papers would enhance the impact of the paper.</p>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-12</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05818v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05818v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05818v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.05818v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>11566</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/How_to_write_a_CHI_paper_(asking_for_a_friend)/2024-01-11-How_to_write_a_CHI_paper_(asking_for_a_friend).html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
