<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Bayesian beagle</title>
<link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Quarto blog of LLM-generated summaries of Arxiv preprints</description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.450</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>ReLU\(^2\) Wins: Discovering Efficient Activation Functions for Sparse LLMs</title>
  <dc:creator>Zhengyan Zhang, Yixin Song, Guanghui Yu, Xu Han, Yankai Lin, Chaojun Xiao, Chenyang Song, Zhiyuan Liu, Zeyu Mi, Maosong Sun</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ReLU$^2$_Wins_Discovering_Efficient_Activation_Functions_for_Sparse_LLMs/2024-02-06-ReLU$^2$_Wins_Discovering_Efficient_Activation_Functions_for_Sparse_LLMs.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/../bayesian-beagle.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article discusses the use of sparse computation for Large Language Models (LLMs) in low-resource scenarios, proposing a systematic framework to examine the sparsity of LLMs and comparing the performance of different activation functions.</li>
<li>It presents findings from experiments analyzing the impact of different activation functions on LLMs, highlighting ReLU2 as the most efficient activation function for sparse LLMs.</li>
<li>The section also discusses the computational relationships between tokens and neurons in LLMs, identifying ReLU2 as the most efficient activation function for reducing computational cost and I/O overhead significantly.</li>
<li>Additionally, the article provides detailed information about the experimental setup and training process of the 1.3B model, including the architecture, pre-training data, and training hyperparameters, as well as the threshold-finding method used in the experiments.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>ReLU2 is identified as the most efficient activation function for sparse LLMs, offering substantial reductions in computational cost and I/O overhead.</li>
<li>The performance of LLMs is not sensitive to tail truncation when the sparsity ratio is smaller than 0.7, but drops significantly when the sparsity ratio is larger than 0.7.</li>
<li>ReGLU-based LLaMA models achieve comparable performance with the original LLaMA-27B models under certain sizes, but there is a performance gap under larger sizes, potentially due to insufficient pre-training data.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides valuable insights into optimizing LLMs and can guide future research in developing more efficient language models.</li>
<li>The findings suggest that the ReGLU-based LLaMA models may require additional pre-training data to achieve optimal performance, highlighting a potential area for further research.</li>
<li>The threshold-finding method and the concept of hot-activated neurons are crucial for understanding the efficiency of activation functions in sparse LLMs, providing avenues for further exploration and research.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-07</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03804v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03804v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03804v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03804v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>27556</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ReLU$^2$_Wins_Discovering_Efficient_Activation_Functions_for_Sparse_LLMs/2024-02-06-ReLU$^2$_Wins_Discovering_Efficient_Activation_Functions_for_Sparse_LLMs.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Multi-line AI-assisted Code Authoring</title>
  <dc:creator>Omer Dunay, Daniel Cheng, Adam Tait, Parth Thakkar, Peter C Rigby, Andy Chiu, Imad Ahmad, Arun Ganesan, Chandra Maddila, Vijayaraghavan Murali, Ali Tayyebi, Nachiappan Nagappan</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Multi_line_AI_assisted_Code_Authoring/2024-02-06-Multi_line_AI_assisted_Code_Authoring.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.04141v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<p>CodeCompose is an AI-assisted code authoring tool that provides inline suggestions to developers at Meta. In this paper, the authors present the challenges and solutions in scaling the product from single-line to multi-line suggestions. They discuss the “jarring” effect of multi-line suggestions, the latency in generating them, and the impact on user experience.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Jarring Effect of Multi-line Suggestions:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Multi-line suggestions can disrupt the user’s existing code, causing a “jarring” effect and increased cognitive load.</li>
<li>The authors developed a scope-based algorithm to trigger multi-line suggestions only when the cursor is at the end of the current scope, reducing the disruption.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Latency Reduction for Multi-line Suggestions:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Multi-line suggestions take longer to generate, leading to decreased display rate and user satisfaction.</li>
<li>The authors implemented various optimizations to reduce latency, including Flash Attention, CUDA graphs, and streaming with early cancellation.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Effectiveness of Multi-line Suggestions:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Despite the longer generation time, multi-line suggestions accounted for 42% of total characters accepted by users, demonstrating their impact.</li>
<li>User feedback indicated a noticeable improvement in the coding experience with multi-line suggestions.</li>
</ul></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The authors effectively addressed the challenges of scaling CodeCompose to support multi-line suggestions, providing innovative solutions to reduce latency and improve user experience.</li>
<li>However, the study’s generalizability may be limited to large-scale industrial environments like Meta, and the impact of multi-line suggestions on different types of codebases and programming languages remains to be explored.</li>
<li>The user feedback and opt-out rate data provide valuable insights into the adoption and favorability of multi-line suggestions, but further research is needed to understand the long-term impact on developer productivity and code quality.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-07</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.04141v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.04141v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.04141v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.04141v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>12672</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Multi_line_AI_assisted_Code_Authoring/2024-02-06-Multi_line_AI_assisted_Code_Authoring.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.04141v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>RevOrder: A Novel Method for Enhanced Arithmetic in Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Si Shen, Peijun Shen, Danhao Zhu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/RevOrder_A_Novel_Method_for_Enhanced_Arithmetic_in_Language_Models/2024-02-06-RevOrder_A_Novel_Method_for_Enhanced_Arithmetic_in_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.03822v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper introduces RevOrder, a novel technique aimed at improving arithmetic operations in large language models (LLMs) by reversing the output digits in addition, subtraction, and n-digit by 1-digit (nD by 1D) multiplication tasks.</li>
<li>RevOrder significantly reduces the Count of Sequential Intermediate Digits (CSID) to O(1), a new metric introduced to assess equation complexity.</li>
<li>Through comprehensive testing, RevOrder achieves perfect accuracy in basic arithmetic operations and substantially boosts LLM performance in division tasks, particularly with large numbers where traditional models struggle.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>RevOrder significantly reduces the Count of Sequential Intermediate Digits (CSID) to O(1), improving arithmetic operations in large language models (LLMs).</li>
<li>RevOrder achieves perfect accuracy in basic arithmetic operations and substantially boosts LLM performance in division tasks, particularly with large numbers where traditional models struggle.</li>
<li>Implementation of RevOrder is cost-effective for both training and inference phases.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper presents a novel and effective technique, RevOrder, for enhancing arithmetic operations in large language models.</li>
<li>The method significantly reduces the complexity of arithmetic equations and improves the accuracy of LLMs in performing arithmetic tasks.</li>
<li>The study provides comprehensive testing and demonstrates the cost-effectiveness of implementing RevOrder for both training and inference phases.</li>
<li>The potential shortcomings of RevOrder may include challenges in maintaining accuracy in large-digit division tasks and the need for further research to address these limitations.</li>
<li>The paper highlights the importance of integrating RevOrder into LLMs’ pretraining to enhance arithmetic capabilities more fundamentally than fine-tuning.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-07</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03822v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03822v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03822v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03822v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>10704</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/RevOrder_A_Novel_Method_for_Enhanced_Arithmetic_in_Language_Models/2024-02-06-RevOrder_A_Novel_Method_for_Enhanced_Arithmetic_in_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.03822v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Empowering Language Models with Active Inquiry for Deeper Understanding</title>
  <dc:creator>Jing-Cheng Pang, Heng-Bo Fan, Pengyuan Wang, Jia-Hao Xiao, Nan Tang, Si-Hang Yang, Chengxing Jia, Sheng-Jun Huang, Yang Yu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Empowering_Language_Models_with_Active_Inquiry_for_Deeper_Understanding/2024-02-06-Empowering_Language_Models_with_Active_Inquiry_for_Deeper_Understanding.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.03719v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The academic article introduces LaMAI, a method designed to improve Large Language Models’ (LLMs) understanding of user queries by actively inquiring the user for clarification. LaMAI leverages active learning techniques to select and formulate the most informative questions, fostering a dynamic bidirectional dialogue. The method aims to narrow the contextual gap and refine the output of LLMs, aligning it more closely with user expectations. The article also presents the experimental setting for the study, including the datasets used, baseline methods compared, and the evaluation metrics employed. Additionally, it discusses the usage of datasets in experiments and the implementation of active learning in LaMAI, highlighting the challenges and potential enhancements for active learning techniques and presenting a practical algorithm for LaMAI. Furthermore, the article provides information about the hyper-parameters used in the experiments, examples of datasets used, and additional experiment results, including full results on QMSum, an ablation study on active inquiry threshold, performance on user queries with less context, and more algorithm running examples.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LaMAI effectively improves the comprehension ability of language models regarding user queries.</li>
<li>The active inquiry strategy significantly improves performance, especially in situations with less context.</li>
<li>LaMAI’s practical algorithm streamlines the iterative interaction process, making it more user-friendly while still eliciting the necessary clarifications.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article effectively presents LaMAI as a novel approach to enhancing LLMs’ understanding of user queries, addressing the challenges of ambiguous user queries through active learning and uncertainty estimation.</li>
<li>The experimental setting provides a comprehensive foundation for the study, allowing for the comparison of LaMAI with baseline methods across various datasets, enhancing the credibility and relevance of the study’s findings.</li>
<li>The content in the section about the implementation of active learning in LaMAI is significant as it provides insights into the challenges and potential improvements for active learning techniques and the practical implementation of LaMAI.</li>
<li>The section providing information about the experimental setup, datasets, and results of the study is crucial for understanding the methodology and outcomes of the study, making it a crucial part of the academic paper.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-07</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03719v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03719v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03719v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03719v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>18153</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Empowering_Language_Models_with_Active_Inquiry_for_Deeper_Understanding/2024-02-06-Empowering_Language_Models_with_Active_Inquiry_for_Deeper_Understanding.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.03719v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Learning to Generate Explainable Stock Predictions using Self-Reflective Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Kelvin J. L. Koa, Yunshan Ma, Ritchie Ng, Tat-Seng Chua</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Learning_to_Generate_Explainable_Stock_Predictions_using_Self_Reflective_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-06-Learning_to_Generate_Explainable_Stock_Predictions_using_Self_Reflective_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Learning_to_Generate_Explainable_Stock_Predictions_using_Self_Reflective_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03659v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article proposes the Summarize-Explain-Predict (SEP) framework to teach Large Language Models (LLMs) to generate explainable stock predictions in a fully autonomous manner. The framework utilizes a verbal self-reflective agent and Proximal Policy Optimization (PPO) to fine-tune the LLM.</li>
<li>The article demonstrates that the SEP framework outperforms traditional deep-learning and LLM methods in prediction accuracy and explanation quality for stock classification tasks.</li>
<li>The SEP framework is also validated for portfolio construction tasks, showing its effectiveness in generating explainable weights for a stock portfolio.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The SEP framework outperforms traditional deep-learning and LLM methods in prediction accuracy and explanation quality for stock classification tasks.</li>
<li>The Summarize module reduces noise and length of input texts, leading to better results. The Explain module generates more decisive and correct annotated samples through self-reflection. The Predict module, particularly the PPO reinforcement learning, significantly improves the model’s performance.</li>
<li>The SEP framework is effective in generating explainable weights for a stock portfolio, outperforming other methods in most portfolio metrics.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article effectively demonstrates the effectiveness of the SEP framework in improving the accuracy and quality of stock predictions, as well as its generalizability to portfolio construction tasks.</li>
<li>The framework’s ability to generate explainable predictions and portfolio weights showcases its potential for practical applications in stock market analysis.</li>
<li>The article does not address potential ethical implications of using LLMs for stock prediction, such as the risk of manipulation, misinformation, and prediction bias. It would be beneficial to include a more comprehensive discussion of these ethical considerations and potential mitigation strategies.</li>
<li>The article could benefit from a more detailed discussion of the limitations and challenges of the SEP framework, as well as potential future research directions to address these limitations.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-07</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03659v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03659v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03659v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03659v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>11286</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Learning_to_Generate_Explainable_Stock_Predictions_using_Self_Reflective_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-06-Learning_to_Generate_Explainable_Stock_Predictions_using_Self_Reflective_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03659v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>In-context learning agents are asymmetric belief updaters</title>
  <dc:creator>Johannes A. Schubert, Akshay K. Jagadish, Marcel Binz, Eric Schulz</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/In_context_learning_agents_are_asymmetric_belief_updaters/2024-02-06-In_context_learning_agents_are_asymmetric_belief_updaters.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.03969v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The study investigates the in-context learning dynamics of large language models (LLMs) using three instrumental learning tasks adapted from cognitive psychology.</li>
<li>LLMs update their beliefs in an asymmetric manner and learn more from better-than-expected outcomes than from worse-than-expected ones.</li>
<li>The effect reverses when learning about counterfactual feedback and disappears when no agency is implied.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs exhibit an optimism bias, learning more from positive than from negative prediction errors.</li>
<li>The bias reverses when learning about the value of the unchosen option, and disappears when no agency is implied.</li>
<li>Idealized in-context learning agents trained specifically to solve 2AFC tasks using meta-reinforcement learning show similar patterns.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study provides valuable insights into the in-context learning dynamics of LLMs and idealized agents.</li>
<li>The findings have implications for understanding how learning occurs in both natural and artificial agents.</li>
<li>The study’s methodological approach of fitting simpler computational models to the behavior of LLMs provides a tool for explainable machine learning.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the study contributes to our understanding of in-context learning and its implications for real-world applications. However, the study’s external validity and causal links between observed patterns and behavior need further investigation.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-07</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03969v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03969v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03969v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03969v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>15607</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/In_context_learning_agents_are_asymmetric_belief_updaters/2024-02-06-In_context_learning_agents_are_asymmetric_belief_updaters.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.03969v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Instinctive Bias: Spurious Images lead to Hallucination in MLLMs</title>
  <dc:creator>Tianyang Han, Qing Lian, Rui Pan, Renjie Pi, Jipeng Zhang, Shizhe Diao, Yong Lin, Tong Zhang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/The_Instinctive_Bias_Spurious_Images_lead_to_Hallucination_in_MLLMs/2024-02-06-The_Instinctive_Bias_Spurious_Images_lead_to_Hallucination_in_MLLMs.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.03757v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article discusses the challenges faced by multi-modal large language models (MLLMs) when presented with certain image and text inputs, leading to hallucination.</li>
<li>The authors propose a benchmark called CorrelationQA to quantify the hallucination level given spurious images and conduct a thorough analysis on 9 mainstream MLLMs.</li>
<li>The impact of different image formats on the instinctive bias of MLLMs is discussed, along with examples of question-answer (QA) pairs generated using GPT-4.</li>
<li>Tables showing the accuracy of different MLLMs on CorrelationQA under twelve categories when applied to spurious images are presented.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Multi-modal large language models (MLLMs) universally suffer from an instinctive bias when presented with misleading images.</li>
<li>Image formats, particularly typography, significantly influence the instinctive bias of MLLMs, affecting their accuracy and susceptibility to spurious information.</li>
<li>GPT-4 demonstrates the ability to generate accurate and diverse responses based on complex prompts, with varying accuracy rates for different categories.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The proposed benchmark and evaluation results contribute to the ongoing efforts to improve the performance and reliability of MLLMs in multi-modal tasks.</li>
<li>The findings have implications for refining training strategies and improving the modality alignment of MLLMs to mitigate instinctive bias and enhance their performance in real-world scenarios.</li>
<li>The accuracy results of different MLLMs on spurious images highlight the impact of spurious information on the performance of these models, emphasizing the need for accurate and reliable QA generation.</li>
<li>The section provides important insights into the performance of MLLMs on CorrelationQA under different conditions, highlighting the impact of spurious images and typography on accuracy, crucial for understanding the robustness and limitations of these models in real-world applications.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-07</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03757v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03757v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03757v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03757v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>16105</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/The_Instinctive_Bias_Spurious_Images_lead_to_Hallucination_in_MLLMs/2024-02-06-The_Instinctive_Bias_Spurious_Images_lead_to_Hallucination_in_MLLMs.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.03757v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Minds versus Machines: Rethinking Entailment Verification with Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Soumya Sanyal, Tianyi Xiao, Jiacheng Liu, Wenya Wang, Xiang Ren</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Minds_versus_Machines_Rethinking_Entailment_Verification_with_Language_Models/2024-02-06-Minds_versus_Machines_Rethinking_Entailment_Verification_with_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/../bayesian-beagle.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper evaluates the inference judgments of humans and Large Language Models (LLMs) across various reasoning categories, including natural language inference (NLI), contextual question-answering (QA), and rationales.</li>
<li>LLMs outperform humans in multi-hop reasoning across long contexts, while humans excel in tasks requiring simple deductive reasoning.</li>
<li>The paper introduces a fine-tuned Flan-T5 model that outperforms GPT-3.5 and rivals with GPT-4, offering a robust open-source solution for entailment verification.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs are superior in multi-hop reasoning across extended contexts, while humans excel in tasks necessitating simple deductive reasoning.</li>
<li>General instruction-finetuned models are better than task-finetuned models trained on a specific dataset category.</li>
<li>Fine-tuned models outperform GPT-3.5 and perform comparably to GPT-4 on the benchmark, providing a strong open-sourced model for entailment verification.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper provides valuable insights into the differences in inference capabilities between humans and LLMs, but it does not address the potential limitations of using LLMs for entailment verification in real-world applications.</li>
<li>The study focuses on the performance of LLMs and humans in specific reasoning categories, but it does not thoroughly discuss the broader implications of these findings for natural language understanding and AI applications.</li>
<li>The paper lacks a comprehensive discussion of the ethical and societal implications of using LLMs for entailment verification, which is essential for understanding the broader impact of this research.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-07</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03686v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03686v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03686v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03686v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>12397</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Minds_versus_Machines_Rethinking_Entailment_Verification_with_Language_Models/2024-02-06-Minds_versus_Machines_Rethinking_Entailment_Verification_with_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>HarmBench: A Standardized Evaluation Framework for Automated Red Teaming and Robust Refusal</title>
  <dc:creator>Mantas Mazeika, Long Phan, Xuwang Yin, Andy Zou, Zifan Wang, Norman Mu, Elham Sakhaee, Nathaniel Li, Steven Basart, Bo Li, David Forsyth, Dan Hendrycks</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/HarmBench_A_Standardized_Evaluation_Framework_for_Automated_Red_Teaming_and_Robust_Refusal/2024-02-06-HarmBench_A_Standardized_Evaluation_Framework_for_Automated_Red_Teaming_and_Robust_Refusal.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.04249v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article introduces HarmBench, a standardized evaluation framework for automated red teaming, and discusses its significance in evaluating and improving the safety of Large Language Models (LLMs).</li>
<li>It outlines the functional categories of behavior, evaluation pipeline, curation of harmful behaviors, and differential harm within the HarmBench framework.</li>
<li>The article provides an extensive list of references to related works and research papers in the field of adversarial attacks and defenses in natural language processing and large language models.</li>
<li>It presents the development of an adversarial training method for robust refusal, called Robust Refusal Dynamic Defense (R2D2), and discusses its significance in addressing the need for model-level defenses beyond standard fine-tuning.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>HarmBench serves as a valuable framework for evaluating and improving the safety of Large Language Models (LLMs).</li>
<li>The R2D2 method presents a novel approach to adversarial training for LLMs, with potential implications for improving their robustness against adversarial attacks.</li>
<li>The article provides valuable insights into the performance of different models in carrying out successful attacks on the HarmBench validation set, shedding light on the effectiveness of each model in different attack scenarios.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article effectively addresses the lack of a standardized evaluation framework for automated red teaming and highlights the potential of HarmBench in enabling large-scale comparisons and the development of stronger attacks and defenses.</li>
<li>The comprehensive overview of the HarmBench framework emphasizes its significance in evaluating and improving the safety of LLMs, highlighting the need for sophisticated defense strategies and the ethical implications of advancing AI development.</li>
<li>The extensive list of references provides a valuable resource for researchers and practitioners in the field of adversarial attacks and defenses in natural language processing and large language models, demonstrating the collaborative nature of academic inquiry in this domain.</li>
<li>The development of the R2D2 method addresses the need for model-level defenses beyond standard fine-tuning, providing a novel approach to adversarial training for LLMs with potential implications for improving their robustness against adversarial attacks.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-07</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.04249v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.04249v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.04249v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.04249v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>39372</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/HarmBench_A_Standardized_Evaluation_Framework_for_Automated_Red_Teaming_and_Robust_Refusal/2024-02-06-HarmBench_A_Standardized_Evaluation_Framework_for_Automated_Red_Teaming_and_Robust_Refusal.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.04249v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Leak, Cheat, Repeat: Data Contamination and Evaluation Malpractices in Closed-Source LLMs</title>
  <dc:creator>Simone Balloccu, Patrícia Schmidtová, Mateusz Lango, Ondřej Dušek</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Leak_Cheat_Repeat_Data_Contamination_and_Evaluation_Malpractices_in_Closed_Source_LLMs/2024-02-06-Leak_Cheat_Repeat_Data_Contamination_and_Evaluation_Malpractices_in_Closed_Source_LLMs.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.03927v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li><p>The article discusses data contamination and evaluation malpractices in the context of Large Language Models (LLMs), focusing on OpenAI’s GPT-3.5 and GPT-4. It provides a systematic analysis of 255 papers evaluating these models, revealing data leakage and evaluation malpractices. The authors propose suggested practices for the evaluation of closed-source LLMs.</p></li>
<li><p>The majority of papers that leaked data were published before the official release of the ChatGPT API. The web interface access decreased after March 2023, but some work continued to use it until September 2023. The leaked data after the API release suggests that some researchers are unaware of OpenAI’s data policy or do not consider it a problem. The severity of data leaks was quantified, with over 4.7M samples leaked from 263 unique datasets. Most samples came from whole datasets, followed by test and development sets, and training sets. The leaked data included examples’ labels, which is considered the worst case of data leaking. The evaluation of ChatGPT’s performance was often unfair, with comparisons to open models missing or unequal comparisons. The evaluation reproducibility and fairness were also analyzed.</p></li>
<li><p>The section covers various aspects of ChatGPT, such as its multilingual learning capabilities, performance evaluation on benchmark datasets, meta-analysis after 2.5 months, information extraction capabilities, and its potential in reviving anime characters in reality. Additionally, the section discusses the use of ChatGPT as a database interface, its promise in detecting and discriminating hateful, offensive, and toxic comments on social media, and its grounding via dynamic knowledge adapting over heterogeneous sources. Furthermore, the section delves into guiding large language models via directional stimulus prompting, holistic evaluation of language models, and few-shot text classification for finance. The section also explores ChatGPT’s capabilities in zero-shot text-to-SQL, modeling ambiguity, and evaluating large language models on graphs. Additionally, it covers the evaluation of logical reasoning ability, code generation, vulnerability description mappings, and NLG evaluation using GPT-4. Lastly, the section discusses the future of large language models and their potential in generative pre-training.</p></li>
<li><p>The utility of ChatGPT throughout the entire clinical workflow is explored in this academic paper. The authors investigate the potential of large language models, such as ChatGPT, for various applications in the clinical domain. They analyze the performance of ChatGPT in tasks such as summarization, question answering, knowledge retrieval, and more.</p></li>
<li><p>This section provides additional details on the evaluation reproducibility and fairness of the work reviewed. Concrete numbers for the assessment of reproducibility and evaluation practices are presented in Tables 2 and 3. Additionally, Tables 4, 5, and 6 show the datasets that have been leaked to ChatGPT, categorized according to the task and the level of leakage.</p></li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Data leakage and evaluation malpractices are prevalent in the evaluation of Large Language Models, particularly with respect to OpenAI’s GPT-3.5 and GPT-4.</li>
<li>ChatGPT demonstrates diverse capabilities, including multilingual learning, information extraction, and addressing real-world issues such as detecting hateful and offensive comments on social media.</li>
<li>ChatGPT shows potential for various applications in the clinical domain, including summarization, question answering, and knowledge retrieval.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The findings highlight the need for improved evaluation practices and transparency in the use of large language models, particularly in addressing data leakage and ensuring fairness and reproducibility.</li>
<li>The diverse capabilities of ChatGPT underscore its potential impact on real-world applications, but further empirical studies and comprehensive evaluations are necessary to understand its effectiveness and limitations in different domains.</li>
<li>The detailed statistics and information provided in the section on evaluation reproducibility and fairness offer transparency and insight into the validity and trustworthiness of the evaluated models and their outputs.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-07</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03927v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03927v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03927v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03927v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>31020</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Leak_Cheat_Repeat_Data_Contamination_and_Evaluation_Malpractices_in_Closed_Source_LLMs/2024-02-06-Leak_Cheat_Repeat_Data_Contamination_and_Evaluation_Malpractices_in_Closed_Source_LLMs.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.03927v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Professional Agents – Evolving Large Language Models into Autonomous Experts with Human-Level Competencies</title>
  <dc:creator>Zhixuan Chu, Yan Wang, Feng Zhu, Lu Yu, Longfei Li, Jinjie Gu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Professional_Agents____Evolving_Large_Language_Models_into_Autonomous_Experts_with_Human_Level_Competencies/2024-02-06-Professional_Agents____Evolving_Large_Language_Models_into_Autonomous_Experts_with_Human_Level_Competencies.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Professional_Agents____Evolving_Large_Language_Models_into_Autonomous_Experts_with_Human_Level_Competencies/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03628v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article introduces the concept of Professional Agents (PAgents) as an application framework that utilizes large language models to create autonomous agents with specialized expertise.</li>
<li>It discusses the genesis, evolution, and multi-agent synergy aspects of PAgents, providing a pipeline for constructing PAgents that can replicate and exceed human-level expertise through continuous learning.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Advancements in Large Language Models (LLMs):</strong>
<ul>
<li>LLMs like GPT-3, PaLM, and ChatGPT demonstrate human-like language fluency and reasoning capacities, showcasing potential for artificial general intelligence (AGI).</li>
<li>LLMs can craft high-quality long-form text, hold conversations, translate between languages, comprehend and respond to queries, and generate code based on textual descriptions.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Agents and Artificial General Intelligence (AGI):</strong>
<ul>
<li>Agents capable of autonomous planning and action have shown promise as a pathway to achieving AGI, adapting to acquire skills and knowledge displayed by human experts in various fields.</li>
<li>The advent of agents with human and super-human level AGI promises to transform professional services in revolutionary ways, expanding the capacities of companies and industries.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Professional Agents Framework:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The PAgents framework entails a tri-layered architecture for genesis, evolution, and synergy, including a base tool layer, middle agent layer, and top synergy layer.</li>
<li>PAgents are initialized according to a specified “gene” and can constantly evolve through self-evolution, coevolution, human feedback evolution, gene refinement, and guidance from superstratum PAgents.</li>
</ul></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article presents a comprehensive framework for developing PAgents, but it raises several challenges and limitations, including sample inefficiency in learning, brittleness when operating outside training distributions, insufficient reasoning abilities for multifaceted tasks, expressing complex motor skills for physical embodiment, and difficulty ensuring human-aligned behavior as agent capabilities grow.</li>
<li>Mitigating these issues to create increasingly capable, safe, and robust PAgents will require innovations in prompt engineering, simulator design, memory architectures, model training techniques, explainability methods, and policy learning algorithms.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-07</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03628v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03628v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03628v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03628v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8060</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Professional_Agents____Evolving_Large_Language_Models_into_Autonomous_Experts_with_Human_Level_Competencies/2024-02-06-Professional_Agents____Evolving_Large_Language_Models_into_Autonomous_Experts_with_Human_Level_Competencies.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03628v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Scaling Laws for Downstream Task Performance of Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Berivan Isik, Natalia Ponomareva, Hussein Hazimeh, Dimitris Paparas, Sergei Vassilvitskii, Sanmi Koyejo</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Scaling_Laws_for_Downstream_Task_Performance_of_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-06-Scaling_Laws_for_Downstream_Task_Performance_of_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.04177v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>B.3 Comparison of T5-3B and T5-770M In Figures 7 and 8, we compare the scaling behavior of T5-3B and T5-770M models for the en-de and en-fr translation tasks. We observe that the scaling laws for both models are consistent with each other, showing similar trends in the scaling behavior for both the BLEU score and the downstream cross-entropy loss. This suggests that the scaling laws are robust and consistent across different model sizes. Figure 7: Comparison of scaling behavior for T5-3B and T5-770M models for the en-de translation task. (top) BLEU score vs pretraining dataset size: f(Dp) = (log(A · Dα p))β. (bottom) Cross-entropy (CE) validation loss vs pretraining dataset size: L(Dp) = E + A Dα p . Figure 8: Comparison of scaling behavior for T5-3B and T5-770M models for the en-fr translation task. (top) BLEU score vs pretraining dataset size: f(Dp) = (log(A · Dα p))β. (bottom) Cross-entropy (CE) validation loss vs pretraining dataset size: L(Dp) = E + A Dα p . Overall, the comparison of the scaling behavior between T5-3B and T5-770M models shows that the scaling laws are consistent and provide similar insights into the relationship between pretraining dataset size and downstream task performance for both models. This consistency across different model sizes adds credibility to the findings and insights derived from the scaling laws.</p>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-07</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.04177v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.04177v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.04177v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.04177v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>15391</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Scaling_Laws_for_Downstream_Task_Performance_of_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-06-Scaling_Laws_for_Downstream_Task_Performance_of_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.04177v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Can Generative Agents Predict Emotion?</title>
  <dc:creator>Ciaran Regan, Nanami Iwahashi, Shogo Tanaka, Mizuki Oka</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Can_Generative_Agents_Predict_Emotion/2024-02-06-Can_Generative_Agents_Predict_Emotion.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/../bayesian-beagle.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article presents a template for PRIME AI Style, providing a structured format for academic writing.</li>
<li>The template includes sections such as Abstract, Keywords, Introduction, Headings, Examples of citations, figures, tables, and Conclusion.</li>
<li>It emphasizes the importance of proper formatting, organization, and citation in academic writing.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The template provides a clear structure for academic writing, including sections such as Abstract, Keywords, Introduction, and Conclusion.</li>
<li>It emphasizes the significance of proper citation and referencing, providing examples of how to cite sources and include figures and tables.</li>
<li>The article highlights the importance of consistency and clarity in academic writing, ensuring that the content is well-organized and easy to follow.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article lacks specific examples or detailed guidelines for writing in the PRIME AI Style, making it challenging for readers to fully understand how to implement the template.</li>
<li>While the template provides a structured format, it does not address potential challenges or variations in academic writing, such as different citation styles or specific requirements for various disciplines.</li>
<li>The article could benefit from more practical examples and detailed explanations to help readers effectively apply the PRIME AI Style template in their academic writing.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-07</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.04232v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.04232v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.04232v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.04232v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>2475</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Can_Generative_Agents_Predict_Emotion/2024-02-06-Can_Generative_Agents_Predict_Emotion.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Position Paper: Against Spurious Sparks-Dovelating Inflated AI Claims</title>
  <dc:creator>Patrick Altmeyer, Andrew M. Demetriou, Antony Bartlett, Cynthia C. S. Liem</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Position_Paper_Against_Spurious_Sparks_Dovelating_Inflated_AI_Claims/2024-02-06-Position_Paper_Against_Spurious_Sparks_Dovelating_Inflated_AI_Claims.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.03962v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<p>In this position paper, the authors discuss the tendency to attribute human-like qualities to Large Language Models (LLMs) in the context of Artificial General Intelligence (AGI). They argue that the current search for AGI is prone to over-attributing human-like qualities to LLMs due to professional incentives, human biases, and methodological setups. The authors present several experiments to demonstrate that the discovery of human-interpretable patterns in latent spaces should not be a surprising outcome. They also call for the academic community to exercise extra caution in interpreting and communicating about AI research outcomes.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The authors argue that the current search for AGI is prone to over-attributing human-like qualities to LLMs due to professional incentives, human biases, and methodological setups.</li>
<li>Several experiments demonstrate that the discovery of human-interpretable patterns in latent spaces should not be a surprising outcome.</li>
<li>The authors call for the academic community to exercise extra caution in interpreting and communicating about AI research outcomes.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The authors provide a comprehensive and critical analysis of the current state of AI research, highlighting the potential biases and limitations in interpreting AI outcomes.</li>
<li>They emphasize the need for rigorous testing and caution in attributing human-like qualities to AI systems, especially in the context of AGI.</li>
<li>The paper raises important questions about the interpretation and communication of AI research outcomes, calling for a more nuanced and thorough approach to understanding the capabilities of AI systems.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the paper provides valuable insights into the challenges and potential biases in AI research, emphasizing the need for critical evaluation and careful interpretation of AI outcomes.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-07</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03962v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03962v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03962v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03962v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>15626</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Position_Paper_Against_Spurious_Sparks_Dovelating_Inflated_AI_Claims/2024-02-06-Position_Paper_Against_Spurious_Sparks_Dovelating_Inflated_AI_Claims.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.03962v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Systematic Biases in LLM Simulations of Debates</title>
  <dc:creator>Amir Taubenfeld, Yaniv Dover, Roi Reichart, Ariel Goldstein</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Systematic_Biases_in_LLM_Simulations_of_Debates/2024-02-06-Systematic_Biases_in_LLM_Simulations_of_Debates.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.04049v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Recent advancements in natural language processing, especially the emergence of Large Language Models (LLMs), have opened exciting possibilities for constructing computational simulations designed to replicate human behavior accurately.</li>
<li>However, LLMs are complex statistical learners without straightforward deductive rules, making them prone to unexpected behaviors.</li>
<li>In this study, the limitations of LLMs in simulating human interactions, particularly focusing on LLMs’ ability to simulate political debates, are highlighted.</li>
<li>Findings indicate a tendency for LLM agents to conform to the model’s inherent social biases despite being directed to debate from certain political perspectives.</li>
<li>The study reinforces these observations using an automatic self-fine-tuning method, which enables the manipulation of the biases within the LLM and demonstrates that agents subsequently align with the altered biases.</li>
<li>These results underscore the need for further research to develop methods that help agents overcome these biases, a critical step toward creating more realistic simulations.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLM agents tend to conform to the model’s inherent social biases despite being directed to debate from certain political perspectives.</li>
<li>The study reinforces these observations using an automatic self-fine-tuning method, which enables the manipulation of the biases within the LLM and demonstrates that agents subsequently align with the altered biases.</li>
<li>The results underscore the need for further research to develop methods that help agents overcome these biases, a critical step toward creating more realistic simulations.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study provides valuable insights into the limitations of LLMs in simulating human interactions, particularly in the context of political debates.</li>
<li>The findings raise important questions about the reliability and accuracy of LLM-based simulations, especially in capturing diverse human perspectives and behaviors.</li>
<li>The study’s focus on the need for further research to develop methods that help agents overcome biases is a critical step toward creating more realistic simulations.</li>
<li>However, the study’s scope is limited to debates involving LLM agents, and further research is needed to explore the broader implications of LLM biases in large-scale simulations and real-world applications.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-07</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.04049v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.04049v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.04049v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.04049v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>12506</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Systematic_Biases_in_LLM_Simulations_of_Debates/2024-02-06-Systematic_Biases_in_LLM_Simulations_of_Debates.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.04049v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Iterative Prompt Refinement for Radiation Oncology Symptom Extraction Using Teacher-Student Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Reza Khanmohammadi, Ahmed I Ghanem, Kyle Verdecchia, Ryan Hall, Mohamed Elshaikh, Benjamin Movsas, Hassan Bagher-Ebadian, Indrin Chetty, Mohammad M. Ghassemi, Kundan Thind</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Iterative_Prompt_Refinement_for_Radiation_Oncology_Symptom_Extraction_Using_Teacher_Student_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-06-Iterative_Prompt_Refinement_for_Radiation_Oncology_Symptom_Extraction_Using_Teacher_Student_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.04075v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study introduces a novel teacher-student architecture using Large Language Models (LLMs) to improve prostate cancer radiotherapy symptom extraction from clinical notes.</li>
<li>The iterative prompt refinement process involved 294 single symptom clinical notes across 12 symptoms, with up to 16 rounds of refinement per epoch.</li>
<li>Results showed significant improvements in extracting symptoms from both single and multi-symptom notes.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The teacher-student architecture using Large Language Models (LLMs) significantly improved the extraction of symptoms from both single and multi-symptom clinical notes.</li>
<li>The iterative prompt refinement process led to substantial increases in accuracy, precision, recall, and F1 scores for both single and multi-symptom notes.</li>
<li>The study demonstrated the effectiveness of advanced prompt engineering in LLMs for radiation oncology use.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study’s findings are promising, but potential limitations include the small sample size of single symptom notes used for optimization, which may have led to overfitting.</li>
<li>Hyperparameter selection for both student and teacher models could have a significant impact on the overall optimization process and should be further explored.</li>
<li>The study’s approach presents a pathway for self-optimized local LLM agents that can extract key concepts in medical notes with a zero-shot learning approach, addressing data privacy concerns in healthcare. However, further research and experimentation are needed to enhance robustness and performance.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-07</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.04075v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.04075v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.04075v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.04075v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5555</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Iterative_Prompt_Refinement_for_Radiation_Oncology_Symptom_Extraction_Using_Teacher_Student_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-06-Iterative_Prompt_Refinement_for_Radiation_Oncology_Symptom_Extraction_Using_Teacher_Student_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.04075v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Can Large Language Models Detect Rumors on Social Media?</title>
  <dc:creator>Qiang Liu, Xiang Tao, Junfei Wu, Shu Wu, Liang Wang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Can_Large_Language_Models_Detect_Rumors_on_Social_Media/2024-02-06-Can_Large_Language_Models_Detect_Rumors_on_Social_Media.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.03916v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The authors propose the LeRuD approach to address the challenges of reasoning over complex propagation information on social media, using prompts to teach LLMs to concentrate on important clues in news and comments, and dividing the propagation information into a Chain-of-Propagation to reduce the burden on LLMs.</li>
<li>Extensive experiments on Twitter and Weibo datasets show that LeRuD outperforms several state-of-the-art rumor detection models by 2.4% to 7.6% and demonstrates promising rumor detection ability in few-shot or zero-shot scenarios.</li>
<li>LeRuD uses reasoning from a commonsense perspective to judge the credibility of news samples, considering factors such as the regularity of writing, adequacy of details, plausibility of contents, attitudes of the public, and consistency of comments to make its judgments.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LeRuD outperforms several state-of-the-art rumor detection models by 2.4% to 7.6%.</li>
<li>LeRuD demonstrates promising rumor detection ability in few-shot or zero-shot scenarios.</li>
<li>LeRuD uses reasoning from a commonsense perspective to judge the credibility of news samples, considering various factors to make its judgments.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The LeRuD approach addresses the limitations of LLMs in reasoning over excessive information and presents a novel solution to improve their performance in detecting rumors on social media platforms.</li>
<li>The use of AI to assess the credibility of news based on user comments on social media platforms has implications for combating misinformation and fake news by leveraging AI technology to gauge public trust and skepticism.</li>
<li>The analysis of news articles and comments highlights the importance of considering writing style, specific details, and the presence of conflicting opinions in the comments to determine the credibility of news sources. This process demonstrates the significance of critical evaluation in assessing the authenticity of news.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-07</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03916v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03916v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03916v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03916v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>27219</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Can_Large_Language_Models_Detect_Rumors_on_Social_Media/2024-02-06-Can_Large_Language_Models_Detect_Rumors_on_Social_Media.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.03916v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Automatic Robotic Development through Collaborative Framework by Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Zhirong Luan, Yujun Lai</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Automatic_Robotic_Development_through_Collaborative_Framework_by_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-06-Automatic_Robotic_Development_through_Collaborative_Framework_by_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.03699v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article proposes an automated collaboration framework for robot development using large language models (LLMs).</li>
<li>The framework employs multiple LLMs in distinct roles—analysts, programmers, and testers—to handle diverse, critical tasks within the development process.</li>
<li>Through this framework, complex robot development tasks can be accomplished without requiring specialized knowledge, relying solely on non-experts’ participation.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The proposed framework utilizes multiple LLMs in distinct roles—analysts, programmers, and testers—to handle diverse, critical tasks within the development process.</li>
<li>Analysts delve deep into user requirements, enabling programmers to produce precise code, while testers fine-tune the parameters based on user feedback for practical robot application.</li>
<li>Clear collaboration rules emulate real-world teamwork among LLMs, enabling individuals with no expertise in robotics to accomplish highly complex robot development tasks.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article presents a novel approach to automated robot development, but it may face challenges in real-world implementation and practical scalability.</li>
<li>The reliance on large language models for complex tasks raises concerns about the interpretability and explainability of the generated code.</li>
<li>The experimental results demonstrate the feasibility of the proposed framework, but further research is needed to address potential limitations and refine the collaborative development process.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-07</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03699v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03699v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03699v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03699v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5670</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Automatic_Robotic_Development_through_Collaborative_Framework_by_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-06-Automatic_Robotic_Development_through_Collaborative_Framework_by_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.03699v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Embedding Large Language Models into Extended Reality: Opportunities and Challenges for Inclusion, Engagement, and Privacy</title>
  <dc:creator>Efe Bozkir, Süleyman Özdel, Ka Hei Carrie Lau, Mengdi Wang, Hong Gao, Enkelejda Kasneci</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Embedding_Large_Language_Models_into_Extended_Reality_Opportunities_and_Challenges_for_Inclusion_Engagement_and_Privacy/2024-02-06-Embedding_Large_Language_Models_into_Extended_Reality_Opportunities_and_Challenges_for_Inclusion_Engagement_and_Privacy.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.03907v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Recent developments in computer graphics, hardware, artificial intelligence (AI), and human-computer interaction have led to extended reality (XR) devices and setups becoming more pervasive.</li>
<li>Large language models (LLMs) can be embedded in virtual avatars or as narratives to facilitate more inclusive experiences through prompt engineering according to user profiles and fine-tuning the LLMs for particular purposes.</li>
<li>LLMs can enhance diversity, equity, and engagement in XR environments, but may also lead to privacy invasions.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs can be used to create more inclusive and engaging XR experiences through prompt engineering and fine-tuning for specific purposes.</li>
<li>The versatile conversational capabilities of LLMs can lead to more engaging XR environments, making XR more pervasive in everyday life.</li>
<li>Combining user-provided information with biometric sensor data in LLM-powered environments may lead to novel privacy invasions, necessitating an investigation into user privacy concerns and preferences.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The use of LLMs in XR environments presents promising opportunities for inclusion, diversity, and engagement. However, the potential for privacy invasions and the ethical implications of combining user-provided information with biometric data need to be carefully considered and addressed.</li>
<li>The rapid advancements in LLM technology and its integration into XR environments may outpace the development of ethical guidelines and privacy-preserving methods, posing a challenge for researchers and developers.</li>
<li>Longitudinal studies and ongoing assessments of user privacy attitudes and behaviors in LLM-powered XR environments are necessary to ensure that privacy concerns are adequately addressed.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-07</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03907v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03907v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03907v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03907v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>13421</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Embedding_Large_Language_Models_into_Extended_Reality_Opportunities_and_Challenges_for_Inclusion_Engagement_and_Privacy/2024-02-06-Embedding_Large_Language_Models_into_Extended_Reality_Opportunities_and_Challenges_for_Inclusion_Engagement_and_Privacy.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.03907v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Batch Universal Prediction</title>
  <dc:creator>Marco Bondaschi, Michael Gastpar</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Batch_Universal_Prediction/2024-02-06-Batch_Universal_Prediction.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/../bayesian-beagle.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Large language models (LLMs) have gained popularity for generating human-like English sentences.</li>
<li>LLMs are predictors that estimate the probability of a sequence of words given the past.</li>
<li>The article introduces the notion of batch regret and studies its asymptotical value for add-constant predictors in memoryless and first-order Markov sources.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs are essentially predictors that estimate the probability of the next words in an online fashion.</li>
<li>The article introduces the concept of batch regret as a modification of the classical average regret to evaluate LLMs from a universal prediction perspective.</li>
<li>The study focuses on the asymptotical batch regret for add-constant predictors in memoryless and first-order Markov sources.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides valuable insights into the evaluation of large language models from a universal prediction perspective.</li>
<li>However, the article lacks practical examples or applications of the proposed concepts.</li>
<li>The theoretical nature of the study may limit its immediate applicability in real-world scenarios.</li>
<li>Further research is needed to validate the proposed concepts in practical settings and to explore their potential impact on language model evaluation.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-07</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03901v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.03901v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03901v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.03901v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8083</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Batch_Universal_Prediction/2024-02-06-Batch_Universal_Prediction.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
