<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Bayesian beagle</title>
<link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Quarto blog of LLM-generated summaries of Arxiv preprints</description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.450</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>The Butterfly Effect of Altering Prompts: How Small Changes and Jailbreaks Affect Large Language Model Performance</title>
  <dc:creator>Abel Salinas, Fred Morstatter</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/The_Butterfly_Effect_of_Altering_Prompts_How_Small_Changes_and_Jailbreaks_Affect_Large_Language_Model_Performance/2024-01-08-The_Butterfly_Effect_of_Altering_Prompts_How_Small_Changes_and_Jailbreaks_Affect_Large_Language_Model_Performance.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/The_Butterfly_Effect_of_Altering_Prompts_How_Small_Changes_and_Jailbreaks_Affect_Large_Language_Model_Performance/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03729v1/extracted/5335133/figures/aggregate/aggregate-labels-styles-only.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="major-takeaways" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-takeaways">Major Takeaways</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><p>Prompting variations, including output format, perturbations, jailbreaks, and tipping, significantly impact the predictions and accuracy of Large Language Models (LLMs) across various text classification tasks.</p></li>
<li><p>Even minor changes to prompts, such as adding a space or using different output formats like JSON or CSV, can cause LLMs to change their answers and impact their accuracy.</p></li>
<li><p>Jailbreaks, used to bypass LLM content filters for sensitive topics, can lead to substantial changes in predictions and considerable performance losses.</p></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="summary-of-sections" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-of-sections">Summary of Sections</h3>
<section id="introduction" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h4>
<ul>
<li>Large Language Models (LLMs) have become popular for labeling data, with prompt construction being a crucial process involving decisions on wording, output format, and jailbreaks for sensitive topics.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="related-work" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="related-work">Related Work</h4>
<ul>
<li>Prompt generation and its impact on LLM behavior has been recognized in related literature, highlighting the importance of variations in prompts and prompt ensembles for robust insights.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="methodology" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="methodology">Methodology</h4>
<ul>
<li>The study explores prompt variations in output formats, perturbations, jailbreaks, and tipping across 11 text classification tasks, using OpenAI’s ChatGPT.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="results" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="results">Results</h4>
<ul>
<li>Prompt variations lead to changes in LLM predictions, with formatting specifications, minor perturbations, and jailbreaks affecting accuracy. The similarity of predictions across different prompt variations is explored, and the correlation between prompt variations and annotator disagreement is studied, revealing the minimal impact of confusion on prediction changes.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="conclusion" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="conclusion">Conclusion</h4>
<ul>
<li>Overall, prompt variations, particularly formatting changes and jailbreaks, have a significant impact on LLM predictions and accuracy, with implications for future work on generating LLMs resilient to prompt variations.</li>
</ul>
</section>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<p>The study provides a comprehensive analysis of how prompt variations affect LLM performance. However, the findings should be interpreted with caution due to the study’s reliance on a specific LLM model (ChatGPT) and prompt variations that may not generalize to all LLMs. Additionally, the impact of these prompt variations on real-world applications and user interactions with LLMs remains to be explored. Further research could involve wider experimentation across different LLMs and application scenarios to validate the generalizability of these findings.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-09</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.03729v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.03729v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03729v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03729v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6734</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/The_Butterfly_Effect_of_Altering_Prompts_How_Small_Changes_and_Jailbreaks_Affect_Large_Language_Model_Performance/2024-01-08-The_Butterfly_Effect_of_Altering_Prompts_How_Small_Changes_and_Jailbreaks_Affect_Large_Language_Model_Performance.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03729v1/extracted/5335133/figures/aggregate/aggregate-labels-styles-only.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Assessing AI Detectors in Identifying AI-Generated Code: Implications for Education</title>
  <dc:creator>Wei Hung Pan, Ming Jie Chok, Jonathan Leong Shan Wong, Yung Xin Shin, Yeong Shian Poon, Zhou Yang, Chun Yong Chong, David Lo, Mei Kuan Lim</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Assessing_AI_Detectors_in_Identifying_AI_Generated_Code_Implications_for_Education/2024-01-08-Assessing_AI_Detectors_in_Identifying_AI_Generated_Code_Implications_for_Education.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Assessing_AI_Detectors_in_Identifying_AI_Generated_Code_Implications_for_Education/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03676v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="assessing-ai-detectors-in-identifying-ai-generated-code-implications-for-education" class="level1">
<h1>Assessing AI Detectors in Identifying AI-Generated Code: Implications for Education</h1>
<section id="key-findings" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="key-findings">Key Findings</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Existing AIGC Detectors perform poorly</strong> in distinguishing between human-written code and AI-generated code, indicating the inherent weaknesses of current detectors. This underscores the need for further research and development in this domain to enhance their efficacy.</li>
<li>Variations in the prompts used to generate AI-generated content significantly impact the <strong>sensitivity and accuracy</strong> of AIGC Detectors, particularly the GLTR model.</li>
<li>A need for <strong>comprehensive guidelines and policies</strong> to safeguard the responsible and ethical usage of AI in the educational context is emphasized. Educators are encouraged to consider the <strong>integration of generative AI</strong> into education processes, the automation level, and its ethical focus.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="abstract" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="abstract">Abstract</h2>
<p>The paper presents an empirical study evaluating the performance of AI-generated content (AIGC) detectors in distinguish AI-generated code from human-written code. A dataset comprising programming problems and corresponding human-written and AI-generated Python solutions was collected from various online sources. 13 variations of prompts were used to instruct an AI model to generate outputs, and the performance of five AIGC detectors was evaluated. Results indicate that existing detectors perform poorly in distinguishing AI-generated from human-written code.</p>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<ul>
<li>Large Language Models (LLMs) have advanced to the point of generating human-like code, raising concerns in programming education about potential academic misconduct.</li>
<li>Accessibility of LLMs has implications for educational assessment and academic dishonesty, thereby compelling educators to utilize AIGC Detectors to ascertain student integrity.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="background-and-motivations" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="background-and-motivations">Background and Motivations</h2>
<ul>
<li>Software Engineering (SE) and Computer Science (CS) education are significantly impacted by the emergence of generative AI, introducing complexities and challenges in educational assessment and evaluation.</li>
<li>There is a noticeable impact on academic dishonesty due to growing student reliance on AI-driven solutions.</li>
<li>Educators find themselves compelled to utilize AIGC Detectors, while the limitations of these detectors in recognizing AI-generated code remain uncertain.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="empirical-study-design-and-methodology" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="empirical-study-design-and-methodology">Empirical Study Design and Methodology</h2>
<ul>
<li>The study includes the research questions, methodology, process overview, and data collection details.</li>
<li>Research questions revolve around the accuracy and limitations of existing AIGC Detectors in detecting AI-generated code, evaluating their effectiveness and potential vulnerabilities with different code variants.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="results" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="results">Results</h2>
<ul>
<li>Existing AIGC Detectors perform poorly in distinguishing between human-written and AI-generated code, indicating the inherent weaknesses of current detectors. GLTR demonstrates the highest sensitivity and significant variability across different code variants.</li>
<li>Limitations of AIGC Detectors include their struggle in detecting AI-generated code accurately, highlighting the need for ongoing research and development to enhance their reliability.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="discussion" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="discussion">Discussion</h2>
<ul>
<li>Suggestions are provided for SE and CS educators to address the challenges and opportunities presented by the integration of AI into education.</li>
<li>Key areas for improvement include defining objectives, considering automation levels, focusing on ethical considerations, continuous evaluation, and comprehensive policies.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="threats-to-validity" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="threats-to-validity">Threats to Validity</h2>
<ul>
<li>The study acknowledges challenges related to prompts used for AIGC generation, verification of human-written code, and the impact of vague queries on AIGC Detector performance.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="conclusion-and-future-work" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="conclusion-and-future-work">Conclusion and Future Work</h2>
<ul>
<li>Promising opportunities exist for AIGC Detector tools to positively impact education, but challenges need to be addressed. Ethical guidelines and ongoing tool refinement are vital for responsible AI usage in education.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="data-availability" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="data-availability">Data Availability</h2>
<p>The replication package, including associated data, has been made publicly available for transparency and reproducibility.</p>
</section>
<section id="critique-and-potential-problems" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique-and-potential-problems">Critique and Potential Problems</h2>
<ul>
<li>The study’s reliance on one specific type of AI model, ChatGPT, might limit the generalizability of the findings to other AI models.</li>
<li>The study could benefit from a more diverse range of programming languages and problem types to better assess the performance of AIGC Detectors in a broader context.</li>
<li>The implications of the findings on educational practice and student learning outcomes could be further elucidated for a more comprehensive understanding of the study’s practical significance.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-09</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.03676v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.03676v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03676v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03676v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>12715</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>programming</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Assessing_AI_Detectors_in_Identifying_AI_Generated_Code_Implications_for_Education/2024-01-08-Assessing_AI_Detectors_in_Identifying_AI_Generated_Code_Implications_for_Education.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03676v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>LLMs for Robotic Object Disambiguation</title>
  <dc:creator>Connie Jiang, Yiqing Xu, David Hsu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLMs_for_Robotic_Object_Disambiguation/2024-01-07-LLMs_for_Robotic_Object_Disambiguation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLMs_for_Robotic_Object_Disambiguation/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03388v1/extracted/5332947/ManeuveringOccludingFig.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Pre-trained large language models (LLMs) demonstrate capability in solving complex decision making challenges in robotics</strong> such as object disambiguation tasks within tabletop environments. The model efficiently identifies and retrieves a desired object from a cluttered scene.</li>
<li>The LLMs are capable of efficiently disambiguating any object from any arbitrarily large tabletop scene by harnessing the “common sense” knowledge embedded in the model.</li>
<li><strong>Few-shot prompt engineering significantly improves the LLM’s ability to pose disambiguating queries</strong>, allowing the model to generate and navigate down a precise decision tree to the correct object, even when faced with identical options.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="i-introduction" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="i-introduction">I Introduction</h3>
<ul>
<li>Several challenges in disambiguating objects from a scene.
<ul>
<li>Developing a multi-step plan for disambiguation.</li>
<li>Inferring new features if the scene description provided is insufficient.</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Previous methods of solving this task have limitations.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="ii-related-work" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="ii-related-work">II Related Work</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Prior methods</strong> of disambiguation include enumeration, greedy approach, and attribute-guided disambiguation.</li>
<li><strong>Growing research</strong> on the use of LLMs in robotics, specifically for decision making, is evident.</li>
<li><strong>Advantages</strong> of using LLMs for disambiguation tasks in robotics are highlighted.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="iii-problem-formulation" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="iii-problem-formulation">III Problem Formulation</h3>
<ul>
<li>Generalizing user requests to interpret and respond to any reasonable, generalized request.</li>
<li>Maneuvering occluding objects, such as relocating obstructing objects to access the desired one.</li>
<li><strong>Disambiguating the target object</strong> stands as the primary focus with a detailed description of this task and its limitations.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="iv-proposed-method" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="iv-proposed-method">IV Proposed Method</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Few-shot prompt-engineering approach</strong> proposed to enable the LLM to generate its own features.</li>
<li><strong>Results</strong> from employing this approach and an example of results are provided to illustrate the improvement in the model’s ability to infer features.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="v-experiments" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="v-experiments">V Experiments</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Comparison</strong> of the model’s performance with four baseline methods, including optimal split, enumeration, human performance, and POMDP-ATTR.</li>
<li>Conducted experiments in twelve distinct scenes to evaluate the model’s performance and accuracy.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="vi-results" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="vi-results">VI Results</h3>
<ul>
<li>The effective performance of the proposed model is highlighted, detailing its <strong>efficiency and success rate</strong> in disambiguating target objects.</li>
<li><strong>Visual representations</strong> of the results are used to present the findings effectively.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="vii-next-steps" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="vii-next-steps">VII Next Steps</h3>
<ul>
<li>Plans for <strong>completing the visual portion</strong> of the pipeline and further details on zero-shot and few-shot prompting are outlined as the next steps for the research.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<ul>
<li>While the study demonstrates the effectiveness of LLMs for object disambiguation, limitations in inferring unspecified features are highlighted, posing potential challenges in more complex scenes.</li>
<li>The comparison with baseline methods provides a benchmark, but the study could benefit from a more extensive comparison with a wider range of existing methods in the field.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-09</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.03388v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.03388v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03388v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03388v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5796</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLMs_for_Robotic_Object_Disambiguation/2024-01-07-LLMs_for_Robotic_Object_Disambiguation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03388v1/extracted/5332947/ManeuveringOccludingFig.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Grimoire is All You Need for Enhancing Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Ding Chen, Shichao Song, Qingchen Yu, Zhiyu Li, Wenjin Wang, Feiyu Xiong, Bo Tang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Grimoire_is_All_You_Need_for_Enhancing_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-07-Grimoire_is_All_You_Need_for_Enhancing_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Grimoire_is_All_You_Need_for_Enhancing_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03385v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><p><strong>SleIcl Method</strong>: The paper introduces a method called SleIcl for enhancing the performance of weak language models by utilizing strong language models to learn from representative samples and distill skills for solving specific tasks, known as grimoire.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Grimoire Types</strong>: The paper explores four representative sample selection methods and a zero-shot approach, alongside two grimoire generation templates, resulting in the creation of 10 types of single grimoires.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Performance Improvement</strong>: The study demonstrates that the SleIcl method substantially enhances the performance of weak language models with varying parameter sizes on diverse tasks, with smaller models exhibiting more pronounced improvements. On certain datasets, weak language models, with the aid of the method, outperformed GPT4-1106-preview in zero-shot scenarios.</p></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="related-works" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="related-works">Related Works</h3>
<ul>
<li><p><strong>In-context Learning of Large Language Model</strong>: The paper discusses the significance of In-context Learning (ICL) in enhancing the performance of large language models on specific tasks. It emphasizes the importance of data structure and the influence of contextual learning on the model’s latent concepts and specific functions.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Prompt Engineering of Demo Examples</strong>: The construction and ordering of demonstration examples significantly impact ICL performance. The study explores the characteristics, ordering, and selection strategies of demonstration examples.</p></li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<p>The paper provides a comprehensive exploration of the SleIcl method and its applicability in enhancing the performance of weak language models. However, it could benefit from a more in-depth analysis of the potential limitations or challenges in implementing the proposed SleIcl method. Additionally, concrete examples or case studies showcasing the real-world application of the SleIcl method would enhance the practical understanding of its effectiveness.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-09</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.03385v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.03385v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03385v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03385v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7777</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Grimoire_is_All_You_Need_for_Enhancing_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-07-Grimoire_is_All_You_Need_for_Enhancing_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03385v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>An Investigation of Large Language Models for Real-World Hate Speech Detection</title>
  <dc:creator>Keyan Guo, Alexander Hu, Jaden Mu, Ziheng Shi, Ziming Zhao, Nishant Vishwamitra, Hongxin Hu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/An_Investigation_of_Large_Language_Models_for_Real_World_Hate_Speech_Detection/2024-01-07-An_Investigation_of_Large_Language_Models_for_Real_World_Hate_Speech_Detection.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/An_Investigation_of_Large_Language_Models_for_Real_World_Hate_Speech_Detection/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Key Takeaways</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated strong performance in identifying hate speech, even surpassing benchmark machine learning models in some cases.</li>
<li>The choice of <strong>prompting strategies</strong> significantly impacts the effectiveness of LLMs in detecting hate speech, with a carefully crafted reasoning prompt showing the most promising results.</li>
<li>LLMs show proficiency in detecting hate speech in English but underperform in non-English text, highlighting the need for further investigation into multilingual hate speech detection.</li>
</ul>
<section id="introduction" class="level1">
<h1>Introduction</h1>
<ul>
<li>Hate speech is a significant issue in online spaces, and existing methods for detecting it are limited in capturing contextual nuances.</li>
<li>Large language models (LLMs) have shown promise in addressing this limitation due to their extensive training on natural language data, but there is a lack of studies on effectively prompting LLMs for hate speech detection.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="background-and-related-work" class="level1">
<h1>Background and Related Work</h1>
<section id="hate-speech-detection" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="hate-speech-detection">Hate Speech Detection</h2>
<ul>
<li>Hate speech online has become a critical threat, with current AI/ML detectors primarily relying on supervised learning techniques and facing limitations in capturing the contextual diversity of hate speech.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="llms-and-prompts-based-hate-speech-detection" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="llms-and-prompts-based-hate-speech-detection">LLMs and Prompts-based Hate Speech Detection</h2>
<ul>
<li>LLMs, like ChatGPT, have shown proficiency in natural language tasks, and prompting strategies have been found effective in guiding LLMs for specific tasks.</li>
<li>Prior studies have explored LLMs for hate speech detection but there is a need for a more comprehensive understanding of LLMs’ proficiency, especially with varied prompting strategies.</li>
</ul>
</section>
</section>
<section id="hate-speech-datasets" class="level1">
<h1>Hate Speech Datasets</h1>
<ul>
<li>The study employs five diverse hate speech datasets, each with specific characteristics and compositions, providing a comprehensive basis for evaluation.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="prompt-engineering-for-hate-speech-detection" class="level1">
<h1>Prompt-engineering for Hate Speech Detection</h1>
<ul>
<li>The study introduces four diverse prompting strategies - general prompt, general prompt with hate speech definition, few-shot learning prompt, and chain-of-thought prompt.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="measuring-the-effectiveness-of-prompting-strategies" class="level1">
<h1>Measuring the Effectiveness of Prompting Strategies</h1>
<section id="llm-based-general-prompting-strategy-vs.-baselines" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="llm-based-general-prompting-strategy-vs.-baselines">LLM-based General Prompting Strategy vs.&nbsp;Baselines</h2>
<ul>
<li>LLMs consistently outperform benchmark models, demonstrating higher accuracy and F1 scores in hate speech detection.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="analysis-of-different-prompts" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-of-different-prompts">Analysis of Different Prompts</h2>
<ul>
<li>Different prompts show varying levels of effectiveness, with the chain-of-thought reasoning prompt outperforming others, indicating the high impact of prompt design on model performance.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="effectiveness-of-llms-against-multilingual-hate-speech" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="effectiveness-of-llms-against-multilingual-hate-speech">Effectiveness of LLMs against multilingual hate speech</h2>
<ul>
<li>LLMs show proficiency in detecting hate speech in English but underperform in non-English text, highlighting the need for further investigation into multilingual hate speech detection.</li>
</ul>
</section>
</section>
<section id="conclusion-and-future-work" class="level1">
<h1>Conclusion and Future Work</h1>
<ul>
<li>The study fills an important gap in exploring effective LLM prompting strategies for hate speech detection, with potential future research in multilingual settings and multimodal hate speech detection.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Critique and Potential Problems</strong> - The study is limited to specific prompting strategies and datasets, potentially overlooking other effective strategies and diverse hate speech instances. - The findings may not be generalizable to all LLMs or applicable to all hate speech contexts.</p>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-09</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.03346v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.03346v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03346v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03346v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6521</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/An_Investigation_of_Large_Language_Models_for_Real_World_Hate_Speech_Detection/2024-01-07-An_Investigation_of_Large_Language_Models_for_Real_World_Hate_Speech_Detection.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>InFoBench: Evaluating Instruction Following Ability in Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Yiwei Qin, Kaiqiang Song, Yebowen Hu, Wenlin Yao, Sangwoo Cho, Xiaoyang Wang, Xuansheng Wu, Fei Liu, Pengfei Liu, Dong Yu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/InFoBench_Evaluating_Instruction_Following_Ability_in_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-07-InFoBench_Evaluating_Instruction_Following_Ability_in_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/InFoBench_Evaluating_Instruction_Following_Ability_in_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03601v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary</h2>
<section id="findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="findings">Findings</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper introduces a new metric, the <strong>Decomposed Requirements Following Ratio (DRFR)</strong>, for evaluating Large Language Models’ (LLMs) ability to follow instructions.</li>
<li>The study compares DRFR with traditional scoring methods and explores annotation sources, finding DRFR to have higher reliability and GPT-4 to be a cost-effective annotator.</li>
<li>The evaluation of several advanced LLMs using this framework reveals their strengths and areas needing improvement, particularly in complex instruction-following.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h3>
<p>The paper addresses the lack of evaluation methodologies dedicated to the crucial aspect of instruction-following in Large Language Models (LLMs) and aims to establish a reliable protocol and benchmark for appraising the instruction-following aptitude of LLMs.</p>
</section>
<section id="infobench" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="infobench">InFoBench</h3>
<ul>
<li>Introduces <strong>DRFR</strong> and <strong>InFoBench</strong>, a benchmark dataset, for assessing LLMs’ proficiency in adhering to complex instructions in a detailed and structured manner.</li>
<li>DRFR decomposes each instruction into distinct, simpler criteria, allowing a granular analysis of a model’s performance.</li>
<li>InFoBench dataset presents diverse instructions and decomposed questions across different constraint categories.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="experiments" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="experiments">Experiments</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Compared DRFR with traditional Direct Scoring (DS), results showed higher annotator consensus with DRFR, indicating its enhanced reliability.</li>
<li>Explored cost-efficient annotation sources, finding GPT-4 to be highly accurate, cost-effective, and time-efficient.</li>
<li>Employed GPT-4 as an annotator and evaluated advanced LLMs, revealing the need for improvement in handling complex instructions.</li>
</ol>
</section>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h2>
<p>The paper presents significant contributions to the evaluation of LLMs’ instruction-following abilities. However, it has limitations: 1. The reliance on human annotation for only a fraction of the instruction set limits the reliability of comparisons among different annotations. 2. The dataset size is limited, and the manual nature of instruction writing restricts scalability. 3. The evaluation primarily focuses on the explicit intentions contained within the provided instructions, neglecting crucial factors such as truthfulness and harmlessness.</p>
<p>Overall, while the paper’s contributions pave the way for future research and development in LLM evaluation, the limitations in dataset size and human annotation demonstrate areas for potential improvement.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-09</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.03601v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.03601v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03601v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03601v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>13442</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/InFoBench_Evaluating_Instruction_Following_Ability_in_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-07-InFoBench_Evaluating_Instruction_Following_Ability_in_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03601v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>ChatGPT for Conversational Recommendation: Refining Recommendations by Reprompting with Feedback</title>
  <dc:creator>Kyle Dylan Spurlock, Cagla Acun, Esin Saka, Olfa Nasraoui</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ChatGPT_for_Conversational_Recommendation_Refining_Recommendations_by_Reprompting_with_Feedback/2024-01-07-ChatGPT_for_Conversational_Recommendation_Refining_Recommendations_by_Reprompting_with_Feedback.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ChatGPT_for_Conversational_Recommendation_Refining_Recommendations_by_Reprompting_with_Feedback/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03605v1/extracted/5334641/figures/methodology.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary</h3>
<p>In the paper “ChatGPT for Conversational Recommendation: Refining Recommendations by Reprompting with Feedback,” the authors investigate the effectiveness of <strong>ChatGPT</strong> as a conversational recommendation system. They develop a pipeline to rigorously evaluate ChatGPT’s recommendation ability using conversation and explore the impact of popularity bias in its recommendations.</p>
<section id="major-takeaways" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-takeaways">Major Takeaways</h4>
<ol type="1">
<li><p><strong>Conversation Improves Recommendation Relevancy:</strong> Reprompting ChatGPT with feedback is found to be an effective strategy to improve recommendation relevancy.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>ChatGPT Outperforms Baseline Models:</strong> ChatGPT is significantly better than both a random and traditional recommender systems, showcasing its utility in zero-shot recommendation tasks.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Popularity Bias Mitigation:</strong> The study examines strategies to counteract popularity bias in ChatGPT’s recommendations, highlighting the potential for more novel recommendations.</p></li>
</ol>
</section>
</section>
<section id="methodology" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="methodology">Methodology</h3>
<ul>
<li><p><strong>Prompt Engineering</strong>: The paper discusses the three predominant means of communication with LLMs through prompting: zero-shot, few-shot, and chain-of-thought prompting.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Language Models as Recommenders</strong>: The extensive domain knowledge encapsulated in Large Language Models (LLMs) has recently captured interest for their use in recommendation tasks.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Algorithmic Recourse</strong>: The paper draws parallels with the concept of algorithmic recourse and highlights the differences in the context of a recommendation system.</p></li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="experiments" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="experiments">Experiments</h3>
<ul>
<li><p><strong>Effect of Embedding Content</strong>: The study validates the impact of embedding content on recommendation results and identifies content level 4 embeddings as the most suitable for experimentation.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Iterative Feedback Analysis</strong>: The authors explore the impact of reprompting with feedback during a conversation and highlight its significant impact on recommendation performance.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>ChatGPT as a Top-n Recommender</strong>: The study compares ChatGPT with NMF as a baseline model and showcases ChatGPT’s significant improvement over a random baseline.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Popularity Bias Analysis</strong>: The authors explore strategies to counteract popularity bias in ChatGPT’s recommendations and highlight the trade-off between recommendation variety and performance.</p></li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="conclusion" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="conclusion">Conclusion</h3>
<p>The paper concludes that reprompting ChatGPT with feedback significantly improves recommendation performance. Additionally, ChatGPT outperforms baseline models and strategies to counteract popularity bias in recommendations are proposed. The authors highlight the limitations of the study and suggest future work in comparing ChatGPT’s performance against other recommendation algorithms.</p>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<p>The paper provides valuable insights into the use of ChatGPT for conversational recommendation. However, the study’s limitations include dependency on a relatively large amount of text data and the use of an older movie dataset. Additionally, the study lacks comparable models to compare with ChatGPT in the pipeline, suggesting a need for further investigation.</p>
<p>Overall, the study presents valuable findings but should address the limitations and potential biases in future research.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-09</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.03605v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.03605v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03605v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03605v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>10455</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>programming</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>recommender</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ChatGPT_for_Conversational_Recommendation_Refining_Recommendations_by_Reprompting_with_Feedback/2024-01-07-ChatGPT_for_Conversational_Recommendation_Refining_Recommendations_by_Reprompting_with_Feedback.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03605v1/extracted/5334641/figures/methodology.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Exploring Large Language Model based Intelligent Agents: Definitions, Methods, and Prospects</title>
  <dc:creator>Yuheng Cheng, Ceyao Zhang, Zhengwen Zhang, Xiangrui Meng, Sirui Hong, Wenhao Li, Zihao Wang, Zekai Wang, Feng Yin, Junhua Zhao, Xiuqiang He</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Exploring_Large_Language_Model_based_Intelligent_Agents_Definitions_Methods_and_Prospects/2024-01-07-Exploring_Large_Language_Model_based_Intelligent_Agents_Definitions_Methods_and_Prospects.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Exploring_Large_Language_Model_based_Intelligent_Agents_Definitions_Methods_and_Prospects/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03428v1/extracted/5333121/imgs/introduction.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>Key Findings:</p>
<ul>
<li>LLM-based agents present a promising solution to the limitations faced by Large Language Models (LLMs) in pragmatic applications, thanks to their potent natural language processing and comprehensive knowledge.</li>
<li>The Rethinking capability of LLM-based agents involves evaluating prior decisions and subsequent environmental feedback, enabling introspection and improvement of agent performance.</li>
<li>LLM-based agents can interact and learn from various environments, including computer, gaming, code, real-world, and simulation environments, providing robust solutions for different tasks.</li>
</ul>
<section id="introduction" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h3>
<p>Introduces the concept of intelligent agents and their autonomous capabilities in perceiving the environment and taking actions without external instructions.</p>
</section>
<section id="overview" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="overview">Overview</h3>
<ul>
<li>Discusses single-agent and multi-agent systems, delving into their differences and application domains.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="llm-based-agent-system-framework" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="llm-based-agent-system-framework">LLM-based Agent System Framework</h3>
<ul>
<li>Details the components of the LLM-based single agent system, including planning, memory, rethinking, environment, and action.</li>
<li>Explores the mechanisms of deploying LLM-based agents in multi-agent systems, such as relationship of multi-agent systems, planning type, and methods of enhancing communication efficiency.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="performance-evaluation" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="performance-evaluation">Performance Evaluation</h3>
<ul>
<li>Covers the prevalent datasets and evaluation methodologies for agents.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="prospect-applications" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="prospect-applications">Prospect Applications</h3>
<ul>
<li>Examines the employment of LLM-based agents across diverse domains, encompassing natural sciences, social sciences, engineering systems, and general domains.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="discussion" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="discussion">Discussion</h3>
<ul>
<li>Investigates the developmental trajectories of LLM-based agents, including augmenting adaptive capacity, incorporating multimodal models, and addressing challenges.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="conclusion" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="conclusion">Conclusion</h3>
<p>Concludes the paper by summarizing the contributions and envisioning prospects for LLM-based agents.</p>
<p>Critique:</p>
<ul>
<li>The paper could benefit from more concrete examples of real-world applications and case studies involving LLM-based agents to illustrate their effectiveness.</li>
<li>The range of datasets and evaluation methodologies for LLM-based agents could be further explored and compared to provide a comprehensive understanding of their performance.</li>
<li>The discussion on challenges may benefit from a more detailed analysis of potential ethical and societal implications of LLM-based agents.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the paper provides a comprehensive overview of LLM-based intelligent agents, highlighting their potential applications and capabilities. However, it could benefit from more practical examples and in-depth analysis of performance evaluation and challenges.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-09</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.03428v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.03428v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03428v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03428v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>38668</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Exploring_Large_Language_Model_based_Intelligent_Agents_Definitions_Methods_and_Prospects/2024-01-07-Exploring_Large_Language_Model_based_Intelligent_Agents_Definitions_Methods_and_Prospects.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03428v1/extracted/5333121/imgs/introduction.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>LLM-Powered Code Vulnerability Repair with Reinforcement Learning and Semantic Reward</title>
  <dc:creator>Nafis Tanveer Islam, Joseph Khoury, Andrew Seong, Gonzalo De La Torre Parra, Elias Bou-Harb, Peyman Najafirad</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLM_Powered_Code_Vulnerability_Repair_with_Reinforcement_Learning_and_Semantic_Reward/2024-01-07-LLM_Powered_Code_Vulnerability_Repair_with_Reinforcement_Learning_and_Semantic_Reward.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLM_Powered_Code_Vulnerability_Repair_with_Reinforcement_Learning_and_Semantic_Reward/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03374v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="llm-powered-code-vulnerability-repair-with-reinforcement-learning-and-semantic-reward" class="level1">
<h1>LLM-Powered Code Vulnerability Repair with Reinforcement Learning and Semantic Reward</h1>
<section id="major-takeaways" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-takeaways">Major Takeaways</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Automation Tools and Security</strong>: This paper highlights the increasing trend of <strong>AI-driven automation tools</strong> like GitHub Copilot in software development, which aid developers in functional code development while also potentially causing security vulnerabilities due to pre-training on publicly available repositories.</li>
<li><strong>SecRepair System</strong>: The paper introduces SecRepair, a <strong>multipurpose code vulnerability analysis system</strong> powered by a large language model, CodeGen2, and reinforced by semantic reward to identify and generate fixed code, provide vulnerability descriptions, and generate code comments.</li>
<li><strong>Effectiveness of SecRepair</strong>: The study demonstrates the effectiveness of SecRepair in identifying, repairing, and describing code vulnerabilities with code comments, as well as the optimization of the program description through reinforcement learning and semantic reward.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Cybersecurity Concerns</strong>: Cybersecurity and code vulnerabilities are critical concerns in today’s digital age, with vulnerabilities arising from technical glitches, human errors, open-source software reuse, and zero-day attacks.</li>
<li><strong>Advancements in AI-driven Tools</strong>: Advancements in neural language modeling and AI-assisted automation tools like GitHub Copilot have improved software development but have also raised concerns about their training datasets, generated code outputs, and code security resilience.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="approach" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="approach">Approach</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Code Vulnerability Repair and Description</strong>: The SecRepair system is designed to help developers generate fixed code while providing comprehensive descriptions of the vulnerability with a code comment. It leverages reinforcement learning with semantic reward to enhance its capabilities.</li>
<li><strong>Instruction Dataset</strong>: The paper introduces InstructVul, an instruction-based dataset for vulnerability identification, repair, and description with code comment generation. The dataset comprises vulnerability identification, repair, description, and code comment generation tasks.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="experiments-and-discussions" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="experiments-and-discussions">Experiments and Discussions</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Evaluation Metrics</strong>: The paper uses BLEU, Rouge-L, and human evaluation scores for generative models’ effectiveness and F1, Precision, Recall, and Accuracy for vulnerability identification tasks.</li>
<li><strong>Results and Discussions</strong>: The study addresses three research questions (RQs) concerning the effectiveness and capabilities of the proposed system for vulnerability analysis, providing in-depth experimental results and discussions for each RQ.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="ablation-studies" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="ablation-studies">Ablation Studies</h2>
<ul>
<li>The paper conducts ablation studies on the impact of temperature and beam size on generative models, highlighting the effect of these components on the performance of the model in code generation tasks.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h2>
<p>The paper demonstrates the development and effectiveness of the SecRepair system in addressing code vulnerabilities. However, it would benefit from providing more detailed real-world case studies and user feedback to further validate the practical usability and impact of the system. Additionally, addressing potential ethics and biases related to AI-generated code and its impact on security would enhance the paper’s scope and relevance.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-09</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.03374v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.03374v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03374v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03374v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8165</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLM_Powered_Code_Vulnerability_Repair_with_Reinforcement_Learning_and_Semantic_Reward/2024-01-07-LLM_Powered_Code_Vulnerability_Repair_with_Reinforcement_Learning_and_Semantic_Reward.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03374v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Overview of Dialogue Robot Competition 2023</title>
  <dc:creator>Takashi Minato, Ryuichiro Higashinaka, Kurima Sakai, Tomo Funayama, Hiromitsu Nishizaki, Takayuki Naga</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Overview_of_Dialogue_Robot_Competition_2023/2024-01-07-Overview_of_Dialogue_Robot_Competition_2023.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Overview_of_Dialogue_Robot_Competition_2023/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03547v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="major-takeaways" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-takeaways">Major Takeaways</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Dialogue Robot Competition 2023 (DRC2023)</strong> was designed to advance dialogue systems for interactive robots, pushing teams to effectively use real-time information and challenge the capabilities of large-scale language models (LLMs).</li>
<li>The competition’s preliminary round was held at actual travel agency stores, catering to the practicality of evaluation and encouraging the use of advanced technologies in real-world settings.</li>
<li>Teams were provided with android robots and access to middleware, face recognition, speech synthesis, dialogue corpora, and recognition systems to support the development of their dialogue systems.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h3>
<p>The paper introduces the significance of dialogue development for humanoid robots and the evolution of voice interactive devices, emphasizing the need to effectively use multimodal input/output information, especially real-time information. DRC2023 is highlighted as the first competition for dialogue performance of android robots, following previous competitions in travel agency dialogue tasks.</p>
</section>
<section id="task-settings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="task-settings">Task Settings</h3>
<p>DRC2023’s task was to help customers plan visits to multiple sightseeing spots, requiring dialogue systems to listen to customer requests, propose feasible plans, and gather necessary information. The teams were provided with information about the sightseeing spots and allowed to use external resources. The dialogue was conducted in Japanese, and teams could use a monitor to display pictures of the sightseeing spots and maps.</p>
</section>
<section id="available-resources" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="available-resources">Available Resources</h3>
<p>Teams were provided with android robots, middleware, and several module softwares to support the development of their dialogue systems. Additionally, hardware specifications, evaluation from customer feedback, and the criteria for the preliminary round were detailed.</p>
</section>
<section id="preliminary-round" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="preliminary-round">Preliminary Round</h3>
<p>The preliminary round evaluation involved actual customers interacting with the dialogue systems at travel agency locations, considering impression evaluation and plan feasibility. Customer feedback was assessed based on informativeness, naturalness, satisfaction, and other criteria. The evaluation results and the selection of top teams were discussed, highlighting the use of a baseline system using GPT-4, a large-scale language model developed by OpenAI.</p>
</section>
<section id="overview-of-dialogue-systems-developed-by-participating-teams" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="overview-of-dialogue-systems-developed-by-participating-teams">Overview of Dialogue Systems Developed by Participating Teams</h3>
<p>A detailed overview of the dialogue systems developed by each participating team was provided, focusing on the use of LLMs, dialogue scenarios, customer relationship-building, and specific strategies employed by each team.</p>
</section>
<section id="final-round" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="final-round">Final Round</h3>
<p>The upcoming final round of the competition was briefly mentioned, wherein dialogue systems will be evaluated by designated dialogue researchers and tourism industry experts.</p>
</section>
<section id="conclusion" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="conclusion">Conclusion</h3>
<p>The paper concluded with a summary of the top teams’ performance in the preliminary round and the significance of the two evaluation factors in assessing overall system performance.</p>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<p>The paper provides comprehensive information about the DRC2023 competition, but it primarily presents an overview of the competition and its preliminary round. A deeper analysis of the specific technical advancements and challenges faced by the participating teams would enhance the paper’s insights. Additionally, while the customer feedback evaluation process was detailed, further discussion on the technical evaluation by dialogue researchers and industry experts in the final round would provide a more balanced perspective on the dialogue systems’ performance.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-09</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.03547v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.03547v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03547v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03547v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5677</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Overview_of_Dialogue_Robot_Competition_2023/2024-01-07-Overview_of_Dialogue_Robot_Competition_2023.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03547v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Malla: Demystifying Real-world Large Language Model Integrated Malicious Services</title>
  <dc:creator>Zilong Lin, Jian Cui, Xiaojing Liao, XiaoFeng Wang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Malla_Demystifying_Real_world_Large_Language_Model_Integrated_Malicious_Services/2024-01-06-Malla_Demystifying_Real_world_Large_Language_Model_Integrated_Malicious_Services.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Malla_Demystifying_Real_world_Large_Language_Model_Integrated_Malicious_Services/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03315v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><p><strong>Increased Proliferation of Mallas</strong>: The study uncovers a significant growth in Mallas, with a rapid increase in listings and projects, reflecting the prevalence of malicious services in the underground marketplaces. This trend signifies an alarming escalation in the exploitation of LLMs for cybercriminal activities.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Economic Significance</strong>: The research reveals the substantial financial allure of Malla vendors, with a case study highlighting a single Malla service generating revenues exceeding $28,000 in just three months. This underscores the economic incentives driving the proliferation of malicious LLM-integrated applications.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Effectiveness and Exploitation Techniques</strong>: The effectiveness of Mallas in generating malicious content, including malware, phishing emails, and deceptive websites, is demonstrated. Additionally, the study demystifies the tactics employed by Mallas, including the abuse of uncensored LLMs and the exploitation of public LLM APIs through jailbreak prompts.</p></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="malla-ecosystem-analysis" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="malla-ecosystem-analysis">Malla Ecosystem Analysis</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Scope and Magnitude</strong>
<ul>
<li>The study reveals the dominance of malware generation by Mallas, with a notable surge in Malla projects and an emphasis on the subscription-based pricing model.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Malla Ecosystem</strong>
<ul>
<li>The research presents insights into the characteristics of Malla providers, their activeness, and the hosting platforms utilized for Malla services. Prominently, the misuse of LLMA hosting platforms by Malla vendors is highlighted.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Malla Effectiveness</strong>
<ul>
<li>The effectiveness of Malla services and projects in generating malicious content is extensively analyzed, shedding light on the variability in performance across different Malla services and projects.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Price Strategy and Revenue</strong>
<ul>
<li>The pricing strategies and revenue generation of Malla services are explored, highlighting the competitive pricing and significant revenue potential of Mallas.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Reverse-engineering Malla</strong>
<ul>
<li>The study employs reverse-engineering techniques to uncover the backend LLMs and jailbreak prompts of Malla services and projects, revealing insights into the infrastructures commonly leveraged to construct Mallas.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<p>The study offers a comprehensive exploration of the real-world exploitation of LLMs by cybercriminals. However, it’s important to note potential ethical concerns surrounding the interaction and purchase of Malla services for research purposes. Additionally, the study’s focus on Mallas’ effectiveness and revenue generation may benefit from a deeper analysis of the broader implications and countermeasures to address the growing threat landscape posed by Mallas. Further research into the impact on cybersecurity ecosystems and potential regulatory and technological interventions could enhance the study’s contribution to combating cybercrime.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-09</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.03315v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.03315v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03315v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03315v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>17982</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Malla_Demystifying_Real_world_Large_Language_Model_Integrated_Malicious_Services/2024-01-06-Malla_Demystifying_Real_world_Large_Language_Model_Integrated_Malicious_Services.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.03315v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>DIALIGHT: Lightweight Multilingual Development and Evaluation of Task-Oriented Dialogue Systems with Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Songbo Hu, Xiaobin Wang, Zhangdie Yuan, Anna Korhonen, Ivan Vulić</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/DIALIGHT_Lightweight_Multilingual_Development_and_Evaluation_of_Task_Oriented_Dialogue_Systems_with_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-04-DIALIGHT_Lightweight_Multilingual_Development_and_Evaluation_of_Task_Oriented_Dialogue_Systems_with_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/DIALIGHT_Lightweight_Multilingual_Development_and_Evaluation_of_Task_Oriented_Dialogue_Systems_with_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.02208v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-lightweight-multilingual-development-and-evaluation-of-task-oriented-dialogue-systems-with-large-language-models" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-of-lightweight-multilingual-development-and-evaluation-of-task-oriented-dialogue-systems-with-large-language-models">Summary of “: Lightweight Multilingual Development and Evaluation of Task-Oriented Dialogue Systems with Large Language Models”</h3>
<section id="key-findings" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="key-findings">Key Findings</h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Task-Oriented Dialogue (ToD) systems</strong> facilitate interactions between human users and system agents, focusing on specific tasks such as booking hotels or providing domain-specific information.</li>
<li>The prevailing approach for ToD system development has been fine-tuning <strong>Pretrained Language Models (PLMs)</strong>, but there’s a shift towards <strong>Large Language Models (LLMs)</strong> with in-context learning capabilities.</li>
<li>While PLM fine-tuning leads to higher accuracy and coherence, LLM-based systems excel in producing diverse and likeable responses but face challenges in adherence to task-specific instructions and generating outputs in multiple languages.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h4>
<ul>
<li>ToD systems serve as access points to cutting-edge AI applications and drivers of technological expansion.</li>
<li>The shift in ToD system development from fine-tuning PLMs to relying on LLMs’ in-context learning and generalization capabilities is highlighted.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="related-work" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="related-work">Related Work</h4>
<ul>
<li>*** is a novel addition to the landscape of ToD system toolkits, offering support for in-context learning (ICL) compared to existing frameworks.</li>
<li>It aims to lower entry barriers and facilitate comprehensive comparative analyses between PLM fine-tuning and ICL-based systems.</li>
</ul>
</section>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper acknowledges the limitations of the toolkit, such as focusing only on text input and its underperformance compared to more sophisticated systems. It also raises concerns about the dominance of English instructions biasing model outputs towards English, indicating potential biases in the toolkit’s approach.</li>
<li>The superficial tone and stylized infoboxes find little impact in interpreting the utility or contribution of the product. This makes the paper overlook potential areas.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02208v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02208v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.02208v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.02208v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>9836</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>programming</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/DIALIGHT_Lightweight_Multilingual_Development_and_Evaluation_of_Task_Oriented_Dialogue_Systems_with_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-04-DIALIGHT_Lightweight_Multilingual_Development_and_Evaluation_of_Task_Oriented_Dialogue_Systems_with_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.02208v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Self-Contrast: Better Reflection Through Inconsistent Solving Perspectives</title>
  <dc:creator>Wenqi Zhang, Yongliang Shen, Linjuan Wu, Qiuying Peng, Jun Wang, Yueting Zhuang, Weiming Lu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Self_Contrast_Better_Reflection_Through_Inconsistent_Solving_Perspectives/2024-01-04-Self_Contrast_Better_Reflection_Through_Inconsistent_Solving_Perspectives.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Self_Contrast_Better_Reflection_Through_Inconsistent_Solving_Perspectives/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.02009v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary</h3>
<p><strong>Self-Contrast: Better Reflection Through Inconsistent Solving Perspectives</strong></p>
<p><strong>1. Major Findings</strong> - <strong>Intrinsic Reflection Deficiencies</strong>: Large Language Models (LLMs) struggle with self-correction due to ineffective intrinsic reflection. - <strong>Overconfident and Inconsistent Feedback</strong>: LLMs often exhibit overconfidence (46.7%) or inconsistency (45.7%) when self-evaluating, hindering accurate self-reflection. - <strong>Self-Contrast Approach</strong>: The Self-Contrast method, which involves creating diverse solving perspectives and contrasting the differences, significantly improves LLMs’ reflection capabilities across reasoning and translation tasks.</p>
<p><strong>2. Evaluation of Intrinsic Reflection</strong> - <strong>Limited Reflection Capability</strong>: LLMs show insignificant performance gains from reflection and struggle to correct incorrect initial responses. - <strong>Feedback Analysis</strong>: The self-evaluate process results in overconfident and inconsistent feedback, impeding effective reflection.</p>
<p><strong>3. Self-Contrast</strong> - <strong>Create Diverse Perspectives</strong>: LLMs autonomously generate multiple prompts tailored to the user’s request, fostering diverse solving perspectives. - <strong>Contrast Inter-Perspective Discrepancies</strong>: LLM contrasts the differences between responses, identifying errors and providing re-examining instructions. - <strong>Eliminate Discrepancies</strong>: Discrepancies between perspectives guide LLMs to revise inconsistent responses for more accurate reflection.</p>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<p>The paper presents a novel approach, but it may benefit from a discussion on potential limitations and challenges in implementing the Self-Contrast method. Additionally, further exploration of real-world application and scalability would enhance the paper’s practical significance. Moreover, a comparison with existing state-of-the-art reflection strategies could provide a better understanding of the method’s effectiveness.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02009v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02009v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.02009v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.02009v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>10949</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Self_Contrast_Better_Reflection_Through_Inconsistent_Solving_Perspectives/2024-01-04-Self_Contrast_Better_Reflection_Through_Inconsistent_Solving_Perspectives.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.02009v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>ICE-GRT: Instruction Context Enhancement by Generative Reinforcement based Transformers</title>
  <dc:creator>Chen Zheng, Ke Sun, Da Tang, Yukun Ma, Yuyu Zhang, Chenguang Xi, Xun Zhou</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ICE_GRT_Instruction_Context_Enhancement_by_Generative_Reinforcement_based_Transformers/2024-01-04-ICE_GRT_Instruction_Context_Enhancement_by_Generative_Reinforcement_based_Transformers.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ICE_GRT_Instruction_Context_Enhancement_by_Generative_Reinforcement_based_Transformers/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.02072v1/extracted/5329451/images/model_architecture.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="major-takeaways" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-takeaways">Major Takeaways</h3>
<ul>
<li>ICE-GRT, a Large Language Model (LLM), addresses limitations in domain-specific tasks by utilizing Reinforcement Learning from Human Feedback (RLHF) grounded in Proximal Policy Optimization (PPO).</li>
<li>ICE-GRT demonstrates exceptional performance in both general and domain-specific tasks, showcasing improved ability for detailed analysis, particularly in scenarios where smaller-sized LLMs fall short.</li>
<li>The success of ICE-GRT is dependent on crucial factors such as appropriate data, reward size scaling, KL-control, and advantage normalization.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h3>
<ul>
<li>Large Language Models like ChatGPT and LLaMA face limitations in domain-specific tasks, lacking depth and accuracy.</li>
<li>ICE-GRT, leveraging RLHF based on PPO, excels in domain-specific scenarios without compromising general task performance.</li>
<li>The model displays profound understanding and reasoning abilities, going beyond Supervised Fine-Tuning (SFT) models.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="related-works" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="related-works">Related Works</h3>
<ul>
<li>Recent advancements in Large Language Models have focused on instruction-tuning and RLHF to improve LLMs’ capabilities in specialized tasks.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="model" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="model">Model</h3>
<ul>
<li>ICE-GRT is built upon the ICE-Instruct model and utilizes RLHF for training the reward model and the entire ICE-GRT model.</li>
<li>The model components include the Actor, Reference, Reward, and Critic models.</li>
<li>Important training strategies such as data collection, reward size scaling, KL-control, and advantage normalization contribute to ICE-GRT’s effectiveness.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="experimental-details" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="experimental-details">Experimental Details</h3>
<ul>
<li>ICE-GRT’s training process employs a multi-node, multi-GPU strategy and utilizes data collected from diverse sources, including in-domain data and public resources.</li>
<li>Evaluations involve general task benchmarks and manual annotation-based assessments.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="results-and-analysis" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="results-and-analysis">Results and Analysis</h3>
<ul>
<li>ICE-GRT outperforms other models in general and in-domain tasks, demonstrating its superior performance and comprehension abilities.</li>
<li>ICE-GRT’s training data significantly influences its performance, and strategies like advantage normalization contribute to its effectiveness.</li>
<li>Case studies illustrate ICE-GRT’s comprehensive understanding and creative compliance in domain-specific tasks.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="conclusion" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="conclusion">Conclusion</h3>
<ul>
<li>ICE-GRT represents a significant advancement in LLMs, especially in domain-specific performance, and offers insights into effective RLHF training methodologies.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper largely focuses on the capabilities of ICE-GRT without addressing potential limitations or challenges encountered during the development and implementation of the model.</li>
<li>The paper could benefit from a more extensive evaluation and comparison with a wider range of existing models to provide a more comprehensive understanding of ICE-GRT’s positioning in the field.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02072v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02072v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.02072v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.02072v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8390</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/ICE_GRT_Instruction_Context_Enhancement_by_Generative_Reinforcement_based_Transformers/2024-01-04-ICE_GRT_Instruction_Context_Enhancement_by_Generative_Reinforcement_based_Transformers.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.02072v1/extracted/5329451/images/model_architecture.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>LLM Augmented LLMs: Expanding Capabilities through Composition</title>
  <dc:creator>Rachit Bansal, Bidisha Samanta, Siddharth Dalmia, Nitish Gupta, Shikhar Vashishth, Sriram Ganapathy, Abhishek Bapna, Prateek Jain, Partha Talukdar</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLM_Augmented_LLMs_Expanding_Capabilities_through_Composition/2024-01-04-LLM_Augmented_LLMs_Expanding_Capabilities_through_Composition.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLM_Augmented_LLMs_Expanding_Capabilities_through_Composition/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.02412v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Major Takeaways</strong> - The paper introduces the concept of Composition to Augment Language Models (CALM) which enables the composition of existing foundational language models with more specific models to enable newer capabilities. - The CALM framework introduces cross-attention between models to compose their representations and enable new capabilities, allowing for the reuse of existing models with established capabilities. - The paper demonstrates the practical applications of CALM in language inclusivity and code generation, showing significant improvements in translation, arithmetic reasoning, and code-related tasks.</p>
<p><strong>Introduction</strong> - Large Language Models (LLMs) have foundational capabilities and have been fine-tuned for domain-specific capabilities, resulting in the development of several specialized large models with domain-specific capabilities. - The paper aims to enable the composition of an anchor model with a domain-specific augmenting model to enable new capabilities, such as composing an augmenting model’s code understanding capability with an anchor LLM’s language generation capability to enable code-to-text generation capability.</p>
<p><strong>The CALM Framework</strong> - CALM aims to compose an anchor model and an augmenting model to enable new capabilities as a composition of capabilities of the two individual models. - It operates over a selected set of layers from the anchor and augmenting models and introduces a small number of trainable parameters over these layers. - The composition training data depicts a “combined skill” of the given models for the target composition domain and is used to learn the composition parameters.</p>
<p><strong>Experiments</strong> - The paper demonstrates the effectiveness of CALM in three domains: key-value arithmetic, low-resource language inclusivity, and code completion and explanation tasks. - The experiments show the significant improvements achieved by composing an augmenting model with an anchor LLM, surpassing the individual models and versions that have been fine-tuned for the specific tasks.</p>
<p><strong>Critique</strong> - The paper lacks a discussion on the potential limitations or challenges of the CALM framework, such as its scalability to larger models or its adaptability to diverse languages and domains. - The experimental results could benefit from a more extensive comparison with other relevant methods or frameworks to establish the unique advantages of CALM.</p>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02412v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02412v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.02412v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.02412v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5397</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>programming</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLM_Augmented_LLMs_Expanding_Capabilities_through_Composition/2024-01-04-LLM_Augmented_LLMs_Expanding_Capabilities_through_Composition.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.02412v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Using LLM to select the right SQL Query from candidates</title>
  <dc:creator>Zhenwen Li, Tao Xie</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Using_LLM_to_select_the_right_SQL_Query_from_candidates/2024-01-04-Using_LLM_to_select_the_right_SQL_Query_from_candidates.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Using_LLM_to_select_the_right_SQL_Query_from_candidates/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.02115v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-using-llm-to-select-the-right-sql-query-from-candidates" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary-of-using-llm-to-select-the-right-sql-query-from-candidates">Summary of “Using LLM to select the right SQL Query from candidates”</h3>
<section id="major-findings" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings</h4>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Automatic Test Case Generation</strong>: The paper proposes a method to automatically generate test cases for text-to-SQL, without ground truth SQL queries, and conducts experiments to explore how to generate easily predicted databases for large language models (LLMs) and design easy-to-understand prompts.</li>
<li><strong>Re-rank Method</strong>: The paper introduces a re-rank method to select the right SQL query from a candidate list and demonstrates its effectiveness on the validation dataset of Spider, showing a 3.6% improvement in the performance of state-of-the-art text-to-SQL models.</li>
<li><strong>Hyper-parameter Optimization</strong>: Through experiments, the study identifies optimal hyper-parameters for generating test cases, such as database size, naturalness of database contents, format of database contents, and number of examples. It also highlights the effectiveness of constraining the range of numbers in database columns participating in aggregation/sort operations.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h4>
<ul>
<li>Text-to-SQL is the task of translating natural language into a SQL query, and the top-performing models often generate a list of candidate SQL queries, with the best query not always at the top of the list.</li>
<li>Previous studies have focused on re-ranking the candidate SQL queries, but automatic test case generation for text-to-SQL is an understudied field.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="test-case-generation" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="test-case-generation">Test Case Generation</h4>
<ul>
<li>The method consists of database generation and using LLMs to predict the expected execution results.</li>
<li>Database generation involves fuzzing and random selection methods, exploring the impact of maximum table size and naturalness of database contents.</li>
<li>LLMs are guided by prompts containing the NL question, database representation, and examples to predict expected execution results.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="candidate-selection" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="candidate-selection">Candidate Selection</h4>
<ul>
<li>The paper proposes a three-step method to select the right SQL query, involving candidate list classification, test suite generation, and re-ranking based on pass numbers on test cases and their generation probabilities.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="experiment" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="experiment">Experiment</h4>
<ul>
<li>The study conducts experiments on the Spider dataset, using GPT-4-turbo and GPT-4 to generate test cases and state-of-the-art models like DAIL-SQL and RESDSQL to generate candidate lists.</li>
<li>Results indicate a 3.6% improvement for DAIL-SQL and a 2% improvement for RESDSQL after applying the proposed re-rank methods.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="hyper-parameter-optimization" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="hyper-parameter-optimization">Hyper-parameter Optimization</h4>
<ul>
<li>The study explores hyper-parameters related to database generation and prompt design, identifying optimal values and showing the effectiveness of constraining number ranges in certain columns.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="related-work" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="related-work">Related Work</h4>
<ul>
<li>The paper discusses the use of LLMs in text-to-SQL, the relationship to previous re-ranking studies, and the advantages of its database generation algorithm compared to previous work.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="conclusion" class="level4">
<h4 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="conclusion">Conclusion</h4>
<ul>
<li>The study emphasizes the efficacy of using test cases to re-rank candidate lists for text-to-SQL, calling for further exploration in this research direction.</li>
</ul>
</section>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<p>The paper presents an innovative approach to test case generation and re-ranking of candidate SQL queries, demonstrating notable improvements in model performance. However, there are some potential limitations: 1. <strong>Prediction Accuracy of LLMs</strong>: The study acknowledges that only about 60% of the test cases generated are correct, raising questions about the overall reliability of using LLMs to predict expected execution results. 2. <strong>Complexity and Token Consumption</strong>: The re-rank method’s reliance on OpenAI’s API for generating test cases multiple times highlights potential challenges in scalability and token consumption for large-scale applications. 3. <strong>Database Generation Limitations</strong>: The limitations of the proposed database generation method, including its inability to distinguish some SQL queries, could impact the overall effectiveness of the test case generation process.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02115v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02115v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.02115v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.02115v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7353</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Using_LLM_to_select_the_right_SQL_Query_from_candidates/2024-01-04-Using_LLM_to_select_the_right_SQL_Query_from_candidates.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.02115v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Understanding LLMs: A Comprehensive Overview from Training to Inference</title>
  <dc:creator>Yiheng Liu, Hao He, Tianle Han, Xu Zhang, Mengyuan Liu, Jiaming Tian, Yutong Zhang, Jiaqi Wang, Xiaohui Gao, Tianyang Zhong, Yi Pan, Shaochen Xu, Zihao Wu, Zhengliang Liu, Xin Zhang, Shu Zhang, Xintao Hu, Tuo Zhang, Ning Qiang, Tianming Liu, Bao Ge</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Understanding_LLMs_A_Comprehensive_Overview_from_Training_to_Inference/2024-01-04-Understanding_LLMs_A_Comprehensive_Overview_from_Training_to_Inference.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Understanding_LLMs_A_Comprehensive_Overview_from_Training_to_Inference/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.02038v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="major-takeaways" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-takeaways">Major Takeaways:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><p><strong>Evolution of Large Language Models (LLMs)</strong>: The introduction of ChatGPT has led to the popular use of LLMs for addressing downstream tasks. The focus is now on cost-efficient training and deployment of LLMs, representing the future development trend.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Training Techniques</strong>: LLMs training includes aspects such as data preprocessing, training architecture, pre-training tasks, parallel training, and model fine-tuning. On the inference side, the paper covers topics such as model compression, parallel computation, memory scheduling, and structural optimization.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Fine-Tuning</strong>: The paper categorizes fine-tuning techniques into supervised fine-tuning, alignment tuning, and parameter-efficient tuning. The supervision of fine-tuning involves adjusting the model based on large-scale pre-training.</p></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="background-knowledge" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="background-knowledge">Background Knowledge</h3>
<p>The section provides an overview of language modeling in the context of natural language processing (NLP) and the evolution of language models from statistical language models (SLM) to neural language models (NLM) and pre-trained language models (PLM). It also details the Transformer architecture, self-attention, encoder-decoder architecture, positional embedding, and prompt learning as widely adopted machine learning approach.</p>
</section>
<section id="training-of-large-language-models" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="training-of-large-language-models">Training of Large Language Models</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Data Preparation and Preprocessing</strong>: Discusses data pre-training tasks such as language modeling, and model pre-training tasks, including data parallel, model parallel, mixed precision training, offloading, overlapping, and checkpoint mechanisms.</li>
<li><strong>Supervised Fine-Tuning</strong>: The paper categorizes fine-tuning techniques into supervised fine-tuning, alignment tuning, and parameter-efficient tuning. The supervision of fine-tuning involves adjusting the model based on large-scale pre-training.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="model-training" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="model-training">Model Training</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Parallel Training</strong>: Discusses data parallel, distributed data parallel, model parallel and ZeRO framework.</li>
<li><strong>Mixed Precision Training</strong>: Details the use of 16-bit floating-point numbers to reduce memory usage and communication overhead.</li>
<li><strong>Offloading</strong>: Discusses the idea of moving the optimizer’s parameters from the GPU to the CPU.</li>
<li><strong>Overlapping</strong>: Describes asynchronous memory operations to optimize the training process.</li>
<li><strong>Checkpoint</strong>: Details the use of a checkpoint mechanism to optimize the backward propagation process.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="fine-tuning" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="fine-tuning">Fine-Tuning</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Supervised Fine-Tuning</strong>: The core concept involves adjusting the model in a supervised manner on the basis of large-scale pre-training.</li>
<li><strong>Alignment Tuning</strong>: Aligns the model with specific task requirements, task prompt, or examples.</li>
<li><strong>Parameter-Efficient Tuning</strong>: Designed to fine-tune the model with minimal additional parameters.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h3>
<p>The article lacks a clear distinction between the literature review and original contributions, making it challenging to identify the author’s unique position or perspective on the subject matter. Additionally, some sections provide detailed technical descriptions that may be overwhelming for readers without a strong background in NLP and machine learning. Finally, the absence of empirical evidence or case studies limits the practical applicability of the paper’s findings.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02038v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02038v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.02038v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.02038v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>21883</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Understanding_LLMs_A_Comprehensive_Overview_from_Training_to_Inference/2024-01-04-Understanding_LLMs_A_Comprehensive_Overview_from_Training_to_Inference.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.02038v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Text2MDT: Extracting Medical Decision Trees from Medical Texts</title>
  <dc:creator>Wei Zhu, Wenfeng Li, Xing Tian, Pengfei Wang, Xiaoling Wang, Jin Chen, Yuanbin Wu, Yuan Ni, Guotong Xie</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Text2MDT_Extracting_Medical_Decision_Trees_from_Medical_Texts/2024-01-04-Text2MDT_Extracting_Medical_Decision_Trees_from_Medical_Texts.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Text2MDT_Extracting_Medical_Decision_Trees_from_Medical_Texts/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.02034v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary-of-text2mdt-extracting-medical-decision-trees-from-medical-texts" class="level1">
<h1>Summary of “Text2MDT: Extracting Medical Decision Trees from Medical Texts”</h1>
<section id="major-takeaways" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-takeaways">Major Takeaways</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Text2MDT</strong>: The paper proposes a novel task, <strong>Text2MDT</strong>, which aims to automatically extract <strong>medical decision trees (MDTs)</strong> from medical texts such as medical guidelines and textbooks. This is significant for the development of clinical decision support systems.</li>
<li><strong>End-to-end vs.&nbsp;Pipeline Framework</strong>: The paper investigates both an end-to-end framework and a pipeline framework for the Text2MDT task and demonstrates that large language models (LLMs) show promising results in automated MDT extraction.</li>
<li><strong>Open-Sourced Dataset and Source Code</strong>: The study contributes to the field by constructing the first Text2MDT benchmark dataset and making it openly available to facilitate further research.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<ul>
<li>The development of clinical decision support systems, which rely on medical decision processes modeled as MDTs, has drawn significant attention in the medical field.</li>
<li>Current methods for constructing MDTs rely on manual tree construction, which is time-consuming and laborious, leading to a need for automated pipelines for precise MDT extraction. This motivates the proposal of the Text2MDT task.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="text2mdt-task" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="text2mdt-task">Text2MDT Task</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Structure</strong>: The knowledge of a medical decision process embedded in the medical text is modeled as a binary decision tree consisting of condition nodes and decision nodes, linked by the logical relationships</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="data-collection-and-evaluation" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="data-collection-and-evaluation">Data Collection and Evaluation</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Data Collection</strong>: A Text2MDT dataset was constructed using clinical practice guidelines and clinical medicine textbooks, and medical practitioners evaluated the ability of medical texts and decision trees to represent the medical decision process.</li>
<li><strong>Manual Evaluation</strong>: The quality of the annotated MDTs was evaluated by medical practitioners and individuals without a medical background.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="methods-of-modeling-text2mdt" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="methods-of-modeling-text2mdt">Methods of modeling Text2MDT</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Pipelined Framework</strong>: The study investigates triplet extraction, node grouping, and tree assembling as subtasks for the pipeline framework. Both encoder-based and LLM-based methods are explored.</li>
<li><strong>End-to-end Framework</strong>: The paper proposes various COT-style generation methods for the end-to-end framework, considering the complexity of the Text2MDT task and the potential benefit of COT reasoning.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="experiments-and-results" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="experiments-and-results">Experiments and Results</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Evaluation Metrics</strong>: The study uses metrics such as triplet precision, recall, and F1 scores for triplet extraction, edit distance-based metrics for node grouping, and additional metrics for tree assembling.</li>
<li><strong>Performance Findings</strong>: The study shows competitive results for MedBERT-based methods and demonstrates the potential of COT-style reasoning in improving the performance of generative LMs on the Text2MDT task.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="limitations-and-critique" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="limitations-and-critique">Limitations and Critique</h2>
<ul>
<li>The study acknowledges limitations related to the expressiveness of the tree, limited logic expression of nodes, and text length constraints. Further improvements are identified as future work.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="conclusion" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<ul>
<li>The paper concludes with the significance of the proposed Text2MDT task for automated extraction of MDTs and highlights the contributions of the study, including the construction of the Text2MDT dataset and the exploration of novel method frameworks.</li>
<li>Additionally, the study identifies potential future work to address the limitations and challenges encountered in the investigation.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h2>
<p>The paper provides a comprehensive overview of the Text2MDT task and presents valuable contributions to the field of automated MDT extraction. However, a more detailed discussion of potential challenges and future directions for improving the proposed methods would enhance the paper’s completeness. Additionally, addressing the limitations of the proposed framework and its applicability in real-world clinical settings would provide a more comprehensive evaluation of the study’s contributions.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02034v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02034v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.02034v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.02034v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>13994</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>programming</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Text2MDT_Extracting_Medical_Decision_Trees_from_Medical_Texts/2024-01-04-Text2MDT_Extracting_Medical_Decision_Trees_from_Medical_Texts.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.02034v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>DCR-Consistency: Divide-Conquer-Reasoning for Consistency Evaluation and Improvement of Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Wendi Cui, Jiaxin Zhang, Zhuohang Li, Lopez Damien, Kamalika Das, Bradley Malin, Sricharan Kumar</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/DCR_Consistency_Divide_Conquer_Reasoning_for_Consistency_Evaluation_and_Improvement_of_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-04-DCR_Consistency_Divide_Conquer_Reasoning_for_Consistency_Evaluation_and_Improvement_of_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/DCR_Consistency_Divide_Conquer_Reasoning_for_Consistency_Evaluation_and_Improvement_of_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.02132v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary</h2>
<p><strong>DCR-Consistency: Divide-Conquer-Reasoning for Consistency Evaluation and Improvement of Large Language Models</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Findings</strong>
<ul>
<li>The paper proposes a new framework, DCR, for evaluating and improving the consistency of Large Language Model (LLM)-generated texts which outperforms state-of-the-art methods by a large margin in semantic, factual, and summarization consistency tasks.</li>
<li>The framework employs three components: Divide-Conquer Evaluator (DCE), Auto-Metric Converter (AMC), and Reason-Assisted Improver (RAI) to evaluate and improve the consistency of generated responses.</li>
<li>The DCR framework demonstrates high correlations with human judgments, reduces output inconsistencies, and shows promise for effective hallucination mitigation.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Preliminaries</strong>
<ul>
<li>Conventional evaluation methods relying on token-level comparison fail to capture overall semantic meaning, leading to low correlation with human judgments.</li>
<li>The consistency of LLMs is essential for AI safety and reliability, but current methods often overlook self-consistency failures.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Divide-Conquer-Reasoning</strong>
<ul>
<li>DCE evaluates semantic consistency between reference and candidate paragraphs at a sentence level using a divide-and-conquer strategy.</li>
<li>AMC converts the evaluation reasons into a numeric score for quantitative interpretation.</li>
<li>RAI utilizes the outputs of DCE to generate new responses to mitigate inconsistencies.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Experiments</strong>
<ul>
<li>The DCR framework outperforms baseline methods in semantic, factual, and summarization consistency evaluations, showing high correlations with human judgment.</li>
<li>RAI significantly improves consistency, reducing nearly 90% of output inconsistencies.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h2>
<p>While the DCR framework shows promise in evaluating and improving LLM-generated texts’ consistency, several limitations should be considered.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Not Comprehensive</strong>: The approach may not universally address all dimensions of text evaluation, such as coherence and relevance.</li>
<li><strong>Input Dependence</strong>: The accuracy of the framework is inherently limited by the correctness of the input paragraphs, potentially affecting the detection of non-factual statements.</li>
<li><strong>Manual Prompting</strong>: The requirement for hand-crafted prompts for specific tasks may limit the scalability and automation of the framework.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the paper provides valuable insights into consistency evaluation and improvement for LLM-generated texts, but further research is needed to address the identified limitations.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-06</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02132v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02132v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.02132v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.02132v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>9608</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/DCR_Consistency_Divide_Conquer_Reasoning_for_Consistency_Evaluation_and_Improvement_of_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-04-DCR_Consistency_Divide_Conquer_Reasoning_for_Consistency_Evaluation_and_Improvement_of_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.02132v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Exploring Boundary of GPT-4V on Marine Analysis: A Preliminary Case Study</title>
  <dc:creator>Ziqiang Zheng, Yiwei Chen, Jipeng Zhang, Tuan-Anh Vu, Huimin Zeng, Yue Him Wong Tim, Sai-Kit Yeung</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Exploring_Boundary_of_GPT_4V_on_Marine_Analysis_A_Preliminary_Case_Study/2024-01-04-Exploring_Boundary_of_GPT_4V_on_Marine_Analysis_A_Preliminary_Case_Study.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Exploring_Boundary_of_GPT_4V_on_Marine_Analysis_A_Preliminary_Case_Study/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="exploring-boundary-of-gpt-4v-on-marine-analysis-a-preliminary-case-study" class="level1">
<h1>Exploring Boundary of GPT-4V on Marine Analysis: A Preliminary Case Study</h1>
<section id="major-takeaways" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-takeaways">Major Takeaways</h2>
<ul>
<li>The study explores the preliminary case study of utilizing <strong>GPT-4V</strong> for marine analysis, assessing the feasibility of <strong>MLLMs</strong> in domain-specific analysis.</li>
<li>The experimental results demonstrate that while <strong>GPT-4V</strong> showcases impressive general-purpose visual understanding, it has limitations in fine-grained marine object recognition and advanced marine analysis.</li>
<li>The paper highlights the potential shortcomings of <strong>GPT-4V</strong> and emphasizes the need for further research and inclusion of more domain-specific training data to improve its performance.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="introduction" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<ul>
<li>Large language models (LLMs) like <strong>GPT-4V</strong> have demonstrated powerful abilities in various tasks, but their performance in domain-specific analysis like marine analysis has gained less attention.</li>
<li>The study investigates whether <strong>GPT-4V</strong> can serve as an effective visual perception system and professional expert for marine analysis, evaluating its performance from different aspects.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="experiments" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="experiments">Experiments</h2>
<section id="approach" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="approach">Approach</h3>
<ul>
<li>The data construction involves samples from private data, internet images, and public datasets to ensure consistency and reliability.</li>
<li><strong>GPT-4V’s</strong> diverse prompt designs aim to generate comprehensive and descriptive responses aligned with user intents.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="perception" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="perception">Perception</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study explores <strong>GPT-4V’s</strong> performance in marine object recognition, fine-grained marine object recognition, robustness analysis, and physical world knowledge understanding.</li>
<li>Results show limitations in fine-grained object recognition and robustness with different image formats.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="statistics" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="statistics">Statistics</h3>
<ul>
<li>Object counting experiments reveal <strong>GPT-4V’s</strong> limited ability, especially in crowded or occluded settings.</li>
<li>The study also assesses <strong>GPT-4V’s</strong> capability to recognize all existing objects within visual images, demonstrating more limitations in recognizing all objects.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="domain-specific-question-answering" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="domain-specific-question-answering">Domain-specific Question-Answering</h3>
<ul>
<li>Evaluation on marine multiple choice questions and domain-specific visual question-answering shows <strong>GPT-4V’s</strong> strong optical character recognition but also limitations in handling more advanced marine analysis requirements.</li>
<li>The study also evaluates <strong>GPT-4V’s</strong> support for multi-round conversations and its struggle with marine object recognition.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="marine-cultural-understanding" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="marine-cultural-understanding">Marine Cultural Understanding</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>GPT-4V’s</strong> performance in marine logo understanding, artist image understanding, and landmark recognition displays mixed results, highlighting its capability in recognizing certain visual elements but also its limitations.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="advanced-functions" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="advanced-functions">Advanced Functions</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study tests <strong>GPT-4V’s</strong> abilities in coral coverage estimation, benthic composition, relationship summarization, event detection, framework understanding, aesthetic evaluation, and temporal sequence understanding.</li>
<li><strong>GPT-4V</strong> demonstrated limitations in providing accurate analysis and understanding specific details in these advanced functions.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="prompt-engineering" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="prompt-engineering">Prompt Engineering</h3>
<ul>
<li>Evaluation of prompt engineering techniques shows limited effectiveness in promoting GPT-4V’s visual recognition ability for marine images.</li>
</ul>
</section>
</section>
<section id="discussions-and-future-directions" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="discussions-and-future-directions">Discussions and Future Directions</h2>
<section id="discussions" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="discussions">Discussions</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study questions the potential roles of <strong>GPT-4V</strong> as an educational or labeling tool and highlights the challenges and potential sample biases in the constructed testing samples.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="future-works" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="future-works">Future Works</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper emphasizes the need for continued research to enhance the accuracy and expertise of responses generated by <strong>GPT-4V</strong>, emphasizing the inclusion of more domain-specific training data and feedback-driven model improvements.</li>
</ul>
</section>
</section>
<section id="conclusion" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<ul>
<li>The study concludes that while <strong>GPT-4V</strong> demonstrates valuable findings in visual understanding and reasoning, it falls short of being a strong artificial intelligence domain expert, indicating more research is needed in leveraging multimodal systems for domain-specific analysis.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="critique" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="critique">Critique</h2>
<ul>
<li>The study provides comprehensive insights into the performance of <strong>GPT-4V</strong> in marine analysis but may benefit from a more extensive comparison with other MLLMs for a more holistic view of the capabilities in domain-specific analysis.</li>
<li>The paper could also benefit from addressing potential biases in the evaluation dataset and providing clearer recommendations for future research directions.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-07</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02147v1">http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02147v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.02147v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.02147v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>11778</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Exploring_Boundary_of_GPT_4V_on_Marine_Analysis_A_Preliminary_Case_Study/2024-01-04-Exploring_Boundary_of_GPT_4V_on_Marine_Analysis_A_Preliminary_Case_Study.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
