<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Bayesian beagle</title>
<link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Quarto blog of LLM-generated summaries of Arxiv preprints</description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.450</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Exploring ChatGPT App Ecosystem: Distribution, Deployment and Security</title>
  <dc:creator>Chuan Yan, Ruomai Ren, Mark Huasong Meng, Liuhuo Wan, Tian Yang Ooi, Guangdong Bai</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Exploring_ChatGPT_App_Ecosystem_Distribution_Deployment_and_Security/2024-08-26-Exploring_ChatGPT_App_Ecosystem_Distribution_Deployment_and_Security.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Exploring_ChatGPT_App_Ecosystem_Distribution_Deployment_and_Security/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14357v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level1">
<h1>Summary:</h1>
<p>The paper presents a comprehensive study of the ChatGPT app ecosystem, focusing on the distribution, deployment, and security of plugins. The study aims to illuminate the landscape of the ecosystem for the research community. The authors collect and analyze all currently available plugins from the store (overall 1,038) and categorize them based on their functionality. They also investigate the deployment and execution models of the plugins through reverse engineering. The study reveals an uneven distribution of functionality among ChatGPT plugins, highlighting prevalent and emerging topics. However, the authors also identify severe flaws in the authentication and user data protection for third-party app APIs integrated within LLMs, revealing a concerning status quo of security and privacy in this app ecosystem.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level1">
<h1>Major Findings:</h1>
<ol type="1">
<li>The study reveals an uneven distribution of functionality among ChatGPT plugins, with more than half of the plugins concentrated in five categories: data &amp; research, tools, developer &amp; code, business, and entertainment.</li>
<li>The authors identify severe flaws in the authentication and user data protection for third-party app APIs integrated within LLMs, revealing a concerning status quo of security and privacy in this app ecosystem.</li>
<li>The study provides insights for the secure and sustainable development of this rapidly evolving ecosystem.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level1">
<h1>Analysis and Critique:</h1>
<p>The paper provides a comprehensive overview of the ChatGPT app ecosystem, highlighting the potential of this ecosystem to offer personalized AI services and establish ChatGPT as the backbone of an open app ecosystem. However, the authors also identify several critical issues that need to be addressed to ensure the security and privacy of this ecosystem. The lack of well-labeled data and the black-box nature of LLMs make it challenging to accurately capture and interpret the runtime workflow and data flow. The study also reveals a concerning prevalence of security and privacy flaws among ChatGPT plugins. The authors suggest that the ChatGPT app ecosystem is still in its nascent stage and lacks a mature regulatory mechanism to enforce user privacy compliance and security standards. The study not only contributes to the improvement of the current store but also provides insights into the future development of the entire ecosystem.</p>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-27</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14357v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14357v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14357v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14357v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>11784</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Exploring_ChatGPT_App_Ecosystem_Distribution_Deployment_and_Security/2024-08-26-Exploring_ChatGPT_App_Ecosystem_Distribution_Deployment_and_Security.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14357v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>LLM-3D Print: Large Language Models To Monitor and Control 3D Printing</title>
  <dc:creator>Yayati Jadhav, Peter Pak, Amir Barati Farimani</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLM_3D_Print_Large_Language_Models_To_Monitor_and_Control_3D_Printing/2024-08-26-LLM_3D_Print_Large_Language_Models_To_Monitor_and_Control_3D_Printing.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLM_3D_Print_Large_Language_Models_To_Monitor_and_Control_3D_Printing/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14307v1/extracted/5814314/framework.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The article presents a novel process monitoring and control framework that leverages pre-trained Large Language Models (LLMs) alongside 3D printers to detect and address printing defects. The proposed framework employs LLM-based agents to evaluate print quality, identify failure modes, gather relevant information, and plan and solve issues by adjusting print parameters. The study compares the effectiveness of the proposed framework against a control group of engineers with diverse AM expertise. The results demonstrate that LLM-based agents not only accurately identify common 3D printing errors but also effectively determine the parameters causing these failures and autonomously correct them without any need for human intervention.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The proposed framework utilizes LLMs to evaluate print quality, identify failure modes, gather relevant information, and plan and solve issues by adjusting print parameters, ensuring high-quality defect-free parts.</li>
<li>The study compares the effectiveness of the proposed framework against a control group of engineers with diverse AM expertise, demonstrating that LLM-based agents accurately identify common 3D printing errors and effectively determine the parameters causing these failures.</li>
<li>The LLM-based agents autonomously correct the identified issues without any need for human intervention, improving efficiency and reducing material waste.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The proposed framework presents a promising approach to addressing the challenges of error detection and correction in 3D printing. By leveraging the capabilities of LLMs, the framework offers a more flexible and adaptable solution for robust error detection and correction across diverse printing environments. However, the study does not provide a detailed analysis of the limitations, unanswered questions, or potential biases that may have been apparent while reviewing the text. Additionally, the methodology for comparing the effectiveness of the proposed framework against the control group of engineers is not explicitly stated, making it difficult to assess the validity of the results. Further research is needed to evaluate the generalizability of the proposed framework across different 3D printer setups, firmware, and sensors, as well as to address any potential methodological issues or conflicting evidence.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-27</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14307v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14307v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14307v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14307v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8288</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLM_3D_Print_Large_Language_Models_To_Monitor_and_Control_3D_Printing/2024-08-26-LLM_3D_Print_Large_Language_Models_To_Monitor_and_Control_3D_Printing.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14307v1/extracted/5814314/framework.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Video-CCAM: Enhancing Video-Language Understanding with Causal Cross-Attention Masks for Short and Long Videos</title>
  <dc:creator>Jiajun Fei, Dian Li, Zhidong Deng, Zekun Wang, Gang Liu, Hui Wang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Video_CCAM_Enhancing_Video_Language_Understanding_with_Causal_Cross_Attention_Masks_for_Short_and_Long_Videos/2024-08-26-Video_CCAM_Enhancing_Video_Language_Understanding_with_Causal_Cross_Attention_Masks_for_Short_and_Long_Videos.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Video_CCAM_Enhancing_Video_Language_Understanding_with_Causal_Cross_Attention_Masks_for_Short_and_Long_Videos/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14023v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level1">
<h1>Summary:</h1>
<p><strong>Summary:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The paper introduces Video-CCAM, a novel Video-MLLM designed for advanced video-language understanding.</li>
<li>Video-CCAM employs cross-attention mechanism to process videos of variable frames and CCAMs to capture the temporal relationship within videos.</li>
<li>The paper provides a theoretical analysis on the temporal consistency of CCAM, demonstrating that the CCAM projector remains consistent for videos with different numbers of frames.</li>
<li>Extensive experiments show that Video-CCAM ranks 1st in MVBench, 1st in VideoVista, 1st in MLVU, and 3rd in Video-MME among all open-source Video-MLLMs.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level1">
<h1>Major Findings:</h1>
<ol type="1">
<li>Video-CCAM is a flexible model composed of a visual encoder, an LLM, and a projector, which employs cross-attention mechanism to process videos of variable frames and CCAMs to capture the temporal relationship within videos.</li>
<li>The paper provides a theoretical analysis on the temporal consistency of CCAM, demonstrating that the CCAM projector remains consistent for videos with different numbers of frames.</li>
<li>Video-CCAM shows outstanding performance in various benchmarks, ranking 1st in MVBench, 1st in VideoVista, 1st in MLVU, and 3rd in Video-MME among all open-source Video-MLLMs.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level1">
<h1>Analysis and Critique:</h1>
<ul>
<li>The paper provides a comprehensive analysis of the temporal consistency of CCAM, which is a significant contribution to the field of video-language understanding.</li>
<li>The experimental results demonstrate the effectiveness of Video-CCAM in handling both short and long videos, which is a significant advantage over existing models.</li>
<li>However, the paper does not discuss the limitations or potential biases of Video-CCAM, which could be a topic for future research.</li>
<li>Additionally, the paper does not provide a comparison with other state-of-the-art models in terms of computational efficiency, which could be an important factor for practical applications.</li>
</ul>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-27</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14023v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14023v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14023v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14023v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5520</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Video_CCAM_Enhancing_Video_Language_Understanding_with_Causal_Cross_Attention_Masks_for_Short_and_Long_Videos/2024-08-26-Video_CCAM_Enhancing_Video_Language_Understanding_with_Causal_Cross_Attention_Masks_for_Short_and_Long_Videos.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14023v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Investigating the Effectiveness of Bayesian Spam Filters in Detecting LLM-modified Spam Mails</title>
  <dc:creator>Malte Josten, Torben Weis</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Investigating_the_Effectiveness_of_Bayesian_Spam_Filters_in_Detecting_LLM_modified_Spam_Mails/2024-08-26-Investigating_the_Effectiveness_of_Bayesian_Spam_Filters_in_Detecting_LLM_modified_Spam_Mails.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Investigating_the_Effectiveness_of_Bayesian_Spam_Filters_in_Detecting_LLM_modified_Spam_Mails/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14293v1/extracted/5814127/res/wordcloud-rejected-all.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level1">
<h1>Summary:</h1>
<p><strong>Investigating the Effectiveness of Bayesian Spam Filters in Detecting LLM-modified Spam Mails</strong></p>
<p>This study aims to evaluate the robustness and effectiveness of SpamAssassin, a Bayesian spam filter, against LLM-modified email content. The researchers developed a pipeline to test the vulnerability of SpamAssassin in classifying LLM-modified spam emails correctly. The results show that SpamAssassin misclassified up to 73.7% of LLM-modified spam emails as legitimate, compared to a simpler dictionary-replacement attack, which showed a maximum success rate of only 0.4%. These findings highlight the significant threat posed by LLM-modified spam, especially given the cost-efficiency of such attacks (0.17 cents per email).</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>LLM-modified spam emails bypass traditional spam filters</strong>: The study found that LLM-modified spam emails can evade traditional spam filters, with SpamAssassin misclassifying up to 73.7% of these emails as legitimate.</li>
<li><strong>Cost-efficiency of LLM-modified spam attacks</strong>: The cost-efficiency of LLM-modified spam attacks (0.17 cents per email) makes them a significant threat to cybersecurity.</li>
<li><strong>Limited effectiveness of simpler attacks</strong>: Simpler attacks, such as dictionary-replacement attacks, have limited effectiveness in bypassing spam filters, with a maximum success rate of only 0.4%.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h2>
<ul>
<li>The study provides valuable insights into the vulnerabilities of current spam filters against LLM-modified spam emails. However, it only evaluates SpamAssassin, and the results may not be generalizable to other spam filters.</li>
<li>The study uses a dataset that is almost 20 years old, which may not accurately represent the current state of spam emails. The use of more recent datasets could provide a more accurate evaluation of the effectiveness of LLM-modified spam emails.</li>
<li>The study does not consider the potential impact of LLM-modified spam emails on users, such as the potential for these emails to be more convincing and therefore more likely to result in successful phishing attacks.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-27</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14293v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14293v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14293v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14293v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>4258</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Investigating_the_Effectiveness_of_Bayesian_Spam_Filters_in_Detecting_LLM_modified_Spam_Mails/2024-08-26-Investigating_the_Effectiveness_of_Bayesian_Spam_Filters_in_Detecting_LLM_modified_Spam_Mails.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14293v1/extracted/5814127/res/wordcloud-rejected-all.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Are LLM-based Recommenders Already the Best? Simple Scaled Cross-entropy Unleashes the Potential of Traditional Sequential Recommenders</title>
  <dc:creator>Cong Xu, Zhangchi Zhu, Mo Yu, Jun Wang, Jianyong Wang, Wei Zhang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Are_LLM_based_Recommenders_Already_the_Best_Simple_Scaled_Cross_entropy_Unleashes_the_Potential_of_Traditional_Sequential_Recommenders/2024-08-26-Are_LLM_based_Recommenders_Already_the_Best_Simple_Scaled_Cross_entropy_Unleashes_the_Potential_of_Traditional_Sequential_Recommenders.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Are_LLM_based_Recommenders_Already_the_Best_Simple_Scaled_Cross_entropy_Unleashes_the_Potential_of_Traditional_Sequential_Recommenders/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14238v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level1">
<h1>Summary</h1>
<p>This study aims to clarify the superiority of the cross-entropy loss in improving the ranking capability of recommenders. The authors provide theoretical justification for the tightness and coverage properties of the cross-entropy loss and shed light on additional novel insights. They find that the cross-entropy loss is not yet optimal in terms of some ranking metrics and propose an effective alternative, scaling up the sampled normalizing term, when full softmax cannot be performed. These findings help unleash the potential of traditional recommendation models, allowing them to surpass LLM-based counterparts.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li>The cross-entropy loss has two desirable properties: tightness and coverage, which contribute to its superiority in improving the ranking capability of recommenders.</li>
<li>The cross-entropy loss is not yet optimal in terms of some ranking metrics, and an effective alternative is to scale up the sampled normalizing term when full softmax cannot be performed.</li>
<li>Traditional recommendation models can surpass LLM-based counterparts by utilizing the cross-entropy loss and the proposed alternative.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li>The study provides a valuable theoretical foundation for understanding the superiority of the cross-entropy loss in improving the ranking capability of recommenders.</li>
<li>The proposed alternative to the cross-entropy loss, scaling up the sampled normalizing term, is a promising approach when full softmax cannot be performed.</li>
<li>The study highlights the potential of traditional recommendation models, which can surpass LLM-based counterparts by utilizing the cross-entropy loss and the proposed alternative.</li>
<li>However, the study does not provide empirical evidence to support the theoretical findings, which could be a limitation.</li>
<li>The study focuses on the cross-entropy loss and its alternative, but other loss functions, such as binary cross-entropy and Bayesian personalized ranking, are not discussed in detail.</li>
<li>The study does not consider the computational complexity of the proposed alternative, which could be a concern in practical applications.</li>
</ol>
<p>In conclusion, this study provides valuable insights into the superiority of the cross-entropy loss in improving the ranking capability of recommenders and proposes an effective alternative when full softmax cannot be performed. However, the lack of empirical evidence and the focus on a single loss</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-27</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14238v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14238v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14238v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14238v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7714</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>recommender</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Are_LLM_based_Recommenders_Already_the_Best_Simple_Scaled_Cross_entropy_Unleashes_the_Potential_of_Traditional_Sequential_Recommenders/2024-08-26-Are_LLM_based_Recommenders_Already_the_Best_Simple_Scaled_Cross_entropy_Unleashes_the_Potential_of_Traditional_Sequential_Recommenders.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14238v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>LMM-VQA: Advancing Video Quality Assessment with Large Multimodal Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Qihang Ge, Wei Sun, Yu Zhang, Yunhao Li, Zhongpeng Ji, Fengyu Sun, Shangling Jui, Xiongkuo Min, Guangtao Zhai</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LMM_VQA_Advancing_Video_Quality_Assessment_with_Large_Multimodal_Models/2024-08-26-LMM_VQA_Advancing_Video_Quality_Assessment_with_Large_Multimodal_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LMM_VQA_Advancing_Video_Quality_Assessment_with_Large_Multimodal_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14008v1/x2.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level1">
<h1>Summary</h1>
<p>The paper introduces a novel approach to video quality assessment (VQA) using large multimodal models (LMMs), called LMM-VQA. The proposed method reformulates the quality regression problem into a question-and-answering (Q&amp;A) task and constructs Q&amp;A prompts for VQA instruction tuning. LMM-VQA employs a spatiotemporal vision encoder to extract spatial and temporal features, which are then mapped into the language space for modality alignment. The aligned visual tokens and quality-inquired text tokens are aggregated as inputs for the large language model (LLM) to generate the quality score and level.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li>LMM-VQA achieves state-of-the-art performance across five VQA benchmarks, demonstrating an average improvement of in generalization ability over existing methods.</li>
<li>The advanced design of the spatiotemporal encoder and projector enables LMM-VQA to perform exceptionally well on general video understanding tasks.</li>
<li>The code for LMM-VQA will be made available at <a href="https://github.com/Sueqk/LMM-VQA" class="uri">https://github.com/Sueqk/LMM-VQA</a>.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper presents a promising approach to VQA using LMMs, which has the potential to improve the performance and generalization ability of VQA models.</li>
<li>The use of a spatiotemporal vision encoder and modality alignment is a novel approach to addressing the challenges of VQA, which could inspire further research in this area.</li>
<li>The paper does not provide a detailed comparison of LMM-VQA with other state-of-the-art VQA methods, which could help to better understand its strengths and limitations.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the computational complexity and efficiency of LMM-VQA, which are important considerations for practical applications.</li>
<li>The paper does not provide a detailed analysis of the limitations and potential biases of LMM-VQA, which could help to identify areas for improvement and further research.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-27</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14008v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14008v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14008v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14008v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8834</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LMM_VQA_Advancing_Video_Quality_Assessment_with_Large_Multimodal_Models/2024-08-26-LMM_VQA_Advancing_Video_Quality_Assessment_with_Large_Multimodal_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14008v1/x2.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>TF-Attack: Transferable and Fast Adversarial Attacks on Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Zelin Li, Kehai Chen, Xuefeng Bai, Lemao Liu, Mingming Yang, Yang Xiang, Min Zhang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/TF_Attack_Transferable_and_Fast_Adversarial_Attacks_on_Large_Language_Models/2024-08-26-TF_Attack_Transferable_and_Fast_Adversarial_Attacks_on_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/TF_Attack_Transferable_and_Fast_Adversarial_Attacks_on_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.13985v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary:</strong></p>
<p>The paper introduces a new scheme, TF-Attack, for Transferable and Fast adversarial attacks on Large Language Models (LLMs). TF-Attack employs an external LLM as a third-party overseer to identify critical units within sentences, rather than the victim model. It also introduces the concept of Importance Level, which allows for parallel substitutions of attacks. The proposed method is evaluated on 6 widely adopted benchmarks, and results show that it consistently surpasses previous methods in transferability and delivers significant speed improvements, up to 20 times faster than earlier attack strategies.</p>
<p><strong>Major Findings:</strong></p>
<ol type="1">
<li>TF-Attack employs an external LLM as a third-party overseer to identify critical units within sentences, rather than the victim model.</li>
<li>TF-Attack introduces the concept of Importance Level, which allows for parallel substitutions of attacks.</li>
<li>TF-Attack consistently surpasses previous methods in transferability and delivers significant speed improvements, up to 20 times faster than earlier attack strategies.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></p>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper provides a detailed analysis of the core mechanisms of previous predominant adversarial attack methods, revealing their limitations in transferability and efficiency.</li>
<li>The proposed TF-Attack method addresses these limitations by employing an external LLM and introducing the concept of Importance Level.</li>
<li>The paper presents extensive experimental results on 6 widely adopted benchmarks, demonstrating the effectiveness of the proposed method.</li>
<li>However, the paper does not discuss potential countermeasures that could be developed to defend against TF-Attack.</li>
<li>The paper also does not discuss the potential ethical implications of using adversarial attacks on LLMs.</li>
<li>The paper could benefit from a more detailed discussion of the potential applications and implications of the proposed method.</li>
</ol>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-27</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13985v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13985v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.13985v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.13985v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7417</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>security</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/TF_Attack_Transferable_and_Fast_Adversarial_Attacks_on_Large_Language_Models/2024-08-26-TF_Attack_Transferable_and_Fast_Adversarial_Attacks_on_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.13985v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Exploring the Potential of Large Language Models for Heterophilic Graphs</title>
  <dc:creator>Yuxia Wu, Shujie Li, Yuan Fang, Chuan Shi</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Exploring_the_Potential_of_Large_Language_Models_for_Heterophilic_Graphs/2024-08-26-Exploring_the_Potential_of_Large_Language_Models_for_Heterophilic_Graphs.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Exploring_the_Potential_of_Large_Language_Models_for_Heterophilic_Graphs/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14134v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>This paper explores the potential of Large Language Models (LLMs) for enhancing Graph Neural Networks (GNNs) in handling heterophilic graphs, where connected nodes often exhibit dissimilar characteristics. The proposed two-stage framework, LLM4HeG, fine-tunes LLMs to improve GNNs for heterophilic graphs. The first stage involves LLM-enhanced edge discrimination, where an LLM is fine-tuned using Low-Rank Adaptation (LoRA) to distinguish heterophilic and homophilic edges based on a limited amount of ground truth labels. The second stage, LLM-guided edge reweighting, learns adaptive weights for both heterophilic and homophilic edges, enabling fine-grained, edge-sensitive aggregation in GNNs. To cope with the computational demands of deploying LLMs, model distillation techniques are explored to condense the knowledge from fine-tuned LLMs into smaller, more efficient models.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs can be effectively adapted to characterize and identify heterophilic contexts by fine-tuning an LLM using LoRA to discriminate heterophilic and homophilic edges based on a limited amount of ground truth labels.</li>
<li>LLMs can effectively guide the fine-grained integration of heterophilic contexts into graph models by learning adaptive weights for both heterophilic and homophilic edges, which are adapted to individual edges based on their features, structure, and heterophilic or homophilic characteristics.</li>
<li>Model distillation techniques can be used to condense the knowledge from fine-tuned LLMs into smaller, more efficient models, achieving faster inference time with minimal performance degradation.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The proposed framework, LLM4HeG, demonstrates the potential of LLMs for enhancing GNNs in handling heterophilic graphs. However, the following limitations and potential areas for improvement should be considered:</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>The computational demands of deploying LLMs for edge discrimination and reweighting may limit their practical deployment for real-world applications. While model distillation techniques can help address this issue, further research is needed</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-27</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14134v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14134v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14134v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14134v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8228</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Exploring_the_Potential_of_Large_Language_Models_for_Heterophilic_Graphs/2024-08-26-Exploring_the_Potential_of_Large_Language_Models_for_Heterophilic_Graphs.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14134v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Say Your Reason: Extract Contextual Rules In Situ for Context-aware Service Recommendation</title>
  <dc:creator>Yuxuan Li, Jiahui Li, Lihang Pan, Chun Yu, Yuanchun Shi</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Say_Your_Reason_Extract_Contextual_Rules_In_Situ_for_Context_aware_Service_Recommendation/2024-08-26-Say_Your_Reason_Extract_Contextual_Rules_In_Situ_for_Context_aware_Service_Recommendation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Say_Your_Reason_Extract_Contextual_Rules_In_Situ_for_Context_aware_Service_Recommendation/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.13977v1/extracted/5812909/image/ruleflow.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary:</strong></p>
<p>SayRea is an interactive system that facilitates the extraction of contextual rules for personalized context-aware service recommendations in mobile scenarios. The system monitors a user’s execution of registered services on their smartphones and proactively requests a single-sentence reason from the user. By utilizing a Large Language Model (LLM), SayRea parses the reason and predicts contextual relationships between the observed service and potential contexts. A 10-day field study involving 20 participants showed that SayRea accumulated an average of 62.4 rules per user and successfully recommended 45% of service usage. The participants provided positive feedback on the system’s usability, interpretability, and controllability.</p>
<p><strong>Major Findings:</strong></p>
<ol type="1">
<li>SayRea significantly reduces the cognitive load on users in anticipating future needs and selecting contextual attributes.</li>
<li>The system accumulated an average of 62.4 rules per user during the 10-day field study.</li>
<li>SayRea successfully recommended 45% of service usage during the study.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></p>
<ol type="1">
<li>The study could have included a larger and more diverse participant pool to increase the generalizability of the findings.</li>
<li>The study did not compare SayRea to other context-aware service recommendation systems, which could have provided a more comprehensive evaluation of its effectiveness.</li>
<li>The study did not address potential privacy concerns related to the collection and use of user data for context-aware service recommendations.</li>
<li>The study did not discuss the potential for the system to be used for targeted advertising or other potentially invasive purposes.</li>
<li>The study did not address the potential for the system to be used to manipulate user behavior or influence user decisions.</li>
<li>The study did not discuss the potential for the system to be used to collect sensitive user data, such as location or activity data, without user consent.</li>
<li>The study did not address the potential for the system to be used to collect and use user data in ways that are not transparent or easily understood by users.</li>
<li>The study did not discuss the potential for the system to be used to collect and use user data in ways that are not in the best interests of users.</li>
<li>The study did not address the potential for the</li>
</ol>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-27</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13977v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13977v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.13977v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.13977v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7194</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>recommender</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Say_Your_Reason_Extract_Contextual_Rules_In_Situ_for_Context_aware_Service_Recommendation/2024-08-26-Say_Your_Reason_Extract_Contextual_Rules_In_Situ_for_Context_aware_Service_Recommendation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.13977v1/extracted/5812909/image/ruleflow.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Towards Synthetic Trace Generation of Modeling Operations using In-Context Learning Approach</title>
  <dc:creator>Vittoriano Muttillo, Claudio Di Sipio, Riccardo Rubei, Luca Berardinelli, MohammadHadi Dehghani</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Towards_Synthetic_Trace_Generation_of_Modeling_Operations_using_In_Context_Learning_Approach/2024-08-26-Towards_Synthetic_Trace_Generation_of_Modeling_Operations_using_In_Context_Learning_Approach.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Towards_Synthetic_Trace_Generation_of_Modeling_Operations_using_In_Context_Learning_Approach/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14259v1/extracted/5814110/figs/imgMotivation.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper presents a conceptual framework that combines modeling event logs, intelligent modeling assistants (IMAs), and the generation of modeling operations using large language models (LLMs). The proposed framework aims to address the challenge of producing accurate software models in model-driven software engineering (MDE), which is an error-prone task that requires deep application domain knowledge. The framework leverages the in-context learning approach to generate modeling operations using LLMs, which can be used to train IMAs. The proposed framework is evaluated using a set of existing modeling tools employed in industrial use cases within different European projects. The evaluation focuses on assessing the capability of LLMs to generate realistic modeling operations and the recommended operations’ performance using real-world industrial modeling artifacts. The findings demonstrate that LLMs can generate modeling events, although the overall accuracy is higher when considering human-based operations. The proposed framework can be an alternative when modeling operations are not available to train traditional IMAs specifically conceived to support industrial practitioners.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The proposed framework combines modeling event logs, intelligent modeling assistants (IMAs), and the generation of modeling operations using large language models (LLMs) to address the challenge of producing accurate software models in MDE.</li>
<li>The framework leverages the in-context learning approach to generate modeling operations using LLMs, which can be used to train IMAs.</li>
<li>The proposed framework is evaluated using a set of existing modeling tools employed in industrial use cases within different European projects.</li>
<li>The evaluation focuses on assessing the capability of LLMs to generate realistic modeling operations and the recommended operations’ performance using real-world industrial modeling artifacts.</li>
<li>The findings demonstrate that LLMs can generate modeling events, although the overall accuracy is higher when considering human-based operations.</li>
<li>The proposed framework can be an alternative when modeling operations are not available to train traditional IMAs specifically conceived to support industrial practitioners.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The proposed framework presents a promising approach to address the challenge of producing accurate software models in MDE. The use of LLMs to generate modeling operations can be a valuable alternative when training data are not available due to different factors, such as internal regulations or privacy issues. However, the evaluation of the proposed framework is limited to a set of existing modeling tools employed in industrial</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-27</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14259v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14259v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14259v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14259v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>11478</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Towards_Synthetic_Trace_Generation_of_Modeling_Operations_using_In_Context_Learning_Approach/2024-08-26-Towards_Synthetic_Trace_Generation_of_Modeling_Operations_using_In_Context_Learning_Approach.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14259v1/extracted/5814110/figs/imgMotivation.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Probing Causality Manipulation of Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Chenyang Zhang, Haibo Tong, Bin Zhang, Dongyu Zhang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Probing_Causality_Manipulation_of_Large_Language_Models/2024-08-26-Probing_Causality_Manipulation_of_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Probing_Causality_Manipulation_of_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14380v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level1">
<h1>Summary:</h1>
<ul>
<li>The paper proposes a novel approach to probe the intrinsic manipulation of causality in large language models (LLMs) by providing different shortcuts and observing their behaviors.</li>
<li>The authors use retrieval augmented generation (RAG) and in-context learning (ICL) for models on a designed causality classification task.</li>
<li>The experiments are conducted on mainstream LLMs, including GPT-4 and some smaller and domain-specific models.</li>
<li>The results suggest that LLMs can detect entities related to causality and recognize direct causal relationships. However, LLMs lack specialized cognition for causality, merely treating them as part of the global semantic of the sentence.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level1">
<h1>Major Findings:</h1>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs can detect entities related to causality and recognize direct causal relationships.</li>
<li>LLMs lack specialized cognition for causality, treating causality as part of the global semantic of the sentence.</li>
<li>The proposed approach can effectively probe the intrinsic manipulation of causality in LLMs.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level1">
<h1>Analysis and Critique:</h1>
<ul>
<li>The paper provides a valuable contribution to the understanding of causality manipulation in LLMs.</li>
<li>The proposed approach is innovative and effective in probing the intrinsic manipulation of causality in LLMs.</li>
<li>The experiments are conducted on a diverse set of LLMs, which enhances the generalizability of the findings.</li>
<li>However, the paper does not discuss the limitations of the proposed approach or the potential biases in the experiments.</li>
<li>The paper also does not provide a detailed analysis of the results, which could have helped to better understand the strengths and weaknesses of the proposed approach.</li>
<li>The paper could have also discussed the implications of the findings for the development and evaluation of LLMs.</li>
</ul>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-27</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14380v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14380v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14380v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14380v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>4755</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Probing_Causality_Manipulation_of_Large_Language_Models/2024-08-26-Probing_Causality_Manipulation_of_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14380v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Beyond Detection: Leveraging Large Language Models for Cyber Attack Prediction in IoT Networks</title>
  <dc:creator>Alaeddine Diaf, Abdelaziz Amara Korba, Nour Elislem Karabadji, Yacine Ghamri-Doudane</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Beyond_Detection_Leveraging_Large_Language_Models_for_Cyber_Attack_Prediction_in_IoT_Networks/2024-08-26-Beyond_Detection_Leveraging_Large_Language_Models_for_Cyber_Attack_Prediction_in_IoT_Networks.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Beyond_Detection_Leveraging_Large_Language_Models_for_Cyber_Attack_Prediction_in_IoT_Networks/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14045v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper proposes a novel network intrusion prediction framework that combines Large Language Models (LLMs) with Long Short Term Memory (LSTM) networks to anticipate and mitigate malicious activities before they cause damage in IoT networks. The framework incorporates two LLMs in a feedback loop: a fine-tuned Generative Pre-trained Transformer (GPT) model for predicting network traffic and a fine-tuned Bidirectional Encoder Representations from Transformers (BERT) for evaluating the predicted traffic. The LSTM classifier model then identifies malicious packets among these predictions. The framework, evaluated on the CICIoT2023 IoT attack dataset, demonstrates a significant improvement in predictive capabilities, achieving an overall accuracy of 98%.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The proposed framework combines LLMs and LSTM networks to predict and evaluate network traffic, enabling the identification of malicious packets.</li>
<li>The framework achieves an overall accuracy of 98% when evaluated on the CICIoT2023 IoT attack dataset.</li>
<li>The use of LLMs in the framework allows for the prediction of network traffic, while the LSTM classifier identifies malicious packets.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The paper presents an innovative approach to network intrusion prediction by combining LLMs and LSTM networks. The use of LLMs for predicting network traffic is a novel application of these models, and the results demonstrate the effectiveness of this approach. However, the paper does not discuss the potential limitations or biases of the LLMs used in the framework. Additionally, the evaluation of the framework is limited to a single dataset, and further evaluation on diverse datasets would provide a more comprehensive understanding of the framework’s performance. The paper also does not discuss the potential for false positives or false negatives in the framework’s predictions, which is an important consideration in the context of network security.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-27</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14045v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14045v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14045v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14045v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5262</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Beyond_Detection_Leveraging_Large_Language_Models_for_Cyber_Attack_Prediction_in_IoT_Networks/2024-08-26-Beyond_Detection_Leveraging_Large_Language_Models_for_Cyber_Attack_Prediction_in_IoT_Networks.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14045v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>SWE-bench-java: A GitHub Issue Resolving Benchmark for Java</title>
  <dc:creator>Daoguang Zan, Zhirong Huang, Ailun Yu, Shaoxin Lin, Yifan Shi, Wei Liu, Dong Chen, Zongshuai Qi, Hao Yu, Lei Yu, Dezhi Ran, Muhan Zeng, Bo Shen, Pan Bian, Guangtai Liang, Bei Guan, Pengjie Huang, Tao Xie, Yongji Wang, Qianxiang Wang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SWE_bench_java_A_GitHub_Issue_Resolving_Benchmark_for_Java/2024-08-26-SWE_bench_java_A_GitHub_Issue_Resolving_Benchmark_for_Java.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SWE_bench_java_A_GitHub_Issue_Resolving_Benchmark_for_Java/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14354v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper introduces SWE-bench-java-verified, a Java version of the SWE-bench dataset, which is a benchmark for evaluating issue resolving capabilities of large language models (LLMs). The authors chose to develop a Java version of SWE-bench due to the popularity and platform independence of Java, as well as the need to support more programming languages in the industry. The paper describes the details of dataset construction, the main challenges, and potential problems. The authors also evaluate the performance of SWE-agent with state-of-the-art models on SWE-bench-java-verified.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The authors have developed a Java version of SWE-bench, named SWE-bench-java-verified, which marks the first step in establishing a multilingual GitHub issue-resolving benchmark with a focus on Java.</li>
<li>The dataset, along with a comprehensive evaluation Docker environment and a leaderboard, has been open-sourced to advance further research in this field.</li>
<li>The authors implemented SWE-Agent on SWE-bench-java-verified and derived several insightful findings that enhance our understanding of issue resolving in Java projects.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The paper provides a detailed description of the construction process of SWE-bench-java-verified and presents a comprehensive statistical analysis of the dataset. The authors have also open-sourced the dataset, evaluation Docker environment, and leaderboard, which is a significant contribution to the field. However, the paper does not provide a detailed analysis of the performance of the evaluated models on SWE-bench-java-verified. Additionally, the paper does not discuss any potential limitations or biases in the dataset. It would be beneficial to have a more in-depth analysis of the performance of the evaluated models and a discussion of any potential limitations or biases in the dataset.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-27</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14354v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14354v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14354v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14354v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>4964</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/SWE_bench_java_A_GitHub_Issue_Resolving_Benchmark_for_Java/2024-08-26-SWE_bench_java_A_GitHub_Issue_Resolving_Benchmark_for_Java.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14354v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Claim Verification in the Age of Large Language Models: A Survey</title>
  <dc:creator>Alphaeus Dmonte, Roland Oruche, Marcos Zampieri, Prasad Calyam, Isabelle Augenstein</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Claim_Verification_in_the_Age_of_Large_Language_Models_A_Survey/2024-08-26-Claim_Verification_in_the_Age_of_Large_Language_Models_A_Survey.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Claim_Verification_in_the_Age_of_Large_Language_Models_A_Survey/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14317v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level1">
<h1>Summary</h1>
<p>The increasing amount of data on the internet and the laborious task of manual claim and fact verification have led to the development of automated claim verification systems. This survey focuses on the use of Large Language Models (LLMs) in claim verification, which have shown superior performance in several NLP tasks. The survey covers the different components of the claim verification pipeline, including retrieval, prompting, and fine-tuning, and describes publicly available English datasets created for this task.</p>
<section id="major-findings" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs have been successful in claim verification, but they are prone to hallucinations and can generate incorrect information.</li>
<li>Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) is a novel method used in claim verification to aid LLMs in their decision-making abilities.</li>
<li>LLMs can be used to generate misinformation at scale, which can be exploited by malicious actors to spread wrong and factually incorrect information.</li>
<li>LLMs can generate incorrect veracity labels, as they may rely on obsolete information to assess the veracity of a claim.</li>
<li>Several English datasets have been created for claim verification, but there is a lack of multilingual fact-verification datasets.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique</h2>
<ul>
<li>The survey provides a comprehensive account of recent claim verification frameworks using LLMs, but it does not discuss the limitations and potential biases of these models.</li>
<li>The survey does not discuss the methodological issues and conflicting evidence in the use of LLMs for claim verification.</li>
<li>The survey does not provide a critical evaluation of the performance of LLMs in claim verification compared to traditional NLP-based models.</li>
<li>The survey does not discuss the potential risks and ethical implications of using LLMs for claim verification.</li>
<li>The survey does not provide a detailed analysis of the performance of LLMs in handling complex and long claims.</li>
<li>The survey does not discuss the potential applications of LLMs in claim verification beyond text-based data.</li>
<li>The survey does not discuss the potential impact of LLMs on the labor market and the future of fact-checking.</li>
<li>The survey does not discuss the potential impact of LLMs on the spread of misinformation and the role of fact-checking organizations in the age of LLMs.</li>
<li>The survey does not discuss the potential impact of LLMs on the development of new fact-checking</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-27</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14317v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14317v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14317v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14317v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7510</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Claim_Verification_in_the_Age_of_Large_Language_Models_A_Survey/2024-08-26-Claim_Verification_in_the_Age_of_Large_Language_Models_A_Survey.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14317v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Sifting through the Chaff: On Utilizing Execution Feedback for Ranking the Generated Code Candidates</title>
  <dc:creator>Zhihong Sun, Yao Wan, Jia Li, Hongyu Zhang, Zhi Jin, Ge Li, Chen Lyu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Sifting_through_the_Chaff_On_Utilizing_Execution_Feedback_for_Ranking_the_Generated_Code_Candidates/2024-08-26-Sifting_through_the_Chaff_On_Utilizing_Execution_Feedback_for_Ranking_the_Generated_Code_Candidates.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2408.13976v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>The paper presents a novel approach called RankEF, which utilizes execution feedback to enhance the efficiency of code ranking. The method integrates execution feedback and classification labels using multi-task learning, enabling the ranker to understand the underlying factors contributing to diverse code errors. The experimental results demonstrate that RankEF outperforms existing baseline methods due to its profound grasp of error causality. The paper also provides the availability of the experimental dataset and source code for further research.</p>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-27</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13976v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.13976v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.13976v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.13976v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>25044</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Sifting_through_the_Chaff_On_Utilizing_Execution_Feedback_for_Ranking_the_Generated_Code_Candidates/2024-08-26-Sifting_through_the_Chaff_On_Utilizing_Execution_Feedback_for_Ranking_the_Generated_Code_Candidates.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2408.13976v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>MLR-Copilot: Autonomous Machine Learning Research based on Large Language Models Agents</title>
  <dc:creator>Ruochen Li, Teerth Patel, Qingyun Wang, Xinya Du</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MLR_Copilot_Autonomous_Machine_Learning_Research_based_on_Large_Language_Models_Agents/2024-08-26-MLR_Copilot_Autonomous_Machine_Learning_Research_based_on_Large_Language_Models_Agents.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MLR_Copilot_Autonomous_Machine_Learning_Research_based_on_Large_Language_Models_Agents/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14033v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level1">
<h1>Summary:</h1>
<ul>
<li>The paper introduces MLR-Copilot, a framework for autonomous machine learning research using large language models (LLMs).</li>
<li>The framework consists of three phases: research idea generation, experiment implementation, and implementation execution.</li>
<li>Research idea generation involves using IdeaAgent, an LLM-powered agent, to generate hypotheses and experimental plans from existing research papers.</li>
<li>Experiment implementation translates these plans into executable experiments using ExperimentAgent, which leverages retrieved prototype code and candidate models and data.</li>
<li>The implementation execution phase involves running experiments with mechanisms for human feedback and iterative debugging.</li>
<li>The framework is evaluated on five machine learning research tasks, demonstrating its potential to facilitate research progress and innovations.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level1">
<h1>Major Findings:</h1>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Autonomous Machine Learning Research Framework</strong>: MLR-Copilot is a new systematic framework designed to enhance machine learning research productivity through the automatic generation and implementation of research ideas using LLM agents.</li>
<li><strong>Three-Phase Process</strong>: The framework operates in three integrated phases: research idea generation, experiment implementation, and implementation execution.</li>
<li><strong>Evaluation on Five Machine Learning Research Tasks</strong>: The experimental results show the framework’s potential to facilitate research progress and innovations.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level1">
<h1>Analysis and Critique:</h1>
<ul>
<li>The paper presents a novel approach to automating machine learning research using LLMs. However, it does not discuss the potential limitations or biases of the LLMs used in the framework.</li>
<li>The evaluation of the framework is limited to five machine learning research tasks. Further research is needed to assess its performance and applicability across a broader range of tasks and domains.</li>
<li>The paper does not provide a detailed comparison with other existing approaches to autonomous machine learning research, which could help to better understand the advantages and disadvantages of the proposed framework.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential ethical implications of using LLMs for autonomous research, such as the risk of perpetuating biases present in the training data.</li>
<li>The paper does not provide a clear explanation of how the framework handles the iterative nature of the research process, such as the refinement of hypotheses based on experimental results.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential impact of the framework on the role of human researchers in the research process. While the framework is designed to enhance research productivity,</li>
</ul>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-27</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14033v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14033v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14033v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14033v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>3929</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MLR_Copilot_Autonomous_Machine_Learning_Research_based_on_Large_Language_Models_Agents/2024-08-26-MLR_Copilot_Autonomous_Machine_Learning_Research_based_on_Large_Language_Models_Agents.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14033v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Fire-Flyer AI-HPC: A Cost-Effective Software-Hardware Co-Design for Deep Learning</title>
  <dc:creator>Wei An, Xiao Bi, Guanting Chen, Shanhuang Chen, Chengqi Deng, Honghui Ding, Kai Dong, Qiushi Du, Wenjun Gao, Kang Guan, Jianzhong Guo, Yongqiang Guo, Zhe Fu, Ying He, Panpan Huang, Jiashi Li, Wenfeng Liang, Xiaodong Liu, Xin Liu, Yiyuan Liu, Yuxuan Liu, Shanghao Lu, Xuan Lu, Xiaotao Nie, Tian Pei, Junjie Qiu, Hui Qu, Zehui Ren, Zhangli Sha, Xuecheng Su, Xiaowen Sun, Yixuan Tan, Minghui Tang, Shiyu Wang, Yaohui Wang, Yongji Wang, Ziwei Xie, Yiliang Xiong, Yanhong Xu, Shengfeng Ye, Shuiping Yu, Yukun Zha, Liyue Zhang, Haowei Zhang, Mingchuan Zhang, Wentao Zhang, Yichao Zhang, Chenggang Zhao, Yao Zhao, Shangyan Zhou, Shunfeng Zhou, Yuheng Zou</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Fire_Flyer_AI_HPC_A_Cost_Effective_Software_Hardware_Co_Design_for_Deep_Learning/2024-08-26-Fire_Flyer_AI_HPC_A_Cost_Effective_Software_Hardware_Co_Design_for_Deep_Learning.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Fire_Flyer_AI_HPC_A_Cost_Effective_Software_Hardware_Co_Design_for_Deep_Learning/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14158v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary:</strong></p>
<p>The paper introduces the Fire-Flyer AI-HPC architecture, a cost-effective hardware-software co-design framework for deep learning and large language models (LLMs). The authors deployed a cluster of 10,000 PCIe A100 GPUs for deep learning training, achieving performance comparable to the DGX-A100 while reducing costs by half and energy consumption by 40%. The architecture features a Two-Layer Fat-Tree Network integrating storage and computation, HFReduce for computation-communication overlap, and various software optimizations to keep the Computation-Storage Integrated Network congestion-free. The system-oriented experience from deep learning training provides valuable insights for future advancements in AI-HPC.</p>
<p><strong>Major Findings:</strong></p>
<ol type="1">
<li>The Fire-Flyer AI-HPC architecture, utilizing 10,000 PCIe A100 GPUs, achieves performance comparable to the DGX-A100 while reducing costs by half and energy consumption by 40%.</li>
<li>The Two-Layer Fat-Tree Network integrates storage and computation, while HFReduce enables computation-communication overlap, improving overall system performance.</li>
<li>Various software optimizations, such as HaiScale, 3FS, and HAI-Platform, contribute to the system’s scalability and congestion-free operation.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></p>
<p>The Fire-Flyer AI-HPC architecture presents a promising approach to addressing the increasing demands of computational power and bandwidth in deep learning and LLMs. The authors’ focus on cost-effectiveness and energy efficiency is commendable, as these factors are crucial for the widespread adoption of AI-HPC systems.</p>
<p>However, the paper could benefit from a more detailed discussion of the limitations and potential biases in the proposed architecture. For instance, the authors mention the need for software optimizations to address the performance challenges of the PCIe architecture, but they do not provide specific examples or discuss the potential trade-offs between performance and cost-effectiveness.</p>
<p>Additionally, the paper could benefit from a more comprehensive comparison with other existing AI-HPC architectures, highlighting the unique advantages and disadvantages of the Fire-Flyer AI-H</p>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-27</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14158v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14158v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14158v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14158v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>11170</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Fire_Flyer_AI_HPC_A_Cost_Effective_Software_Hardware_Co_Design_for_Deep_Learning/2024-08-26-Fire_Flyer_AI_HPC_A_Cost_Effective_Software_Hardware_Co_Design_for_Deep_Learning.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14158v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Assessing Contamination in Large Language Models: Introducing the LogProber method</title>
  <dc:creator>Nicolas Yax, Pierre-Yves Oudeyer, Stefano Palminteri</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Assessing_Contamination_in_Large_Language_Models_Introducing_the_LogProber_method/2024-08-26-Assessing_Contamination_in_Large_Language_Models_Introducing_the_LogProber_method.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Assessing_Contamination_in_Large_Language_Models_Introducing_the_LogProber_method/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14352v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper introduces LogProber, a novel algorithm designed to detect contamination in Large Language Models (LLMs) using token probability in given sentences. The method is particularly relevant for evaluating LLMs’ performance in cognitive tasks, where traditional evaluation methods may not be suitable due to the short length of the sequences. The authors demonstrate the effectiveness of LogProber in dedicated experiments, where they fine-tune a LLM with specific items from a cognitive test. The results show that the method is effective in detecting contamination, but it may not be able to identify contamination when the model is only trained on the answer tokens.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LogProber is a computationally cheap algorithm that can disentangle contamination from confidence in LLMs, making it suitable for evaluating LLMs’ performance in cognitive tasks.</li>
<li>The method is effective in detecting contamination when the model is trained on the full sequence of question and answer tokens.</li>
<li>LogProber may not be able to detect contamination when the model is only trained on the answer tokens, highlighting the need for further research in this area.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The paper presents a promising approach to detecting contamination in LLMs, but it is limited to evaluating contamination in the context of cognitive tasks. Further research is needed to determine the applicability of LogProber to other types of LLM evaluation tasks.</li>
<li>The authors acknowledge that LogProber may not be able to detect contamination when the model is only trained on the answer tokens. This limitation highlights the need for further research to develop more robust methods for detecting contamination in LLMs.</li>
<li>The paper does not provide a comprehensive evaluation of LogProber’s performance across different LLMs and datasets. Further research is needed to determine the generalizability of the method and its potential limitations.</li>
<li>The paper does not discuss the potential impact of contamination on the performance of LLMs in real-world applications. Further research is needed to determine the extent to which contamination may affect the reliability and validity of LLM-based systems.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-27</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14352v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14352v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14352v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14352v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6889</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Assessing_Contamination_in_Large_Language_Models_Introducing_the_LogProber_method/2024-08-26-Assessing_Contamination_in_Large_Language_Models_Introducing_the_LogProber_method.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14352v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Language-specific Calibration for Pruning Multilingual Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Simon Kurz, Zhixue Zhao, Jian-Jia Chen, Lucie Flek</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Language_specific_Calibration_for_Pruning_Multilingual_Language_Models/2024-08-26-Language_specific_Calibration_for_Pruning_Multilingual_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Language_specific_Calibration_for_Pruning_Multilingual_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14398v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The paper presents a comprehensive empirical study on the impact of calibration language on pruning multilingual language models. The authors investigate the performance of pruned models in various languages, comparing them to their full-sized counterparts. The study focuses on two state-of-the-art language model families, Llama-3 and Aya-23, and employs two post-training pruning methods, Wanda and SparseGPT. The experiments cover seven languages, including Arabic, German, English, Spanish, Russian, Swahili, and Chinese.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Calibrating on the target language consistently yields the lowest perplexity, but does not guarantee optimal performance on downstream tasks.</li>
<li>Pruning re-orders the strength language of the multilingual model, sacrificing performance in some strength languages for others after pruning.</li>
<li>No single pruning technique consistently outperforms others across different models and tasks. In general, SparseGPT is recommended for pruning Llama-3 8B, while both Wanda and SparseGPT exhibit mixed performance with Aya-23 8B.</li>
<li>Pruning substantially impacts the storage and retrieval of knowledge in a multilingual model across different languages.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The paper provides valuable insights into the impact of calibration language on pruning multilingual language models. However, the study is limited to two model families and does not explore the potential impact of other factors, such as model architecture or training data. Additionally, the experiments are primarily conducted on smaller models, and the results may not generalize to larger models or other tasks.</p>
<p>The authors acknowledge the limitations of their study, including the focus on a small number of languages and the lack of support for underrepresented languages. They also note that the results may not translate to future models or different training techniques.</p>
<p>In conclusion, the paper offers practical recommendations for future practitioners, emphasizing the importance of calibrating pruning in the target language and directly testing on downstream tasks. However, further research is needed to explore the impact of other factors and to validate the findings on a broader range of models and tasks.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-27</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14398v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14398v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14398v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14398v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5621</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Language_specific_Calibration_for_Pruning_Multilingual_Language_Models/2024-08-26-Language_specific_Calibration_for_Pruning_Multilingual_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14398v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Foundation Models for Music: A Survey</title>
  <dc:creator>Yinghao Ma, Anders Øland, Anton Ragni, Bleiz MacSen Del Sette, Charalampos Saitis, Chris Donahue, Chenghua Lin, Christos Plachouras, Emmanouil Benetos, Elio Quinton, Elona Shatri, Fabio Morreale, Ge Zhang, György Fazekas, Gus Xia, Huan Zhang, Ilaria Manco, Jiawen Huang, Julien Guinot, Liwei Lin, Luca Marinelli, Max W. Y. Lam, Megha Sharma, Qiuqiang Kong, Roger B. Dannenberg, Ruibin Yuan, Shangda Wu, Shih-Lun Wu, Shuqi Dai, Shun Lei, Shiyin Kang, Simon Dixon, Wenhu Chen, Wehhao Huang, Xingjian Du, Xingwei Qu, Xu Tan, Yizhi Li, Zeyue Tian, Zhiyong Wu, Zhizheng Wu, Ziyang Ma, Ziyu Wang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Foundation_Models_for_Music_A_Survey/2024-08-26-Foundation_Models_for_Music_A_Survey.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Foundation_Models_for_Music_A_Survey/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14340v1/extracted/5814373/fig/1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary:</strong></p>
<p>The paper discusses the significance of foundation models (FMs) in music, which have the potential to address data scarcity, reduce annotation costs, and enhance generalisation in music information retrieval and creation. FMs can provide a better understanding of unseen structures, genres, or instruments, and contribute to the protection of the cultural heritage of music. The paper focuses on two types of self-supervisedly pre-trained foundation models: single-modality pre-trained models in the waveform or symbolic domain, and multimodal pre-trained models that can take both natural language and music as input.</p>
<p><strong>Major Findings:</strong></p>
<ol type="1">
<li>Foundation models (FMs) can address data scarcity, reduce annotation costs, and enhance generalisation in music information retrieval and creation.</li>
<li>FMs can provide a better understanding of unseen structures, genres, or instruments, and contribute to the protection</li>
</ol>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>accounts/fireworks/models/mixtral-8x22b-instruct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-08-27</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14340v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14340v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14340v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14340v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>74043</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Foundation_Models_for_Music_A_Survey/2024-08-26-Foundation_Models_for_Music_A_Survey.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2408.14340v1/extracted/5814373/fig/1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
