<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Bayesian beagle</title>
<link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Quarto blog of LLM-generated summaries of Arxiv preprints</description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.450</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>From Summary to Action: Enhancing Large Language Models for Complex Tasks with Open World APIs</title>
  <dc:creator>Yulong Liu, Yunlong Yuan, Chunwei Wang, Jianhua Han, Yongqiang Ma, Li Zhang, Nanning Zheng, Hang Xu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/From_Summary_to_Action_Enhancing_Large_Language_Models_for_Complex_Tasks_with_Open_World_APIs/2024-02-28-From_Summary_to_Action_Enhancing_Large_Language_Models_for_Complex_Tasks_with_Open_World_APIs.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/From_Summary_to_Action_Enhancing_Large_Language_Models_for_Complex_Tasks_with_Open_World_APIs/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18157v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article introduces Sum2Act, a novel tool invocation pipeline designed to control real-world APIs and enhance Large Language Models (LLMs) for complex tasks.</li>
<li>Sum2Act is evaluated on the ToolBench benchmark and demonstrates significant performance improvements, outperforming established methods like ReAct and DFSDT.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Sum2Act outperforms existing baselines, including CoT and DFSDT, demonstrating its effectiveness in addressing complicated real-world tasks.</li>
<li>Sum2Act showcases high efficiency and adaptability across diverse testing scenarios, achieving impressive pass and win rates in evaluations.</li>
<li>The integration of visual APIs with Sum2Act enhances its capabilities, allowing LLMs to process visual data alongside textual data.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Sum2Act’s state manager effectively maintains an accurate understanding of the current task states, avoiding error propagation commonly observed in other methods.</li>
<li>The article highlights the limitations of simpler, chain-based reasoning methods in tackling complex, multi-faceted tasks, emphasizing the need for models with advanced error-handling capabilities.</li>
<li>The study demonstrates the practical application of Sum2Act in real-world scenarios, showcasing its proficiency in understanding and acting upon complex user directives.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18157v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18157v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18157v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18157v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6242</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/From_Summary_to_Action_Enhancing_Large_Language_Models_for_Complex_Tasks_with_Open_World_APIs/2024-02-28-From_Summary_to_Action_Enhancing_Large_Language_Models_for_Complex_Tasks_with_Open_World_APIs.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18157v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Making Them Ask and Answer: Jailbreaking Large Language Models in Few Queries via Disguise and Reconstruction</title>
  <dc:creator>Tong Liu, Yingjie Zhang, Zhe Zhao, Yinpeng Dong, Guozhu Meng, Kai Chen</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Making_Them_Ask_and_Answer_Jailbreaking_Large_Language_Models_in_Few_Queries_via_Disguise_and_Reconstruction/2024-02-28-Making_Them_Ask_and_Answer_Jailbreaking_Large_Language_Models_in_Few_Queries_via_Disguise_and_Reconstruction.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Making_Them_Ask_and_Answer_Jailbreaking_Large_Language_Models_in_Few_Queries_via_Disguise_and_Reconstruction/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18104v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The academic article “Making Them Ask and Answer: Jailbreaking Large Language Models in Few Queries via Disguise and Reconstruction” explores the vulnerability of large language models (LLMs) to jailbreak attacks, particularly in the context of harmful or toxic responses. The authors propose a theoretical foundation in LLM security and develop a black-box jailbreak method named DRA (Disguise and Reconstruction Attack) to exploit this vulnerability. The method involves disguising harmful instructions through puzzle-based obfuscation and word-level character split, prompting the model to reconstruct the disguised content, and manipulating the context to facilitate the reconstruction of harmful instructions. The authors evaluate DRA across various open-source and close-source models, showcasing state-of-the-art jailbreak success rates and attack efficiency.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The vulnerability of LLMs to jailbreak attacks is attributed to biases inherent in the fine-tuning process, which results in a diminished ability to reject harmful content in completions compared to queries.</li>
<li>The DRA method, which combines disguise, payload reconstruction, and context manipulation, demonstrates superior attack success rates and efficiency compared to state-of-the-art baselines across various LLMs.</li>
<li>The ablation study highlights the critical role of disguise, payload reconstruction, and context manipulation in bypassing the safeguard of LLMs.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article effectively identifies and analyzes the vulnerability of LLMs to jailbreak attacks, providing a novel approach to exploit this vulnerability.</li>
<li>The empirical evaluation of the DRA method demonstrates its effectiveness and efficiency in bypassing LLM safeguards.</li>
<li>The ablation study provides valuable insights into the nuanced interplay between disguise, payload reconstruction, and context manipulation in bypassing LLM safeguards.</li>
<li>The article could benefit from a more detailed discussion of potential ethical considerations and implications of the proposed jailbreak method.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the article makes a significant contribution to the understanding of LLM vulnerabilities and provides a novel approach to exploit these vulnerabilities for jailbreak attacks. Further research and discussions on the ethical implications of such methods are warranted.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18104v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18104v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18104v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18104v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>10757</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Making_Them_Ask_and_Answer_Jailbreaking_Large_Language_Models_in_Few_Queries_via_Disguise_and_Reconstruction/2024-02-28-Making_Them_Ask_and_Answer_Jailbreaking_Large_Language_Models_in_Few_Queries_via_Disguise_and_Reconstruction.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18104v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Editing Factual Knowledge and Explanatory Ability of Medical Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Derong Xu, Ziheng Zhang, Zhihong Zhu, Zhenxi Lin, Qidong Liu, Xian Wu, Tong Xu, Xiangyu Zhao, Yefeng Zheng, Enhong Chen</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Editing_Factual_Knowledge_and_Explanatory_Ability_of_Medical_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-28-Editing_Factual_Knowledge_and_Explanatory_Ability_of_Medical_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Editing_Factual_Knowledge_and_Explanatory_Ability_of_Medical_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18099v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Model editing aims to modify the behaviors of large language models (LLMs) by precisely manipulating specific knowledge while keeping other knowledge unaffected.</li>
<li>The proposed MedLaSA strategy employs causal tracing to identify the precise location of knowledge in neurons and introduces scalable adapters into the dense layers of LLMs.</li>
<li>Extensive experiments on medical LLMs demonstrate the editing efficiency of MedLaSA, without affecting irrelevant knowledge that is not edited.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Model editing methods struggle with the specialization and complexity of medical knowledge.</li>
<li>MedLaSA significantly outperforms existing cutting-edge methods in editing medical LLMs.</li>
<li>The removal of Scaling Rank (SR) leads to a decline in all metrics, indicating its crucial role in maintaining the overall performance.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The proposed MedLaSA method effectively addresses the challenges of specialization and complexity of medical knowledge in model editing.</li>
<li>However, the method may have a negative impact on Generality and lacks consideration for batch editing and sequence editing.</li>
<li>The datasets used for medical model editing do not consider more robust evaluations, such as portability, and the number of samples for medical model editing is relatively small.</li>
<li>The performance of MedLaSA on encyclopedic data remains to be explored.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18099v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18099v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18099v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18099v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6898</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Editing_Factual_Knowledge_and_Explanatory_Ability_of_Medical_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-28-Editing_Factual_Knowledge_and_Explanatory_Ability_of_Medical_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18099v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Unsupervised Information Refinement Training of Large Language Models for Retrieval-Augmented Generation</title>
  <dc:creator>Shicheng Xu, Liang Pang, Mo Yu, Fandong Meng, Huawei Shen, Xueqi Cheng, Jie Zhou</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Unsupervised_Information_Refinement_Training_of_Large_Language_Models_for_Retrieval_Augmented_Generation/2024-02-28-Unsupervised_Information_Refinement_Training_of_Large_Language_Models_for_Retrieval_Augmented_Generation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Unsupervised_Information_Refinement_Training_of_Large_Language_Models_for_Retrieval_Augmented_Generation/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18150v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper proposes a novel perspective that considers the role of Large Language Models (LLMs) in Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) as an “Information Refiner”.</li>
<li>It introduces an unsupervised training method named InFO-RAG that optimizes LLMs for RAG in a low-cost and general manner across various tasks.</li>
<li>Extensive experiments on 11 datasets in diverse tasks show that InFO-RAG improves the performance of LLaMA2 by an average of 9.39% relative points and demonstrates advantages in in-context learning and robustness of RAG.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The proposed InFO-RAG method improves the performance of LLMs for RAG across various tasks by an average of 9.39% relative points.</li>
<li>InFO-RAG demonstrates advantages in in-context learning and robustness of RAG.</li>
<li>The paper introduces a novel perspective that considers the role of LLMs in RAG as an “Information Refiner”.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The proposed InFO-RAG method shows significant improvements in RAG performance, especially in scenarios where retrieved texts contain incomplete, incorrect, or noisy information.</li>
<li>The paper provides a thorough analysis of the robustness of InFO-RAG to changes in retrieval performance, positive passage position, and the number of retrieved passages.</li>
<li>The experiments demonstrate that InFO-RAG avoids catastrophic forgetting and maintains the basic language understanding ability of LLMs.</li>
<li>However, the paper is limited by the lack of experiments on models with larger parameter sizes due to computing resource constraints. Further exploration of the performance of larger models is recommended.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18150v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18150v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18150v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18150v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7475</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Unsupervised_Information_Refinement_Training_of_Large_Language_Models_for_Retrieval_Augmented_Generation/2024-02-28-Unsupervised_Information_Refinement_Training_of_Large_Language_Models_for_Retrieval_Augmented_Generation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18150v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>No Token Left Behind: Reliable KV Cache Compression via Importance-Aware Mixed Precision Quantization</title>
  <dc:creator>June Yong Yang, Byeongwook Kim, Jeongin Bae, Beomseok Kwon, Gunho Park, Eunho Yang, Se Jung Kwon, Dongsoo Lee</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/No_Token_Left_Behind_Reliable_KV_Cache_Compression_via_Importance_Aware_Mixed_Precision_Quantization/2024-02-28-No_Token_Left_Behind_Reliable_KV_Cache_Compression_via_Importance_Aware_Mixed_Precision_Quantization.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/No_Token_Left_Behind_Reliable_KV_Cache_Compression_via_Importance_Aware_Mixed_Precision_Quantization/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18096v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article discusses the challenges posed by the memory footprint of Key-Value (KV) caching in Large Language Models (LLMs) and proposes a reliable cache compression method, Mixed-precision KV cache (MiKV), to address these challenges.</li>
<li>Recent methods for KV cache eviction to reduce memory consumption have been proposed, but the potential risks and impact on the generative process have not been thoroughly examined.</li>
<li>The proposed MiKV method retains evicted KV pairs in low precision and important KV pairs in high precision, effectively balancing compression ratio and performance.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The detrimental impact of cache eviction on the generative process, leading to safety breaches, hallucinations, and context loss.</li>
<li>Preserving even a small amount of information contained in the evicted KV pairs via reduced precision quantization substantially recovers the incurred degradation.</li>
<li>MiKV offers a state-of-the-art trade-off between compression ratio and performance compared to other baselines.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides a comprehensive analysis of the risks associated with KV cache eviction and proposes a novel method, MiKV, to address these risks.</li>
<li>The experiments conducted demonstrate the effectiveness of MiKV in preserving generation quality while achieving a high compression rate.</li>
<li>The proposed method addresses the limitations of existing cache compression strategies and provides a promising solution for the challenges posed by the memory footprint of KV caching in LLMs.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18096v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18096v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18096v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18096v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7020</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/No_Token_Left_Behind_Reliable_KV_Cache_Compression_via_Importance_Aware_Mixed_Precision_Quantization/2024-02-28-No_Token_Left_Behind_Reliable_KV_Cache_Compression_via_Importance_Aware_Mixed_Precision_Quantization.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18096v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Towards Generalist Prompting for Large Language Models by Mental Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Haoxiang Guan, Jiyan He, Shuxin Zheng, En-Hong Chen, Weiming Zhang, Nenghai Yu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Towards_Generalist_Prompting_for_Large_Language_Models_by_Mental_Models/2024-02-28-Towards_Generalist_Prompting_for_Large_Language_Models_by_Mental_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Towards_Generalist_Prompting_for_Large_Language_Models_by_Mental_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18252v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Large language models (LLMs) have shown impressive performance on various tasks, but still require specially designed prompting methods for optimal performance.</li>
<li>The article introduces the concept of generalist prompting, aiming to achieve optimal or near-optimal performance on a wide range of tasks without manual selection and customization of prompts.</li>
<li>MeMo (Mental Models) is proposed as a simple-designed prompting method that effectively fulfills the criteria of generalist prompting, achieving state-of-the-art results on diverse tasks in zero-shot settings.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The evolution of artificial intelligence (AI) models towards generalist capabilities has followed a distinct trajectory, with LLMs capable of handling a wide range of natural language processing tasks.</li>
<li>MeMo, as a generalist prompting method, achieves or is near to the state-of-the-art performance on diverse tasks with LLMs in zero-shot settings, eliminating manual selection and customization of prompts.</li>
<li>MeMo leverages the concept of mental models to enable LLMs to autonomously select and apply suitable mental models for problem-solving, surpassing existing prompting methods that require task-specific customization.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>MeMo suffers from high computational costs due to the long prompt that informs LLMs with the knowledge of mental models.</li>
<li>The approach relies on the availability and quality of exemplars, which can affect the selection and application of mental models.</li>
<li>The article does not guarantee the correctness or consistency of the mental models that LLMs employ, which can lead to errors or contradictions in some cases.</li>
<li>Future work could investigate how to verify and refine the mental models that LLMs generate, as well as how to enable LLMs to understand and apply mental models more accurately.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18252v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18252v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18252v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18252v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6820</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Towards_Generalist_Prompting_for_Large_Language_Models_by_Mental_Models/2024-02-28-Towards_Generalist_Prompting_for_Large_Language_Models_by_Mental_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18252v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>An Iterative Associative Memory Model for Empathetic Response Generation</title>
  <dc:creator>Zhou Yang, Zhaochun Ren, Yufeng Wang, Chao Chen, Haizhou Sun, Xiaofei Zhu, Xiangwen Liao</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/An_Iterative_Associative_Memory_Model_for_Empathetic_Response_Generation/2024-02-28-An_Iterative_Associative_Memory_Model_for_Empathetic_Response_Generation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/An_Iterative_Associative_Memory_Model_for_Empathetic_Response_Generation/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.17959v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Empathetic response generation is the task of understanding the cognitive and emotional states in dialogue utterances and generating appropriate responses.</li>
<li>Existing approaches overlook the associated words between dialogue utterances, leading to inaccurate understanding of emotional and cognitive states.</li>
<li>The proposed Iterative Associative Memory Model (IAMM) employs a second-order interaction attention mechanism to iteratively capture vital associated words between dialogue utterances and situations, dialogue history, and a memory module, thereby accurately and nuancedly comprehending the utterances.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>IAMM outperforms the baselines on most metrics, demonstrating better performance in emotion accuracy, diversity, and human evaluation.</li>
<li>Ablation studies show that both explicit and implicit associative information have considerable influence on emotion accuracy and diversity.</li>
<li>IAMM focusing on associative relationships has stronger emotion recognition and expression abilities, further demonstrating the effectiveness of iterative associations.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The proposed IAMM demonstrates superior performance in accurately understanding emotions and expressing more empathetic responses compared to the baselines.</li>
<li>The model effectively captures associated words and utilizes them to generate informative and relevant responses.</li>
<li>The analysis of associated words reveals that the model pays attention to common words with low emotions, while its most highly weighted words have high emotion intensity or are less common.</li>
<li>The limitations of the work include the reliance on text-based empathetic comprehension mechanisms and the lack of situation information in some datasets. Future work may explore multimodal empathetic comprehension mechanisms and effective construction of situation information.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.17959v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.17959v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.17959v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.17959v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6504</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/An_Iterative_Associative_Memory_Model_for_Empathetic_Response_Generation/2024-02-28-An_Iterative_Associative_Memory_Model_for_Empathetic_Response_Generation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.17959v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Decomposed Prompting: Unveiling Multilingual Linguistic Structure Knowledge in English-Centric Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Ercong Nie, Shuzhou Yuan, Bolei Ma, Helmut Schmid, Michael Färber, Frauke Kreuter, Hinrich Schütze</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Decomposed_Prompting_Unveiling_Multilingual_Linguistic_Structure_Knowledge_in_English_Centric_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-28-Decomposed_Prompting_Unveiling_Multilingual_Linguistic_Structure_Knowledge_in_English_Centric_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Decomposed_Prompting_Unveiling_Multilingual_Linguistic_Structure_Knowledge_in_English_Centric_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18397v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper introduces the decomposed prompting approach to probe the linguistic structure understanding of English-centric Large Language Models (LLMs) in sequence labeling tasks.</li>
<li>The method generates an individual prompt for each token of the input sentence, asking for its linguistic label.</li>
<li>The study assesses the method on the Universal Dependencies part-of-speech tagging dataset for 38 languages, utilizing both English-centric and multilingual LLMs.</li>
<li>Findings show that decomposed prompting surpasses the iterative prompting baseline in efficacy and efficiency under zero- and few-shot settings.</li>
<li>The study offers insights into the multilingual transferability of English-centric LLMs, contributing to the understanding of their multilingual linguistic knowledge.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Decomposed prompting outperforms iterative prompting in efficacy and efficiency under zero- and few-shot settings.</li>
<li>English-centric LLMs perform better on average than multilingual models in multilingual investigations.</li>
<li>The inclusion of an instruction in prompts negatively impacts the performance of LLMs in both probability-based and generation-based evaluation methods.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The decomposed prompting strategy struggles if the same word occurs twice in a sentence with different POS tags.</li>
<li>The efficiency of decomposed prompting suffers as the length of the input sequence and the complexity of the task increase.</li>
<li>The study uses decomposed prompting methods for part-of-speech (POS) tagging as a means to evaluate the multilingual structural knowledge of English-centric Large Language Models (LLMs). However, the scope for extending this methodology to probe more intricate aspects of linguistic structure is substantial.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18397v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18397v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18397v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18397v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6429</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Decomposed_Prompting_Unveiling_Multilingual_Linguistic_Structure_Knowledge_in_English_Centric_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-28-Decomposed_Prompting_Unveiling_Multilingual_Linguistic_Structure_Knowledge_in_English_Centric_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18397v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Benchmarking Large Language Models on Answering and Explaining Challenging Medical Questions</title>
  <dc:creator>Hanjie Chen, Zhouxiang Fang, Yash Singla, Mark Dredze</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Benchmarking_Large_Language_Models_on_Answering_and_Explaining_Challenging_Medical_Questions/2024-02-28-Benchmarking_Large_Language_Models_on_Answering_and_Explaining_Challenging_Medical_Questions.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Benchmarking_Large_Language_Models_on_Answering_and_Explaining_Challenging_Medical_Questions/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18060v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Large language models (LLMs) have shown impressive performance in answering medical questions, including passing medical licensing exams.</li>
<li>However, existing benchmarks do not capture the complexity of realistic clinical cases and lack reference explanations for answers, hindering the evaluation of model explanations.</li>
<li>To address these challenges, two new datasets, JAMA Clinical Challenge and Medbullets, have been constructed, consisting of challenging clinical cases and USMLE Step 2&amp;3 style clinical questions, respectively.</li>
<li>Four LLMs were evaluated on the two datasets, and it was found that the datasets are harder than previous benchmarks, highlighting the need for new metrics to support future research on explainable medical question-answering.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The new datasets, JAMA Clinical Challenge and Medbullets, are harder than previous benchmarks, posing a new challenge for medical LLM research.</li>
<li>The inconsistency between automatic and human evaluations of model-generated explanations emphasizes the necessity of developing new metrics for explainable medical question-answering.</li>
<li>LLMs have shown promising results in generating explanations for medical questions, but the quality of these explanations is challenging to evaluate.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article effectively highlights the limitations of existing benchmarks and the need for more challenging datasets to evaluate LLMs in the medical domain.</li>
<li>The inconsistency between automatic and human evaluations of model-generated explanations raises concerns about the reliability of current evaluation metrics and the need for more robust measures.</li>
<li>The article provides valuable insights into the challenges of evaluating LLMs in the medical domain and emphasizes the importance of developing new metrics to support future research in this area. However, the article could benefit from a more detailed discussion of potential biases in the datasets and the ethical implications of using LLMs in medical question-answering tasks.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18060v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18060v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18060v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18060v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7906</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Benchmarking_Large_Language_Models_on_Answering_and_Explaining_Challenging_Medical_Questions/2024-02-28-Benchmarking_Large_Language_Models_on_Answering_and_Explaining_Challenging_Medical_Questions.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18060v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Exploring Advanced Methodologies in Security Evaluation for LLMs</title>
  <dc:creator>Jun Huang, Jiawei Zhang, Qi Wang, Weihong Han, Yanchun Zhang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Exploring_Advanced_Methodologies_in_Security_Evaluation_for_LLMs/2024-02-28-Exploring_Advanced_Methodologies_in_Security_Evaluation_for_LLMs.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Exploring_Advanced_Methodologies_in_Security_Evaluation_for_LLMs/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.17970v1/extracted/5433502/fig_llm.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Large Language Models (LLMs) have advanced capabilities to handle complex language patterns and generate coherent text, images, audios, and videos.</li>
<li>The rapid expansion of LLMs has raised security and ethical concerns, emphasizing the need for ongoing research into security evaluation during their development and deployment.</li>
<li>The article provides a comprehensive analysis of commonly used evaluation metrics, advanced evaluation frameworks, and the routine evaluation processes for LLMs.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The proliferation of LLMs has raised security and ethical concerns, necessitating ongoing research into security evaluation during their development and deployment.</li>
<li>The article provides a comprehensive analysis of commonly used evaluation metrics, advanced evaluation frameworks, and the routine evaluation processes for LLMs.</li>
<li>The research highlights the need for more dedicated attention to security threats and evaluations of LLMs, particularly in the area of multimodal LLMs.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides a comprehensive overview of evaluation metrics, evaluation frameworks, and evaluation processes for LLMs, addressing the need for more research in the area of multimodal LLMs.</li>
<li>However, the article lacks a specific implementation plan necessary for conducting a security evaluation, and the discussion of known evaluation frameworks is not comprehensive.</li>
<li>Future research should focus on the development of automated evaluation platforms, comprehensive coverage of threats, and dedicated research into the unique vulnerabilities and security complexities of multimodal LLMs.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.17970v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.17970v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.17970v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.17970v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5922</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Exploring_Advanced_Methodologies_in_Security_Evaluation_for_LLMs/2024-02-28-Exploring_Advanced_Methodologies_in_Security_Evaluation_for_LLMs.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.17970v1/extracted/5433502/fig_llm.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Retrieval-based Full-length Wikipedia Generation for Emergent Events</title>
  <dc:creator>Jiebin Zhang, Eugene J. Yu, Qinyu Chen, Chenhao Xiong, Dawei Zhu, Han Qian, Mingbo Song, Xiaoguang Li, Qun Liu, Sujian Li</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Retrieval_based_Full_length_Wikipedia_Generation_for_Emergent_Events/2024-02-28-Retrieval_based_Full_length_Wikipedia_Generation_for_Emergent_Events.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Retrieval_based_Full_length_Wikipedia_Generation_for_Emergent_Events/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18264v1/extracted/5437378/figures/intro.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper addresses the challenge of quickly generating comprehensive and accurate Wikipedia documents for emerging events.</li>
<li>It introduces a new benchmark, WikiGenBen, consisting of 309 events paired with their corresponding retrieved web pages for generating evidence.</li>
<li>The study simulates a real-world scenario where structured full-length Wikipedia documents are generated for emergent events using input retrieved from web sources.</li>
<li>The authors design a comprehensive set of systematic evaluation metrics and baseline methods to evaluate the capability of Large Language Models (LLMs) in generating factual full-length Wikipedia documents.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Wikipedia serves as an important reference for various NLP tasks, but the task of automatically generating Wikipedia content in real-world scenarios has not been fully explored.</li>
<li>The retrieval-based generation of full-length Wikipedia articles is a common scenario ideally suited for the Retrieve-then-Read (RR) and Retrieve-Plan-Retrieve-Read (RPRR) methods.</li>
<li>The study finds that the number of retrieved documents, the type of retriever used, and the source of related documents all impact the informativeness and faithfulness of the generated Wikipedia articles.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study highlights the complexity of balancing various metrics in the generation of Wikipedia articles, emphasizing the need for refining task segmentation methods to enhance performance.</li>
<li>The authors acknowledge limitations in their section-by-section generation approach, potential redundancy, and the challenge of direct citation by LLMs, suggesting the need for further exploration of post-citation methods.</li>
<li>The paper raises ethical considerations and asserts that the research does not present any ethical issues, adhering to the ACL Ethics Policy.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18264v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18264v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18264v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18264v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6608</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Retrieval_based_Full_length_Wikipedia_Generation_for_Emergent_Events/2024-02-28-Retrieval_based_Full_length_Wikipedia_Generation_for_Emergent_Events.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18264v1/extracted/5437378/figures/intro.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>MIKO: Multimodal Intention Knowledge Distillation from Large Language Models for Social-Media Commonsense Discovery</title>
  <dc:creator>Feihong Lu, Weiqi Wang, Yangyifei Luo, Ziqin Zhu, Qingyun Sun, Baixuan Xu, Haochen Shi, Shiqi Gao, Qian Li, Yangqiu Song, Jianxin Li</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MIKO_Multimodal_Intention_Knowledge_Distillation_from_Large_Language_Models_for_Social_Media_Commonsense_Discovery/2024-02-28-MIKO_Multimodal_Intention_Knowledge_Distillation_from_Large_Language_Models_for_Social_Media_Commonsense_Discovery.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MIKO_Multimodal_Intention_Knowledge_Distillation_from_Large_Language_Models_for_Social_Media_Commonsense_Discovery/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18169v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article introduces Miko, a framework for extracting social intention knowledge from multimodal social media posts.</li>
<li>Miko leverages a Large Language Model (LLM) and a Multimodal Large Language Model (MLLM) to interpret images and extract key information from text to generate intentions.</li>
<li>The framework is evaluated intrinsically and extrinsically, demonstrating its effectiveness in generating high-quality intentions and improving sarcasm detection accuracy.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Miko uses MLLM to interpret images and LLM to extract key information from text to generate intentions.</li>
<li>The framework is capable of generating intentions that are highly plausible and typical to the user’s original post.</li>
<li>Incorporating intentions in current methods leads to state-of-the-art performances in sarcasm detection tasks.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides a comprehensive and well-structured framework for extracting social intention knowledge from social media posts.</li>
<li>The intrinsic and extrinsic evaluations demonstrate the effectiveness of the framework in generating high-quality intentions and improving the accuracy of downstream tasks.</li>
<li>The framework addresses the challenges of understanding implicit and commonsense intentions in social media posts, providing a valuable contribution to the field.</li>
<li>The article could benefit from a more detailed discussion of potential limitations or future research directions for the Miko framework.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18169v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18169v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18169v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18169v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7809</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MIKO_Multimodal_Intention_Knowledge_Distillation_from_Large_Language_Models_for_Social_Media_Commonsense_Discovery/2024-02-28-MIKO_Multimodal_Intention_Knowledge_Distillation_from_Large_Language_Models_for_Social_Media_Commonsense_Discovery.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18169v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Learning or Self-aligning? Rethinking Instruction Fine-tuning</title>
  <dc:creator>Mengjie Ren, Boxi Cao, Hongyu Lin, Liu Cao, Xianpei Han, Ke Zeng, Guanglu Wan, Xunliang Cai, Le Sun</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Learning_or_Self_aligning_Rethinking_Instruction_Fine_tuning/2024-02-28-Learning_or_Self_aligning_Rethinking_Instruction_Fine_tuning.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Learning_or_Self_aligning_Rethinking_Instruction_Fine_tuning/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18243v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Instruction Fine-tuning (IFT) is a critical phase in building large language models (LLMs).</li>
<li>Previous works mainly focus on the IFT’s role in the transfer of behavioral norms and the learning of additional world knowledge.</li>
<li>Surprisingly, attempts to learn additional world knowledge through IFT often struggle to yield positive impacts and can even lead to markedly negative effects.</li>
<li>Maintaining internal knowledge consistency before and after IFT is a critical factor for achieving successful IFT.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>IFT data consistent with model parameter knowledge leads to superior IFT outcomes.</li>
<li>Using IFT data that aligns with model parameter knowledge yet is erroneous yields better performance than employing those that are correct but incongruent with model parameter knowledge.</li>
<li>Ensuring that the model does not learn world knowledge conflicting with parameter knowledge during IFT enhances the effectiveness of IFT.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study focuses on the role of Instruction Fine-tuning (IFT) in large language models (LLMs) and its impact on the transfer of behavioral norms and additional world knowledge.</li>
<li>The findings reveal that the core function of IFT is not to learn domain-specific world knowledge, but to facilitate self-aligning instruction with the already existing parameter knowledge of LLMs.</li>
<li>The study provides guidance for future IFT data construction, model training, and model evaluation, shedding light on the future direction of data construction, model learning, and model evaluation for IFT.</li>
<li>The limitations of the study include the focus on multiple-choice questions and the use of models with about 10B parameters, which may limit the generalizability of the findings. Further research on larger models and free-style generation is recommended.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18243v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18243v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18243v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18243v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7107</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Learning_or_Self_aligning_Rethinking_Instruction_Fine_tuning/2024-02-28-Learning_or_Self_aligning_Rethinking_Instruction_Fine_tuning.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18243v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>How to think step-by-step: A mechanistic understanding of chain-of-thought reasoning</title>
  <dc:creator>Subhabrata Dutta, Joykirat Singh, Soumen Chakrabarti, Tanmoy Chakraborty</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/How_to_think_step_by_step_A_mechanistic_understanding_of_chain_of_thought_reasoning/2024-02-28-How_to_think_step_by_step_A_mechanistic_understanding_of_chain_of_thought_reasoning.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/../bayesian-beagle.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study investigates the neural sub-structures within Large Language Models (LLMs) that facilitate Chain-of-Thought (CoT) reasoning from a mechanistic point of view.</li>
<li>It identifies the components of the language model that are most important for a given task and explores the depth at which the model starts following the context provided as input.</li>
<li>The section discusses the attention heads in the language model (LLM) and their role in generating answers for different subtasks, as well as the use of fictional and false ontologies in the PrOntoQA dataset to prompt reasoning in large language models.</li>
<li>It presents Figure 14, illustrating the information flow through attention heads towards answer-writing heads in LLaMA-27B for subtask 5.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Large Language Models (LLMs) deploy multiple parallel pathways of answer generation for step-by-step reasoning.</li>
<li>The tasks are not structurally well-differentiated in the language model, and a good majority of heads share the importance of all three subtasks.</li>
<li>The model employs multiple pathways to compute answers, collecting information from different segments of the input.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The findings have implications for understanding the neural functional components involved in CoT reasoning and provide insights into the complex reasoning capabilities of LLMs.</li>
<li>The identification of parallel pathways for answer generation and the functional rift within the model layers contribute to a deeper understanding of LLMs’ reasoning processes.</li>
<li>The insights contribute to a deeper understanding of the circuitry of step-by-step generation in language models and can inform future research on language modeling and contribute to the development of more interpretable and reliable models.</li>
<li>The visual representation of the information flow highlights the complexity and multi-layered nature of the model’s processing, emphasizing the intricate mechanisms involved in generating responses and predicting specific tokens.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18312v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18312v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18312v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18312v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>24207</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/How_to_think_step_by_step_A_mechanistic_understanding_of_chain_of_thought_reasoning/2024-02-28-How_to_think_step_by_step_A_mechanistic_understanding_of_chain_of_thought_reasoning.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Cause and Effect: Can Large Language Models Truly Understand Causality?</title>
  <dc:creator>Swagata Ashwani, Kshiteesh Hegde, Nishith Reddy Mannuru, Mayank Jindal, Dushyant Singh Sengar, Krishna Chaitanya Rao Kathala, Dishant Banga, Vinija Jain, Aman Chadha</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Cause_and_Effect_Can_Large_Language_Models_Truly_Understand_Causality/2024-02-28-Cause_and_Effect_Can_Large_Language_Models_Truly_Understand_Causality.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Cause_and_Effect_Can_Large_Language_Models_Truly_Understand_Causality/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18139v1/extracted/5423783/model_accuracy_across_datasets.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article introduces the Context-Aware Reasoning Enhancement with Counterfactual Analysis (CARE-CA) framework to enhance causal reasoning and explainability in Large Language Models (LLMs).</li>
<li>The framework combines explicit causal detection with ConceptNet and implicit causal detection through LLMs, along with a layer of counterfactual explanations to accentuate LLMs’ understanding of causality.</li>
<li>Evaluation of benchmark datasets shows improved performance across all metrics, and the introduction of CausalNet, a new dataset, is aimed at facilitating further research in this domain.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The CARE-CA framework combines explicit and implicit causal reasoning to enhance LLMs’ understanding of causality.</li>
<li>Evaluation of benchmark datasets shows improved performance across all metrics, such as accuracy, precision, recall, and F1 scores.</li>
<li>The introduction of CausalNet, a new dataset, is aimed at facilitating further research in the domain of causal reasoning.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides a comprehensive approach to enhancing LLMs’ causal reasoning faculties, but it is limited to English language models, limiting its generalizability across languages and cultures.</li>
<li>The computational resources required by the CARE-CA framework may limit accessibility for those with constrained computational budgets, pointing to a need for optimization strategies.</li>
<li>The article acknowledges the ethical responsibilities of conducting research with LLMs and strives to prevent the propagation of bias within the CausalNet dataset. However, further research is required to improve transparency and explain the model’s reasoning processes, especially for non-expert users.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18139v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18139v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18139v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18139v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5773</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Cause_and_Effect_Can_Large_Language_Models_Truly_Understand_Causality/2024-02-28-Cause_and_Effect_Can_Large_Language_Models_Truly_Understand_Causality.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18139v1/extracted/5423783/model_accuracy_across_datasets.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>LeMo-NADe: Multi-Parameter Neural Architecture Discovery with LLMs</title>
  <dc:creator>Md Hafizur Rahman, Prabuddha Chakraborty</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LeMo_NADe_Multi_Parameter_Neural_Architecture_Discovery_with_LLMs/2024-02-28-LeMo_NADe_Multi_Parameter_Neural_Architecture_Discovery_with_LLMs.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LeMo_NADe_Multi_Parameter_Neural_Architecture_Discovery_with_LLMs/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18443v1/extracted/5438029/Figure/Overview.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Building efficient neural network architectures for edge devices is challenging due to parameters like power consumption, model size, and inferencing speed.</li>
<li>LeMo-NADe is a framework designed to automatically discover new neural network architectures based on user-defined parameters, an expert system, and an LLM trained on open-domain knowledge.</li>
<li>The framework was validated using CIFAR-10, CIFAR-100, and ImageNet16-120 datasets with GPT-4 Turbo and Gemini as the LLM component, showing rapid discovery of intricate neural network models.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Traditional NAS frameworks are limited by predefined search spaces, while LeMo-NADe does not rely on such spaces, allowing for the discovery of novel neural network architectures.</li>
<li>LeMo-NADe is capable of prioritizing metrics besides accuracy, making it optimal for different IoT/Edge requirements.</li>
<li>The framework outperforms traditional NAS techniques in terms of efficiency and performance across diverse application settings.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Traditional NAS techniques focus primarily on improving task accuracy with little emphasis on additional parameters such as frames-per-second, power consumption, and emissions, which are increasingly relevant.</li>
<li>The use of LLMs for neural architecture discovery raises questions about the generalization of the discovered architectures and the potential biases in the open-domain knowledge used to train the LLM.</li>
<li>The framework’s reliance on an expert system and user-defined metrics may introduce subjectivity and bias into the neural architecture discovery process.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18443v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18443v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18443v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18443v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5440</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LeMo_NADe_Multi_Parameter_Neural_Architecture_Discovery_with_LLMs/2024-02-28-LeMo_NADe_Multi_Parameter_Neural_Architecture_Discovery_with_LLMs.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18443v1/extracted/5438029/Figure/Overview.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Lemur: Log Parsing with Entropy Sampling and Chain-of-Thought Merging</title>
  <dc:creator>Hongcheng Guo, Wei Zhang, Anjie Le, Jian Yang, Jiaheng Liu, Zhoujun Li, Tieqiao Zheng, Shi Xu, Runqiang Zang, Liangfan Zheng, Bo Zhang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Lemur_Log_Parsing_with_Entropy_Sampling_and_Chain_of_Thought_Merging/2024-02-28-Lemur_Log_Parsing_with_Entropy_Sampling_and_Chain_of_Thought_Merging.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Lemur_Log_Parsing_with_Entropy_Sampling_and_Chain_of_Thought_Merging/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18205v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Logs are crucial for monitoring system behaviors and log parsing is essential for automating log analytics.</li>
<li>Existing log parsers rely on human-made rules and fail to identify correct templates due to a focus on statistical features and ignorance of semantic information in log messages.</li>
<li>Lemur, a new log parsing framework, introduces entropy sampling and chain-of-thought merging to address these challenges and achieves state-of-the-art performance and efficiency.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Lemur introduces entropy sampling to efficiently cluster typical logs and chain-of-thought merging for large language models to enhance log template merging.</li>
<li>Lemur outperforms other state-of-the-art methods in F1 score of grouping and template accuracy.</li>
<li>Lemur is the first unsupervised framework to combine information entropy and large language models for online log parsing.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Syntax-based log parsers are heavily dependent on meticulously crafted rules and their performance diminishes with the increase in log data volume and complexity.</li>
<li>Semantic-based log parsers falter in understanding semantics when applied to unfamiliar domains.</li>
<li>Lemur’s entropy sampling and chain-of-thought merging show promising results, but the improvement with chain-of-thought merging is limited, likely due to the relative simplicity of the loghub datasets.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18205v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18205v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18205v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18205v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5116</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Lemur_Log_Parsing_with_Entropy_Sampling_and_Chain_of_Thought_Merging/2024-02-28-Lemur_Log_Parsing_with_Entropy_Sampling_and_Chain_of_Thought_Merging.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18205v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Prospect Personalized Recommendation on Large Language Model-based Agent Platform</title>
  <dc:creator>Jizhi Zhang, Keqin Bao, Wenjie Wang, Yang Zhang, Wentao Shi, Wanhong Xu, Fuli Feng, Tat-Seng Chua</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Prospect_Personalized_Recommendation_on_Large_Language_Model_based_Agent_Platform/2024-02-28-Prospect_Personalized_Recommendation_on_Large_Language_Model_based_Agent_Platform.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/../bayesian-beagle.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article presents a clear and well-documented LATEX document formatted for publication by ACM in a conference proceedings or journal publication.</li>
<li>It explains many common variations and formatting elements an author may use in the preparation of their work.</li>
<li>The “acmart” document class can be used to prepare articles for any ACM publication, and the article provides insight and instruction into recent changes to the article template.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>ACM’s consolidated article template, introduced in 2017, provides a consistent LATEX style for use across ACM publications, incorporating accessibility and metadata-extraction functionality.</li>
<li>The “acmart” document class can be used to prepare different kinds of documentation, such as a double-blind initial submission of a full-length technical paper, a two-page SIGGRAPH Emerging Technologies abstract, a “camera-ready” journal article, a SIGCHI Extended Abstract, and more.</li>
<li>The article explains the primary parameter given to the “acmart” document class, which is the template style corresponding to the kind of publication or SIG publishing the work.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides a comprehensive guide for authors new to publishing with ACM, but it lacks a detailed discussion of the potential challenges or limitations of using the “acmart” document class.</li>
<li>The article does not address any methodological issues, conflicting evidence, or areas that require further research or clarification.</li>
<li>It would be beneficial to include a section discussing the potential biases or limitations of using the “acmart” document class and the impact on the publication process.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18240v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18240v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18240v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18240v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>4979</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>recommender</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Prospect_Personalized_Recommendation_on_Large_Language_Model_based_Agent_Platform/2024-02-28-Prospect_Personalized_Recommendation_on_Large_Language_Model_based_Agent_Platform.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>MEGAnno+: A Human-LLM Collaborative Annotation System</title>
  <dc:creator>Hannah Kim, Kushan Mitra, Rafael Li Chen, Sajjadur Rahman, Dan Zhang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MEGAnno+_A_Human_LLM_Collaborative_Annotation_System/2024-02-28-MEGAnno+_A_Human_LLM_Collaborative_Annotation_System.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MEGAnno+_A_Human_LLM_Collaborative_Annotation_System/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18050v1/extracted/5429938/fig/architecture.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>MEGAnno+ is a collaborative annotation system that advocates for human-LLM collaboration to produce reliable and high-quality labels.</li>
<li>The system offers effective LLM agent and annotation management, convenient and robust LLM annotation, and exploratory verification of LLM labels by humans.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs can label data faster and cheaper than humans for various NLP tasks, but they may fall short in understanding complex, sociocultural, or domain-specific context.</li>
<li>LLMs have limitations and may produce biased labels, making human intervention in the data annotation process necessary.</li>
<li>MEGAnno+ is a human-LLM collaborative annotation system that offers effective management of LLM agents, annotations, and artifacts, convenient and robust interfacing with LLMs to obtain labels, and selective, exploratory verification of LLM labels by humans.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Designing an annotation task: The article suggests that designing an annotation task and prompt similar to more widely used and standardized NLP tasks is beneficial.</li>
<li>Consistency and reliability of LLM annotators: The article highlights the need to understand that LLM annotators and human annotators should not be treated the same, and annotation tools should carefully design their data models and workflows to accommodate both types of annotators.</li>
<li>Limitations: The post-processing mechanism may not be robust to cover all tasks and prompts entered by the user, and the ability to capture metadata is contingent on the LLM model used.</li>
<li>Future work: The authors plan to add more LLM agents, support customized extraction of metadata, and improve prompt template UI for data-aware in-context learning.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the article provides valuable insights into the collaborative annotation system and highlights the need for careful consideration of the limitations and challenges associated with LLM annotation. The article’s emphasis on future work and ethical considerations demonstrates a thoughtful approach to addressing potential problems and shortcomings in the field of human-LLM collaborative annotation.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18050v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18050v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18050v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18050v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5302</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/MEGAnno+_A_Human_LLM_Collaborative_Annotation_System/2024-02-28-MEGAnno+_A_Human_LLM_Collaborative_Annotation_System.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18050v1/extracted/5429938/fig/architecture.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Keeping LLMs Aligned After Fine-tuning: The Crucial Role of Prompt Templates</title>
  <dc:creator>Kaifeng Lyu, Haoyu Zhao, Xinran Gu, Dingli Yu, Anirudh Goyal, Sanjeev Arora</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Keeping_LLMs_Aligned_After_Fine_tuning_The_Crucial_Role_of_Prompt_Templates/2024-02-28-Keeping_LLMs_Aligned_After_Fine_tuning_The_Crucial_Role_of_Prompt_Templates.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.18540v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article emphasizes the critical role of prompt templates in maintaining safety alignment in Large Language Models (LLMs) after fine-tuning. It introduces the “Pure Tuning, Safe Testing” (PTST) principle and demonstrates its effectiveness through extensive experiments on various chat models and datasets. The section also discusses the importance of using system prompts at test time to ensure safety and helpfulness.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The “Pure Tuning, Safe Testing” (PTST) principle significantly reduces unsafe behaviors in fine-tuned models.</li>
<li>Prompt template switching and testing (PTST) is effective in mitigating safety degradation and reducing the attack success rate on harmful queries.</li>
<li>The methodology used to evaluate the helpfulness of models in generating responses provides valuable insights into their reliability and effectiveness.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides valuable insights into the trade-off between model helpfulness and safety, contributing to the broader understanding of LLM fine-tuning practices.</li>
<li>The experiments on different models and datasets offer significant implications for the deployment of fine-tuned LLMs in public settings, emphasizing the importance of considering prompt templates in preserving safety.</li>
<li>The discussion on prompt templates for fine-tuning highlights the potential safety degradation when using the same training and test prompt templates, pointing to the significance of this aspect in LLM development and deployment.</li>
<li>The evaluation methodology used for assessing the helpfulness of models in generating responses provides essential insight into their reliability and effectiveness.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18540v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18540v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18540v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18540v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>19722</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Keeping_LLMs_Aligned_After_Fine_tuning_The_Crucial_Role_of_Prompt_Templates/2024-02-28-Keeping_LLMs_Aligned_After_Fine_tuning_The_Crucial_Role_of_Prompt_Templates.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.18540v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
