<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Bayesian beagle</title>
<link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Quarto blog of LLM-generated summaries of Arxiv preprints</description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.450</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Language Models Represent Beliefs of Self and Others</title>
  <dc:creator>Wentao Zhu, Zhining Zhang, Yizhou Wang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Language_Models_Represent_Beliefs_of_Self_and_Others/2024-02-28-Language_Models_Represent_Beliefs_of_Self_and_Others.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Language_Models_Represent_Beliefs_of_Self_and_Others/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18496v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Large Language Models (LLMs) possess Theory of Mind (ToM) capabilities, but the mechanisms underlying these capabilities are not well understood.</li>
<li>It is possible to linearly decode belief status from the perspectives of various agents through neural activations of language models, indicating the existence of internal representations of self and others’ beliefs.</li>
<li>Manipulating these representations can dramatically change the models’ ToM performance, underscoring their pivotal role in the social reasoning process.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs can distinguish between different belief states of multiple perspectives through their intermediate activation with simple linear models.</li>
<li>Manipulating these representations significantly affects the model’s social reasoning performances.</li>
<li>The internal belief representations in LLMs generalize across diverse social reasoning task scenarios.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study provides valuable insights into the ToM capabilities of LLMs, but it is limited to certain types of LLMs and specific social reasoning tasks, which may not capture the full spectrum of ToM capabilities.</li>
<li>Future work should aim to address these gaps, broadening the understanding of ToM in AI systems across various models and more complex contexts.</li>
<li>Ethical considerations are crucial to prevent misuse and bias propagation, ensuring AI’s societal impact is positive. Responsible development and transparent deployment are imperative to safeguard against unintended consequences and maintain trust in AI advancements.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18496v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18496v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18496v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18496v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6809</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Language_Models_Represent_Beliefs_of_Self_and_Others/2024-02-28-Language_Models_Represent_Beliefs_of_Self_and_Others.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18496v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Prospect Personalized Recommendation on Large Language Model-based Agent Platform</title>
  <dc:creator>Jizhi Zhang, Keqin Bao, Wenjie Wang, Yang Zhang, Wentao Shi, Wanhong Xu, Fuli Feng, Tat-Seng Chua</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Prospect_Personalized_Recommendation_on_Large_Language_Model_based_Agent_Platform/2024-02-28-Prospect_Personalized_Recommendation_on_Large_Language_Model_based_Agent_Platform.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/../bayesian-beagle.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article presents a clear and well-documented LATEX document formatted for publication by ACM in a conference proceedings or journal publication.</li>
<li>It explains many common variations and formatting elements an author may use in the preparation of their work.</li>
<li>The “acmart” document class can be used to prepare articles for any ACM publication, and the article provides insight and instruction into recent changes to the article template.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>ACM’s consolidated article template, introduced in 2017, provides a consistent LATEX style for use across ACM publications, incorporating accessibility and metadata-extraction functionality.</li>
<li>The “acmart” document class can be used to prepare different kinds of documentation, such as a double-blind initial submission of a full-length technical paper, a two-page SIGGRAPH Emerging Technologies abstract, a “camera-ready” journal article, a SIGCHI Extended Abstract, and more.</li>
<li>The article explains the primary parameter given to the “acmart” document class, which is the template style corresponding to the kind of publication or SIG publishing the work.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides a comprehensive guide for authors new to publishing with ACM, but it lacks a detailed discussion of the potential challenges or limitations of using the “acmart” document class.</li>
<li>The article does not address any methodological issues, conflicting evidence, or areas that require further research or clarification.</li>
<li>It would be beneficial to include a section discussing the potential biases or limitations of using the “acmart” document class and the impact on the publication process.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18240v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18240v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18240v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18240v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>4979</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>recommender</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Prospect_Personalized_Recommendation_on_Large_Language_Model_based_Agent_Platform/2024-02-28-Prospect_Personalized_Recommendation_on_Large_Language_Model_based_Agent_Platform.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>No Token Left Behind: Reliable KV Cache Compression via Importance-Aware Mixed Precision Quantization</title>
  <dc:creator>June Yong Yang, Byeongwook Kim, Jeongin Bae, Beomseok Kwon, Gunho Park, Eunho Yang, Se Jung Kwon, Dongsoo Lee</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/No_Token_Left_Behind_Reliable_KV_Cache_Compression_via_Importance_Aware_Mixed_Precision_Quantization/2024-02-28-No_Token_Left_Behind_Reliable_KV_Cache_Compression_via_Importance_Aware_Mixed_Precision_Quantization.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/No_Token_Left_Behind_Reliable_KV_Cache_Compression_via_Importance_Aware_Mixed_Precision_Quantization/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18096v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article discusses the challenges posed by the memory footprint of Key-Value (KV) caching in Large Language Models (LLMs) and proposes a reliable cache compression method, Mixed-precision KV cache (MiKV), to address these challenges.</li>
<li>Recent methods for KV cache eviction to reduce memory consumption have been proposed, but the potential risks and impact on the generative process have not been thoroughly examined.</li>
<li>The proposed MiKV method retains evicted KV pairs in low precision and important KV pairs in high precision, effectively balancing compression ratio and performance.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The detrimental impact of cache eviction on the generative process, leading to safety breaches, hallucinations, and context loss.</li>
<li>Preserving even a small amount of information contained in the evicted KV pairs via reduced precision quantization substantially recovers the incurred degradation.</li>
<li>MiKV offers a state-of-the-art trade-off between compression ratio and performance compared to other baselines.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides a comprehensive analysis of the risks associated with KV cache eviction and proposes a novel method, MiKV, to address these risks.</li>
<li>The experiments conducted demonstrate the effectiveness of MiKV in preserving generation quality while achieving a high compression rate.</li>
<li>The proposed method addresses the limitations of existing cache compression strategies and provides a promising solution for the challenges posed by the memory footprint of KV caching in LLMs.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18096v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18096v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18096v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18096v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7020</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/No_Token_Left_Behind_Reliable_KV_Cache_Compression_via_Importance_Aware_Mixed_Precision_Quantization/2024-02-28-No_Token_Left_Behind_Reliable_KV_Cache_Compression_via_Importance_Aware_Mixed_Precision_Quantization.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18096v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Making Them Ask and Answer: Jailbreaking Large Language Models in Few Queries via Disguise and Reconstruction</title>
  <dc:creator>Tong Liu, Yingjie Zhang, Zhe Zhao, Yinpeng Dong, Guozhu Meng, Kai Chen</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Making_Them_Ask_and_Answer_Jailbreaking_Large_Language_Models_in_Few_Queries_via_Disguise_and_Reconstruction/2024-02-28-Making_Them_Ask_and_Answer_Jailbreaking_Large_Language_Models_in_Few_Queries_via_Disguise_and_Reconstruction.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Making_Them_Ask_and_Answer_Jailbreaking_Large_Language_Models_in_Few_Queries_via_Disguise_and_Reconstruction/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18104v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The academic article “Making Them Ask and Answer: Jailbreaking Large Language Models in Few Queries via Disguise and Reconstruction” explores the vulnerability of large language models (LLMs) to jailbreak attacks, particularly in the context of harmful or toxic responses. The authors propose a theoretical foundation in LLM security and develop a black-box jailbreak method named DRA (Disguise and Reconstruction Attack) to exploit this vulnerability. The method involves disguising harmful instructions through puzzle-based obfuscation and word-level character split, prompting the model to reconstruct the disguised content, and manipulating the context to facilitate the reconstruction of harmful instructions. The authors evaluate DRA across various open-source and close-source models, showcasing state-of-the-art jailbreak success rates and attack efficiency.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The vulnerability of LLMs to jailbreak attacks is attributed to biases inherent in the fine-tuning process, which results in a diminished ability to reject harmful content in completions compared to queries.</li>
<li>The DRA method, which combines disguise, payload reconstruction, and context manipulation, demonstrates superior attack success rates and efficiency compared to state-of-the-art baselines across various LLMs.</li>
<li>The ablation study highlights the critical role of disguise, payload reconstruction, and context manipulation in bypassing the safeguard of LLMs.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article effectively identifies and analyzes the vulnerability of LLMs to jailbreak attacks, providing a novel approach to exploit this vulnerability.</li>
<li>The empirical evaluation of the DRA method demonstrates its effectiveness and efficiency in bypassing LLM safeguards.</li>
<li>The ablation study provides valuable insights into the nuanced interplay between disguise, payload reconstruction, and context manipulation in bypassing LLM safeguards.</li>
<li>The article could benefit from a more detailed discussion of potential ethical considerations and implications of the proposed jailbreak method.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the article makes a significant contribution to the understanding of LLM vulnerabilities and provides a novel approach to exploit these vulnerabilities for jailbreak attacks. Further research and discussions on the ethical implications of such methods are warranted.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18104v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18104v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18104v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18104v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>10757</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Making_Them_Ask_and_Answer_Jailbreaking_Large_Language_Models_in_Few_Queries_via_Disguise_and_Reconstruction/2024-02-28-Making_Them_Ask_and_Answer_Jailbreaking_Large_Language_Models_in_Few_Queries_via_Disguise_and_Reconstruction.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18104v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Benchmarking Large Language Models on Answering and Explaining Challenging Medical Questions</title>
  <dc:creator>Hanjie Chen, Zhouxiang Fang, Yash Singla, Mark Dredze</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Benchmarking_Large_Language_Models_on_Answering_and_Explaining_Challenging_Medical_Questions/2024-02-28-Benchmarking_Large_Language_Models_on_Answering_and_Explaining_Challenging_Medical_Questions.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Benchmarking_Large_Language_Models_on_Answering_and_Explaining_Challenging_Medical_Questions/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18060v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Large language models (LLMs) have shown impressive performance in answering medical questions, including passing medical licensing exams.</li>
<li>However, existing benchmarks do not capture the complexity of realistic clinical cases and lack reference explanations for answers, hindering the evaluation of model explanations.</li>
<li>To address these challenges, two new datasets, JAMA Clinical Challenge and Medbullets, have been constructed, consisting of challenging clinical cases and USMLE Step 2&amp;3 style clinical questions, respectively.</li>
<li>Four LLMs were evaluated on the two datasets, and it was found that the datasets are harder than previous benchmarks, highlighting the need for new metrics to support future research on explainable medical question-answering.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The new datasets, JAMA Clinical Challenge and Medbullets, are harder than previous benchmarks, posing a new challenge for medical LLM research.</li>
<li>The inconsistency between automatic and human evaluations of model-generated explanations emphasizes the necessity of developing new metrics for explainable medical question-answering.</li>
<li>LLMs have shown promising results in generating explanations for medical questions, but the quality of these explanations is challenging to evaluate.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article effectively highlights the limitations of existing benchmarks and the need for more challenging datasets to evaluate LLMs in the medical domain.</li>
<li>The inconsistency between automatic and human evaluations of model-generated explanations raises concerns about the reliability of current evaluation metrics and the need for more robust measures.</li>
<li>The article provides valuable insights into the challenges of evaluating LLMs in the medical domain and emphasizes the importance of developing new metrics to support future research in this area. However, the article could benefit from a more detailed discussion of potential biases in the datasets and the ethical implications of using LLMs in medical question-answering tasks.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18060v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18060v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18060v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18060v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7906</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Benchmarking_Large_Language_Models_on_Answering_and_Explaining_Challenging_Medical_Questions/2024-02-28-Benchmarking_Large_Language_Models_on_Answering_and_Explaining_Challenging_Medical_Questions.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18060v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Hire a Linguist!: Learning Endangered Languages with In-Context Linguistic Descriptions</title>
  <dc:creator>Kexun Zhang, Yee Man Choi, Zhenqiao Song, Taiqi He, William Yang Wang, Lei Li</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Hire_a_Linguist!_Learning_Endangered_Languages_with_In_Context_Linguistic_Descriptions/2024-02-28-Hire_a_Linguist!_Learning_Endangered_Languages_with_In_Context_Linguistic_Descriptions.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Hire_a_Linguist!_Learning_Endangered_Languages_with_In_Context_Linguistic_Descriptions/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18025v1/extracted/5435348/figs/resource_comparison.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<p>The article introduces LingoLLM, a novel approach for enabling large language models (LLMs) to process and translate endangered languages. LingoLLM integrates linguistic descriptions such as grammar books and dictionaries, which are often more available for endangered languages than extensive corpora. The authors demonstrate the effectiveness of LingoLLM on multiple tasks across eight endangered and/or low-resource languages. The results show significant improvements in translation, conversation understanding, mathematical reasoning, word reordering, and keyword-to-text tasks.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LingoLLM significantly improves translation capability from GPT-4’s to BLEU for 9 out of 10 translation directions.</li>
<li>LingoLLM improves LLMs’ ability to select correct responses, achieving performance comparable to high-resource language inputs.</li>
<li>LingoLLM significantly improves the mathematical reasoning ability of LLMs on Manchu, solving 75% of the problems.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides valuable insights into the potential of linguistic knowledge in the age of LLMs for endangered languages.</li>
<li>The limitations of the study include the experiment being limited to 8 languages and potential contamination in reasoning tasks.</li>
<li>The impact statement highlights the importance of LingoLLM in preserving endangered languages and promoting linguistic equity.</li>
</ul>
<p>The article provides a comprehensive and innovative approach to addressing the challenges of processing and translating endangered languages using LLMs. However, the limitations and potential biases in the study should be carefully considered in future research.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18025v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18025v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18025v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18025v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7035</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Hire_a_Linguist!_Learning_Endangered_Languages_with_In_Context_Linguistic_Descriptions/2024-02-28-Hire_a_Linguist!_Learning_Endangered_Languages_with_In_Context_Linguistic_Descriptions.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18025v1/extracted/5435348/figs/resource_comparison.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Gradient-Free Adaptive Global Pruning for Pre-trained Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Guangji Bai, Yijiang Li, Chen Ling, Kibaek Kim, Liang Zhao</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Gradient_Free_Adaptive_Global_Pruning_for_Pre_trained_Language_Models/2024-02-28-Gradient_Free_Adaptive_Global_Pruning_for_Pre_trained_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Gradient_Free_Adaptive_Global_Pruning_for_Pre_trained_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.17946v1/extracted/5436159/figures/adagp_intro.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<p>The article introduces Adaptive Global Pruning (AdaGP), a novel framework for compressing large language models (LLMs) by introducing sparsity to enhance memory and computational efficiency. AdaGP redefines the global pruning process into manageable subproblems, allowing for resource-efficient optimization with global optimality. The proposed approach not only facilitates a pragmatic application on LLMs but also demonstrates significant performance improvements, particularly in high-sparsity regimes where it surpasses current state-of-the-art methods.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Large language models (LLMs) necessitate significant computational resources, leading to extensive efforts in model compression, including pruning, quantization, knowledge distillation, and low-rank factorization.</li>
<li>Traditional global pruning is impractical for LLMs due to scalability issues, while local pruning leads to suboptimal solutions, especially in high-sparsity regimes.</li>
<li>Adaptive Global Pruning (AdaGP) decomposes the global pruning objective into many subproblems, each of which can be solved using low resources and can coordinate each other toward the global pruning objective. It consistently improves the performance of local pruning methods, particularly in high sparsity regimes.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>AdaGP marks a significant step forward in efficient pruning of large language models, but there is an inevitable balance between sparsity and performance that requires careful calibration.</li>
<li>The effectiveness of AdaGP may vary across different models and tasks, and its generalizability to all scenarios remains an area for further exploration.</li>
<li>The approach assumes certain structural properties of the neural network, such as layer-wise decomposability, which may not hold for all architectures.</li>
<li>The article provides detailed experiments and results, showcasing the potential of AdaGP in enhancing the performance and accessibility of LLMs. However, further research and refinement are needed to address the limitations and challenges identified.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.17946v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.17946v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.17946v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.17946v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6875</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Gradient_Free_Adaptive_Global_Pruning_for_Pre_trained_Language_Models/2024-02-28-Gradient_Free_Adaptive_Global_Pruning_for_Pre_trained_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.17946v1/extracted/5436159/figures/adagp_intro.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>How to think step-by-step: A mechanistic understanding of chain-of-thought reasoning</title>
  <dc:creator>Subhabrata Dutta, Joykirat Singh, Soumen Chakrabarti, Tanmoy Chakraborty</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/How_to_think_step_by_step_A_mechanistic_understanding_of_chain_of_thought_reasoning/2024-02-28-How_to_think_step_by_step_A_mechanistic_understanding_of_chain_of_thought_reasoning.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/../bayesian-beagle.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study investigates the neural sub-structures within Large Language Models (LLMs) that facilitate Chain-of-Thought (CoT) reasoning from a mechanistic point of view.</li>
<li>It identifies the components of the language model that are most important for a given task and explores the depth at which the model starts following the context provided as input.</li>
<li>The section discusses the attention heads in the language model (LLM) and their role in generating answers for different subtasks, as well as the use of fictional and false ontologies in the PrOntoQA dataset to prompt reasoning in large language models.</li>
<li>It presents Figure 14, illustrating the information flow through attention heads towards answer-writing heads in LLaMA-27B for subtask 5.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Large Language Models (LLMs) deploy multiple parallel pathways of answer generation for step-by-step reasoning.</li>
<li>The tasks are not structurally well-differentiated in the language model, and a good majority of heads share the importance of all three subtasks.</li>
<li>The model employs multiple pathways to compute answers, collecting information from different segments of the input.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The findings have implications for understanding the neural functional components involved in CoT reasoning and provide insights into the complex reasoning capabilities of LLMs.</li>
<li>The identification of parallel pathways for answer generation and the functional rift within the model layers contribute to a deeper understanding of LLMs’ reasoning processes.</li>
<li>The insights contribute to a deeper understanding of the circuitry of step-by-step generation in language models and can inform future research on language modeling and contribute to the development of more interpretable and reliable models.</li>
<li>The visual representation of the information flow highlights the complexity and multi-layered nature of the model’s processing, emphasizing the intricate mechanisms involved in generating responses and predicting specific tokens.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18312v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18312v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18312v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18312v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>24207</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/How_to_think_step_by_step_A_mechanistic_understanding_of_chain_of_thought_reasoning/2024-02-28-How_to_think_step_by_step_A_mechanistic_understanding_of_chain_of_thought_reasoning.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Automated Discovery of Integral with Deep Learning</title>
  <dc:creator>Xiaoxin Yin</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Automated_Discovery_of_Integral_with_Deep_Learning/2024-02-28-Automated_Discovery_of_Integral_with_Deep_Learning.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Automated_Discovery_of_Integral_with_Deep_Learning/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18040v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Recent advancements in deep learning have shown that AI can solve complex mathematical problems and programming challenges.</li>
<li>This study explores the potential of using deep learning to rediscover the fundamental mathematical concept of integrals.</li>
<li>The experiments demonstrate that deep learning models can approach the task of inferring integrals with high accuracy.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Deep Learning for Rediscovering Integrals:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The study delves into the potential of using deep learning to rediscover the fundamental mathematical concept of integrals.</li>
<li>Trained on a large set of randomly generated univariate functions, AI models can successfully infer the mathematical expression of the integral of a given function.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Model Training and Accuracy:</strong>
<ul>
<li>GPT-Neo and Flan-T5 models were trained to predict the integral function from the original function.</li>
<li>GPT-Neo demonstrated higher accuracy in inferring integrals of both polynomial and non-polynomial functions.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Discovering Rules of Integrals:</strong>
<ul>
<li>A rule search system was designed to automatically discover the basic rules of integrals for different types of functions, such as polynomials, exponential, and trigonometric functions.</li>
</ul></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The study demonstrates the potential of deep learning models in rediscovering mathematical concepts such as integrals, showcasing high accuracy in inferring integral functions.</li>
<li>The rule search system successfully discovered the basic rules of integrals for different types of functions, providing valuable insights into the capabilities of AI in mathematical discovery.</li>
<li>However, the study’s focus on basic mathematical concepts leaves room for further exploration into more complex problems and scientific discoveries using AI.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the study presents a promising approach to using deep learning for rediscovering mathematical concepts and lays the groundwork for future research in automated scientific discovery using AI. However, further research is needed to explore more complex problems and scientific discoveries using AI.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18040v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18040v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18040v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18040v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8583</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Automated_Discovery_of_Integral_with_Deep_Learning/2024-02-28-Automated_Discovery_of_Integral_with_Deep_Learning.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18040v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Exploring Multi-Document Information Consolidation for Scientific Sentiment Summarization</title>
  <dc:creator>Miao Li, Jey Han Lau, Eduard Hovy</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Exploring_Multi_Document_Information_Consolidation_for_Scientific_Sentiment_Summarization/2024-02-28-Exploring_Multi_Document_Information_Consolidation_for_Scientific_Sentiment_Summarization.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Exploring_Multi_Document_Information_Consolidation_for_Scientific_Sentiment_Summarization/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18005v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article explores the capability of modern natural language generation systems to consolidate information from multiple documents and generate plausible summaries, especially when the source documents contain opinionated information.</li>
<li>The authors propose a three-layer framework of sentiment consolidation in meta-review generation and validate it through human annotation. They also introduce evaluation metrics to assess the quality of generated meta-reviews and find empirical validation of the sentiment consolidation framework when integrated as prompts for language models (LLMs) in extensive experiments.</li>
<li>The authors conclude that integrating the sentiment consolidation framework into LLMs can improve the generation of meta-reviews and propose future work to adapt the framework to other domains and investigate its application to fine-tuned models.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Notable strides have been made in abstractive text summarization with the advancement of large language models (LLMs) over recent years.</li>
<li>The proposed three-layer framework of sentiment consolidation in meta-review generation is validated through human annotation and empirical experiments.</li>
<li>Integration of the sentiment consolidation framework into LLMs improves the generation of meta-reviews.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides valuable insights into the potential of integrating sentiment consolidation logic into language models for generating meta-reviews.</li>
<li>The proposed framework and evaluation metrics offer a systematic approach to assess the quality of generated meta-reviews.</li>
<li>However, the limitations of the study, such as the lack of publicly available peer review data and the focus on English texts, should be addressed in future research.</li>
<li>The authors emphasize the importance of manual verification and review of generated results, highlighting the ethical considerations of relying solely on machine-generated meta-reviews.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18005v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18005v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18005v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18005v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6260</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Exploring_Multi_Document_Information_Consolidation_for_Scientific_Sentiment_Summarization/2024-02-28-Exploring_Multi_Document_Information_Consolidation_for_Scientific_Sentiment_Summarization.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18005v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>LeMo-NADe: Multi-Parameter Neural Architecture Discovery with LLMs</title>
  <dc:creator>Md Hafizur Rahman, Prabuddha Chakraborty</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LeMo_NADe_Multi_Parameter_Neural_Architecture_Discovery_with_LLMs/2024-02-28-LeMo_NADe_Multi_Parameter_Neural_Architecture_Discovery_with_LLMs.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LeMo_NADe_Multi_Parameter_Neural_Architecture_Discovery_with_LLMs/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18443v1/extracted/5438029/Figure/Overview.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Building efficient neural network architectures for edge devices is challenging due to parameters like power consumption, model size, and inferencing speed.</li>
<li>LeMo-NADe is a framework designed to automatically discover new neural network architectures based on user-defined parameters, an expert system, and an LLM trained on open-domain knowledge.</li>
<li>The framework was validated using CIFAR-10, CIFAR-100, and ImageNet16-120 datasets with GPT-4 Turbo and Gemini as the LLM component, showing rapid discovery of intricate neural network models.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Traditional NAS frameworks are limited by predefined search spaces, while LeMo-NADe does not rely on such spaces, allowing for the discovery of novel neural network architectures.</li>
<li>LeMo-NADe is capable of prioritizing metrics besides accuracy, making it optimal for different IoT/Edge requirements.</li>
<li>The framework outperforms traditional NAS techniques in terms of efficiency and performance across diverse application settings.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Traditional NAS techniques focus primarily on improving task accuracy with little emphasis on additional parameters such as frames-per-second, power consumption, and emissions, which are increasingly relevant.</li>
<li>The use of LLMs for neural architecture discovery raises questions about the generalization of the discovered architectures and the potential biases in the open-domain knowledge used to train the LLM.</li>
<li>The framework’s reliance on an expert system and user-defined metrics may introduce subjectivity and bias into the neural architecture discovery process.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18443v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18443v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18443v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18443v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5440</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LeMo_NADe_Multi_Parameter_Neural_Architecture_Discovery_with_LLMs/2024-02-28-LeMo_NADe_Multi_Parameter_Neural_Architecture_Discovery_with_LLMs.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18443v1/extracted/5438029/Figure/Overview.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>A Survey on Recent Advances in LLM-Based Multi-turn Dialogue Systems</title>
  <dc:creator>Zihao Yi, Jiarui Ouyang, Yuwen Liu, Tianhao Liao, Zhe Xu, Ying Shen</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_Survey_on_Recent_Advances_in_LLM_Based_Multi_turn_Dialogue_Systems/2024-02-28-A_Survey_on_Recent_Advances_in_LLM_Based_Multi_turn_Dialogue_Systems.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_Survey_on_Recent_Advances_in_LLM_Based_Multi_turn_Dialogue_Systems/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18013v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides an overview of large language models (LLMs) and their application in multi-turn dialogue systems, discussing the limitations of conventional dialogue systems and delving into different types of LLMs, such as decoder-only and encoder-only architectures, as well as specific LLM models like GPT and BERT series.</li>
<li>It discusses the encoder-decoder Transformer architecture, focusing on BART and T5 models, fine-tuning methods, and mitigating fine-tuning instabilities through methods like Regularization Fine-tuning (R3F), SMART, and Free Large-Batch Adversarial Training (FreeLB), as well as prompt engineering and LLM Based Task-oriented Dialogue Systems.</li>
<li>The article also covers pipeline-based methods in task-oriented dialogue (TOD) systems, highlighting natural language understanding, dialogue state tracking, policy learning, and natural language generation, and the challenges and advancements in each module.</li>
<li>It discusses the development and application of LLMs in multi-turn dialogue systems, emphasizing the significance of LLMs in advancing dialogue systems and addressing challenges such as emotionalization, personalization, multi-task dialogue systems, multi-model dialogue systems, bias identification, and privacy protection.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Large language models (LLMs) play a crucial role in advancing multi-turn dialogue systems, addressing challenges such as emotionalization, personalization, and bias identification.</li>
<li>The article highlights the significance of pre-training and fine-tuning methods for Transformer models, showcasing their potential in natural language processing tasks and dialogue systems.</li>
<li>Pipeline-based methods in task-oriented dialogue systems are essential for natural language understanding, dialogue state tracking, policy learning, and natural language generation, contributing to the overall effectiveness of dialogue systems.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides a comprehensive overview of LLMs and their application in dialogue systems, but it could benefit from more in-depth discussions on the ethical implications and potential biases associated with LLM-based dialogue systems.</li>
<li>While the article covers various pre-training and fine-tuning methods, it would be valuable to include a comparative analysis of their effectiveness in different dialogue system applications.</li>
<li>The discussion on pipeline-based methods in task-oriented dialogue systems is informative, but further exploration of real-world applications and case studies would enhance the practical relevance of the article.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18013v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18013v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18013v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18013v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>18047</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_Survey_on_Recent_Advances_in_LLM_Based_Multi_turn_Dialogue_Systems/2024-02-28-A_Survey_on_Recent_Advances_in_LLM_Based_Multi_turn_Dialogue_Systems.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18013v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Beyond Natural Language: LLMs Leveraging Alternative Formats for Enhanced Reasoning and Communication</title>
  <dc:creator>Weize Chen, Chenfei Yuan, Jiarui Yuan, Yusheng Su, Chen Qian, Cheng Yang, Ruobing Xie, Zhiyuan Liu, Maosong Sun</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Beyond_Natural_Language_LLMs_Leveraging_Alternative_Formats_for_Enhanced_Reasoning_and_Communication/2024-02-28-Beyond_Natural_Language_LLMs_Leveraging_Alternative_Formats_for_Enhanced_Reasoning_and_Communication.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Beyond_Natural_Language_LLMs_Leveraging_Alternative_Formats_for_Enhanced_Reasoning_and_Communication/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18439v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article challenges the default use of natural language (NL) by exploring the utility of non-NL formats in single-LLM reasoning and multi-agent communication.</li>
<li>Allowing LLMs to autonomously select the most suitable format before reasoning or communicating leads to a 3.3 to 5.7% improvement in reasoning efficiency for different LLMs and up to a 72.7% reduction in token usage in multi-agent communication.</li>
<li>LLMs can devise a format from limited task instructions and the devised format is effectively transferable across different LLMs.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs can autonomously select the most suitable format before reasoning or communicating, leading to improved reasoning efficiency and reduced token usage in multi-agent communication.</li>
<li>LLMs can devise a format from limited task instructions and the devised format is effectively transferable across different LLMs.</li>
<li>The communication formats decided by LLMs exhibit notable parallels with established agent communication languages, suggesting a natural evolution towards efficient, structured communication in agent communication.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides valuable insights into the potential of LLMs to utilize non-NL formats for reasoning and communication. However, the scope of alternative formats explored is still not exhaustive, and further research is needed to fully harness the capabilities of alternative formats.</li>
<li>The generalization of chosen formats across tasks shows variability in effectiveness depending on the complexity of the task and the specific LLM used, highlighting the need for further exploration.</li>
<li>While LLMs can emulate the formality of traditional ACL formats, the AutoForm approach optimizes communication by enhancing clarity and structure, yet concurrently reduces token usage.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18439v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18439v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18439v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18439v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7115</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Beyond_Natural_Language_LLMs_Leveraging_Alternative_Formats_for_Enhanced_Reasoning_and_Communication/2024-02-28-Beyond_Natural_Language_LLMs_Leveraging_Alternative_Formats_for_Enhanced_Reasoning_and_Communication.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18439v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Decomposed Prompting: Unveiling Multilingual Linguistic Structure Knowledge in English-Centric Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Ercong Nie, Shuzhou Yuan, Bolei Ma, Helmut Schmid, Michael Färber, Frauke Kreuter, Hinrich Schütze</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Decomposed_Prompting_Unveiling_Multilingual_Linguistic_Structure_Knowledge_in_English_Centric_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-28-Decomposed_Prompting_Unveiling_Multilingual_Linguistic_Structure_Knowledge_in_English_Centric_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Decomposed_Prompting_Unveiling_Multilingual_Linguistic_Structure_Knowledge_in_English_Centric_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18397v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper introduces the decomposed prompting approach to probe the linguistic structure understanding of English-centric Large Language Models (LLMs) in sequence labeling tasks.</li>
<li>The method generates an individual prompt for each token of the input sentence, asking for its linguistic label.</li>
<li>The study assesses the method on the Universal Dependencies part-of-speech tagging dataset for 38 languages, utilizing both English-centric and multilingual LLMs.</li>
<li>Findings show that decomposed prompting surpasses the iterative prompting baseline in efficacy and efficiency under zero- and few-shot settings.</li>
<li>The study offers insights into the multilingual transferability of English-centric LLMs, contributing to the understanding of their multilingual linguistic knowledge.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Decomposed prompting outperforms iterative prompting in efficacy and efficiency under zero- and few-shot settings.</li>
<li>English-centric LLMs perform better on average than multilingual models in multilingual investigations.</li>
<li>The inclusion of an instruction in prompts negatively impacts the performance of LLMs in both probability-based and generation-based evaluation methods.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The decomposed prompting strategy struggles if the same word occurs twice in a sentence with different POS tags.</li>
<li>The efficiency of decomposed prompting suffers as the length of the input sequence and the complexity of the task increase.</li>
<li>The study uses decomposed prompting methods for part-of-speech (POS) tagging as a means to evaluate the multilingual structural knowledge of English-centric Large Language Models (LLMs). However, the scope for extending this methodology to probe more intricate aspects of linguistic structure is substantial.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18397v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18397v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18397v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18397v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6429</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Decomposed_Prompting_Unveiling_Multilingual_Linguistic_Structure_Knowledge_in_English_Centric_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-28-Decomposed_Prompting_Unveiling_Multilingual_Linguistic_Structure_Knowledge_in_English_Centric_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18397v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Small But Funny: A Feedback-Driven Approach to Humor Distillation</title>
  <dc:creator>Sahithya Ravi, Patrick Huber, Akshat Shrivastava, Aditya Sagar, Ahmed Aly, Vered Shwartz, Arash Einolghozati</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Small_But_Funny_A_Feedback_Driven_Approach_to_Humor_Distillation/2024-02-28-Small_But_Funny_A_Feedback_Driven_Approach_to_Humor_Distillation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Small_But_Funny_A_Feedback_Driven_Approach_to_Humor_Distillation/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18113v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article explores the use of feedback-driven knowledge distillation to transfer complex language abilities, specifically humor generation, from Large Language Models (LLMs) to Small Language Models (SLMs).</li>
<li>The study hypothesizes that creative tasks like humor generation may be hard to learn by imitation alone and investigates the use of feedback from the LLM as a “critic” to evaluate the student’s performance.</li>
<li>Experiments reveal that incorporating feedback significantly narrows the performance gap between SLMs and LLMs in humor generation, highlighting the potential of using feedback as an additional dimension to data when transferring complex language abilities via distillation.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The study explores the use of feedback-driven knowledge distillation to transfer complex language abilities, specifically humor generation, from LLMs to SLMs.</li>
<li>Incorporating feedback from the LLM as a “critic” significantly narrows the performance gap between SLMs and LLMs in humor generation.</li>
<li>The study highlights the potential of using feedback as an additional dimension to data when transferring complex language abilities via distillation.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides valuable insights into the potential of feedback-driven knowledge distillation for transferring complex language abilities, such as humor generation, from LLMs to SLMs.</li>
<li>The study addresses limitations of relying solely on imitation for creative tasks and proposes a novel approach involving feedback from the LLM as a “critic” to guide the student model.</li>
<li>The article acknowledges potential biases and limitations in LLM-based evaluation and feedback, emphasizing the need for further research in mitigating biases and ensuring cultural sensitivity in humor generation.</li>
<li>The study raises ethical considerations related to data sources, offensive content, and cultural references, highlighting the importance of responsible and inclusive language model training and evaluation.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18113v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18113v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18113v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18113v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7067</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Small_But_Funny_A_Feedback_Driven_Approach_to_Humor_Distillation/2024-02-28-Small_But_Funny_A_Feedback_Driven_Approach_to_Humor_Distillation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18113v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Exploring Advanced Methodologies in Security Evaluation for LLMs</title>
  <dc:creator>Jun Huang, Jiawei Zhang, Qi Wang, Weihong Han, Yanchun Zhang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Exploring_Advanced_Methodologies_in_Security_Evaluation_for_LLMs/2024-02-28-Exploring_Advanced_Methodologies_in_Security_Evaluation_for_LLMs.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Exploring_Advanced_Methodologies_in_Security_Evaluation_for_LLMs/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.17970v1/extracted/5433502/fig_llm.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Large Language Models (LLMs) have advanced capabilities to handle complex language patterns and generate coherent text, images, audios, and videos.</li>
<li>The rapid expansion of LLMs has raised security and ethical concerns, emphasizing the need for ongoing research into security evaluation during their development and deployment.</li>
<li>The article provides a comprehensive analysis of commonly used evaluation metrics, advanced evaluation frameworks, and the routine evaluation processes for LLMs.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The proliferation of LLMs has raised security and ethical concerns, necessitating ongoing research into security evaluation during their development and deployment.</li>
<li>The article provides a comprehensive analysis of commonly used evaluation metrics, advanced evaluation frameworks, and the routine evaluation processes for LLMs.</li>
<li>The research highlights the need for more dedicated attention to security threats and evaluations of LLMs, particularly in the area of multimodal LLMs.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides a comprehensive overview of evaluation metrics, evaluation frameworks, and evaluation processes for LLMs, addressing the need for more research in the area of multimodal LLMs.</li>
<li>However, the article lacks a specific implementation plan necessary for conducting a security evaluation, and the discussion of known evaluation frameworks is not comprehensive.</li>
<li>Future research should focus on the development of automated evaluation platforms, comprehensive coverage of threats, and dedicated research into the unique vulnerabilities and security complexities of multimodal LLMs.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.17970v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.17970v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.17970v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.17970v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5922</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Exploring_Advanced_Methodologies_in_Security_Evaluation_for_LLMs/2024-02-28-Exploring_Advanced_Methodologies_in_Security_Evaluation_for_LLMs.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.17970v1/extracted/5433502/fig_llm.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Rethinking the Bounds of LLM Reasoning: Are Multi-Agent Discussions the Key?</title>
  <dc:creator>Qineng Wang, Zihao Wang, Ying Su, Hanghang Tong, Yangqiu Song</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Rethinking_the_Bounds_of_LLM_Reasoning_Are_Multi_Agent_Discussions_the_Key/2024-02-28-Rethinking_the_Bounds_of_LLM_Reasoning_Are_Multi_Agent_Discussions_the_Key.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Rethinking_the_Bounds_of_LLM_Reasoning_Are_Multi_Agent_Discussions_the_Key/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18272v1/extracted/5436554/assets/pic/fig1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<p>Recent progress in LLMs discussion suggests that multi-agent discussion improves the reasoning abilities of LLMs. In this work, a novel group discussion framework is proposed to enrich the set of discussion mechanisms. The results show that a single-agent LLM with strong prompts can achieve almost the same performance as the best existing discussion approach on a wide range of reasoning tasks and backbone LLMs. Multi-agent discussion performs better than a single agent only when there is no demonstration in the prompt. Further study reveals the common interaction mechanisms of LLMs during the discussion.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>A single-agent LLM with strong prompts can achieve almost the same performance as the best existing discussion approach on a wide range of reasoning tasks and backbone LLMs.</li>
<li>Multi-agent discussion performs better than a single agent only when there is no demonstration in the prompt.</li>
<li>Common interaction mechanisms of LLMs during the discussion were revealed.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study provides valuable insights into the effectiveness of multi-agent discussions for reasoning tasks.</li>
<li>The findings suggest that prompt engineering can significantly boost reasoning performance in large language models.</li>
<li>The study highlights the potential for multi-agent discussions to enhance reasoning abilities in scenarios where expert knowledge or detailed examples are insufficient.</li>
<li>The research also identifies two common types of errors in multi-agent discussions: Judge Mistake and Wrong Answer Propagation.</li>
<li>The study provides a comprehensive and fair assessment of the performance of a strong single agent and multi-agent discussions, offering valuable insights for future research.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18272v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18272v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18272v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18272v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>9233</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Rethinking_the_Bounds_of_LLM_Reasoning_Are_Multi_Agent_Discussions_the_Key/2024-02-28-Rethinking_the_Bounds_of_LLM_Reasoning_Are_Multi_Agent_Discussions_the_Key.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18272v1/extracted/5436554/assets/pic/fig1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Human Simulacra: A Step toward the Personification of Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Qiuejie Xie, Qiming Feng, Tianqi Zhang, Qingqiu Li, Yuejie Zhang, Rui Feng, Shang Gao</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Human_Simulacra_A_Step_toward_the_Personification_of_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-28-Human_Simulacra_A_Step_toward_the_Personification_of_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Human_Simulacra_A_Step_toward_the_Personification_of_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18180v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Large language models (LLMs) are being explored as systems that can mimic human intelligence, with potential applications in replacing human participants in experiments.</li>
<li>The paper introduces a framework for large language models personification, including a strategy for constructing virtual characters’ life stories, a Multi-Agent Cognitive Mechanism for simulating human cognitive processes, and a psychology-guided evaluation method.</li>
<li>Experimental results demonstrate that the constructed simulacra can produce personified responses that align with their target characters.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs can simulate human cognitive processes, assisting researchers in exploring human interactions without real human participants.</li>
<li>The Multi-Agent Cognitive Mechanism enhances the quality of simulacra by simulating human brain’s information processing and memory systems.</li>
<li>The psychology-guided evaluation method assesses the quality of human simulations from both self-reporting and external observation perspectives.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper’s approach has limitations, including data insufficiency, evaluation challenges, and inherited model limitations.</li>
<li>The evaluation framework for measuring LLMs’ humanizing capabilities is complex and subjective, requiring further development.</li>
<li>LLMs may face challenges in accurately defining the knowledge boundaries of the target persona and producing harmful viewpoints or toxic content during interaction.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the paper provides a preliminary exploration of the potential of Large Language Model Personification, offering a fresh perspective for understanding complex human behaviors and expanding the potential applications of artificial intelligence in social science and psychological research. However, there are several limitations and challenges that need to be addressed in future research.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18180v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18180v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18180v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18180v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6794</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Human_Simulacra_A_Step_toward_the_Personification_of_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-28-Human_Simulacra_A_Step_toward_the_Personification_of_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18180v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The First Place Solution of WSDM Cup 2024: Leveraging Large Language Models for Conversational Multi-Doc QA</title>
  <dc:creator>Yiming Li, Zhao Zhang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/The_First_Place_Solution_of_WSDM_Cup_2024_Leveraging_Large_Language_Models_for_Conversational_Multi_Doc_QA/2024-02-28-The_First_Place_Solution_of_WSDM_Cup_2024_Leveraging_Large_Language_Models_for_Conversational_Multi_Doc_QA.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/The_First_Place_Solution_of_WSDM_Cup_2024_Leveraging_Large_Language_Models_for_Conversational_Multi_Doc_QA/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18385v1/extracted/5437883/sample-franklin.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article presents a clear and well-documented LATEX document formatted for publication by ACM in a conference proceedings or journal publication.</li>
<li>It explains many common variations and formatting elements an author may use in the preparation of their work.</li>
<li>The “acmart” document class can be used to prepare articles for any ACM publication, and it provides insight and instruction into recent changes to the article template.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>ACM’s consolidated article template provides a consistent LATEX style for use across ACM publications and incorporates accessibility and metadata-extraction functionality.</li>
<li>The “acmart” document class can be used to prepare different kinds of documentation, such as a full-length technical paper, a two-page SIGGRAPH Emerging Technologies abstract, a “camera-ready” journal article, and more.</li>
<li>The article template provides a valuable guide to the process of preparing work for publication, including recent changes to the article template.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article lacks specific examples or case studies to illustrate the application of the “acmart” document class.</li>
<li>It does not address potential challenges or limitations that authors may face when using the article template.</li>
<li>The article could benefit from a more detailed discussion of the impact of recent changes to the article template on the publication process.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18385v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18385v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18385v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18385v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>4975</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/The_First_Place_Solution_of_WSDM_Cup_2024_Leveraging_Large_Language_Models_for_Conversational_Multi_Doc_QA/2024-02-28-The_First_Place_Solution_of_WSDM_Cup_2024_Leveraging_Large_Language_Models_for_Conversational_Multi_Doc_QA.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18385v1/extracted/5437883/sample-franklin.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Towards Generalist Prompting for Large Language Models by Mental Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Haoxiang Guan, Jiyan He, Shuxin Zheng, En-Hong Chen, Weiming Zhang, Nenghai Yu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Towards_Generalist_Prompting_for_Large_Language_Models_by_Mental_Models/2024-02-28-Towards_Generalist_Prompting_for_Large_Language_Models_by_Mental_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Towards_Generalist_Prompting_for_Large_Language_Models_by_Mental_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18252v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Large language models (LLMs) have shown impressive performance on various tasks, but still require specially designed prompting methods for optimal performance.</li>
<li>The article introduces the concept of generalist prompting, aiming to achieve optimal or near-optimal performance on a wide range of tasks without manual selection and customization of prompts.</li>
<li>MeMo (Mental Models) is proposed as a simple-designed prompting method that effectively fulfills the criteria of generalist prompting, achieving state-of-the-art results on diverse tasks in zero-shot settings.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The evolution of artificial intelligence (AI) models towards generalist capabilities has followed a distinct trajectory, with LLMs capable of handling a wide range of natural language processing tasks.</li>
<li>MeMo, as a generalist prompting method, achieves or is near to the state-of-the-art performance on diverse tasks with LLMs in zero-shot settings, eliminating manual selection and customization of prompts.</li>
<li>MeMo leverages the concept of mental models to enable LLMs to autonomously select and apply suitable mental models for problem-solving, surpassing existing prompting methods that require task-specific customization.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>MeMo suffers from high computational costs due to the long prompt that informs LLMs with the knowledge of mental models.</li>
<li>The approach relies on the availability and quality of exemplars, which can affect the selection and application of mental models.</li>
<li>The article does not guarantee the correctness or consistency of the mental models that LLMs employ, which can lead to errors or contradictions in some cases.</li>
<li>Future work could investigate how to verify and refine the mental models that LLMs generate, as well as how to enable LLMs to understand and apply mental models more accurately.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18252v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18252v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18252v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18252v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6820</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Towards_Generalist_Prompting_for_Large_Language_Models_by_Mental_Models/2024-02-28-Towards_Generalist_Prompting_for_Large_Language_Models_by_Mental_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18252v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
