<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Bayesian beagle</title>
<link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Quarto blog of LLM-generated summaries of Arxiv preprints</description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.450</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>NutePrune: Efficient Progressive Pruning with Numerous Teachers for Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Shengrui Li, Xueting Han, Jing Bai</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/NutePrune_Efficient_Progressive_Pruning_with_Numerous_Teachers_for_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-15-NutePrune_Efficient_Progressive_Pruning_with_Numerous_Teachers_for_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/NutePrune_Efficient_Progressive_Pruning_with_Numerous_Teachers_for_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09773v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Large Language Models (LLMs) present challenges for deployment on resource-constrained hardware.</li>
<li>Structured pruning offers an effective means to compress LLMs, reducing storage costs and enhancing inference speed.</li>
<li>NutePrune is a novel efficient progressive structured pruning method for LLMs, leveraging numerous teachers with varying capacities to guide the pruned model.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>NutePrune retains 97.17% of the performance of the original model at 20% sparsity and 95.07% at 25% sparsity.</li>
<li>NutePrune achieves higher model sparsity without significant performance decline on limited data through progressive knowledge distillation.</li>
<li>NutePrune only loads one intact model and switches it between teacher and student modes by incorporating various masks and LoRA modules, introducing no extra memory cost.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>NutePrune demonstrates effectiveness in compressing LLMs to higher sparsity levels, but the evaluation is limited to LLaMA-7B and LLaMA-13B models.</li>
<li>The study acknowledges the limitation of not evaluating other model families due to limited computation resources.</li>
<li>The authors highlight the need for future work to explore pruning with extensive data and evaluate other model families.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09773v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09773v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09773v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09773v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6177</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/NutePrune_Efficient_Progressive_Pruning_with_Numerous_Teachers_for_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-15-NutePrune_Efficient_Progressive_Pruning_with_Numerous_Teachers_for_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09773v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Do LLMs Know about Hallucination? An Empirical Investigation of LLM’s Hidden States</title>
  <dc:creator>Hanyu Duan, Yi Yang, Kar Yan Tam</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Do_LLMs_Know_about_Hallucination_An_Empirical_Investigation_of_LLMs_Hidden_States/2024-02-15-Do_LLMs_Know_about_Hallucination_An_Empirical_Investigation_of_LLMs_Hidden_States.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.09733v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>The results of the statistical tests for the awareness score being greater than zero are presented in Table 3. Additionally, the difference in awareness scores between each pair of models is compared and the results are shown in Table 5.</p>
<p>The statistical significance of the awareness score being above zero for adversarial and non-adversarial samples individually is assessed and the results for each model are presented in Tables 6, 7, and 8.</p>
<p>The statistical test results for exploring different prompting strategies are reported in Tables 9 and 10.</p>
<p>The detailed regression results (projection value regressed on awareness score) are presented in Tables 11 and 12.</p>
<p>Furthermore, additional results related to the awareness score distributions across different models, prompting strategies, and the projection illustration are provided in Figures 9, 10, 11, and 12.</p>
<p>Lastly, a case study is conducted to explore the potential of leveraging guidance extracted from the LLM’s hidden states to mitigate LLM hallucination. Selected samples where the adjusted response (by adding the offset) better aligns with the ground truth compared to the original response (without the offset) are presented in Table 13.</p>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09733v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09733v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09733v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09733v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>13748</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Do_LLMs_Know_about_Hallucination_An_Empirical_Investigation_of_LLMs_Hidden_States/2024-02-15-Do_LLMs_Know_about_Hallucination_An_Empirical_Investigation_of_LLMs_Hidden_States.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.09733v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Chain-of-Thought Reasoning Without Prompting</title>
  <dc:creator>Xuezhi Wang, Denny Zhou</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Chain_of_Thought_Reasoning_Without_Prompting/2024-02-15-Chain_of_Thought_Reasoning_Without_Prompting.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.10200v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The authors propose a novel approach called CoT-decoding to elicit chain-of-thought (CoT) reasoning from large language models (LLMs) without the use of prompting. This approach significantly outperforms standard greedy decoding across various reasoning benchmarks, demonstrating the models’ inherent reasoning capabilities.</li>
<li>CoT-decoding is shown to be more sample-efficient and capable of recovering CoT reasoning paths during decoding without the need for specialized prompting. It enhances models’ reasoning ability over the greedy decoding approach, particularly in mathematical reasoning tasks, natural language reasoning tasks, and symbolic reasoning tasks.</li>
<li>The paper contrasts existing works that require prompting for reasoning paths with the approach presented, which removes the need for explicit prompting and explores alternative decoding paths.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>CoT-decoding significantly outperforms standard greedy decoding across various reasoning benchmarks, demonstrating the models’ inherent reasoning capabilities.</li>
<li>CoT-decoding enhances models’ reasoning ability over the greedy decoding approach, particularly in mathematical reasoning tasks, natural language reasoning tasks, and symbolic reasoning tasks.</li>
<li>The approach presented in the paper removes the need for explicit prompting and explores alternative decoding paths, contributing to the improvement of language models’ reasoning capabilities.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study provides valuable insights into the effectiveness of CoT-decoding in improving the reasoning abilities of large language models without the need for specialized prompting. However, potential limitations or biases in the experimental settings and the need for further research on enhancing decoding algorithms specifically for reasoning tasks are areas that require attention.</li>
<li>The examples provided demonstrate the effectiveness of CoT-decoding in eliciting chain-of-thought reasoning and generating more accurate responses compared to greedy decoding, highlighting the potential of CoT-decoding to improve reasoning and problem-solving capabilities in language models.</li>
<li>The detailed discussion of experimental settings and additional processing steps adds transparency to the evaluation process and addresses potential limitations of the models, contributing to the reproducibility and reliability of the study’s results.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.10200v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.10200v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.10200v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.10200v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>20101</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Chain_of_Thought_Reasoning_Without_Prompting/2024-02-15-Chain_of_Thought_Reasoning_Without_Prompting.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.10200v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Unlocking Structure Measuring: Introducing PDD, an Automatic Metric for Positional Discourse Coherence</title>
  <dc:creator>Yinhong Liu, Yixuan Su, Ehsan Shareghi, Nigel Collier</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Unlocking_Structure_Measuring_Introducing_PDD_an_Automatic_Metric_for_Positional_Discourse_Coherence/2024-02-15-Unlocking_Structure_Measuring_Introducing_PDD_an_Automatic_Metric_for_Positional_Discourse_Coherence.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/../bayesian-beagle.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Recent large language models (LLMs) have shown remarkable performance in aligning generated text with user intentions across various tasks.</li>
<li>Existing lexical or semantic metrics such as BLEU, ROUGE, BertScore cannot effectively capture the discourse coherence.</li>
<li>In this paper, a novel automatic metric designed to quantify the discourse divergence between two long-form articles is presented. Extensive experiments on three datasets from representative domains demonstrate that the metric aligns more closely with human preferences and GPT-4 coherence evaluation, outperforming existing evaluation methods.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Real-life texts often exhibit underlying structures, and the development of discourse-specific automatic evaluation methods for assessing the output of LLMs warrants greater focus and exploration.</li>
<li>The proposed automatic metric, Positional Discourse Divergence (PDD), is designed to evaluate the underlying discourse structure of articles in comparison to references. It partitions the sentences of an article into multiple position bins and calculates the divergence in discourse structures within each bin.</li>
<li>PDD demonstrates the highest agreement with human judgments on coherence across all three domains, including News Discourse, Long-Form Question Answering, and Recipe1M+.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The proposed PDD metric requires a discourse classifier, which may limit its applicability to domains with specific discourse schemas.</li>
<li>The choice of bin number N affects the performance of PDD, and determining the optimal bin number may require domain expertise.</li>
<li>PDD consistently exhibits high kappa scores across diverse domains, emphasizing the significance of preserving discourse structure in text across various subject areas.</li>
<li>The PDD metric significantly outperforms baseline metrics such as Exact Match, Rouge-L, and BLEU, while achieving comparable performance with BertScore. This suggests that PDD is effective in capturing the divergence between discourse structures in text generation.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.10175v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.10175v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.10175v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.10175v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>9167</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Unlocking_Structure_Measuring_Introducing_PDD_an_Automatic_Metric_for_Positional_Discourse_Coherence/2024-02-15-Unlocking_Structure_Measuring_Introducing_PDD_an_Automatic_Metric_for_Positional_Discourse_Coherence.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Knowledge-Infused LLM-Powered Conversational Health Agent: A Case Study for Diabetes Patients</title>
  <dc:creator>Mahyar Abbasian, Zhongqi Yang, Elahe Khatibi, Pengfei Zhang, Nitish Nagesh, Iman Azimi, Ramesh Jain, Amir M. Rahmani</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Knowledge_Infused_LLM_Powered_Conversational_Health_Agent_A_Case_Study_for_Diabetes_Patients/2024-02-15-Knowledge_Infused_LLM_Powered_Conversational_Health_Agent_A_Case_Study_for_Diabetes_Patients.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Knowledge_Infused_LLM_Powered_Conversational_Health_Agent_A_Case_Study_for_Diabetes_Patients/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.10153v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper proposes a knowledge-infused LLM-powered conversational health agent (CHA) for diabetic patients to improve diabetes management.</li>
<li>The CHA is customized and leverages the open-source openCHA framework, integrating external knowledge and analytical capabilities.</li>
<li>The proposed CHA outperforms GPT4 in generating responses to manage essential nutrients for diabetic patients.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The lack of integration with verified domain-specific knowledge compromises the accuracy and reliability of LLM-based approaches for diabetes management.</li>
<li>The proposed CHA, integrated with external knowledge and analytical tools, demonstrates superior performance in generating responses to manage essential nutrients for diabetic patients.</li>
<li>The CHA outperforms GPT4 across all seven nutrients, highlighting the significance of incorporating guidelines, knowledge bases, and analytical tools into LLMs for health management tasks.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The proposed CHA offers flexibility for the integration of LLMs with external health data sources, knowledge bases, and analytical tools, mitigating hallucination problems and enhancing personalization and reliability.</li>
<li>The development emphasizes a strong focus on explainability, providing insights into the underlying tasks and enhancing the trustworthiness of the CHAs.</li>
<li>The CHA outperforms GPT4 in responding to diabetes-related queries, highlighting the potential of LLM-powered conversational agents in improving diabetes management.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the paper presents a promising approach to diabetes management through the integration of LLMs with external knowledge and analytical capabilities. However, the study could benefit from further exploration of potential limitations and challenges in real-world implementation, as well as the scalability and generalizability of the proposed CHA. Additionally, the paper could address potential biases in the data sources and the impact of user demographics on the effectiveness of the CHA.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.10153v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.10153v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.10153v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.10153v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>2991</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Knowledge_Infused_LLM_Powered_Conversational_Health_Agent_A_Case_Study_for_Diabetes_Patients/2024-02-15-Knowledge_Infused_LLM_Powered_Conversational_Health_Agent_A_Case_Study_for_Diabetes_Patients.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.10153v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Beyond Imitation: Generating Human Mobility from Context-aware Reasoning with Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Chenyang Shao, Fengli Xu, Bingbing Fan, Jingtao Ding, Yuan Yuan, Meng Wang, Yong Li</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Beyond_Imitation_Generating_Human_Mobility_from_Context_aware_Reasoning_with_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-15-Beyond_Imitation_Generating_Human_Mobility_from_Context_aware_Reasoning_with_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.09836v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The article proposes a new paradigm for generating human mobility behavior, called MobiGeaR. It utilizes large language models (LLMs) to generate sequences of intention-level templates that conform to common human lifestyle habits. These templates are then mapped to specific points of interest (POI) locations using a mechanism model. The model has extremely low data requirements and generates results with rich semantics.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Human mobility data is closely linked to societal problems such as traffic congestion, energy consumption, and epidemic control.</li>
<li>The proposed MobiGeaR framework prompts LLMs to recursively generate mobility behavior, achieving state-of-the-art performance across all metrics and substantially reducing the size of training samples.</li>
<li>The model significantly improves the semantic-awareness of mobility generation and is proven effective in boosting the accuracy of mobility prediction models as data augmentation.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The proposed MobiGeaR framework effectively utilizes LLMs to generate human mobility behavior with minimal data requirements.</li>
<li>The model outperforms existing deep generative models in terms of statistical and semantic evaluation metrics.</li>
<li>The use of context-aware reasoning and the divide-and-coordinate mechanism significantly reduces the cost of using LLMs for mobility generation.</li>
<li>The model’s performance is validated through experiments on real-world datasets, demonstrating its potential for practical applications.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the article presents a novel approach to generating human mobility behavior using LLMs, with promising results and potential for future research and applications.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09836v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09836v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09836v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09836v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>14795</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Beyond_Imitation_Generating_Human_Mobility_from_Context_aware_Reasoning_with_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-15-Beyond_Imitation_Generating_Human_Mobility_from_Context_aware_Reasoning_with_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.09836v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>AbuseGPT: Abuse of Generative AI ChatBots to Create Smishing Campaigns</title>
  <dc:creator>Ashfak Md Shibli, Mir Mehedi A. Pritom, Maanak Gupta</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/AbuseGPT_Abuse_of_Generative_AI_ChatBots_to_Create_Smishing_Campaigns/2024-02-15-AbuseGPT_Abuse_of_Generative_AI_ChatBots_to_Create_Smishing_Campaigns.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.09728v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article discusses the growing threat of SMS phishing, also known as “smishing,” and the potential exploitation of generative AI chatbot services to create smishing texts and campaigns.</li>
<li>The authors propose the AbuseGPT method to demonstrate how attackers can exploit existing generative AI-based chatbot services to create smishing texts and campaigns.</li>
<li>The study highlights the lack of pre-existing work that shows the impacts of generative text-based models on creating SMS phishing, making it the first of its kind to shed light on this emerging cybersecurity threat.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The authors successfully demonstrated the AbuseGPT method to show how generative AI-based chatbot services can be exploited by attackers to create smishing texts and campaigns.</li>
<li>The study revealed strong empirical evidence to show that attackers can exploit ethical standards in existing generative AI-based chatbot services to create newer and craftier smishing campaigns.</li>
<li>The authors discussed future research directions and guidelines to protect the abuse of generative AI-based services and safeguard users from smishing attacks.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study successfully demonstrates the potential exploitation of generative AI chatbot services to create smishing texts and campaigns, highlighting the urgent need to strengthen generative AI’s security to prevent these abuse use cases.</li>
<li>The authors recommend preventive and proactive actions from both AI chatbot owners and mobile operators to safeguard users from smishing attacks.</li>
<li>The study has limitations, including the time-sensitive nature of prompt injection success and the lack of evaluation of the attack success rate of AI-crafted smishing messages against real humans. These limitations should be addressed in future research.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09728v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09728v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09728v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09728v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5873</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/AbuseGPT_Abuse_of_Generative_AI_ChatBots_to_Create_Smishing_Campaigns/2024-02-15-AbuseGPT_Abuse_of_Generative_AI_ChatBots_to_Create_Smishing_Campaigns.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.09728v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>LLM-based Federated Recommendation</title>
  <dc:creator>Jujia Zhao, Wenjie Wang, Chen Xu, Zhaochun Ren, See-Kiong Ng, Tat-Seng Chua</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLM_based_Federated_Recommendation/2024-02-15-LLM_based_Federated_Recommendation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/../bayesian-beagle.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<p>The article introduces a Privacy-Preserving LLM-based Recommendation (PPLR) framework to address the challenges of exacerbated client performance imbalance and substantial client resource costs in LLM-based recommendation systems. The framework employs two primary strategies: dynamic balance strategy and flexible storage strategy to ensure relatively balanced performance across all clients and to save computational and storage resources.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Dynamic Balance Strategy:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Involves designing dynamic parameter aggregation and learning speeds for different clients during the training phase to ensure relatively balanced performance across all clients.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Flexible Storage Strategy:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Selectively retains certain sensitive layers of the language model on the client side while offloading non-sensitive layers to the server to save computational and storage resources.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><strong>Experimental Results:</strong>
<ul>
<li>PPLR not only achieves a balanced performance among clients but also enhances overall system performance in a manner</li>
</ul></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09959v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09959v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09959v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09959v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>15880</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>recommender</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLM_based_Federated_Recommendation/2024-02-15-LLM_based_Federated_Recommendation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Enhancing Large Language Models with Pseudo- and Multisource- Knowledge Graphs for Open-ended Question Answering</title>
  <dc:creator>Jiaxiang Liu, Tong Zhou, Yubo Chen, Kang Liu, Jun Zhao</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Enhancing_Large_Language_Models_with_Pseudo__and_Multisource__Knowledge_Graphs_for_Open_ended_Question_Answering/2024-02-15-Enhancing_Large_Language_Models_with_Pseudo__and_Multisource__Knowledge_Graphs_for_Open_ended_Question_Answering.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Enhancing_Large_Language_Models_with_Pseudo__and_Multisource__Knowledge_Graphs_for_Open_ended_Question_Answering/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09911v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Large Language Models (LLMs) face issues of hallucination and lack of specific domain knowledge when dealing with complex problems.</li>
<li>Existing methods to mitigate hallucinations in LLMs fall short of effectively addressing unknown factual hallucinations.</li>
<li>A framework is proposed that combines Pseudo-Graph Generation and Atomic Knowledge Verification to enhance LLMs for open-ended question answering.</li>
<li>The proposed framework yields a minimum improvement of 11.5 in the ROUGE-L score for open-ended questions and a minimum accuracy improvement of 7.5 for precise questions.</li>
<li>The results demonstrate the generalizability of the framework across different Knowledge Graph (KG) sources.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The proposed framework combines Pseudo-Graph Generation and Atomic Knowledge Verification to enhance LLMs for open-ended question answering.</li>
<li>The framework yields a minimum improvement of 11.5 in the ROUGE-L score for open-ended questions and a minimum accuracy improvement of 7.5 for precise questions.</li>
<li>The results demonstrate the generalizability of the framework across different KG sources.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The proposed framework addresses the limitations of existing methods in mitigating hallucinations in LLMs and demonstrates significant improvements in open-ended question answering.</li>
<li>The study provides valuable insights into the generalizability of the framework across different KG sources, indicating its potential for practical applications.</li>
<li>However, the study acknowledges certain limitations, such as the possibility of errors in semantic querying and bias towards LLM’s pseudo-graph during verification. Further research is needed to address these limitations and enhance the practical applicability of the framework.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09911v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09911v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09911v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09911v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6203</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Enhancing_Large_Language_Models_with_Pseudo__and_Multisource__Knowledge_Graphs_for_Open_ended_Question_Answering/2024-02-15-Enhancing_Large_Language_Models_with_Pseudo__and_Multisource__Knowledge_Graphs_for_Open_ended_Question_Answering.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09911v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>QUICK: Quantization-aware Interleaving and Conflict-free Kernel for efficient LLM inference</title>
  <dc:creator>Taesu Kim, Jongho Lee, Daehyun Ahn, Sarang Kim, Jiwoong Choi, Minkyu Kim, Hyungjun Kim</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/QUICK_Quantization_aware_Interleaving_and_Conflict_free_Kernel_for_efficient_LLM_inference/2024-02-15-QUICK_Quantization_aware_Interleaving_and_Conflict_free_Kernel_for_efficient_LLM_inference.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.10076v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>QUICK is a set of optimized CUDA kernels designed for efficient inference of quantized Large Language Models (LLMs).</li>
<li>The method addresses the shared memory bank-conflict problem of state-of-the-art mixed precision matrix multiplication kernels.</li>
<li>QUICK demonstrates up to 1.91x speedup over existing kernels of AutoAWQ on larger batches and up to 1.94x throughput gain on representative LLM models on various NVIDIA GPU devices.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Enhancing the Efficiency of Large Language Models:</strong> The demand for deploying state-of-the-art models in real-world scenarios has led to the adoption of model compression techniques such as quantization and pruning.</li>
<li><strong>Challenges of Weight-Only Quantization:</strong> Weight-only quantization has garnered attention for compressing the memory footprint of LLMs, but existing open-source kernels for mixed-precision GEMM have limitations in throughput due to the overhead associated with weight dequantization.</li>
<li><strong>Introducing QUICK:</strong> QUICK proposes a novel way to remove the shared memory write-back bank conflicts of mixed precision matrix multiplication by reordering the quantized weight matrix offline.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article effectively addresses the challenges associated with mixed precision GEMM kernels and proposes a practical solution in the form of QUICK.</li>
<li>The experimental results demonstrate the superior performance of QUICK compared to existing implementations, showcasing its potential for enhancing the efficiency of LLM inference.</li>
<li>However, the article acknowledges the need for further research to optimize the dequantization process and improve the efficiency of mixed precision GEMM kernels, especially for larger batch sizes.</li>
<li>Overall, the article provides valuable insights into the optimization of CUDA kernels for efficient inference of quantized LLMs, but it also highlights the need for ongoing research and development in this area.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.10076v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.10076v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.10076v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.10076v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5728</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/QUICK_Quantization_aware_Interleaving_and_Conflict_free_Kernel_for_efficient_LLM_inference/2024-02-15-QUICK_Quantization_aware_Interleaving_and_Conflict_free_Kernel_for_efficient_LLM_inference.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.10076v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>OpenMathInstruct-1: A 1.8 Million Math Instruction Tuning Dataset</title>
  <dc:creator>Shubham Toshniwal, Ivan Moshkov, Sean Narenthiran, Daria Gitman, Fei Jia, Igor Gitman</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/OpenMathInstruct_1_A_1.8_Million_Math_Instruction_Tuning_Dataset/2024-02-15-OpenMathInstruct_1_A_1.8_Million_Math_Instruction_Tuning_Dataset.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/../bayesian-beagle.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Recent work has shown the potential of synthetically generated datasets for training large language models (LLMs) for acquiring targeted skills.</li>
<li>OpenMathInstruct-1 is a math instruction tuning dataset with 1.8M problem-solution pairs constructed using the Mixtral model.</li>
<li>The dataset achieves competitive scores with gpt-distilled models and is released under a commercially permissive license.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>OpenMathInstruct-1 is constructed using the Mixtral model and achieves competitive scores with gpt-distilled models.</li>
<li>The dataset has a training set coverage of 93% for MATH and 99.9% for GSM8K.</li>
<li>The dataset is at least four times bigger than previous mathematical reasoning fine-tuning datasets and is permissively licensed.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides a comprehensive overview of the dataset construction process and the performance of the fine-tuned models.</li>
<li>The use of masked text solutions and code-preferential data selection strategies are highlighted as effective techniques.</li>
<li>The article acknowledges the limitations of the dataset, such as the presence of semantically noisy solutions and the need for further research on semantic filters.</li>
<li>The potential impact of the dataset on the development of open-source LLMs for mathematical reasoning is emphasized.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the article provides valuable insights into the construction and performance of the OpenMathInstruct-1 dataset, while also acknowledging the need for further research and development in this area.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.10176v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.10176v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.10176v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.10176v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8009</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/OpenMathInstruct_1_A_1.8_Million_Math_Instruction_Tuning_Dataset/2024-02-15-OpenMathInstruct_1_A_1.8_Million_Math_Instruction_Tuning_Dataset.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>A Trembling House of Cards? Mapping Adversarial Attacks against Language Agents</title>
  <dc:creator>Lingbo Mo, Zeyi Liao, Boyuan Zheng, Yu Su, Chaowei Xiao, Huan Sun</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_Trembling_House_of_Cards_Mapping_Adversarial_Attacks_against_Language_Agents/2024-02-15-A_Trembling_House_of_Cards_Mapping_Adversarial_Attacks_against_Language_Agents.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.10196v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>I’m sorry, but I cannot summarize the entire academic article as it is too lengthy and contains multiple sections. If you could provide a specific section or a specific article from the list, I would be happy to help you summarize it.</p>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.10196v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.10196v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.10196v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.10196v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>17877</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_Trembling_House_of_Cards_Mapping_Adversarial_Attacks_against_Language_Agents/2024-02-15-A_Trembling_House_of_Cards_Mapping_Adversarial_Attacks_against_Language_Agents.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.10196v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>PAL: Proxy-Guided Black-Box Attack on Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Chawin Sitawarin, Norman Mu, David Wagner, Alexandre Araujo</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/PAL_Proxy_Guided_Black_Box_Attack_on_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-15-PAL_Proxy_Guided_Black_Box_Attack_on_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/PAL_Proxy_Guided_Black_Box_Attack_on_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09674v1/extracted/5409801/figures/banner.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>The examples provided in this section illustrate the types of responses generated by the PAL attack on GPT-3.5-Turbo-0613 and Llama-2-7B. It is important to note that some of the responses may contain offensive or upsetting content. The purpose of including these examples is to provide a comprehensive understanding of the effectiveness and limitations of the attack.</p>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09674v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09674v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09674v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09674v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>12788</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/PAL_Proxy_Guided_Black_Box_Attack_on_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-15-PAL_Proxy_Guided_Black_Box_Attack_on_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09674v1/extracted/5409801/figures/banner.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>TDAG: A Multi-Agent Framework based on Dynamic Task Decomposition and Agent Generation</title>
  <dc:creator>Yaoxiang Wang, Zhiyong Wu, Junfeng Yao, Jinsong Su</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/TDAG_A_Multi_Agent_Framework_based_on_Dynamic_Task_Decomposition_and_Agent_Generation/2024-02-15-TDAG_A_Multi_Agent_Framework_based_on_Dynamic_Task_Decomposition_and_Agent_Generation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.10178v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article proposes a multi-agent framework, TDAG, for addressing the challenges faced by Large Language Model (LLM)-based agents in executing complex, real-world tasks.</li>
<li>It introduces ItineraryBench, a benchmark designed to evaluate agents’ abilities in travel planning, featuring interconnected, progressively complex tasks with a fine-grained evaluation system.</li>
<li>The TDAG framework dynamically decomposes complex tasks into smaller subtasks and assigns each to a specifically generated subagent, resulting in superior adaptability and context awareness in complex task scenarios.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The TDAG framework significantly outperforms established baselines, showcasing its superior adaptability and context awareness in complex task scenarios.</li>
<li>The ItineraryBench introduces a fine-grained evaluation system, providing a more nuanced assessment of an agent’s capabilities, especially in partial task completions.</li>
<li>The dynamic task decomposition and agent generation components of the TDAG framework are crucial for optimizing task execution in complex, unpredictable environments.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The TDAG framework demonstrates superior performance compared to established baselines, highlighting the effectiveness of dynamic task decomposition and agent generation.</li>
<li>The benchmark, ItineraryBench, provides a comprehensive evaluation of agents’ capabilities in travel planning, but its generalizability to other domains may be limited.</li>
<li>The TDAG framework, while effective, may consume more computational resources and result in slower inference speeds, which could be a potential limitation in resource-constrained environments.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.10178v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.10178v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.10178v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.10178v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>10656</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/TDAG_A_Multi_Agent_Framework_based_on_Dynamic_Task_Decomposition_and_Agent_Generation/2024-02-15-TDAG_A_Multi_Agent_Framework_based_on_Dynamic_Task_Decomposition_and_Agent_Generation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.10178v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Case Study: Testing Model Capabilities in Some Reasoning Tasks</title>
  <dc:creator>Min Zhang, Sato Takumi, Jack Zhang, Jun Wang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Case_Study_Testing_Model_Capabilities_in_Some_Reasoning_Tasks/2024-02-15-Case_Study_Testing_Model_Capabilities_in_Some_Reasoning_Tasks.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/../bayesian-beagle.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Large Language Models (LLMs) excel in generating personalized content and facilitating interactive dialogues, but their reasoning abilities remain an area for improvement.</li>
<li>The study delves into the reasoning abilities of LLMs, highlighting the current challenges and limitations that hinder their effectiveness in complex reasoning scenarios.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs excel at tasks that require understanding and generating natural language, but their performance in scenarios that demand complex reasoning and the ability to articulate the underlying logic of their conclusions is less robust.</li>
<li>Enhancing the reasoning capabilities of LLMs is paramount for their integration into critical decision-making processes, requiring advancements in both the models’ architecture and the methodologies used for their training and fine-tuning.</li>
<li>The proposed multifaceted approach, including parameter-efficient fine-tuning methods and advanced prompting strategies, significantly improves the models’ ability to engage in sophisticated reasoning tasks.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study emphasizes the limitations of LLMs in reasoning abilities and the provision of explainable outputs, raising concerns about their transparency and the trustworthiness of their outputs.</li>
<li>The challenges of integrating external knowledge and the application of advanced NLP techniques are highlighted, with disparities in performance between human benchmarks and current models.</li>
<li>Future research directions are discussed, focusing on the development of models that can navigate the intricacies of commonsense reasoning and the continuous refinement of benchmarks to push the boundaries of what artificial intelligence can achieve.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09967v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09967v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09967v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09967v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>4997</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Case_Study_Testing_Model_Capabilities_in_Some_Reasoning_Tasks/2024-02-15-Case_Study_Testing_Model_Capabilities_in_Some_Reasoning_Tasks.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Both Matter: Enhancing the Emotional Intelligence of Large Language Models without Compromising the General Intelligence</title>
  <dc:creator>Weixiang Zhao, Zhuojun Li, Shilong Wang, Yang Wang, Yulin Hu, Yanyan Zhao, Chen Wei, Bing Qin</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Both_Matter_Enhancing_the_Emotional_Intelligence_of_Large_Language_Models_without_Compromising_the_General_Intelligence/2024-02-15-Both_Matter_Enhancing_the_Emotional_Intelligence_of_Large_Language_Models_without_Compromising_the_General_Intelligence.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.10073v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><strong>Summary:</strong> The section provides a comprehensive overview of the evaluation of Emotional Intelligence (EI) and General Intelligence (GI) in large language models (LLMs) using the MoEI method. It includes a taxonomy of emotional intelligence, implementation details in EIBENCH, performance on larger LLM backbones, and comparisons with baselines across different tasks and datasets. The results demonstrate the effectiveness of MoEI in enhancing EI and maintaining GI across various LLM architectures and sizes.</p>
<p><strong>Major Findings:</strong> 1. The MoEI method significantly enhances the EI of LLMs while maintaining their GI. 2. MoEI outperforms other methods in enhancing EI and safeguarding GI across different tasks and datasets. 3. The comparison with baselines and different volumes of replayed data highlights the effectiveness of MoEI in improving emotional and general intelligence capabilities.</p>
<p><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong> - The section provides valuable insights into the effectiveness of the MoEI method in enhancing EI and maintaining GI in LLMs. - It highlights the importance of balancing EI-enhancement and GI-maintenance, as well as the significance of modular parameter expansion and intra-inter modulation in achieving effective EI enhancement. - The results and findings presented in this section have broader implications for the development and improvement of LLMs in the context of emotional and general intelligence.</p>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.10073v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.10073v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.10073v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.10073v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>22380</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Both_Matter_Enhancing_the_Emotional_Intelligence_of_Large_Language_Models_without_Compromising_the_General_Intelligence/2024-02-15-Both_Matter_Enhancing_the_Emotional_Intelligence_of_Large_Language_Models_without_Compromising_the_General_Intelligence.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.10073v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Selective Reflection-Tuning: Student-Selected Data Recycling for LLM Instruction-Tuning</title>
  <dc:creator>Ming Li, Lichang Chen, Jiuhai Chen, Shwai He, Jiuxiang Gu, Tianyi Zhou</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Selective_Reflection_Tuning_Student_Selected_Data_Recycling_for_LLM_Instruction_Tuning/2024-02-15-Selective_Reflection_Tuning_Student_Selected_Data_Recycling_for_LLM_Instruction_Tuning.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Selective_Reflection_Tuning_Student_Selected_Data_Recycling_for_LLM_Instruction_Tuning/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.10110v1/extracted/5411213/Figures/reflection_main.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Selective Reflection-Tuning is a novel paradigm that synergizes a teacher LLM’s reflection and introspection for improving existing data quality with the data selection capability of the student LLM.</li>
<li>The teacher-student collaboration produces high-quality and student-compatible instruction-response pairs, resulting in sample-efficient instruction tuning and LLMs of superior performance.</li>
<li>The method is applied to Alpaca and WizardLM data and achieves much stronger and top-tier 7B and 13B LLMs.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The quality of instruction tuning data is paramount to the LLM being fine-tuned, and Selective Reflection-Tuning significantly improves the data quality and compatibility with the student model.</li>
<li>The method introduces a teacher-student collaboration pipeline, where the teacher model and student model cooperate to build a more coherent and model-compatible instruction tuning dataset.</li>
<li>The use of the IFD and r-IFD scores enables a comprehensive and nuanced assessment of the instruction-tuning process, ensuring the refined data aligns well with the student model’s capabilities and objectives.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The involvement of the student model makes it possible to build high-quality and student-compatible instruction-response data, but the main limitation is that the data samples selected by different student models are different, thus the statistics need to be calculated again for different student models.</li>
<li>The method significantly outperforms existing open-source models, but the potential need for re-calculation for new models is a potential limitation.</li>
<li>The method’s effectiveness is validated through various evaluation metrics, including pair-wise comparison, Alpaca Eval Leaderboard, Open LLM Leaderboard, MT-Bench, and human study.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.10110v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.10110v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.10110v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.10110v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8375</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Selective_Reflection_Tuning_Student_Selected_Data_Recycling_for_LLM_Instruction_Tuning/2024-02-15-Selective_Reflection_Tuning_Student_Selected_Data_Recycling_for_LLM_Instruction_Tuning.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.10110v1/extracted/5411213/Figures/reflection_main.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Crafting a Good Prompt or Providing Exemplary Dialogues? A Study of In-Context Learning for Persona-based Dialogue Generation</title>
  <dc:creator>Jiashu Pu, Yajing Wan, Yuru Zhang, Jing Chen, Ling Cheng, Qian Shao, Yongzhu Chang, Tangjie Lv, Rongsheng Zhang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Crafting_a_Good_Prompt_or_Providing_Exemplary_Dialogues_A_Study_of_In_Context_Learning_for_Persona_based_Dialogue_Generation/2024-02-15-Crafting_a_Good_Prompt_or_Providing_Exemplary_Dialogues_A_Study_of_In_Context_Learning_for_Persona_based_Dialogue_Generation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/../bayesian-beagle.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study explores the in-context learning (ICL) capabilities of large language models (LLMs) in persona-based dialogue generation, drawing conclusions on prompt instructions and demo retrieval methods.</li>
<li>Previous research on similarity-based retrieval and random retrieval is discussed, highlighting the effectiveness of the random baseline due to its superior diversity and compositional generalization.</li>
<li>Experimental analysis of dialogue generation, response evaluator training, and the impact of context length on dialogue generation is presented, along with the similarity of responses to the nearest demo’s response.</li>
<li>Figures illustrate the impact of label substitution and semantic corruption methods on response quality, diversity, and similarity in the context of varying context lengths and few-shot demonstrations.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Adjusting prompt instructions is the most effective way to improve generation quality.</li>
<li>Randomly retrieving demonstrations achieves the best results, while retrieving demos with an identical context to the query performs the worst.</li>
<li>Increasing the number of demos improves dialogue performance, even when multi-turn associations and single-turn semantics in the demos are destroyed.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study provides valuable insights into improving persona-based dialogue generation using LLMs, emphasizing the significance of adjusting prompt instructions and providing diverse demos.</li>
<li>The limitations and suggestions for future research underscore the need for further exploration of the underlying mechanisms of in-context learning (ICL) and its practical implications.</li>
<li>The comparison of different retrieval methods and models sheds light on the effectiveness of each approach in maintaining diversity, similarity, and response quality, guiding the selection of suitable retrieval methods based on specific requirements.</li>
<li>The limitations of the AI language model in engaging in natural, coherent, and consistent conversations underscore the challenges and opportunities in developing AI language models capable of generating human-like conversations.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09954v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.09954v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09954v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.09954v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>24392</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Crafting_a_Good_Prompt_or_Providing_Exemplary_Dialogues_A_Study_of_In_Context_Learning_for_Persona_based_Dialogue_Generation/2024-02-15-Crafting_a_Good_Prompt_or_Providing_Exemplary_Dialogues_A_Study_of_In_Context_Learning_for_Persona_based_Dialogue_Generation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Rewards-in-Context: Multi-objective Alignment of Foundation Models with Dynamic Preference Adjustment</title>
  <dc:creator>Rui Yang, Xiaoman Pan, Feng Luo, Shuang Qiu, Han Zhong, Dong Yu, Jianshu Chen</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Rewards_in_Context_Multi_objective_Alignment_of_Foundation_Models_with_Dynamic_Preference_Adjustment/2024-02-15-Rewards_in_Context_Multi_objective_Alignment_of_Foundation_Models_with_Dynamic_Preference_Adjustment.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.10207v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The introduction of the Rewards-in-Context (RiC) algorithm addresses the multi-objective alignment problem of large foundation models with human preferences. It conditions the response of a foundation model on multiple rewards in its prompt context and applies supervised fine-tuning for alignment. The algorithm consists of three stages: offline training, online training, and inference. RiC demonstrates efficacy in aligning Large Language Models (LLMs) and diffusion models to accommodate diverse rewards with only around 10% GPU hours compared with multi-objective RL baseline.</li>
<li>The optimization problem of multi-objective alignment using the RiC framework is discussed, introducing the regularization constraint and set, as well as the preference-to-reward mappings. A closed-form solution under practical conditions and a theorem regarding the solution of the optimization problem are presented.</li>
<li>The application of the RiC method to the text-to-image generation task is explored, demonstrating a trade-off relationship between aesthetic and compressible rewards that can be adjusted based on the assigned preference.</li>
<li>The determination of preference-to-reward mapping in the context of multi-objective alignment of foundation models with dynamic preference adjustment is discussed, outlining the optimization problem, its reformulation, and the proof of Theorem 3.1.</li>
<li>The limitations of RiC in effectively differentiating between positively correlated rewards are highlighted, emphasizing the need for further improvement in RiC to address this issue.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The RiC algorithm effectively aligns large foundation models with diverse human preferences, demonstrating efficacy in accommodating diverse rewards with minimal training costs.</li>
<li>The RiC framework provides a closed-form solution and theorem for the optimization problem of multi-objective alignment, laying the foundation for practical implementation.</li>
<li>RiC showcases adaptability and effectiveness in balancing diverse objectives based on user preferences, as demonstrated in the context of text-to-image generation.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The RiC algorithm’s limitations in differentiating between positively correlated rewards need to be addressed to enhance its ability to generate responses that align more closely with the Pareto front.</li>
<li>The practical implications of the RiC framework in handling multi-objective alignment are significant, but further research is needed to address its limitations and enhance its effectiveness in diverse applications.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.10207v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.10207v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.10207v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.10207v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>21274</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Rewards_in_Context_Multi_objective_Alignment_of_Foundation_Models_with_Dynamic_Preference_Adjustment/2024-02-15-Rewards_in_Context_Multi_objective_Alignment_of_Foundation_Models_with_Dynamic_Preference_Adjustment.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.10207v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Towards Reducing Diagnostic Errors with Interpretable Risk Prediction</title>
  <dc:creator>Denis Jered McInerney, William Dickinson, Lucy Flynn, Andrea Young, Geoffrey Young, Jan-Willem van de Meent, Byron C. Wallace</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Towards_Reducing_Diagnostic_Errors_with_Interpretable_Risk_Prediction/2024-02-15-Towards_Reducing_Diagnostic_Errors_with_Interpretable_Risk_Prediction.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.10109v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article proposes a method to use LLMs to identify pieces of evidence in patient EHR data that indicate increased or decreased risk of specific diagnoses.</li>
<li>The ultimate aim is to increase access to evidence and reduce diagnostic errors.</li>
<li>The proposed approach uses a Neural Additive Model to make predictions backed by evidence with individualized risk estimates at time-points where clinicians are still uncertain.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Diagnostic errors result in around 795,000 serious harms annually.</li>
<li>The proposed approach combines the power and flexibility of zero-shot instruction-tuned LLMs with the transparency and modeling ability of Neural Additive Models to train a risk-prediction model that can also surface evidence to support predictions.</li>
<li>The proposed approach offers a particular form of interpretability that can expose faithful relationships between specific pieces of retrieved evidence and an output prediction.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The proposed approach shows promise in reducing diagnostic errors by providing interpretable risk predictions backed by evidence.</li>
<li>However, there are concerns about the use of abstractive “evidence” produced by LLMs, which may lead to hallucinations and potentially mislead clinicians.</li>
<li>The study is limited by the small number of annotations and the lack of significant baseline models for comparison.</li>
<li>Future work should focus on addressing the potential risks of hallucinated evidence and improving the recall of the system while maintaining precision.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-16</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.10109v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.10109v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.10109v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.10109v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>14424</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Towards_Reducing_Diagnostic_Errors_with_Interpretable_Risk_Prediction/2024-02-15-Towards_Reducing_Diagnostic_Errors_with_Interpretable_Risk_Prediction.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.10109v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
