<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Bayesian beagle</title>
<link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Quarto blog of LLM-generated summaries of Arxiv preprints</description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.450</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Editing Factual Knowledge and Explanatory Ability of Medical Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Derong Xu, Ziheng Zhang, Zhihong Zhu, Zhenxi Lin, Qidong Liu, Xian Wu, Tong Xu, Xiangyu Zhao, Yefeng Zheng, Enhong Chen</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Editing_Factual_Knowledge_and_Explanatory_Ability_of_Medical_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-28-Editing_Factual_Knowledge_and_Explanatory_Ability_of_Medical_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Editing_Factual_Knowledge_and_Explanatory_Ability_of_Medical_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18099v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Model editing aims to modify the behaviors of large language models (LLMs) by precisely manipulating specific knowledge while keeping other knowledge unaffected.</li>
<li>The proposed MedLaSA strategy employs causal tracing to identify the precise location of knowledge in neurons and introduces scalable adapters into the dense layers of LLMs.</li>
<li>Extensive experiments on medical LLMs demonstrate the editing efficiency of MedLaSA, without affecting irrelevant knowledge that is not edited.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Model editing methods struggle with the specialization and complexity of medical knowledge.</li>
<li>MedLaSA significantly outperforms existing cutting-edge methods in editing medical LLMs.</li>
<li>The removal of Scaling Rank (SR) leads to a decline in all metrics, indicating its crucial role in maintaining the overall performance.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The proposed MedLaSA method effectively addresses the challenges of specialization and complexity of medical knowledge in model editing.</li>
<li>However, the method may have a negative impact on Generality and lacks consideration for batch editing and sequence editing.</li>
<li>The datasets used for medical model editing do not consider more robust evaluations, such as portability, and the number of samples for medical model editing is relatively small.</li>
<li>The performance of MedLaSA on encyclopedic data remains to be explored.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18099v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18099v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18099v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18099v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6898</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Editing_Factual_Knowledge_and_Explanatory_Ability_of_Medical_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-28-Editing_Factual_Knowledge_and_Explanatory_Ability_of_Medical_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18099v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Cause and Effect: Can Large Language Models Truly Understand Causality?</title>
  <dc:creator>Swagata Ashwani, Kshiteesh Hegde, Nishith Reddy Mannuru, Mayank Jindal, Dushyant Singh Sengar, Krishna Chaitanya Rao Kathala, Dishant Banga, Vinija Jain, Aman Chadha</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Cause_and_Effect_Can_Large_Language_Models_Truly_Understand_Causality/2024-02-28-Cause_and_Effect_Can_Large_Language_Models_Truly_Understand_Causality.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Cause_and_Effect_Can_Large_Language_Models_Truly_Understand_Causality/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18139v1/extracted/5423783/model_accuracy_across_datasets.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article introduces the Context-Aware Reasoning Enhancement with Counterfactual Analysis (CARE-CA) framework to enhance causal reasoning and explainability in Large Language Models (LLMs).</li>
<li>The framework combines explicit causal detection with ConceptNet and implicit causal detection through LLMs, along with a layer of counterfactual explanations to accentuate LLMs’ understanding of causality.</li>
<li>Evaluation of benchmark datasets shows improved performance across all metrics, and the introduction of CausalNet, a new dataset, is aimed at facilitating further research in this domain.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The CARE-CA framework combines explicit and implicit causal reasoning to enhance LLMs’ understanding of causality.</li>
<li>Evaluation of benchmark datasets shows improved performance across all metrics, such as accuracy, precision, recall, and F1 scores.</li>
<li>The introduction of CausalNet, a new dataset, is aimed at facilitating further research in the domain of causal reasoning.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides a comprehensive approach to enhancing LLMs’ causal reasoning faculties, but it is limited to English language models, limiting its generalizability across languages and cultures.</li>
<li>The computational resources required by the CARE-CA framework may limit accessibility for those with constrained computational budgets, pointing to a need for optimization strategies.</li>
<li>The article acknowledges the ethical responsibilities of conducting research with LLMs and strives to prevent the propagation of bias within the CausalNet dataset. However, further research is required to improve transparency and explain the model’s reasoning processes, especially for non-expert users.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18139v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18139v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18139v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18139v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5773</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Cause_and_Effect_Can_Large_Language_Models_Truly_Understand_Causality/2024-02-28-Cause_and_Effect_Can_Large_Language_Models_Truly_Understand_Causality.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18139v1/extracted/5423783/model_accuracy_across_datasets.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Meta-Task Prompting Elicits Embedding from Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Yibin Lei, Di Wu, Tianyi Zhou, Tao Shen, Yu Cao, Chongyang Tao, Andrew Yates</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Meta_Task_Prompting_Elicits_Embedding_from_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-28-Meta_Task_Prompting_Elicits_Embedding_from_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Meta_Task_Prompting_Elicits_Embedding_from_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18458v1/extracted/5438050/Figures/Figure-1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>MetaEOL introduces a new unsupervised embedding method for generating high-quality sentence embeddings from Large Language Models (LLMs) without the need for model fine-tuning or task-specific engineering.</li>
<li>The method leverages meta-task prompting to guide LLMs to produce embeddings through a series of carefully designed prompts that address multiple representational aspects.</li>
<li>Comprehensive experiments demonstrate that embeddings averaged from various meta-tasks yield competitive performance on Semantic Textual Similarity (STS) benchmarks and excel in downstream tasks, surpassing contrastive-trained models.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>MetaEOL demonstrates competitive performance on STS benchmarks and excels in downstream tasks, surpassing contrastive-trained models.</li>
<li>Simply averaging embeddings from different meta-tasks without any training leads to general embeddings that are competitive to contrastive-trained models on STS tasks and can achieve the best average result in downstream tasks.</li>
<li>Incrementally integrating more meta-tasks yields consistent improvements across STS tasks, showcasing high generalities, and highlighting the significant impact of meta-task integration on overall performance.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides a comprehensive and innovative approach to generating high-quality sentence embeddings from LLMs without the need for training. The method’s performance on STS benchmarks and downstream tasks is impressive, surpassing contrastive-trained models.</li>
<li>The article acknowledges limitations in terms of computational overhead and restricted evaluation benchmarks, providing avenues for future research and improvement.</li>
<li>The experiments and findings are well-documented and provide valuable insights into the potential of MetaEOL for diverse sentence-centric scenarios.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18458v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18458v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18458v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18458v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5849</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Meta_Task_Prompting_Elicits_Embedding_from_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-28-Meta_Task_Prompting_Elicits_Embedding_from_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18458v1/extracted/5438050/Figures/Figure-1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Retrieval-based Full-length Wikipedia Generation for Emergent Events</title>
  <dc:creator>Jiebin Zhang, Eugene J. Yu, Qinyu Chen, Chenhao Xiong, Dawei Zhu, Han Qian, Mingbo Song, Xiaoguang Li, Qun Liu, Sujian Li</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Retrieval_based_Full_length_Wikipedia_Generation_for_Emergent_Events/2024-02-28-Retrieval_based_Full_length_Wikipedia_Generation_for_Emergent_Events.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Retrieval_based_Full_length_Wikipedia_Generation_for_Emergent_Events/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18264v1/extracted/5437378/figures/intro.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper addresses the challenge of quickly generating comprehensive and accurate Wikipedia documents for emerging events.</li>
<li>It introduces a new benchmark, WikiGenBen, consisting of 309 events paired with their corresponding retrieved web pages for generating evidence.</li>
<li>The study simulates a real-world scenario where structured full-length Wikipedia documents are generated for emergent events using input retrieved from web sources.</li>
<li>The authors design a comprehensive set of systematic evaluation metrics and baseline methods to evaluate the capability of Large Language Models (LLMs) in generating factual full-length Wikipedia documents.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Wikipedia serves as an important reference for various NLP tasks, but the task of automatically generating Wikipedia content in real-world scenarios has not been fully explored.</li>
<li>The retrieval-based generation of full-length Wikipedia articles is a common scenario ideally suited for the Retrieve-then-Read (RR) and Retrieve-Plan-Retrieve-Read (RPRR) methods.</li>
<li>The study finds that the number of retrieved documents, the type of retriever used, and the source of related documents all impact the informativeness and faithfulness of the generated Wikipedia articles.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study highlights the complexity of balancing various metrics in the generation of Wikipedia articles, emphasizing the need for refining task segmentation methods to enhance performance.</li>
<li>The authors acknowledge limitations in their section-by-section generation approach, potential redundancy, and the challenge of direct citation by LLMs, suggesting the need for further exploration of post-citation methods.</li>
<li>The paper raises ethical considerations and asserts that the research does not present any ethical issues, adhering to the ACL Ethics Policy.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18264v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18264v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18264v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18264v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6608</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Retrieval_based_Full_length_Wikipedia_Generation_for_Emergent_Events/2024-02-28-Retrieval_based_Full_length_Wikipedia_Generation_for_Emergent_Events.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18264v1/extracted/5437378/figures/intro.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>No Token Left Behind: Reliable KV Cache Compression via Importance-Aware Mixed Precision Quantization</title>
  <dc:creator>June Yong Yang, Byeongwook Kim, Jeongin Bae, Beomseok Kwon, Gunho Park, Eunho Yang, Se Jung Kwon, Dongsoo Lee</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/No_Token_Left_Behind_Reliable_KV_Cache_Compression_via_Importance_Aware_Mixed_Precision_Quantization/2024-02-28-No_Token_Left_Behind_Reliable_KV_Cache_Compression_via_Importance_Aware_Mixed_Precision_Quantization.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/No_Token_Left_Behind_Reliable_KV_Cache_Compression_via_Importance_Aware_Mixed_Precision_Quantization/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18096v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article discusses the challenges posed by the memory footprint of Key-Value (KV) caching in Large Language Models (LLMs) and proposes a reliable cache compression method, Mixed-precision KV cache (MiKV), to address these challenges.</li>
<li>Recent methods for KV cache eviction to reduce memory consumption have been proposed, but the potential risks and impact on the generative process have not been thoroughly examined.</li>
<li>The proposed MiKV method retains evicted KV pairs in low precision and important KV pairs in high precision, effectively balancing compression ratio and performance.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The detrimental impact of cache eviction on the generative process, leading to safety breaches, hallucinations, and context loss.</li>
<li>Preserving even a small amount of information contained in the evicted KV pairs via reduced precision quantization substantially recovers the incurred degradation.</li>
<li>MiKV offers a state-of-the-art trade-off between compression ratio and performance compared to other baselines.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides a comprehensive analysis of the risks associated with KV cache eviction and proposes a novel method, MiKV, to address these risks.</li>
<li>The experiments conducted demonstrate the effectiveness of MiKV in preserving generation quality while achieving a high compression rate.</li>
<li>The proposed method addresses the limitations of existing cache compression strategies and provides a promising solution for the challenges posed by the memory footprint of KV caching in LLMs.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18096v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18096v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18096v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18096v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7020</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/No_Token_Left_Behind_Reliable_KV_Cache_Compression_via_Importance_Aware_Mixed_Precision_Quantization/2024-02-28-No_Token_Left_Behind_Reliable_KV_Cache_Compression_via_Importance_Aware_Mixed_Precision_Quantization.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18096v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Towards Generalist Prompting for Large Language Models by Mental Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Haoxiang Guan, Jiyan He, Shuxin Zheng, En-Hong Chen, Weiming Zhang, Nenghai Yu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Towards_Generalist_Prompting_for_Large_Language_Models_by_Mental_Models/2024-02-28-Towards_Generalist_Prompting_for_Large_Language_Models_by_Mental_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Towards_Generalist_Prompting_for_Large_Language_Models_by_Mental_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18252v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Large language models (LLMs) have shown impressive performance on various tasks, but still require specially designed prompting methods for optimal performance.</li>
<li>The article introduces the concept of generalist prompting, aiming to achieve optimal or near-optimal performance on a wide range of tasks without manual selection and customization of prompts.</li>
<li>MeMo (Mental Models) is proposed as a simple-designed prompting method that effectively fulfills the criteria of generalist prompting, achieving state-of-the-art results on diverse tasks in zero-shot settings.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The evolution of artificial intelligence (AI) models towards generalist capabilities has followed a distinct trajectory, with LLMs capable of handling a wide range of natural language processing tasks.</li>
<li>MeMo, as a generalist prompting method, achieves or is near to the state-of-the-art performance on diverse tasks with LLMs in zero-shot settings, eliminating manual selection and customization of prompts.</li>
<li>MeMo leverages the concept of mental models to enable LLMs to autonomously select and apply suitable mental models for problem-solving, surpassing existing prompting methods that require task-specific customization.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>MeMo suffers from high computational costs due to the long prompt that informs LLMs with the knowledge of mental models.</li>
<li>The approach relies on the availability and quality of exemplars, which can affect the selection and application of mental models.</li>
<li>The article does not guarantee the correctness or consistency of the mental models that LLMs employ, which can lead to errors or contradictions in some cases.</li>
<li>Future work could investigate how to verify and refine the mental models that LLMs generate, as well as how to enable LLMs to understand and apply mental models more accurately.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18252v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18252v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18252v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18252v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6820</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Towards_Generalist_Prompting_for_Large_Language_Models_by_Mental_Models/2024-02-28-Towards_Generalist_Prompting_for_Large_Language_Models_by_Mental_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18252v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Language Models Represent Beliefs of Self and Others</title>
  <dc:creator>Wentao Zhu, Zhining Zhang, Yizhou Wang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Language_Models_Represent_Beliefs_of_Self_and_Others/2024-02-28-Language_Models_Represent_Beliefs_of_Self_and_Others.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Language_Models_Represent_Beliefs_of_Self_and_Others/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18496v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Large Language Models (LLMs) possess Theory of Mind (ToM) capabilities, but the mechanisms underlying these capabilities are not well understood.</li>
<li>It is possible to linearly decode belief status from the perspectives of various agents through neural activations of language models, indicating the existence of internal representations of self and others’ beliefs.</li>
<li>Manipulating these representations can dramatically change the models’ ToM performance, underscoring their pivotal role in the social reasoning process.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs can distinguish between different belief states of multiple perspectives through their intermediate activation with simple linear models.</li>
<li>Manipulating these representations significantly affects the model’s social reasoning performances.</li>
<li>The internal belief representations in LLMs generalize across diverse social reasoning task scenarios.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study provides valuable insights into the ToM capabilities of LLMs, but it is limited to certain types of LLMs and specific social reasoning tasks, which may not capture the full spectrum of ToM capabilities.</li>
<li>Future work should aim to address these gaps, broadening the understanding of ToM in AI systems across various models and more complex contexts.</li>
<li>Ethical considerations are crucial to prevent misuse and bias propagation, ensuring AI’s societal impact is positive. Responsible development and transparent deployment are imperative to safeguard against unintended consequences and maintain trust in AI advancements.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18496v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18496v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18496v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18496v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6809</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Language_Models_Represent_Beliefs_of_Self_and_Others/2024-02-28-Language_Models_Represent_Beliefs_of_Self_and_Others.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18496v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Small But Funny: A Feedback-Driven Approach to Humor Distillation</title>
  <dc:creator>Sahithya Ravi, Patrick Huber, Akshat Shrivastava, Aditya Sagar, Ahmed Aly, Vered Shwartz, Arash Einolghozati</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Small_But_Funny_A_Feedback_Driven_Approach_to_Humor_Distillation/2024-02-28-Small_But_Funny_A_Feedback_Driven_Approach_to_Humor_Distillation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Small_But_Funny_A_Feedback_Driven_Approach_to_Humor_Distillation/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18113v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article explores the use of feedback-driven knowledge distillation to transfer complex language abilities, specifically humor generation, from Large Language Models (LLMs) to Small Language Models (SLMs).</li>
<li>The study hypothesizes that creative tasks like humor generation may be hard to learn by imitation alone and investigates the use of feedback from the LLM as a “critic” to evaluate the student’s performance.</li>
<li>Experiments reveal that incorporating feedback significantly narrows the performance gap between SLMs and LLMs in humor generation, highlighting the potential of using feedback as an additional dimension to data when transferring complex language abilities via distillation.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The study explores the use of feedback-driven knowledge distillation to transfer complex language abilities, specifically humor generation, from LLMs to SLMs.</li>
<li>Incorporating feedback from the LLM as a “critic” significantly narrows the performance gap between SLMs and LLMs in humor generation.</li>
<li>The study highlights the potential of using feedback as an additional dimension to data when transferring complex language abilities via distillation.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides valuable insights into the potential of feedback-driven knowledge distillation for transferring complex language abilities, such as humor generation, from LLMs to SLMs.</li>
<li>The study addresses limitations of relying solely on imitation for creative tasks and proposes a novel approach involving feedback from the LLM as a “critic” to guide the student model.</li>
<li>The article acknowledges potential biases and limitations in LLM-based evaluation and feedback, emphasizing the need for further research in mitigating biases and ensuring cultural sensitivity in humor generation.</li>
<li>The study raises ethical considerations related to data sources, offensive content, and cultural references, highlighting the importance of responsible and inclusive language model training and evaluation.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18113v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18113v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18113v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18113v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7067</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Small_But_Funny_A_Feedback_Driven_Approach_to_Humor_Distillation/2024-02-28-Small_But_Funny_A_Feedback_Driven_Approach_to_Humor_Distillation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18113v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Rethinking the Bounds of LLM Reasoning: Are Multi-Agent Discussions the Key?</title>
  <dc:creator>Qineng Wang, Zihao Wang, Ying Su, Hanghang Tong, Yangqiu Song</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Rethinking_the_Bounds_of_LLM_Reasoning_Are_Multi_Agent_Discussions_the_Key/2024-02-28-Rethinking_the_Bounds_of_LLM_Reasoning_Are_Multi_Agent_Discussions_the_Key.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Rethinking_the_Bounds_of_LLM_Reasoning_Are_Multi_Agent_Discussions_the_Key/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18272v1/extracted/5436554/assets/pic/fig1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<p>Recent progress in LLMs discussion suggests that multi-agent discussion improves the reasoning abilities of LLMs. In this work, a novel group discussion framework is proposed to enrich the set of discussion mechanisms. The results show that a single-agent LLM with strong prompts can achieve almost the same performance as the best existing discussion approach on a wide range of reasoning tasks and backbone LLMs. Multi-agent discussion performs better than a single agent only when there is no demonstration in the prompt. Further study reveals the common interaction mechanisms of LLMs during the discussion.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>A single-agent LLM with strong prompts can achieve almost the same performance as the best existing discussion approach on a wide range of reasoning tasks and backbone LLMs.</li>
<li>Multi-agent discussion performs better than a single agent only when there is no demonstration in the prompt.</li>
<li>Common interaction mechanisms of LLMs during the discussion were revealed.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study provides valuable insights into the effectiveness of multi-agent discussions for reasoning tasks.</li>
<li>The findings suggest that prompt engineering can significantly boost reasoning performance in large language models.</li>
<li>The study highlights the potential for multi-agent discussions to enhance reasoning abilities in scenarios where expert knowledge or detailed examples are insufficient.</li>
<li>The research also identifies two common types of errors in multi-agent discussions: Judge Mistake and Wrong Answer Propagation.</li>
<li>The study provides a comprehensive and fair assessment of the performance of a strong single agent and multi-agent discussions, offering valuable insights for future research.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18272v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18272v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18272v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18272v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>9233</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Rethinking_the_Bounds_of_LLM_Reasoning_Are_Multi_Agent_Discussions_the_Key/2024-02-28-Rethinking_the_Bounds_of_LLM_Reasoning_Are_Multi_Agent_Discussions_the_Key.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18272v1/extracted/5436554/assets/pic/fig1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Benchmarking Large Language Models on Answering and Explaining Challenging Medical Questions</title>
  <dc:creator>Hanjie Chen, Zhouxiang Fang, Yash Singla, Mark Dredze</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Benchmarking_Large_Language_Models_on_Answering_and_Explaining_Challenging_Medical_Questions/2024-02-28-Benchmarking_Large_Language_Models_on_Answering_and_Explaining_Challenging_Medical_Questions.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Benchmarking_Large_Language_Models_on_Answering_and_Explaining_Challenging_Medical_Questions/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18060v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Large language models (LLMs) have shown impressive performance in answering medical questions, including passing medical licensing exams.</li>
<li>However, existing benchmarks do not capture the complexity of realistic clinical cases and lack reference explanations for answers, hindering the evaluation of model explanations.</li>
<li>To address these challenges, two new datasets, JAMA Clinical Challenge and Medbullets, have been constructed, consisting of challenging clinical cases and USMLE Step 2&amp;3 style clinical questions, respectively.</li>
<li>Four LLMs were evaluated on the two datasets, and it was found that the datasets are harder than previous benchmarks, highlighting the need for new metrics to support future research on explainable medical question-answering.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The new datasets, JAMA Clinical Challenge and Medbullets, are harder than previous benchmarks, posing a new challenge for medical LLM research.</li>
<li>The inconsistency between automatic and human evaluations of model-generated explanations emphasizes the necessity of developing new metrics for explainable medical question-answering.</li>
<li>LLMs have shown promising results in generating explanations for medical questions, but the quality of these explanations is challenging to evaluate.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article effectively highlights the limitations of existing benchmarks and the need for more challenging datasets to evaluate LLMs in the medical domain.</li>
<li>The inconsistency between automatic and human evaluations of model-generated explanations raises concerns about the reliability of current evaluation metrics and the need for more robust measures.</li>
<li>The article provides valuable insights into the challenges of evaluating LLMs in the medical domain and emphasizes the importance of developing new metrics to support future research in this area. However, the article could benefit from a more detailed discussion of potential biases in the datasets and the ethical implications of using LLMs in medical question-answering tasks.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18060v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18060v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18060v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18060v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7906</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Benchmarking_Large_Language_Models_on_Answering_and_Explaining_Challenging_Medical_Questions/2024-02-28-Benchmarking_Large_Language_Models_on_Answering_and_Explaining_Challenging_Medical_Questions.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18060v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Exploring Multilingual Human Value Concepts in Large Language Models: Is Value Alignment Consistent, Transferable and Controllable across Languages?</title>
  <dc:creator>Shaoyang Xu, Weilong Dong, Zishan Guo, Xinwei Wu, Deyi Xiong</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Exploring_Multilingual_Human_Value_Concepts_in_Large_Language_Models_Is_Value_Alignment_Consistent_Transferable_and_Controllable_across_Languages/2024-02-28-Exploring_Multilingual_Human_Value_Concepts_in_Large_Language_Models_Is_Value_Alignment_Consistent_Transferable_and_Controllable_across_Languages.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Exploring_Multilingual_Human_Value_Concepts_in_Large_Language_Models_Is_Value_Alignment_Consistent_Transferable_and_Controllable_across_Languages/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18120v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>This article explores multilingual human value concepts in Large Language Models (LLMs) and investigates the consistency, transferability, and controllability of value alignment across languages. The authors empirically substantiate the existence of multilingual human values in LLMs and disclose three traits arising from language resource disparities: cross-lingual inconsistency, distorted linguistic relationships, and unidirectional cross-lingual transfer between high- and low-resource languages. They also validate the feasibility of cross-lingual control over value alignment capabilities of LLMs, leveraging the dominant language as a source language. The findings suggest that the composition of multilingual data for LLMs pre-training should include a limited number of dominant languages for cross-lingual alignment transfer while avoiding their excessive prevalence and maintaining a balanced distribution of non-dominant languages.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs encode concepts that represent human values in multiple languages, and the larger the models, the more precisely these concepts are captured.</li>
<li>The cross-lingual concept consistency and transferability are intricately tied to the multilinguality pattern of the models to be extracted. The presence of dominant languages tends to bring about a monotonic cross-lingual transfer pattern, whereas a balanced multilinguality facilitates mutual cross-lingual transfer.</li>
<li>The value alignment of LLMs can be effectively transferred across languages, with the dominant language as a source language.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study provides valuable insights into the multilingual human value concepts in LLMs and the potential for cross-lingual control over value alignment. However, the findings are based on specific datasets and models, and the generalizability of the results to other contexts is not fully addressed.</li>
<li>The article acknowledges the limitations of relying on translations from translation engines and the semi-automated evaluation of model control. However, it would be beneficial to discuss potential biases introduced by these limitations and their impact on the validity of the findings.</li>
<li>The suggestions for enhancing multilingual AI safety and utility are based on the authors’ findings and may require further validation and refinement through additional research and experimentation. The potential implications of implementing these suggestions should be thoroughly considered.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the article provides valuable insights into the multilingual human value concepts in LLMs and the potential for cross-lingual control over value alignment, but further research is needed to address the limitations and validate the practical implications of the findings.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18120v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18120v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18120v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18120v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>9194</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Exploring_Multilingual_Human_Value_Concepts_in_Large_Language_Models_Is_Value_Alignment_Consistent_Transferable_and_Controllable_across_Languages/2024-02-28-Exploring_Multilingual_Human_Value_Concepts_in_Large_Language_Models_Is_Value_Alignment_Consistent_Transferable_and_Controllable_across_Languages.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18120v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Learning or Self-aligning? Rethinking Instruction Fine-tuning</title>
  <dc:creator>Mengjie Ren, Boxi Cao, Hongyu Lin, Liu Cao, Xianpei Han, Ke Zeng, Guanglu Wan, Xunliang Cai, Le Sun</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Learning_or_Self_aligning_Rethinking_Instruction_Fine_tuning/2024-02-28-Learning_or_Self_aligning_Rethinking_Instruction_Fine_tuning.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Learning_or_Self_aligning_Rethinking_Instruction_Fine_tuning/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18243v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Instruction Fine-tuning (IFT) is a critical phase in building large language models (LLMs).</li>
<li>Previous works mainly focus on the IFT’s role in the transfer of behavioral norms and the learning of additional world knowledge.</li>
<li>Surprisingly, attempts to learn additional world knowledge through IFT often struggle to yield positive impacts and can even lead to markedly negative effects.</li>
<li>Maintaining internal knowledge consistency before and after IFT is a critical factor for achieving successful IFT.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>IFT data consistent with model parameter knowledge leads to superior IFT outcomes.</li>
<li>Using IFT data that aligns with model parameter knowledge yet is erroneous yields better performance than employing those that are correct but incongruent with model parameter knowledge.</li>
<li>Ensuring that the model does not learn world knowledge conflicting with parameter knowledge during IFT enhances the effectiveness of IFT.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The study focuses on the role of Instruction Fine-tuning (IFT) in large language models (LLMs) and its impact on the transfer of behavioral norms and additional world knowledge.</li>
<li>The findings reveal that the core function of IFT is not to learn domain-specific world knowledge, but to facilitate self-aligning instruction with the already existing parameter knowledge of LLMs.</li>
<li>The study provides guidance for future IFT data construction, model training, and model evaluation, shedding light on the future direction of data construction, model learning, and model evaluation for IFT.</li>
<li>The limitations of the study include the focus on multiple-choice questions and the use of models with about 10B parameters, which may limit the generalizability of the findings. Further research on larger models and free-style generation is recommended.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18243v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18243v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18243v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18243v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>7107</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Learning_or_Self_aligning_Rethinking_Instruction_Fine_tuning/2024-02-28-Learning_or_Self_aligning_Rethinking_Instruction_Fine_tuning.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18243v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>LeMo-NADe: Multi-Parameter Neural Architecture Discovery with LLMs</title>
  <dc:creator>Md Hafizur Rahman, Prabuddha Chakraborty</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LeMo_NADe_Multi_Parameter_Neural_Architecture_Discovery_with_LLMs/2024-02-28-LeMo_NADe_Multi_Parameter_Neural_Architecture_Discovery_with_LLMs.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LeMo_NADe_Multi_Parameter_Neural_Architecture_Discovery_with_LLMs/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18443v1/extracted/5438029/Figure/Overview.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Building efficient neural network architectures for edge devices is challenging due to parameters like power consumption, model size, and inferencing speed.</li>
<li>LeMo-NADe is a framework designed to automatically discover new neural network architectures based on user-defined parameters, an expert system, and an LLM trained on open-domain knowledge.</li>
<li>The framework was validated using CIFAR-10, CIFAR-100, and ImageNet16-120 datasets with GPT-4 Turbo and Gemini as the LLM component, showing rapid discovery of intricate neural network models.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Traditional NAS frameworks are limited by predefined search spaces, while LeMo-NADe does not rely on such spaces, allowing for the discovery of novel neural network architectures.</li>
<li>LeMo-NADe is capable of prioritizing metrics besides accuracy, making it optimal for different IoT/Edge requirements.</li>
<li>The framework outperforms traditional NAS techniques in terms of efficiency and performance across diverse application settings.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Traditional NAS techniques focus primarily on improving task accuracy with little emphasis on additional parameters such as frames-per-second, power consumption, and emissions, which are increasingly relevant.</li>
<li>The use of LLMs for neural architecture discovery raises questions about the generalization of the discovered architectures and the potential biases in the open-domain knowledge used to train the LLM.</li>
<li>The framework’s reliance on an expert system and user-defined metrics may introduce subjectivity and bias into the neural architecture discovery process.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18443v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18443v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18443v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18443v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5440</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LeMo_NADe_Multi_Parameter_Neural_Architecture_Discovery_with_LLMs/2024-02-28-LeMo_NADe_Multi_Parameter_Neural_Architecture_Discovery_with_LLMs.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18443v1/extracted/5438029/Figure/Overview.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>An Iterative Associative Memory Model for Empathetic Response Generation</title>
  <dc:creator>Zhou Yang, Zhaochun Ren, Yufeng Wang, Chao Chen, Haizhou Sun, Xiaofei Zhu, Xiangwen Liao</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/An_Iterative_Associative_Memory_Model_for_Empathetic_Response_Generation/2024-02-28-An_Iterative_Associative_Memory_Model_for_Empathetic_Response_Generation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/An_Iterative_Associative_Memory_Model_for_Empathetic_Response_Generation/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.17959v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Empathetic response generation is the task of understanding the cognitive and emotional states in dialogue utterances and generating appropriate responses.</li>
<li>Existing approaches overlook the associated words between dialogue utterances, leading to inaccurate understanding of emotional and cognitive states.</li>
<li>The proposed Iterative Associative Memory Model (IAMM) employs a second-order interaction attention mechanism to iteratively capture vital associated words between dialogue utterances and situations, dialogue history, and a memory module, thereby accurately and nuancedly comprehending the utterances.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>IAMM outperforms the baselines on most metrics, demonstrating better performance in emotion accuracy, diversity, and human evaluation.</li>
<li>Ablation studies show that both explicit and implicit associative information have considerable influence on emotion accuracy and diversity.</li>
<li>IAMM focusing on associative relationships has stronger emotion recognition and expression abilities, further demonstrating the effectiveness of iterative associations.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The proposed IAMM demonstrates superior performance in accurately understanding emotions and expressing more empathetic responses compared to the baselines.</li>
<li>The model effectively captures associated words and utilizes them to generate informative and relevant responses.</li>
<li>The analysis of associated words reveals that the model pays attention to common words with low emotions, while its most highly weighted words have high emotion intensity or are less common.</li>
<li>The limitations of the work include the reliance on text-based empathetic comprehension mechanisms and the lack of situation information in some datasets. Future work may explore multimodal empathetic comprehension mechanisms and effective construction of situation information.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.17959v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.17959v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.17959v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.17959v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6504</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/An_Iterative_Associative_Memory_Model_for_Empathetic_Response_Generation/2024-02-28-An_Iterative_Associative_Memory_Model_for_Empathetic_Response_Generation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.17959v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Evaluating Quantized Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Shiyao Li, Xuefei Ning, Luning Wang, Tengxuan Liu, Xiangsheng Shi, Shengen Yan, Guohao Dai, Huazhong Yang, Yu Wang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Evaluating_Quantized_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-28-Evaluating_Quantized_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.18158v1/image_1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article evaluates the impact of post-training quantization (PTQ) on large language models (LLMs) across various tasks and model families. It discusses the effects of quantization on different tensor types, context length, and emergent abilities, as well as its implications for adversarial attacks, ethics, and dialogue abilities. The findings provide insights into the performance of quantized LLMs and recommendations for applying quantization techniques.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Quantization has varying effects on different tensor types, with weight-only quantization leading to performance gains and KV cache quantization causing performance loss.</li>
<li>The tolerance for quantization varies based on the model size and the quantization method used, with larger models exhibiting higher tolerance for weight-only quantization.</li>
<li>Quantization has consistent effects across different positions, with only a few exceptions, and is more sensitive to mathematical multi-step reasoning and self-calibration abilities.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides valuable insights into the impact of quantization on LLMs’ performance across various tasks and model families. However, it is essential to address the challenges of restoring performance with extremely low bit-width quantization methods and further investigate the impact of quantization on multi-turn dialogues. Additionally, the lack of a clear relationship between quantization and adversarial robustness highlights the need for further research in this area.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18158v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18158v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18158v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18158v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>48972</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Evaluating_Quantized_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-28-Evaluating_Quantized_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/img/2402.18158v1/image_1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>LLM Task Interference: An Initial Study on the Impact of Task-Switch in Conversational History</title>
  <dc:creator>Akash Gupta, Ivaxi Sheth, Vyas Raina, Mark Gales, Mario Fritz</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLM_Task_Interference_An_Initial_Study_on_the_Impact_of_Task_Switch_in_Conversational_History/2024-02-28-LLM_Task_Interference_An_Initial_Study_on_the_Impact_of_Task_Switch_in_Conversational_History.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLM_Task_Interference_An_Initial_Study_on_the_Impact_of_Task_Switch_in_Conversational_History/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18216v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The study investigates the impact of task-switch in conversational history on large language models (LLMs).</li>
<li>The authors find that task-switches can lead to significant performance degradation in LLMs.</li>
<li>The study makes the first attempt to formalize the study of vulnerabilities and interference of tasks in conversational LLMs caused by task-switches in the conversational history.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The study formalizes the risk of performance degradation of LLMs due to task-switch.</li>
<li>The impact of task-switch on diverse datasets with more than 15 different task-switches is presented.</li>
<li>The study measures the task-switch sensitivity for popular LLMs of different sizes, observing that very large (175B) and small (7B) LLMs can both be susceptible to performance degradation from task-switch.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The study provides valuable insights into the vulnerabilities of LLMs to task-switches in conversational history, shedding light on the potential limitations of these models.</li>
<li>The limitations of the study include the inability to perform task sensitivity analysis on closed models and the maximum token length constraint, which limited the analysis over extremely long conversations.</li>
<li>Future work could focus on aligning humans and the model as a metric, which was out of the scope for this paper. Additionally, further research is needed to address the potential biases and vulnerabilities of LLMs to undesired information leakage from the conversation history.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18216v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18216v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18216v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18216v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5440</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLM_Task_Interference_An_Initial_Study_on_the_Impact_of_Task_Switch_in_Conversational_History/2024-02-28-LLM_Task_Interference_An_Initial_Study_on_the_Impact_of_Task_Switch_in_Conversational_History.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18216v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Making Them Ask and Answer: Jailbreaking Large Language Models in Few Queries via Disguise and Reconstruction</title>
  <dc:creator>Tong Liu, Yingjie Zhang, Zhe Zhao, Yinpeng Dong, Guozhu Meng, Kai Chen</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Making_Them_Ask_and_Answer_Jailbreaking_Large_Language_Models_in_Few_Queries_via_Disguise_and_Reconstruction/2024-02-28-Making_Them_Ask_and_Answer_Jailbreaking_Large_Language_Models_in_Few_Queries_via_Disguise_and_Reconstruction.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Making_Them_Ask_and_Answer_Jailbreaking_Large_Language_Models_in_Few_Queries_via_Disguise_and_Reconstruction/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18104v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The academic article “Making Them Ask and Answer: Jailbreaking Large Language Models in Few Queries via Disguise and Reconstruction” explores the vulnerability of large language models (LLMs) to jailbreak attacks, particularly in the context of harmful or toxic responses. The authors propose a theoretical foundation in LLM security and develop a black-box jailbreak method named DRA (Disguise and Reconstruction Attack) to exploit this vulnerability. The method involves disguising harmful instructions through puzzle-based obfuscation and word-level character split, prompting the model to reconstruct the disguised content, and manipulating the context to facilitate the reconstruction of harmful instructions. The authors evaluate DRA across various open-source and close-source models, showcasing state-of-the-art jailbreak success rates and attack efficiency.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The vulnerability of LLMs to jailbreak attacks is attributed to biases inherent in the fine-tuning process, which results in a diminished ability to reject harmful content in completions compared to queries.</li>
<li>The DRA method, which combines disguise, payload reconstruction, and context manipulation, demonstrates superior attack success rates and efficiency compared to state-of-the-art baselines across various LLMs.</li>
<li>The ablation study highlights the critical role of disguise, payload reconstruction, and context manipulation in bypassing the safeguard of LLMs.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article effectively identifies and analyzes the vulnerability of LLMs to jailbreak attacks, providing a novel approach to exploit this vulnerability.</li>
<li>The empirical evaluation of the DRA method demonstrates its effectiveness and efficiency in bypassing LLM safeguards.</li>
<li>The ablation study provides valuable insights into the nuanced interplay between disguise, payload reconstruction, and context manipulation in bypassing LLM safeguards.</li>
<li>The article could benefit from a more detailed discussion of potential ethical considerations and implications of the proposed jailbreak method.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the article makes a significant contribution to the understanding of LLM vulnerabilities and provides a novel approach to exploit these vulnerabilities for jailbreak attacks. Further research and discussions on the ethical implications of such methods are warranted.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18104v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18104v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18104v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18104v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>10757</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Making_Them_Ask_and_Answer_Jailbreaking_Large_Language_Models_in_Few_Queries_via_Disguise_and_Reconstruction/2024-02-28-Making_Them_Ask_and_Answer_Jailbreaking_Large_Language_Models_in_Few_Queries_via_Disguise_and_Reconstruction.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18104v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Decomposed Prompting: Unveiling Multilingual Linguistic Structure Knowledge in English-Centric Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Ercong Nie, Shuzhou Yuan, Bolei Ma, Helmut Schmid, Michael Färber, Frauke Kreuter, Hinrich Schütze</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Decomposed_Prompting_Unveiling_Multilingual_Linguistic_Structure_Knowledge_in_English_Centric_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-28-Decomposed_Prompting_Unveiling_Multilingual_Linguistic_Structure_Knowledge_in_English_Centric_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Decomposed_Prompting_Unveiling_Multilingual_Linguistic_Structure_Knowledge_in_English_Centric_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18397v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper introduces the decomposed prompting approach to probe the linguistic structure understanding of English-centric Large Language Models (LLMs) in sequence labeling tasks.</li>
<li>The method generates an individual prompt for each token of the input sentence, asking for its linguistic label.</li>
<li>The study assesses the method on the Universal Dependencies part-of-speech tagging dataset for 38 languages, utilizing both English-centric and multilingual LLMs.</li>
<li>Findings show that decomposed prompting surpasses the iterative prompting baseline in efficacy and efficiency under zero- and few-shot settings.</li>
<li>The study offers insights into the multilingual transferability of English-centric LLMs, contributing to the understanding of their multilingual linguistic knowledge.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Decomposed prompting outperforms iterative prompting in efficacy and efficiency under zero- and few-shot settings.</li>
<li>English-centric LLMs perform better on average than multilingual models in multilingual investigations.</li>
<li>The inclusion of an instruction in prompts negatively impacts the performance of LLMs in both probability-based and generation-based evaluation methods.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The decomposed prompting strategy struggles if the same word occurs twice in a sentence with different POS tags.</li>
<li>The efficiency of decomposed prompting suffers as the length of the input sequence and the complexity of the task increase.</li>
<li>The study uses decomposed prompting methods for part-of-speech (POS) tagging as a means to evaluate the multilingual structural knowledge of English-centric Large Language Models (LLMs). However, the scope for extending this methodology to probe more intricate aspects of linguistic structure is substantial.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18397v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18397v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18397v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18397v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6429</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Decomposed_Prompting_Unveiling_Multilingual_Linguistic_Structure_Knowledge_in_English_Centric_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-28-Decomposed_Prompting_Unveiling_Multilingual_Linguistic_Structure_Knowledge_in_English_Centric_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18397v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Human Simulacra: A Step toward the Personification of Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Qiuejie Xie, Qiming Feng, Tianqi Zhang, Qingqiu Li, Yuejie Zhang, Rui Feng, Shang Gao</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Human_Simulacra_A_Step_toward_the_Personification_of_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-28-Human_Simulacra_A_Step_toward_the_Personification_of_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Human_Simulacra_A_Step_toward_the_Personification_of_Large_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18180v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Large language models (LLMs) are being explored as systems that can mimic human intelligence, with potential applications in replacing human participants in experiments.</li>
<li>The paper introduces a framework for large language models personification, including a strategy for constructing virtual characters’ life stories, a Multi-Agent Cognitive Mechanism for simulating human cognitive processes, and a psychology-guided evaluation method.</li>
<li>Experimental results demonstrate that the constructed simulacra can produce personified responses that align with their target characters.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs can simulate human cognitive processes, assisting researchers in exploring human interactions without real human participants.</li>
<li>The Multi-Agent Cognitive Mechanism enhances the quality of simulacra by simulating human brain’s information processing and memory systems.</li>
<li>The psychology-guided evaluation method assesses the quality of human simulations from both self-reporting and external observation perspectives.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper’s approach has limitations, including data insufficiency, evaluation challenges, and inherited model limitations.</li>
<li>The evaluation framework for measuring LLMs’ humanizing capabilities is complex and subjective, requiring further development.</li>
<li>LLMs may face challenges in accurately defining the knowledge boundaries of the target persona and producing harmful viewpoints or toxic content during interaction.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the paper provides a preliminary exploration of the potential of Large Language Model Personification, offering a fresh perspective for understanding complex human behaviors and expanding the potential applications of artificial intelligence in social science and psychological research. However, there are several limitations and challenges that need to be addressed in future research.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18180v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18180v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18180v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18180v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6794</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Human_Simulacra_A_Step_toward_the_Personification_of_Large_Language_Models/2024-02-28-Human_Simulacra_A_Step_toward_the_Personification_of_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18180v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>A Survey on Recent Advances in LLM-Based Multi-turn Dialogue Systems</title>
  <dc:creator>Zihao Yi, Jiarui Ouyang, Yuwen Liu, Tianhao Liao, Zhe Xu, Ying Shen</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_Survey_on_Recent_Advances_in_LLM_Based_Multi_turn_Dialogue_Systems/2024-02-28-A_Survey_on_Recent_Advances_in_LLM_Based_Multi_turn_Dialogue_Systems.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_Survey_on_Recent_Advances_in_LLM_Based_Multi_turn_Dialogue_Systems/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18013v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides an overview of large language models (LLMs) and their application in multi-turn dialogue systems, discussing the limitations of conventional dialogue systems and delving into different types of LLMs, such as decoder-only and encoder-only architectures, as well as specific LLM models like GPT and BERT series.</li>
<li>It discusses the encoder-decoder Transformer architecture, focusing on BART and T5 models, fine-tuning methods, and mitigating fine-tuning instabilities through methods like Regularization Fine-tuning (R3F), SMART, and Free Large-Batch Adversarial Training (FreeLB), as well as prompt engineering and LLM Based Task-oriented Dialogue Systems.</li>
<li>The article also covers pipeline-based methods in task-oriented dialogue (TOD) systems, highlighting natural language understanding, dialogue state tracking, policy learning, and natural language generation, and the challenges and advancements in each module.</li>
<li>It discusses the development and application of LLMs in multi-turn dialogue systems, emphasizing the significance of LLMs in advancing dialogue systems and addressing challenges such as emotionalization, personalization, multi-task dialogue systems, multi-model dialogue systems, bias identification, and privacy protection.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Large language models (LLMs) play a crucial role in advancing multi-turn dialogue systems, addressing challenges such as emotionalization, personalization, and bias identification.</li>
<li>The article highlights the significance of pre-training and fine-tuning methods for Transformer models, showcasing their potential in natural language processing tasks and dialogue systems.</li>
<li>Pipeline-based methods in task-oriented dialogue systems are essential for natural language understanding, dialogue state tracking, policy learning, and natural language generation, contributing to the overall effectiveness of dialogue systems.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The article provides a comprehensive overview of LLMs and their application in dialogue systems, but it could benefit from more in-depth discussions on the ethical implications and potential biases associated with LLM-based dialogue systems.</li>
<li>While the article covers various pre-training and fine-tuning methods, it would be valuable to include a comparative analysis of their effectiveness in different dialogue system applications.</li>
<li>The discussion on pipeline-based methods in task-oriented dialogue systems is informative, but further exploration of real-world applications and case studies would enhance the practical relevance of the article.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-02-29</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18013v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.18013v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18013v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18013v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>18047</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/A_Survey_on_Recent_Advances_in_LLM_Based_Multi_turn_Dialogue_Systems/2024-02-28-A_Survey_on_Recent_Advances_in_LLM_Based_Multi_turn_Dialogue_Systems.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2402.18013v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
