<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Bayesian beagle</title>
<link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Quarto blog of LLM-generated summaries of Arxiv preprints</description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.450</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>PathMMU: A Massive Multimodal Expert-Level Benchmark for Understanding and Reasoning in Pathology</title>
  <dc:creator>Yuxuan Sun, Hao Wu, Chenglu Zhu, Sunyi Zheng, Qizi Chen, Kai Zhang, Yunlong Zhang, Xiaoxiao Lan, Mengyue Zheng, Jingxiong Li, Xinheng Lyu, Tao Lin, Lin Yang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/PathMMU_A_Massive_Multimodal_Expert_Level_Benchmark_for_Understanding_and_Reasoning_in_Pathology/2024-01-29-PathMMU_A_Massive_Multimodal_Expert_Level_Benchmark_for_Understanding_and_Reasoning_in_Pathology.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/PathMMU_A_Massive_Multimodal_Expert_Level_Benchmark_for_Understanding_and_Reasoning_in_Pathology/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The academic article introduces the PathMMU benchmark, a specialized dataset for evaluating large multimodal models (LMMs) in the field of pathology. It comprises a large number of multimodal multi-choice questions and high-quality images from authoritative sources, emphasizing the interpretability of model decision-making. The construction of the dataset involves a meticulous three-step data processing protocol, and fine-tuning experiments demonstrate the adaptability of language and vision models to the pathology domain. Statistical information and experimental findings provide a comprehensive analysis of the dataset’s characteristics and the behavior of LMMs in pathology-related tasks. The article also discusses the performance of the GPT-4V model in interpreting pathology images, highlighting its strengths and limitations. Error analysis and specific histological analyses further contribute to the understanding of the dataset and the limitations of current language models in pathology.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The PathMMU benchmark provides a comprehensive dataset for evaluating large multimodal models in pathology, emphasizing interpretability and high-quality images.</li>
<li>Fine-tuning experiments demonstrate the adaptability of language and vision models to the pathology domain, with significant improvements in model performance.</li>
<li>The GPT-4V model shows strengths in understanding pathology in text form but has limitations in accurately interpreting pathology images, highlighting the need for further development in this area.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article presents a robust and comprehensive dataset for evaluating large multimodal models in pathology, addressing the limitations of current language models in interpreting pathology images. However, potential areas for further research include the development of more interpretable AI models for pathology diagnostics and the exploration of additional clinical information and diagnostic tests for accurate diagnoses. The article’s emphasis on high-quality images and detailed explanations supports the interpretability of model decision-making, contributing to the advancement of research in the pathology domain.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-31</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16355v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16355v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16355v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16355v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>45603</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/PathMMU_A_Massive_Multimodal_Expert_Level_Benchmark_for_Understanding_and_Reasoning_in_Pathology/2024-01-29-PathMMU_A_Massive_Multimodal_Expert_Level_Benchmark_for_Understanding_and_Reasoning_in_Pathology.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>E-EVAL: A Comprehensive Chinese K-12 Education Evaluation Benchmark for Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Jinchang Hou, Chang Ao, Haihong Wu, Xiangtao Kong, Zhigang Zheng, Daijia Tang, Chengming Li, Xiping Hu, Ruifeng Xu, Shiwen Ni, Min Yang</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/E_EVAL_A_Comprehensive_Chinese_K_12_Education_Evaluation_Benchmark_for_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-29-E_EVAL_A_Comprehensive_Chinese_K_12_Education_Evaluation_Benchmark_for_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/E_EVAL_A_Comprehensive_Chinese_K_12_Education_Evaluation_Benchmark_for_Large_Language_Models/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The E-EVAL benchmark is a comprehensive evaluation tool designed for the Chinese K-12 education field, consisting of 4,351 multiple-choice questions across primary, middle, and high school levels. The experiment section details the testing of 15 advanced language models on the E-EVAL benchmark, with a focus on zero-shot, few-shot-answer-only, and few-shot-chain-of-thought evaluation methods. The performance of various language models in solving math problems and Chinese language questions is discussed, highlighting the surprising phenomenon of models struggling with elementary school-level questions despite being capable of solving complex high school math problems. The section also presents the accuracy of different models under zero-shot and five-shot conditions, as well as the impact of Chain-of-Thought prompting on model performance. Additionally, the section explores the latest advancements in large language models in the education domain, including ChatGPT, GPT 4.0, ERNIE-Bot, ERNIE-Bot 4.0, Chinese LLaMA-2, Chinese Alpaca-2, and EduChat, and their potential impact on educational technology and learning outcomes.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The performance of language models varies across different educational subjects and prompt scenarios.</li>
<li>Models struggle with elementary school-level questions despite being capable of solving complex high school math problems.</li>
<li>Advanced large language models specifically tailored for the education domain have the potential to revolutionize the way educational content is delivered and assessed.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The E-EVAL benchmark and the experimental results provide valuable insights into the performance of large language models in the Chinese K-12 education domain. However, the study also reveals the limitations of language models in solving elementary school-level questions and the need for tailored benchmarks to accurately assess their performance. Additionally, the potential impact of advanced large language models on educational technology and learning outcomes is highlighted, suggesting a promising future for these models in the education domain. Further research is needed to address the shortcomings and limitations identified in the study and to enhance the performance of language models in educational applications.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-31</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.15927v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.15927v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.15927v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.15927v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>21938</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/E_EVAL_A_Comprehensive_Chinese_K_12_Education_Evaluation_Benchmark_for_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-29-E_EVAL_A_Comprehensive_Chinese_K_12_Education_Evaluation_Benchmark_for_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>LLM4Vuln: A Unified Evaluation Framework for Decoupling and Enhancing LLMs’ Vulnerability Reasoning</title>
  <dc:creator>Yuqiang Sun, Daoyuan Wu, Yue Xue, Han Liu, Wei Ma, Lyuye Zhang, Miaolei Shi, Yang Liu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLM4Vuln_A_Unified_Evaluation_Framework_for_Decoupling_and_Enhancing_LLMs_Vulnerability_Reasoning/2024-01-29-LLM4Vuln_A_Unified_Evaluation_Framework_for_Decoupling_and_Enhancing_LLMs_Vulnerability_Reasoning.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLM4Vuln_A_Unified_Evaluation_Framework_for_Decoupling_and_Enhancing_LLMs_Vulnerability_Reasoning/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The article introduces the LLM4Vuln framework, which aims to evaluate and enhance the vulnerability reasoning capability of Large Language Models (LLMs). It includes four pluggable components: Knowledge Retrieval, Tool Invocation, Prompt Schemes, and Instruction Following. The framework decouples LLMs’ vulnerability reasoning from their other capabilities and evaluates how their vulnerability reasoning could be enhanced when combined with the enhancement of other capabilities. The article also discusses the effects of different prompt schemes on LLMs’ vulnerability reasoning and the performance of open-source models in detecting vulnerabilities in smart contracts. Additionally, it provides a list of references to academic papers and reports related to security audit findings, vulnerability detection, and large language models.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The LLM4Vuln framework provides a systematic approach to evaluating and enhancing LLMs’ vulnerability reasoning capability, addressing the challenges of incorporating up-to-date vulnerability knowledge and improving instruction-following for structured output.</li>
<li>The choice of prompt scheme has a significant impact on LLMs’ vulnerability reasoning, with the Pre-CoT prompt scheme improving precision but not consistently impacting recall improvement, and the Post-CoT prompt scheme indirectly leading to an increase in both true positives and false positives.</li>
<li>The successful testing of new projects for zero-day vulnerabilities using LLM4Vuln demonstrates its effectiveness, emphasizing the importance of knowledge supplementation in vulnerability detection.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The LLM4Vuln framework has the potential to advance the effectiveness of LLMs in vulnerability detection and has practical implications for real-world security applications. However, the use of original vulnerability reports as knowledge may not be as effective in enhancing LLMs’ vulnerability reasoning. The choice of prompt scheme plays a crucial role in influencing the performance of LLMs in vulnerability detection. The article provides valuable insights into the performance of open-source models in detecting vulnerabilities, highlighting the need for reasoning ability in these models. The section on references offers a comprehensive list of resources for researchers and practitioners in the field of cybersecurity and language model applications. The prompts for summarizing vulnerabilities and their root causes provide a structured approach to analyzing and reporting vulnerabilities, contributing to the overall goal of enhancing the security and integrity of systems handling valuable data and assets.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-31</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16185v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16185v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16185v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16185v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>27275</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLM4Vuln_A_Unified_Evaluation_Framework_for_Decoupling_and_Enhancing_LLMs_Vulnerability_Reasoning/2024-01-29-LLM4Vuln_A_Unified_Evaluation_Framework_for_Decoupling_and_Enhancing_LLMs_Vulnerability_Reasoning.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Security Code Review by LLMs: A Deep Dive into Responses</title>
  <dc:creator>Jiaxin Yu, Peng Liang, Yujia Fu, Amjed Tahir, Mojtaba Shahin, Chong Wang, Yangxiao Cai</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Security_Code_Review_by_LLMs_A_Deep_Dive_into_Responses/2024-01-29-Security_Code_Review_by_LLMs_A_Deep_Dive_into_Responses.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Security_Code_Review_by_LLMs_A_Deep_Dive_into_Responses/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>Security code review aims to combine automated tools and manual efforts to detect security defects during development. This study compared the detection performance of three state-of-the-art Large Language Models (LLMs) under five prompts on 549 code files that contain security defects from real-world code reviews. The results indicate that the responses produced by LLMs often suffer from verbosity, vagueness, and incompleteness, highlighting the necessity to enhance their conciseness, understandability, and compliance to security defect detection.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The study compared the detection performance of three state-of-the-art LLMs (Gemini Pro, GPT-4, and GPT-3.5) under five prompts on 549 code files that contain security defects from real-world code reviews.</li>
<li>The responses produced by LLMs often suffer from verbosity, vagueness, and incompleteness, highlighting the necessity to enhance their conciseness, understandability, and compliance to security defect detection.</li>
<li>The study revealed the deficiencies of LLM-generated responses in security code review and paves the way for future optimization of LLMs towards this task.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The study provides valuable insights into the challenges of utilizing LLMs for automated security code review. However, it is important to note that the LLMs performed poorly in detecting security defects, indicating the need for further improvement in their capabilities. Additionally, the study focused on the deficiencies of LLM-generated responses, but further research is needed to address the underlying problems and optimize LLMs for security code review. The findings of this study have implications for the development and application of LLMs in software development tasks, highlighting the need for domain-specific LLMs and prompt optimization.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-31</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16310v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16310v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16310v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16310v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>9038</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Security_Code_Review_by_LLMs_A_Deep_Dive_into_Responses/2024-01-29-Security_Code_Review_by_LLMs_A_Deep_Dive_into_Responses.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>You tell me: A Dataset of GPT-4-Based Behaviour Change Support Conversations</title>
  <dc:creator>Selina Meyer, David Elsweiler</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/You_tell_me_A_Dataset_of_GPT_4_Based_Behaviour_Change_Support_Conversations/2024-01-29-You_tell_me_A_Dataset_of_GPT_4_Based_Behaviour_Change_Support_Conversations.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/You_tell_me_A_Dataset_of_GPT_4_Based_Behaviour_Change_Support_Conversations/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<p>The article presents a dataset of GPT-4-based conversational interactions related to behavior change, collected in a user study. The dataset includes conversation data, user language analysis, perception measures, and user feedback for large language model (LLM)-generated turns. The study aims to address the lack of user-focused research in the context of conversational agents and behavior change interventions.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Conversational agents are increasingly used to address emotional needs, especially in sensitive contexts such as mental health and behavior change interventions.</li>
<li>Large language models (LLMs) are considered as tools to generate texts for sensitive use cases, such as mental health and counseling, due to their high flexibility and ability to generate human-like language.</li>
<li>The dataset collected from the user study can be used to explore user behavior when interacting with LLM-based conversational agents and to inform the user-oriented design of such systems in the future.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article provides valuable insights into the use of conversational agents for behavior change interventions and the potential of large language models in this context. However, the study has limitations, such as the struggle of participants to adhere to the level of abstraction when interacting with the system and the technical issues experienced during the study. Additionally, the dataset raises ethical considerations related to informed consent and user expectations. Further research is needed to explore user interactions with LLM-based systems and to anticipate implicit information needs expressed during conversations. The potential applications of the dataset in behavioral analysis and natural language processing make it a valuable resource for future research. However, the article lacks a detailed discussion of potential biases and methodological issues in the dataset, which could impact the validity of the findings.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-31</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16167v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16167v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16167v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16167v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8797</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/You_tell_me_A_Dataset_of_GPT_4_Based_Behaviour_Change_Support_Conversations/2024-01-29-You_tell_me_A_Dataset_of_GPT_4_Based_Behaviour_Change_Support_Conversations.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Response Generation for Cognitive Behavioral Therapy with Large Language Models: Comparative Study with Socratic Questioning</title>
  <dc:creator>Kenta Izumi, Hiroki Tanaka, Kazuhiro Shidara, Hiroyoshi Adachi, Daisuke Kanayama, Takashi Kudo, Satoshi Nakamura</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Response_Generation_for_Cognitive_Behavioral_Therapy_with_Large_Language_Models_Comparative_Study_with_Socratic_Questioning/2024-01-29-Response_Generation_for_Cognitive_Behavioral_Therapy_with_Large_Language_Models_Comparative_Study_with_Socratic_Questioning.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Response_Generation_for_Cognitive_Behavioral_Therapy_with_Large_Language_Models_Comparative_Study_with_Socratic_Questioning/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<p>The study explores the use of large language models (LLMs) in cognitive behavioral therapy (CBT) dialogue systems, focusing on the impact of LLM-generated responses on subjective evaluations such as mood change, cognitive change, and dialogue quality. The researchers compared the use of a Transformer-based dialogue model trained with a social media empathetic counseling dataset (OsakaED) and GPT-4, an LLM created by OpenAI. The results indicate that GPT-4 significantly improves mood change, empathy, and other dialogue qualities, suggesting a high counseling ability. However, the study also found that even when using a dialogue model trained with a human counseling dataset, it does not necessarily yield better outcomes compared to scenario-based dialogues. The authors raise ethical concerns about directly using LLM-generated responses in real-life mental health care services, suggesting that human professionals could produce example responses or response templates using LLMs in advance in systems that use rules, scenarios, or example responses.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>GPT-4 significantly improves mood change, empathy, and other dialogue qualities.</li>
<li>Even when using a dialogue model trained with a human counseling dataset, it does not necessarily yield better outcomes compared to scenario-based dialogues.</li>
<li>Ethical concerns are raised about directly using LLM-generated responses in real-life mental health care services.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The study provides valuable insights into the potential of LLMs in CBT dialogue systems, particularly the significant improvements observed with GPT-4. However, the ethical concerns raised about directly using LLM-generated responses in real-life mental health care services are important to consider. The limitations of the study include the focus on subjective evaluations and the need for further research to explore the long-term impact of LLM-generated responses on mental health outcomes. Additionally, the study does not address potential biases in the LLM-generated responses and the challenges of ensuring responsible and ethical use of LLMs in mental health care settings. Further research is needed to address these limitations and provide a comprehensive understanding of the implications of using LLMs in CBT dialogue systems.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-31</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.15966v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.15966v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.15966v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.15966v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>1859</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Response_Generation_for_Cognitive_Behavioral_Therapy_with_Large_Language_Models_Comparative_Study_with_Socratic_Questioning/2024-01-29-Response_Generation_for_Cognitive_Behavioral_Therapy_with_Large_Language_Models_Comparative_Study_with_Socratic_Questioning.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>APIGen: Generative API Method Recommendation</title>
  <dc:creator>Yujia Chen, Cuiyun Gao, Muyijie Zhu, Qing Liao, Yong Wang, Guoai Xu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/APIGen_Generative_API_Method_Recommendation/2024-01-29-APIGen_Generative_API_Method_Recommendation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/APIGen_Generative_API_Method_Recommendation/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>Summary: The academic article proposes APIGen, a generative API method recommendation approach based on enhanced in-context learning. The article presents a detailed methodology for API recommendation, including the deconstruction of user queries, knowledge detection, reason generation, and API recommendation. The experimental setup, evaluation metrics, and baselines used to evaluate APIGen are described, along with the results and a case study to illustrate the effectiveness of APIGen. The article also discusses potential threats to the validity of the experimental results and related works in the field of API method recommendation.</p>
<p>Major Findings: 1. APIGen outperforms the state-of-the-art baseline CLEAR in both method-level and class-level API recommendation tasks, achieving significant improvements in various evaluation metrics. 2. The quality and relevance of the examples retrieved play a crucial role in the performance of APIGen, with variations observed in the success rate and mean average precision when using different examples in both method-level and class-level API recommendation. 3. APIGen performs consistently well across different large language models, demonstrating its robustness and effectiveness in generating high-quality API recommendations.</p>
<p>Analysis and Critique: The article provides valuable insights into the development of API recommendation systems and their applicability to different programming languages. However, potential limitations include the need for further exploration of the impact of example selection and the number of examples on APIGen’s performance. Additionally, the article could benefit from addressing potential biases in the experimental setup and discussing the generalizability of APIGen to other programming languages and domains.</p>
<p>Please note that the above summary is a synthesized version of the individual section summaries provided.</p>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-31</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.15843v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.15843v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.15843v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.15843v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>18648</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>recommender</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/APIGen_Generative_API_Method_Recommendation/2024-01-29-APIGen_Generative_API_Method_Recommendation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Scaling Sparse Fine-Tuning to Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Alan Ansell, Ivan Vulić, Hannah Sterz, Anna Korhonen, Edoardo M. Ponti</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Scaling_Sparse_Fine_Tuning_to_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-29-Scaling_Sparse_Fine_Tuning_to_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Scaling_Sparse_Fine_Tuning_to_Large_Language_Models/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The article introduces the concept of Sparse Fine-Tuning (SFT) for Large Language Models (LLMs) and discusses the challenges associated with it. It presents the SFT-AG and SFT-MA methods, explores their compatibility with quantization and efficient optimizers, and discusses the hyperparameter search for sparsely fine-tuning large language models.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The SFT-AG method demonstrates superior performance and memory usage trade-offs compared to other methods.</li>
<li>The performance of different quantized PEFT methods and their trade-offs in terms of performance, memory usage, and training speed are highlighted.</li>
<li>The hyperparameter search provides valuable insights into the optimal configurations for different SFT methods, contributing to improving the efficiency and effectiveness of training large language models with sparse fine-tuning.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article provides valuable insights into the challenges and solutions related to sparse fine-tuning for Large Language Models. However, it is important to critically evaluate the potential biases and limitations of the methods presented, as well as the need for further research to address computational efficiency and potential shortcomings in the SFT techniques. Additionally, the practical implications of these methods in real-world applications should be further explored to assess their broader impact.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-31</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16405v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16405v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16405v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16405v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>17208</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Scaling_Sparse_Fine_Tuning_to_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-29-Scaling_Sparse_Fine_Tuning_to_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Beyond Direct Diagnosis: LLM-based Multi-Specialist Agent Consultation for Automatic Diagnosis</title>
  <dc:creator>Haochun Wang, Sendong Zhao, Zewen Qiang, Nuwa Xi, Bing Qin, Ting Liu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Beyond_Direct_Diagnosis_LLM_based_Multi_Specialist_Agent_Consultation_for_Automatic_Diagnosis/2024-01-29-Beyond_Direct_Diagnosis_LLM_based_Multi_Specialist_Agent_Consultation_for_Automatic_Diagnosis.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Beyond_Direct_Diagnosis_LLM_based_Multi_Specialist_Agent_Consultation_for_Automatic_Diagnosis/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<p>The article introduces an Agent-derived Multi-Specialist Consultation (AMSC) framework for automatic diagnosis using large language models (LLMs) and medical knowledge. The study demonstrates the superiority of the AMSC approach compared to existing baselines, with significantly less parameter updating and training time, enhancing efficiency and practical utility. The AMSC framework also delves into a novel perspective on the role of implicit symptoms within the context of automatic diagnosis.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings"><strong>Major Findings:</strong></h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The AMSC framework outperforms existing baselines in terms of diagnostic accuracy, training duration, and the average number of turns required for implicit symptom inquiry.</li>
<li>The inclusion of implicit symptoms does not necessarily enhance the performance of the AMSC framework, indicating that explicit symptoms alone can effectively reflect a patient’s condition to a specialist agent.</li>
<li>Medical knowledge significantly impacts the performance of the AMSC framework, with deliberately misaligned disease-knowledge pairings adversely affecting diagnostic accuracy.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique"><strong>Analysis and Critique:</strong></h3>
<p>The AMSC framework demonstrates promising results in the context of automatic diagnosis, with the potential to generalize to real-world scenarios. The study raises important considerations regarding the role of implicit symptoms and medical knowledge in automated diagnostic systems. Additionally, the adaptive probability distribution fusion method introduced in the study shows significant promise in enhancing the effectiveness of the AMSC framework. However, further research is needed to explore the impact of implicit symptoms and medical knowledge in different clinical contexts and to validate the generalizability of the AMSC framework. Additionally, the study could benefit from addressing potential ethical considerations and limitations associated with the use of large language models in medical diagnostics.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-31</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16107v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16107v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16107v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16107v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>10367</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Beyond_Direct_Diagnosis_LLM_based_Multi_Specialist_Agent_Consultation_for_Automatic_Diagnosis/2024-01-29-Beyond_Direct_Diagnosis_LLM_based_Multi_Specialist_Agent_Consultation_for_Automatic_Diagnosis.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Rephrasing the Web: A Recipe for Compute and Data-Efficient Language Modeling</title>
  <dc:creator>Pratyush Maini, Skyler Seto, He Bai, David Grangier, Yizhe Zhang, Navdeep Jaitly</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Rephrasing_the_Web_A_Recipe_for_Compute_and_Data_Efficient_Language_Modeling/2024-01-29-Rephrasing_the_Web_A_Recipe_for_Compute_and_Data_Efficient_Language_Modeling.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Rephrasing_the_Web_A_Recipe_for_Compute_and_Data_Efficient_Language_Modeling/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16380v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>Large language models are typically trained on massive scrapes of the web, which can be unstructured, noisy, and poorly phrased. This poses challenges in terms of the compute and data required for training, as well as the quality of the data. In this work, the authors propose a method called Web Rephrase Augmented Pre-training (WRAP) that uses an off-the-shelf instruction-tuned model prompted to paraphrase documents on the web in specific styles such as “like Wikipedia” or in “question-answer format” to jointly pre-train large language models (LLMs) on real and synthetic rephrases. The authors show that using WRAP on the C4 dataset speeds up pre-training and improves perplexity and zero-shot question answer accuracy across different subsets of the Pile. They also investigate the impact of the re-phrasing style on the performance of the model, offering insights into how the composition of the training data can impact the performance of LLMs in out-of-distribution settings.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Using WRAP on the C4 dataset speeds up pre-training by approximately 3 times and improves perplexity by more than 10% on average across different subsets of the Pile.</li>
<li>The impact of the re-phrasing style on the performance of the model offers insights into how the composition of the training data can impact the performance of LLMs in out-of-distribution settings.</li>
<li>Pre-training LLMs with synthetic data allows equivalent models to be trained with 5 times less data or 3 times less compute.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article provides valuable insights into the use of synthetic data for pre-training large language models. However, it is important to critically evaluate the potential limitations and biases that may arise from using synthetic data. Additionally, further research is needed to fully understand the impact of synthetic data on the performance and generalization of language models.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-31</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16380v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16380v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16380v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16380v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>12696</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Rephrasing_the_Web_A_Recipe_for_Compute_and_Data_Efficient_Language_Modeling/2024-01-29-Rephrasing_the_Web_A_Recipe_for_Compute_and_Data_Efficient_Language_Modeling.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16380v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Machine Translation Meta Evaluation through Translation Accuracy Challenge Sets</title>
  <dc:creator>Nikita Moghe, Arnisa Fazla, Chantal Amrhein, Tom Kocmi, Mark Steedman, Alexandra Birch, Rico Sennrich, Liane Guillou</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Machine_Translation_Meta_Evaluation_through_Translation_Accuracy_Challenge_Sets/2024-01-29-Machine_Translation_Meta_Evaluation_through_Translation_Accuracy_Challenge_Sets.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Machine_Translation_Meta_Evaluation_through_Translation_Accuracy_Challenge_Sets/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16313v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The academic article introduces the ACES challenge set, a comprehensive contrastive challenge set spanning 146 language pairs to test machine translation (MT) evaluation metrics. It covers a wide range of phenomena, from basic alterations at the word/character level to more intricate errors based on discourse and real-world knowledge. The article discusses the creation of challenge sets to test MT evaluation metrics for different types of mistranslation errors, as well as the annotation of error spans in the ACES dataset. It provides an overview of the performance of metrics submitted to the WMT 2022 and 2023 shared tasks and discusses the impact of metric training data size on the performance of automatic MT evaluation metrics.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The ACES challenge set demonstrates that different metric families struggle with different phenomena, and Large Language Models (LLMs) fail to demonstrate reliable performance.</li>
<li>Metrics designed using Large Language Models (LLMs) struggle with the challenge set, indicating the need for better design strategies.</li>
<li>The size of the training data has a significant impact on the performance of automatic MT evaluation metrics, with metrics trained on more data showing improved performance across various categories.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article provides valuable insights into the strengths and weaknesses of different MT evaluation metrics across various linguistic phenomena. It highlights the complexity of evaluating machine translation and the need for comprehensive testing to ensure the accuracy and reliability of MT systems. The findings suggest the need for more holistic evaluation methods for MT metrics, focusing on error labels instead of scores, ensembling, and explicitly focusing on the source sentence. Additionally, the article emphasizes the importance of error-span labeling for MT evaluation, driving the development of the next generation of MT metrics. However, the article could benefit from further discussion on potential biases in the evaluation process and the generalizability of the findings. Further research is needed to address these limitations and to continue advancing the field of MT evaluation metrics.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-31</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16313v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16313v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16313v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16313v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>23702</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Machine_Translation_Meta_Evaluation_through_Translation_Accuracy_Challenge_Sets/2024-01-29-Machine_Translation_Meta_Evaluation_through_Translation_Accuracy_Challenge_Sets.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16313v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The role of library versions in Developer-ChatGPT conversations</title>
  <dc:creator>Rachna Raj, Diego Elias Costa</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/The_role_of_library_versions_in_Developer_ChatGPT_conversations/2024-01-29-The_role_of_library_versions_in_Developer_ChatGPT_conversations.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/The_role_of_library_versions_in_Developer_ChatGPT_conversations/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The article analyzes the role of library versions in Developer-ChatGPT conversations, focusing on the impact of library version constraints on code-related interactions. The study uses the DevGPT dataset, consisting of over 4,000 Developer-ChatGPT interactions, to quantify the frequency of library version constraints in conversations and understand how they are used. The findings reveal that library version constraints are mentioned in only 9% of the conversations, with the majority of constraints being prompted by users rather than specified by ChatGPT. The study also identifies potential problems related to library version constraints that require further research.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Library Version Constraints: Only 9% of the conversations in the DevGPT dataset include mentions of library version constraints, indicating that library versions are not frequently discussed in Developer-ChatGPT interactions.</li>
<li>User-Driven Constraints: The majority of library version constraints are prompted by users, suggesting that users employ different strategies to trigger more library version-aware responses from ChatGPT.</li>
<li>Role of Library Versions: Library versions play a significant role in configuration setup, troubleshooting incompatibility issues, and pinning dependencies in Developer-ChatGPT conversations.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The study provides valuable insights into the role of library versions in Developer-ChatGPT conversations. However, there are limitations to consider, such as the small size of the DevGPT dataset, which may not be fully representative of typical interactions. Additionally, the method for identifying library versions in conversations may have missed relevant discussions, potentially underestimating the frequency of library version constraints. Further research is needed to explore the effectiveness of ChatGPT in mapping library version ranges and its reliability in resolving incompatibility problems.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-31</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16340v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16340v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16340v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16340v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>4176</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/The_role_of_library_versions_in_Developer_ChatGPT_conversations/2024-01-29-The_role_of_library_versions_in_Developer_ChatGPT_conversations.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>An Empirical Study on Usage and Perceptions of LLMs in a Software Engineering Project</title>
  <dc:creator>Sanka Rasnayaka, Guanlin Wang, Ridwan Shariffdeen, Ganesh Neelakanta Iyer</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/An_Empirical_Study_on_Usage_and_Perceptions_of_LLMs_in_a_Software_Engineering_Project/2024-01-29-An_Empirical_Study_on_Usage_and_Perceptions_of_LLMs_in_a_Software_Engineering_Project.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/An_Empirical_Study_on_Usage_and_Perceptions_of_LLMs_in_a_Software_Engineering_Project/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<p>In this study, the usefulness of Large Language Models (LLMs) in an academic software engineering project is explored. The study involved 214 students working in teams, and the findings suggest that LLMs can play a crucial role in the early stages of software development, especially in generating foundational code structures and helping with syntax and error debugging. The study also provides insights into the perceived usefulness, influencing factors, and future outlook of LLMs from a computer science student’s perspective.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLMs can play a crucial role in the early stages of software development, especially in generating foundational code structures and helping with syntax and error debugging.</li>
<li>The study revealed that there was a reduction in LLM usage as the project progressed, with LLMs being used more for simpler tasks in the initial stages and for more complex code generation in later stages.</li>
<li>There was no significant difference in the correctness and quality of code between teams with heavy LLM usage, teams with light LLM usage, and teams that did not use LLMs at all.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The study provides valuable insights into the role of LLMs in software engineering projects and sheds light on the factors influencing their usage. However, the study is subject to limitations, such as incomplete data on LLM usage and prompts used for code generation. Additionally, the study was conducted in an academic setting and may not fully represent the constraints in the software industry. Despite these limitations, the study offers foundational insights into the role of LLMs in software engineering and highlights the need for students to develop skills for effective human-AI collaboration.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-31</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16186v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16186v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16186v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16186v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>11176</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/An_Empirical_Study_on_Usage_and_Perceptions_of_LLMs_in_a_Software_Engineering_Project/2024-01-29-An_Empirical_Study_on_Usage_and_Perceptions_of_LLMs_in_a_Software_Engineering_Project.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Knowledge-Aware Code Generation with Large Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Tao Huang, Zhihong Sun, Zhi Jin, Ge Li, Chen Lyu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Knowledge_Aware_Code_Generation_with_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-29-Knowledge_Aware_Code_Generation_with_Large_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Knowledge_Aware_Code_Generation_with_Large_Language_Models/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The academic article addresses the challenges faced by Large Language Models (LLMs) in handling complex programming problems and introduces a novel dataset, CodeF, to address this issue. It proposes a Knowledge Library for Python programming problems and a new approach called Knowledge-Aware Code Generation (KareCoder) to enhance LLMs’ problem-solving capabilities. The article also discusses the distribution of algorithms and data structure tags in the CodeF dataset and evaluates the effectiveness of KareCoder in code generation using ChatGPT and the SCOT&amp;KareCoder method. Additionally, it emphasizes the limitations of the current training data for ChatGPT and the need for additional datasets to verify the effectiveness of KareCoder in code generation.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The introduction of the CodeF dataset and the Knowledge Library provides valuable resources for further research and development in the field of code generation with LLMs.</li>
<li>KareCoder demonstrates outstanding performance in handling novel problems previously unencountered by LLMs, highlighting its potential impact on the future development of LLMs for code generation tasks.</li>
<li>The limitations of the current training data for ChatGPT raise concerns about the validity and reliability of the research findings, emphasizing the need for additional datasets to verify the effectiveness of KareCoder in code generation.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article’s proposed approach, KareCoder, shows promise in addressing the limitations of LLMs in handling complex programming problems. However, there are potential limitations and challenges, such as the need for a more comprehensive knowledge library and better methods of integrating knowledge. Additionally, the limited availability of training data for ChatGPT raises concerns about the validity and reliability of the research findings, emphasizing the need for continuous exploration of new data to ensure the effectiveness and relevance of KareCoder in code generation. Further research is needed to address these limitations and validate the effectiveness of KareCoder in real-world applications.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-31</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.15940v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.15940v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.15940v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.15940v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>16912</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>programming</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Knowledge_Aware_Code_Generation_with_Large_Language_Models/2024-01-29-Knowledge_Aware_Code_Generation_with_Large_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Corrective Retrieval Augmented Generation</title>
  <dc:creator>Shi-Qi Yan, Jia-Chen Gu, Yun Zhu, Zhen-Hua Ling</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Corrective_Retrieval_Augmented_Generation/2024-01-29-Corrective_Retrieval_Augmented_Generation.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Corrective_Retrieval_Augmented_Generation/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<p>The article proposes Corrective Retrieval Augmented Generation (CRAG) to improve the robustness of generation in large language models (LLMs). The proposed method aims to address the issue of inaccurate knowledge retrieval in retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) approaches.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><strong>Hallucinations in LLMs:</strong> LLMs exhibit hallucinations due to their struggle with factual errors and inability to secure the accuracy of generated texts solely by the parametric knowledge they encapsulate.</li>
<li><strong>Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG):</strong> RAG serves as a practicable complement to LLMs, but its effectiveness is contingent upon the relevance and accuracy of the retrieved documents.</li>
<li><strong>Proposed Corrective Strategies:</strong> The article introduces Corrective Retrieval Augmented Generation (CRAG) to self-correct the results of retriever and improve the utilization of documents for augmenting generation.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article provides a comprehensive overview of the challenges associated with retrieval-augmented generation and proposes a novel method, CRAG, to address these challenges. The proposed method is shown to significantly improve the performance of RAG-based approaches across various generation tasks. However, the article does not thoroughly discuss potential limitations or biases associated with the proposed method. Further research is needed to evaluate the generalizability and scalability of CRAG across different language models and datasets. Additionally, the article could benefit from a more in-depth discussion of the practical implications and real-world applications of CRAG.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-31</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.15884v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.15884v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.15884v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.15884v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>12980</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Corrective_Retrieval_Augmented_Generation/2024-01-29-Corrective_Retrieval_Augmented_Generation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Tradeoffs Between Alignment and Helpfulness in Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Yotam Wolf, Noam Wies, Dorin Shteyman, Binyamin Rothberg, Yoav Levine, Amnon Shashua</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Tradeoffs_Between_Alignment_and_Helpfulness_in_Language_Models/2024-01-29-Tradeoffs_Between_Alignment_and_Helpfulness_in_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Tradeoffs_Between_Alignment_and_Helpfulness_in_Language_Models/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16332v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The article discusses the tradeoffs between alignment and helpfulness in language models (LLMs). It explores representation engineering as a method to alter the behavior of LLMs post-training, showing that it can improve alignment but reduce the helpfulness of the model. The authors propose a theoretical framework that provides bounds for these two quantities and demonstrate their relevance empirically. The findings suggest that while the helpfulness generally decreases, it does so quadratically with the norm of the representation engineering vector, while the alignment increases linearly with it, indicating a regime in which it is efficient to use representation engineering.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Representation engineering yields gains in alignment-oriented tasks such as resistance to adversarial attacks and reduction of social biases but causes a decrease in the ability of the model to perform basic tasks.</li>
<li>The helpfulness of the model decreases quadratically with the representation engineering vector norm, while the alignment increases linearly with it, indicating a tradeoff between alignment and helpfulness.</li>
<li>The linear increase in alignment and parabolic decrease in helpfulness suggest a regime where representation engineering is more effective.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article provides valuable insights into the tradeoffs between alignment and helpfulness in LLMs. However, it is important to note that the linear and quadratic relationships between alignment and helpfulness may not hold universally across all LLMs and tasks. Additionally, the study’s focus on representation engineering as a method for alignment may overlook other potential approaches or combinations of methods that could achieve better tradeoffs. Further research is needed to validate the findings across different LLM architectures and datasets. Additionally, the article’s theoretical framework and empirical evidence provide a strong foundation for future studies in this area.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-31</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16332v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16332v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16332v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16332v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>8041</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>security</category>
  <category>architectures</category>
  <category>production</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Tradeoffs_Between_Alignment_and_Helpfulness_in_Language_Models/2024-01-29-Tradeoffs_Between_Alignment_and_Helpfulness_in_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.16332v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>OpineBot: Class Feedback Reimagined Using a Conversational LLM</title>
  <dc:creator>Henansh Tanwar, Kunal Shrivastva, Rahul Singh, Dhruv Kumar</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/OpineBot_Class_Feedback_Reimagined_Using_a_Conversational_LLM/2024-01-28-OpineBot_Class_Feedback_Reimagined_Using_a_Conversational_LLM.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/OpineBot_Class_Feedback_Reimagined_Using_a_Conversational_LLM/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.15589v1/extracted/5373215/Images/OpineBot_HLD.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<p>The article introduces OpineBot, a novel system utilizing Large Language Models (LLMs) to conduct personalized, conversational class feedback via a chatbot interface. The study assesses OpineBot’s effectiveness in a user study with 20 students from an Indian university’s Operating-Systems class, revealing a preference for OpineBot compared to conventional methods. The research marks a significant step towards revolutionizing class feedback through LLM-based technology, promoting student engagement, and leading to richer data for instructors.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>OpineBot was preferred over conventional methods, highlighting its ability to engage students and produce deeper feedback.</li>
<li>The integration of LLMs for dynamic surveys was successful, leading to a more personalized survey experience.</li>
<li>OpineBot positively influenced user engagement, comfort, and feedback contribution factors, as evidenced by high ratings in these areas.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article presents a promising approach to revolutionizing class feedback through LLM-based technology. However, the study’s limitations, such as a small sample size and course specificity, raise questions about the generalizability of the findings. Additionally, the potential long-term impact of LLM-based surveys on learning outcomes and ethical considerations require further exploration. Despite these limitations, OpineBot’s success in academia suggests broader applications in diverse domains, indicating its potential to revolutionize feedback collection and engagement across different contexts. Further research is needed to explore the broader implications and potential contributions of OpineBot’s conversational approach.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-31</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.15589v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.15589v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.15589v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.15589v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>5595</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>hci</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/OpineBot_Class_Feedback_Reimagined_Using_a_Conversational_LLM/2024-01-28-OpineBot_Class_Feedback_Reimagined_Using_a_Conversational_LLM.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.15589v1/extracted/5373215/Images/OpineBot_HLD.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>YODA: Teacher-Student Progressive Learning for Language Models</title>
  <dc:creator>Jianqiao Lu, Wanjun Zhong, Yufei Wang, Zhijiang Guo, Qi Zhu, Wenyong Huang, Yanlin Wang, Fei Mi, Baojun Wang, Yasheng Wang, Lifeng Shang, Xin Jiang, Qun Liu</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/YODA_Teacher_Student_Progressive_Learning_for_Language_Models/2024-01-28-YODA_Teacher_Student_Progressive_Learning_for_Language_Models.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/YODA_Teacher_Student_Progressive_Learning_for_Language_Models/None.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The article introduces the YODA framework, a teacher-student progressive learning approach that emulates human education processes to enhance model fine-tuning. It leverages the QAFR-dataset and a training objective focused on iterative refinement to improve model learning effectiveness. The training details highlight the hyperparameters and iterative refinement process used in the experiments, while the model to elicit mathematical abilities section discusses recent successes of Language Model Models (LLMs) in mathematical reasoning and the methods used to enhance training dataset quality and accuracy.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>The YODA framework significantly improves model performance in math reasoning tasks.</li>
<li>The training objective focuses on leveraging procedural data for training the candidate model and assessing the accuracy of student responses and the effectiveness of teacher feedback.</li>
<li>Recent advancements in LLMs have shown significant success in mathematical reasoning, achieving comparable accuracy to fine-tuned baselines with minimal examples of problem-solving processes.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The YODA framework introduces a human-like progressive learning approach to enhance model learning effectiveness, addressing the data scarcity problem by effectively exploring and extrapolating from limited unlabeled problems. The QAFR-dataset and training objective emphasize the importance of iterative refinement in enhancing model learning, setting the stage for subsequent experiments. The training details provide crucial information about the methodology and approach used in the experiments, contributing to the broader context of the paper’s research on LLMs for mathematical reasoning. The section on the model to elicit mathematical abilities highlights recent successes of LLMs in mathematical reasoning and the methods used to enhance the training dataset’s quality and accuracy, providing insight into the diverse approaches used to train the model.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-31</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.15670v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.15670v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.15670v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.15670v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>True</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>15562</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>education</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/YODA_Teacher_Student_Progressive_Learning_for_Language_Models/2024-01-28-YODA_Teacher_Student_Progressive_Learning_for_Language_Models.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/bayesian-beagle.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>LLsM: Generative Linguistic Steganography with Large Language Model</title>
  <dc:creator>Yihao Wang, Ruiqi Song, Ru Zhang, Jianyi Liu, Lingxiao Li</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLsM_Generative_Linguistic_Steganography_with_Large_Language_Model/2024-01-28-LLsM_Generative_Linguistic_Steganography_with_Large_Language_Model.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLsM_Generative_Linguistic_Steganography_with_Large_Language_Model/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.15656v1/x1.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<p>The article introduces a novel scheme named LLsM, a generative Linguistic Steganography (LS) based on a Large Language Model (LLM). The scheme aims to generate steganographic texts with specific discourse characteristics in a controllable manner. The proposed LLsM utilizes fine-tuned LLM to generate texts with specific discourse and employs range encoding to ensure the stego imitates natural text distribution. Experiments demonstrate that LLsM outperforms prevalent baselines regarding text quality, statistical analysis, discourse matching, and anti-steganalysis.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>LLsM performs superior to prevalent baselines regarding text quality, statistical analysis, discourse matching, and anti-steganalysis.</li>
<li>The proposed LLsM is the first effort on LS tasks with a larger-scale language model, fine-tuning the LLM with a large-scale constructed dataset encompassing rich discourse characteristics.</li>
<li>LLsM utilizes range coding for encoding the candidate pool, ensuring the stego imitates natural text distribution and exhibits specific discourse characteristics.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The article presents a novel and promising approach to address the challenges of linguistic steganography. However, it is essential to consider potential limitations and unanswered questions. The article does not explicitly discuss the potential ethical implications of using linguistic steganography for covert communication. Additionally, the generalizability of the proposed LLsM scheme to different languages and text genres is not thoroughly explored. Further research is needed to validate the effectiveness of LLsM across diverse linguistic contexts and to address potential ethical concerns related to covert communication.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-31</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.15656v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.15656v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.15656v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.15656v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>4564</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/LLsM_Generative_Linguistic_Steganography_with_Large_Language_Model/2024-01-28-LLsM_Generative_Linguistic_Steganography_with_Large_Language_Model.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.15656v1/x1.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Evaluating Gender Bias in Large Language Models via Chain-of-Thought Prompting</title>
  <dc:creator>Masahiro Kaneko, Danushka Bollegala, Naoaki Okazaki, Timothy Baldwin</dc:creator>
  <link>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Evaluating_Gender_Bias_in_Large_Language_Models_via_Chain_of_Thought_Prompting/2024-01-28-Evaluating_Gender_Bias_in_Large_Language_Models_via_Chain_of_Thought_Prompting.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Evaluating_Gender_Bias_in_Large_Language_Models_via_Chain_of_Thought_Prompting/https:/browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.15585v1/extracted/5373213/abst.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="summary" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="summary"><strong>Summary:</strong></h3>
<p>The study evaluates the impact of Large Language Models (LLMs) equipped with Chain-of-Thought (CoT) prompting on gender bias in unscalable tasks. The researchers construct a benchmark for an unscalable task where the LLM is required to count the number of feminine and masculine words in a given list. Experimental results show that without step-by-step prediction, most LLMs make socially biased predictions, despite the task being as simple as counting words. Interestingly, CoT prompting reduces this unconscious social bias in LLMs and encourages fair predictions.</p>
</section>
<section id="major-findings" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="major-findings">Major Findings:</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Large language models (LLMs) equipped with Chain-of-Thought (CoT) prompting are able to make accurate incremental predictions even on unscalable tasks.</li>
<li>Experimental results show that without step-by-step prediction, most LLMs make socially biased predictions, despite the task being as simple as counting words.</li>
<li>CoT prompting reduces unconscious social bias in LLMs and encourages fair predictions.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="analysis-and-critique" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="analysis-and-critique">Analysis and Critique:</h3>
<p>The study provides valuable insights into the impact of CoT prompting on gender bias in unscalable tasks. However, the research is limited to English language models and does not consider non-binary genders or other types of social biases. Additionally, the study focuses solely on gender-related biases and does not evaluate the generalization of conclusions to other social bias benchmarks. Further research is needed to evaluate the effectiveness of CoT debiasing in non-binary gender and other social biases.</p>
</section>
<section id="appendix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="appendix">Appendix</h2>
<table class="table">
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Model</td>
<td>gpt-3.5-turbo-1106</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Date Generated</td>
<td>2024-01-31</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Abstract</td>
<td><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.15585v1">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.15585v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>HTML</td>
<td><a href="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.15585v1">https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.15585v1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Truncated</td>
<td>False</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Word Count</td>
<td>6157</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>robustness</category>
  <category>prompt-engineering</category>
  <category>social-sciences</category>
  <guid>https://bayesian-beagle.netlify.app/posts/Evaluating_Gender_Bias_in_Large_Language_Models_via_Chain_of_Thought_Prompting/2024-01-28-Evaluating_Gender_Bias_in_Large_Language_Models_via_Chain_of_Thought_Prompting.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://browse.arxiv.org/html/2401.15585v1/extracted/5373213/abst.png" medium="image" type="image/png"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
